<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>high redshift on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/high-redshift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in high redshift on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/high-redshift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Anti)kaon condensation in strongly magnetized dense matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/antikaon_condensation_in_strongly_magnetized_dense_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/antikaon_condensation_in_strongly_magnetized_dense_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Debraj Kundu
Recent observations of several massive pulsars, with masses near and above $2~M_\odot$, point towards the existence of matter at very high densities, compared to normal matter that we are familiar with in our terrestrial world. This leads to the possibility of appearance of exotic degrees of freedom other than nucleons inside the core of the neutrons stars (NS). Another significant property of NSs is the presence of high surface magnetic field, with highest range of the order of $\sim~10^{16}$ G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$Hubble~Space~Telescope$ Reveals Spectacular Light Echoes Associated with the Stripped-envelope Supernova 2016adj in the Iconic Dust Lane of Centaurus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maximilian Stritzinger
We present a multi-band sequence of $Hubble~Space~Telescope$ images documenting the emergence and evolution of multiple light echoes (LEs) linked to the stripped-envelope supernova (SN) 2016adj located in the central dust-lane of Centaurus A. Following point-spread function subtraction, we identify the earliest LE emission associated with a SN at only $+$34 days (d) past the epoch of $B$-band maximum. Additional HST images extending through $+$578 d cover the evolution of LE1 taking the form of a ring, while images taken on $+$1991 d reveals not only LE1, but also segments of a new inner LE ring (LE2) as well as two additional outer LE rings (LE3 &amp;amp; LE4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Callisto&#39;s atmosphere: First evidence for H2 and constraints on H2O</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/callistos_atmosphere_first_evidence_for_h2_and_constraints_on_h2o/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/callistos_atmosphere_first_evidence_for_h2_and_constraints_on_h2o/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shane R. Carberry Mogan
We explore the parameter space for the contribution to Callisto&amp;rsquo;s H corona observed by the Hubble Space Telescope (Roth et al. 2017a) from sublimated H2O and radiolytically produced H2 using the Direct Simulation Monte Carlo (DSMC) method. The spatial morphology of this corona produced via photo- and magnetospheric electron impact-induced dissociation is described by tracking the motion of and simulating collisions between the hot H atoms and thermal molecules including a near-surface O2 component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEERS Key Paper IV: The Diversity of Galaxy Structure and Morphology at z=3-9 with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/ceers_key_paper_iv_the_diversity_of_galaxy_structure_and_morphology_at_z3-9_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/ceers_key_paper_iv_the_diversity_of_galaxy_structure_and_morphology_at_z3-9_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeyhan S. Kartaltepe
We present a comprehensive analysis of the evolution of the morphological and structural properties of a large sample of galaxies at z=3-9 using early JWST CEERS NIRCam observations. Our sample consists of 850 galaxies at z&amp;gt;3 detected in both CANDELS HST imaging and JWST CEERS NIRCam images to enable a comparison of HST and JWST morphologies. Our team conducted a set of visual classifications, with each galaxy in the sample classified by three different individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Inner Halo Angular Momentum on the Peanut/X-shapes of Bars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/effects_of_inner_halo_angular_momentum_on_the_peanut_x-shapes_of_bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/effects_of_inner_halo_angular_momentum_on_the_peanut_x-shapes_of_bars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sandeep Kumar Kataria
Cosmological simulations show that dark matter halos surrounding baryonic disks have a wide range of angular momenta, measured by the spin parameter ($\lambda$). In this study, we bring out the importance of inner angular momentum($&amp;lt;$30 kpc), measured in terms of the halo spin parameter, on the secular evolution of the bar using N-body simulations. We have varied the halo spin parameter $\lambda$ from 0 to 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of pits at the surface of 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evolution_of_pits_at_the_surface_of_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evolution_of_pits_at_the_surface_of_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</guid>
      <description>First author: Selma Benseguane
The observation of pits at the surface of comets offers the opportunity to take a glimpse into the properties and the mechanisms that shape a nucleus through cometary activity. If the origin of these pits is still a matter of debate, multiple studies have recently suggested that known phase transitions alone could not have carved these morphological features on the surface of 67P/C-G. We want to understand how the progressive modification of 67P&amp;rsquo;s surface due to cometary activity might have affected the characteristics of pits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Short-Term Optical Variability of Blazars Using $	extit{TESS}$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exploring_short-term_optical_variability_of_blazars_using___textittess_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exploring_short-term_optical_variability_of_blazars_using___textittess_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vivek Reddy Pininti
We present a first systematic time series study of a sample of blazars observed by the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite $\textit{TESS}$ spacecraft. By cross matching the positions of the sources in the TESS observations with those from Roma-BZCAT, 29 blazars including both BL Lacerate objects and flat-spectrum radio quasars were identified. The observation lengths of the 79 light curves of the sources, across all sectors on which the targets of interest have been observed by $\textit{TESS}$, range between 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far Ultra-Violet Insights Into NGC 1399&#39;s Globular Cluster Population</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/far_ultra-violet_insights_into_ngc_1399s_globular_cluster_population/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/far_ultra-violet_insights_into_ngc_1399s_globular_cluster_population/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kristen C. Dage
We investigate archival Hubble Space Telescope ACS/SBC F140LP observations of NGC~1399 to search for evidence of multiple stellar populations in extragalactic globular clusters. Enhanced FUV populations are thought to be indicators of He-enhanced second generation populations in globular clusters, specifically extreme/blue horizontal branch stars. Out of 149 globular clusters in the field of view, 58 have far ultraviolet (FUV) counterparts with magnitudes brighter than 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint photon-electron Lorentz violation parameter plane from LHAASO data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/joint_photon-electron_lorentz_violation_parameter_plane_from_lhaaso_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/joint_photon-electron_lorentz_violation_parameter_plane_from_lhaaso_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ping He
The Large High Altitude Air Shower Observatory~(LHAASO) is one of the most sensitive gamma-ray detector arrays, whose ultrahigh-energy~(UHE) work bands not only help to study the origin and acceleration mechanism of UHE cosmic rays, but also provide the opportunity to test fundamental physics concepts such as Lorentz symmetry. LHAASO directly observes the $1.42~\mathrm{PeV}$ highest-energy photon. By adopting the synchrotion self-Compton model LHAASO also suggests that the $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical simulations of MHD jets from Keplerian accretion disks I-Recollimation shocks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulations_of_mhd_jets_from_keplerian_accretion_disks_i-recollimation_shocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulations_of_mhd_jets_from_keplerian_accretion_disks_i-recollimation_shocks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Thomas Jannaud
Aims. We wish to establish a firm link between jet simulations and analytical studies of magnetically-driven steady-state jets from Keplerian accretion disks. In particular, the latter have predicted the existence of recollimation shocks due to the dominant hoop-stress, so far never observed in platform simulations. Methods. We perform a set of axisymmetric MHD simulations of non-relativistic jets using the PLUTO code. The simulations are designed to reproduce the boundary conditions generally expected in analytical studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redshift-evolutionary X-ray and UV luminosity relation of quasars from Gaussian copula</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/redshift-evolutionary_x-ray_and_uv_luminosity_relation_of_quasars_from_gaussian_copula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/redshift-evolutionary_x-ray_and_uv_luminosity_relation_of_quasars_from_gaussian_copula/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bao Wang
We construct a three-dimensional and redshift-evolutionary X-ray and ultraviolet ($L_X-L_{UV}$) luminosity relation for quasars from the powerful statistic tool called copula, and find that the constructed $L_X-L_{UV}$ relation from copula is more viable than the standard one and the observations favor the redshift-evolutionary relation more than $3\sigma$. The Akaike and Bayes information criterions indicate that the quasar data support strongly the three-dimensional $L_X-L_{UV}$ relation. Our results show that the quasars can be regarded as a reliable indicator of the cosmic distance if the $L_X-L_{UV}$ relation from copula is used to calibrate quasar data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for shell stars in LAMOST DR4 by probing the Fe 42 multiplet lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/searching_for_shell_stars_in_lamost_dr4_by_probing_the_fe_42_multiplet_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/searching_for_shell_stars_in_lamost_dr4_by_probing_the_fe_42_multiplet_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Huemmerich
Shell stars, in particular the cooler ones, often do not show conspicuous Balmer-line emission and may consequently be missed in surveys that specifically search for emission signatures in the Halpha line. The present work is aimed at identifying stars with shell-signatures via a search for strong FeII multiplet 42 lines at 4924, 5018, 5169A in archival LAMOST spectra. Candidates were selected by probing the FeII 42 lines in the spectra of a sample of colour-preselected early-type stars using a modified version of the MKCLASS code and then categorised by visual inspection of their spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sulphur monoxide emission tracing an embedded planet in the HD 100546 protoplanetary disk</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/sulphur_monoxide_emission_tracing_an_embedded_planet_in_the_hd_100546_protoplanetary_disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/sulphur_monoxide_emission_tracing_an_embedded_planet_in_the_hd_100546_protoplanetary_disk/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alice S. Booth
Molecular line observations are powerful tracers of the physical and chemical conditions across the different evolutionary stages of star, disk and planet formation. Using the high angular resolution and unprecedented sensitivity of the Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) there is now a drive to detect small-scale gas structures in protoplanetary disks that can be attributed directly to forming planets. We report high angular resolution ALMA Band 7 observations of sulphur monoxide (SO) in the nearby planet-hosting disk around Herbig star HD 100546.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-1075 b: A Dense, Massive, Ultra-Short Period Hot Super-Earth Straddling the Radius Gap</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/toi-1075_b_a_dense_massive_ultra-short_period_hot_super-earth_straddling_the_radius_gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/toi-1075_b_a_dense_massive_ultra-short_period_hot_super-earth_straddling_the_radius_gap/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zahra Essack
Populating the exoplanet mass-radius diagram in order to identify the underlying relationship that governs planet composition is driving an interdisciplinary effort within the exoplanet community. The discovery of hot super-Earths - a high temperature, short-period subset of the super-Earth planet population - has presented many unresolved questions concerning the formation, evolution, and composition of rocky planets. We report the discovery of a transiting, ultra-short period hot super-Earth orbiting TOI-1075 (TIC 351601843), a nearby ($d$ = 61.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A long life of excess: The interacting transient SN 2017hcc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_long_life_of_excess_the_interacting_transient_sn_2017hcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_long_life_of_excess_the_interacting_transient_sn_2017hcc/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Moran
In this study we present the results of a five-year follow-up campaign of the long-lived type IIn supernova SN 2017hcc, found in a spiral dwarf host of near-solar metallicity. The long rise time (57 $\pm$ 2 days, ATLAS $o$ band) and high luminosity (peaking at $-$20.78 $\pm$ 0.01 mag in the ATLAS $o$ band) point towards an interaction of massive ejecta with massive and dense circumstellar material (CSM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel approach to correcting $T_e$-based mass-metallicity relations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_novel_approach_to_correcting__t_e_-based_mass-metallicity_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_novel_approach_to_correcting__t_e_-based_mass-metallicity_relations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex J. Cameron
Deriving oxygen abundances from the electron temperature (hereafter the $T_e$-method) is the gold-standard for extragalactic metallicity studies. However, unresolved temperature fluctuations in HII regions can bias metallicity estimates low, with a magnitude that depends on the underlying and typically unknown temperature distribution. Using a toy model, we confirm that computing $T_e$-based metallicities using the temperature derived from the [O III] $\lambda$4363/$\lambda$5007 ratio (&amp;lsquo;ratio temperature&amp;rsquo;; $T_{\rm ratio}$) results in an underprediction of metallicity when temperature fluctuations are present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A statistical study of magnetic field changes in the photosphere during solar flares using high-cadence vector magnetograms and their association with flare ribbons</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_statistical_study_of_magnetic_field_changes_in_the_photosphere_during_solar_flares_using_high-cadence_vector_magnetograms_and_their_association_with_flare_ribbons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_statistical_study_of_magnetic_field_changes_in_the_photosphere_during_solar_flares_using_high-cadence_vector_magnetograms_and_their_association_with_flare_ribbons/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rahul Yadav
Abrupt and permanent photospheric magnetic field changes have been observed in many flares. It is believed that such changes are related to the reconfiguration of magnetic field lines, however, the real origin is still unclear. In this study we analyze 37 flares to understand the magnetic field vector changes in the photosphere using high-cadence (135 s) vector magnetograms obtained from the HMI/SDO. We also co-align these magnetogram sequences with flare ribbon images (1600 \AA), obtained from the AIA/SDO, to understand how the field change is associated with the ribbon morphology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active focal-plane coronagraphy with liquid-crystal spatial-light modulators: Broadband contrast performance in the visible</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/active_focal-plane_coronagraphy_with_liquid-crystal_spatial-light_modulators_broadband_contrast_performance_in_the_visible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/active_focal-plane_coronagraphy_with_liquid-crystal_spatial-light_modulators_broadband_contrast_performance_in_the_visible/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. G. Kuhn
The technological progress in spatial-light modulators (SLM) technology has made it possible to use those devices as programmable active focal-plane phase coronagraphic masks, opening the door to novel versatile and adaptive high-contrast imaging observation strategies. However, the scalar nature of the SLM-induced phase response is a potential hurdle when applying the approach to wideband light, as is typical in astronomical imaging. For the first time, we present laboratory results with broadband light (up to ~12pc bandwidth) for two commercially-available SLM devices used as active focal-plane phase masks in the visible regime (640 nm).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unbiased method of measuring the ratio of two data sets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_unbiased_method_of_measuring_the_ratio_of_two_data_sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_unbiased_method_of_measuring_the_ratio_of_two_data_sets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zeyang Sun
In certain cases of astronomical data analysis, the meaningful physical quantity to extract is the ratio $R$ between two data sets. Examples include the lensing ratio, the interloper rate in spectroscopic redshift samples, the decay rate of gravitational potential and $E_G$ to test gravity. However, simply taking the ratio of the two data sets is biased, since it renders (even statistical) errors in the denominator into systematic errors in $R$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the ionized interstellar medium and orbital dynamics of PSR~J1909-3744 using scintillation arcs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/analysis_of_the_ionized_interstellar_medium_and_orbital_dynamics_of_psr~j1909-3744_using_scintillation_arcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/analysis_of_the_ionized_interstellar_medium_and_orbital_dynamics_of_psr~j1909-3744_using_scintillation_arcs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacob Askew
Long-term studies of binary millisecond pulsars (MSPs) provide precise tests of strong-field gravity and can be used to measure neutron-star masses. PSR~J1909$-$3744, a binary MSP has been the subject of several pulsar timing analyses. The edge-on orbit enables measurement of its mass using the Shapiro delay; however, there is degeneracy in the sense of the inclination angle, $i$, and multiple solutions for the longitude of ascending node, $\Omega$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibration of the first detector flight models for the HERMES constellation and the SpIRIT mission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/calibration_of_the_first_detector_flight_models_for_the_hermes_constellation_and_the_spirit_mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/calibration_of_the_first_detector_flight_models_for_the_hermes_constellation_and_the_spirit_mission/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Campana
HERMES (High Energy Rapid Modular Ensemble of Satellites) is a space-borne mission based on a constellation of six 3U CubeSats flying in a low-Earth orbit, hosting new miniaturized instruments based on a hybrid Silicon Drift Detector/GAGG:Ce scintillator photodetector system sensitive to X-rays and gamma-rays. Moreover, the HERMES constellation will operate in conjunction with the Australian-Italian Space Industry Responsive Intelligent Thermal (SpIRIT) 6U CubeSat, that will carry in a Sun-synchronous orbit (SSO) an actively cooled HERMES detector system payload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clusteringenesis: from Light to Heavy Primordial Black Holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/clusteringenesis_from_light_to_heavy_primordial_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/clusteringenesis_from_light_to_heavy_primordial_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Valerio De Luca
We show that heavy primordial black holes may originate from much lighter ones if the latter are strongly clustered at the time of their formation. While this population is subject to the usual constraints from late-time universe observations, its relation to the initial conditions is different from the standard scenario and provides a new mechanism to generate massive primordial black holes even in the absence of efficient accretion, opening new scenarios, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Report from the Biosignatures Standards of Evidence Workshop</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/community_report_from_the_biosignatures_standards_of_evidence_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/community_report_from_the_biosignatures_standards_of_evidence_workshop/</guid>
      <description>First author: Victoria Meadows
The search for life beyond the Earth is the overarching goal of the NASA Astrobiology Program, and it underpins the science of missions that explore the environments of Solar System planets and exoplanets. However, the detection of extraterrestrial life, in our Solar System and beyond, is sufficiently challenging that it is likely that multiple measurements and approaches, spanning disciplines and missions, will be needed to make a convincing claim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Cosmic-ray Transport with Observations of the Circumgalactic Medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_cosmic-ray_transport_with_observations_of_the_circumgalactic_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_cosmic-ray_transport_with_observations_of_the_circumgalactic_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iryna S. Butsky
Recent theoretical studies predict that the circumgalactic medium (CGM) around low-redshift, $\sim L_{\ast}$ galaxies could have substantial nonthermal pressure support in the form of cosmic rays. However, these predictions are sensitive to the specific model of cosmic-ray transport employed, which is theoretically and observationally underconstrained. In this work, we propose a novel observational constraint for calculating the lower limit of the radially-averaged, effective cosmic-ray transport rate, $\kappa_{\rm min}^{\rm eff}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting dark matter to dark radiation does not solve cosmological tensions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/converting_dark_matter_to_dark_radiation_does_not_solve_cosmological_tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/converting_dark_matter_to_dark_radiation_does_not_solve_cosmological_tensions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fiona McCarthy
Tensions between cosmological parameters (in particular the local expansion rate $H_0$ and the amplitude of matter clustering $S_8$) inferred from low-redshift data and data from the cosmic microwave background (CMB) and large-scale structure (LSS) experiments have inspired many extensions to the standard cosmological model, $\Lambda$CDM. Models which simultaneously lessen both tensions are of particular interest. We consider one scenario with the potential for such a resolution, in which some fraction of the dark matter has converted into dark radiation since the release of the CMB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic ray anisotropy study by means of detection of muon bundles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmic_ray_anisotropy_study_by_means_of_detection_of_muon_bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmic_ray_anisotropy_study_by_means_of_detection_of_muon_bundles/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Trinchero
In this work, we use muon bundles which are formed in extensive air showers and detected at the ground level as a tool for searching anisotropy of high energy cosmic rays. Such choice is explained by the penetrating ability of muons which allows them to retain the direction of primary particles with a good accuracy. In 2012-2022, we performed long-term muon bundle detection with the coordinate-tracking detector DECOR, which is a part of the Experimental complex NEVOD (MEPhI, Moscow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crustal failure as a tool to probe hybrid stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/crustal_failure_as_a_tool_to_probe_hybrid_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/crustal_failure_as_a_tool_to_probe_hybrid_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jonas P. Pereira
It is currently unknown if neutron stars are composed of nucleons only or are hybrid stars, i.e., in addition to nucleonic crusts and outer cores, they also possess quark cores. Quantum chromodynamics allows for such a phase transition possibility, but accurate calculations in the range of interest for compact stars are still elusive. Here we investigate some crust-breaking aspects of hybrid stars. We show that the crust-breaking orbital/gravitational wave frequency and maximum ellipticity are sensitive to the quark-hadron density jump and equation of state stiffness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, integration, and test of the scientific payloads on-board the HERMES constellation and the SpIRIT mission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/design_integration_and_test_of_the_scientific_payloads_on-board_the_hermes_constellation_and_the_spirit_mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/design_integration_and_test_of_the_scientific_payloads_on-board_the_hermes_constellation_and_the_spirit_mission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Evangelista
HERMES (High Energy Rapid Modular Ensemble of Satellites) is a space-borne mission based on a constellation of nano-satellites flying in a low-Earth orbit (LEO). The six 3U CubeSat buses host new miniaturized instruments hosting a hybrid Silicon Drift Detector/GAGG:Ce scintillator photodetector system sensitive to X-rays and gamma-rays. HERMES will probe the temporal emission of bright high-energy transients such as Gamma-Ray Bursts (GRBs), ensuring a fast transient localization (with arcmin-level accuracy) in a field of view of several steradians exploiting the triangulation technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEVILS: Cosmic evolution of SED-derived metallicities and their connection to star-formation histories</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/devils_cosmic_evolution_of_sed-derived_metallicities_and_their_connection_to_star-formation_histories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/devils_cosmic_evolution_of_sed-derived_metallicities_and_their_connection_to_star-formation_histories/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica E. Thorne
Gas-phase metallicities of galaxies are typically measured through auroral or nebular emission lines, but metallicity also leaves an imprint on the overall spectral energy distribution (SED) of a galaxy and can be estimated through SED fitting. We use the ProSpect SED fitting code with a flexible parametric star formation history and an evolving metallicity history to self-consistently measure metallicities, stellar mass, and other galaxy properties for $\sim90,000$ galaxies from the Deep Extragalactic VIsible Legacy Survey (DEVILS) and Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA) survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elemental Abundances of Kepler Objects of Interest in APOGEE DR17</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elemental_abundances_of_kepler_objects_of_interest_in_apogee_dr17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elemental_abundances_of_kepler_objects_of_interest_in_apogee_dr17/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aida Behmard
The elemental abundances of planet host stars can shed light on the conditions of planet forming environments. We test if individual abundances of 130 known/candidate planet hosts in APOGEE are statistically different from those of a reference doppelganger sample. The reference set comprises objects selected with the same Teff, logg, [Fe/H], and [Mg/H] as each Kepler Object of Interest (KOI). We predict twelve individual abundances (X = C, N, O, Na, Al, Si, Ca, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Ni) for the KOIs and their doppelgangers using a local linear model of these four parameters, training on ASPCAP abundance measurements for a sample of field stars with high fidelity (SNR &amp;gt; 200) APOGEE observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FRB emission mechanisms vs. observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/frb_emission_mechanisms_vs._observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/frb_emission_mechanisms_vs._observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Popov S. B.
Presently, it is broadly assumed that fast radio bursts (FRBs) are sources of coherent emission powered by the magnetic energy release in magnetars. However, the exact emission mechanism is not known, yet. Two main frameworks exist: magnetospheric emission and radiation from external relativistic shocks. In this brief review, I describe basics of both approaches and discuss how they are probed by modern observations.
arxiv link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HERMES-Pathfinder</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hermes-pathfinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hermes-pathfinder/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrizio Fiore
HERMES-Pathfinder is a constellation of six 3U nano-satellites hosting simple but innovative X-ray detectors for determining the positions of, and monitoring cosmic high-energy transients such as gamma-ray bursts and the electromagnetic counterparts of gravitational Wave Events. The HERMES Technological Pathfinder project is funded by the Italian Space Agency, while the HERMES Scientific Pathfinder project is funded by the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 Research and Innovation Programme under Grant Agreement No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we explain last UHERC anisotropies?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/how_can_we_explain_last_uherc_anisotropies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/how_can_we_explain_last_uherc_anisotropies/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Fargion
We consider the recent results on UHECR (Ultra High Energy Cosmic Ray), clustering, composition, distribution in the sky, from the energy of several EeV with the dipole anisotropy up to the highest ones. We have suggested since 2008 and we reconfirm here that UHECR at 40 up to 70 EeV are mostly made by light and lightest nuclei. The remarkable Virgo absence and the few localized nearby extragalactic sources as CenA, NG 253, M82 may be well understood by the lightest nuclei fragility and opacity within Mpc distances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Interpret Measurements of Diffuse Light in Stacked Observations of Groups and Clusters of Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/how_to_interpret_measurements_of_diffuse_light_in_stacked_observations_of_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/how_to_interpret_measurements_of_diffuse_light_in_stacked_observations_of_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Syeda Lammim Ahad
The diffuse light within galaxy groups and clusters provides valuable insight into the growth of massive cosmic structures. Groups are particularly interesting in this context, because they represent the link between galactic haloes and massive clusters. However, low surface brightness makes their diffuse light extremely challenging to detect individually. Stacking many groups is a promising alternative, but its physical interpretation is complicated by possible systematic variations of diffuse light profiles with other group properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of post-kick jets in core collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Noam Soker
I argue that the assumption that the jets that shape the axisymmetrical morphological features of core collapse supernova (CCSN) remnants are post-kick jets, i.e., the neutron star (NS) launches these jets after the explosion and after it acquired its natal kick velocity, leads to the conclusion that the pre-collapse cores of CCSN progenitors have sufficient angular momentum fluctuations to support jittering jets that explode the star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inflation from Multiple Pseudo-Scalar Fields: PBH Dark Matter and Gravitational Waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/inflation_from_multiple_pseudo-scalar_fields_pbh_dark_matter_and_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/inflation_from_multiple_pseudo-scalar_fields_pbh_dark_matter_and_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alireza Talebian
We study a model of inflation with multiple pseudo-scalar fields coupled to a $U(1)$ gauge field through Chern-Simons interactions. Because of parity violating interactions, one polarization of the gauge field is amplified yielding to enhanced curvature perturbation power spectrum. Inflation proceeds in multiple stages as each pseudo-scalar field rolls towards its minimum yielding to distinct multiple peaks in the curvature perturbations power spectrum at various scales during inflation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is binning always sinning? The impact of time-averaging for exoplanet phase curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/is_binning_always_sinning_the_impact_of_time-averaging_for_exoplanet_phase_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/is_binning_always_sinning_the_impact_of_time-averaging_for_exoplanet_phase_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giuseppe Morello
We explore how finite integration time or temporal binning can affect the analysis of exoplanet phase-curves. We provide analytical formulae to account for this effect or, if neglected, to estimate the potential biases in the retrieved parameters. As expected, due to their smoother variations over longer time-scales, phase curves can be binned more heavily than transits without causing severe biases. In the simplest case of a sinusoidal phase curve with period $P$, the integration time $\Delta t$ reduces its amplitude by the scaling factor $\text{sinc}{ \left ( \pi \Delta t / P \right ) }$, without altering its phase or shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST reveals a possible z ~ 11 galaxy merger in triply-lensed MACS0647$-$JD</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/jwst_reveals_a_possible__z__sim_11__galaxy_merger_in_triply-lensed_macs0647_-_jd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/jwst_reveals_a_possible__z__sim_11__galaxy_merger_in_triply-lensed_macs0647_-_jd/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tiger Yu-Yang Hsiao
MACS0647$-$JD is a triply-lensed $z\sim11$ galaxy originally discovered with the Hubble Space Telescope. Here we report new JWST imaging, which clearly resolves MACS0647$-$JD as having two components that are either merging galaxies or stellar complexes within a single galaxy. Both are very small, with stellar masses $\sim10^8,M_\odot$ and radii $r&amp;lt;100,\rm pc$. The brighter larger component &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; is intrinsically very blue ($\beta\sim-2.6$), likely due to very recent star formation and no dust, and is spatially extended with an effective radius $\sim70,\rm pc$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal-silicate partitioning of W and Mo and the role of carbon in controlling their abundances in the Bulk Silicate Earth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/metal-silicate_partitioning_of_w_and_mo_and_the_role_of_carbon_in_controlling_their_abundances_in_the_bulk_silicate_earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/metal-silicate_partitioning_of_w_and_mo_and_the_role_of_carbon_in_controlling_their_abundances_in_the_bulk_silicate_earth/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. S. Jennings
The liquid metal-liquid silicate partitioning of molybdenum and tungsten during core formation must be well-constrained in order to understand the evolution of Earth and other planetary bodies, in particular because the Hf-W isotopic system is used to date early planetary evolution. We combine 48 new high pressure and temperature experimental results with a comprehensive database of previous experiments to re-examine the systematics of Mo and W partitioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model constraints based on the IceCube neutrino non-detection of GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/model_constraints_based_on_the_icecube_neutrino_non-detection_of_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/model_constraints_based_on_the_icecube_neutrino_non-detection_of_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shunke Ai
GRB 221009A is a bright Gamma-ray burst (GRB) with isotropic energy being larger than $10^{54} ~{\rm ergs}$. Its fairly low redshift makes it a promising candidate for high energy neutrino detection. However, a neutrino search for this GRB reported by the \emph{IceCube} collaboration yielded a null result. In this paper, we utilize the upper limit from IceCube observation to test different GRB prompt emission models. We find that, at least for this specific burst, the dissipative photosphere model could be ruled out in a large parameter space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Cosmic Radiation Events in the Tree-ring Radiocarbon Record</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modelling_cosmic_radiation_events_in_the_tree-ring_radiocarbon_record/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modelling_cosmic_radiation_events_in_the_tree-ring_radiocarbon_record/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qingyuan Zhang
Annually-resolved measurements of the radiocarbon content in tree-rings have revealed rare sharp rises in carbon-14 production. These &amp;lsquo;Miyake events&amp;rsquo; are likely produced by rare increases in cosmic radiation from the Sun or other energetic astrophysical sources. The radiocarbon produced is not only circulated through the Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere and oceans, but also absorbed by the biosphere and locked in the annual growth rings of trees. To interpret high-resolution tree-ring radiocarbon measurements therefore necessitates modelling the entire global carbon cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Production Detectors for Gamma-ray Astrophysics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/pair_production_detectors_for_gamma-ray_astrophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/pair_production_detectors_for_gamma-ray_astrophysics/</guid>
      <description>First author: David J. Thompson
Electron-positron pair production is the essential process for high-energy gamma-ray astrophysical observations. Following the pioneering OSO-3 counter telescope, the field evolved into use of particle tracking instruments, largely derived from high-energy physics detectors. Although many of the techniques were developed on balloon-borne gamma-ray telescopes, the need to escape the high background in the atmosphere meant that the breakthrough discoveries came from the SAS-2 and COS-B satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarization Observations of AGN Jets: Past and Future</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polarization_observations_of_agn_jets_past_and_future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polarization_observations_of_agn_jets_past_and_future/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jongho Park
The magnetic field is believed to play a critical role in the bulk acceleration and propagation of jets produced in active galactic nuclei (AGN). Polarization observations of AGN jets provide valuable information about their magnetic fields. As a result of radiative transfer, jet structure, and stratification, among other factors, it is not always straightforward to determine the magnetic field structures from observed polarization. We review these effects and their impact on polarization emission at a variety of wavelengths, including radio, optical, and ultraviolet wavelengths in this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision Redshift-Space Galaxy Power Spectra using Zel&#39;dovich Control Variates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/precision_redshift-space_galaxy_power_spectra_using_zeldovich_control_variates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/precision_redshift-space_galaxy_power_spectra_using_zeldovich_control_variates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph DeRose
Numerical simulations in cosmology require trade-offs between volume, resolution and run-time that limit the volume of the Universe that can be simulated, leading to sample variance in predictions of ensemble-average quantities such as the power spectrum or correlation function(s). Sample variance is particularly acute at large scales, which is also where analytic techniques can be highly reliable. This provides an opportunity to combine analytic and numerical techniques in a principled way to improve the dynamic range and reliability of predictions for clustering statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Type Iax Supernova 2019muj in the Late Phase: Existence, Nature and Origin of the Iron-rich Dense Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Type Iax Supernovae (SNe Iax) form a class of peculiar SNe Ia, whose early-phase spectra share main spectral line identifications with canonical SNe Ia but with higher ionization and much lower line velocities. Their late-time behaviors deviate from usual SNe Ia in many respects; SNe Iax keep showing photospheric spectra over several 100 days and the luminosity decline is very slow. In the present work, we study the late-time spectra of SN Iax 2019muj including a newly-presented spectrum at ~500 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for gravitational-wave transients associated with magnetar bursts during the third Advanced LIGO and Advanced Virgo observing run</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/search_for_gravitational-wave_transients_associated_with_magnetar_bursts_during_the_third_advanced_ligo_and_advanced_virgo_observing_run/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/search_for_gravitational-wave_transients_associated_with_magnetar_bursts_during_the_third_advanced_ligo_and_advanced_virgo_observing_run/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kara Merfeld
Magnetars are neutron stars with exceptionally strong dipole magnetic fields which are observed to display a range of x-ray flaring behavior, but the flaring mechanism is not well understood. The third observing run of Advanced LIGO and Virgo extended from April 1, 2019 to March 27, 2020, and contained x-ray flares from known magnetar SGR 1935+2154, as well as the newly-discovered magnetar, Swift J1818-1607. We search for gravitational waves coincident with these magnetar flares with minimally modeled, coherent searches which specifically target both short-duration gravitational waves produced by excited f-modes in the magnetar&amp;rsquo;s core, as well as long-duration gravitational waves motivated by the Quasi-Periodic Oscillations observed in the tails of giant flares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secondary GeV-TeV emission from ultra-high-energy cosmic rays accelerated by GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/secondary_gev-tev_emission_from_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_rays_accelerated_by_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/secondary_gev-tev_emission_from_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_rays_accelerated_by_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nestor Mirabal
The origin of ultra-high-energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) remains elusive. Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are among the best candidates able to meet the stringent energy requirements needed for particle acceleration to such high energies. If UHECRs were accelerated by the central engine of GRB 221009A, it might be possible to detect secondary photons and neutrinos as the UHECRs travel from the source to the Earth. Here we attempt to interpret some of the early publicly available data connected to this burst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dispersion measure of Fast Radio Bursts host galaxies: estimation from cosmological simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts_host_galaxies_estimation_from_cosmological_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts_host_galaxies_estimation_from_cosmological_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jian-Feng Mo
The dispersion measure(DM) of fast radio burst encodes important information such as its distance, properties of intervening medium. Based on simulations in the Illustris and IllustrisTNG projects, we analyze the DM of FRBs contributed by the interstellar medium and circumgalactic medium in the hosts, $\rm{DM_{host}}$. We explore two population models - tracing the star formation rate (SFR), and the stellar mass, i.e. young and old progenitors respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power supply unit onboard the HERMES nano-satellite constellation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_power_supply_unit_onboard_the_hermes_nano-satellite_constellation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_power_supply_unit_onboard_the_hermes_nano-satellite_constellation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paolo Nogara
HERMES Pathfinder (High Energy Rapid Modular Ensemble of Satellites Pathfinder) is a space mission based on a constellation of nano-satellites in a low Earth Orbit, hosting new miniaturized detectors to probe the X-ray temporal emission of bright high-energy transients such as Gamma-Ray Bursts and the electromagnetic counterparts of Gravitational Waves. This ambitious goal will be achieved exploiting at most Commercial offthe-shelf components. For HERMES-SP, a custom Power Supply Unit board has been designed to supply the needed voltages to the payload and, at the same time, protecting it from Latch-Up events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stellar Chemical Abundances of Simulated Massive Galaxies at $z = 2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_stellar_chemical_abundances_of_simulated_massive_galaxies_at__z__2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_stellar_chemical_abundances_of_simulated_massive_galaxies_at__z__2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jee-Ho Kim
We analyze the stellar abundances of massive galaxies ($\log M_\ast/M_\odot&amp;gt;10.5$) at $z=2$ in the IllustrisTNG simulation with the goal of guiding the interpretation of current and future observations, particularly from the James Webb Space Telescope. We find that the effective size, $R_e$, of galaxies strongly affects the abundance measurements: both [Mg/H] and [Fe/H] are anti-correlated with $R_e$, while the relative abundance [Mg/Fe] slightly increases with $R_e$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a non-Gaussian Generative Model of large-scale Reionization Maps</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/towards_a_non-gaussian_generative_model_of_large-scale_reionization_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/towards_a_non-gaussian_generative_model_of_large-scale_reionization_maps/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yu-Heng Lin
High-dimensional data sets are expected from the next generation of large-scale surveys. These data sets will carry a wealth of information about the early stages of galaxy formation and cosmic reionization. Extracting the maximum amount of information from the these data sets remains a key challenge. Current simulations of cosmic reionization are computationally too expensive to provide enough realizations to enable testing different statistical methods, such as parameter inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Black-Hole Excision Scheme for General Relativistic Core-Collapse Supernova Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Sykes
Fallback supernovae and the collapsar scenario for long-gamma ray burst and hypernovae have received considerable interest as pathways to black-hole formation and extreme transient events. Consistent simulations of these scenarios require a general relativistic treatment and need to deal appropriately with the formation of a singularity. Free evolution schemes for the Einstein equations can handle the formation of black holes by means of excision or puncture schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Wavelength Study of Multiple Spectral Component Jets in AGN: Testing the IC/CMB Model for the Large-Scale-Jet X-ray Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_multi-wavelength_study_of_multiple_spectral_component_jets_in_agn_testing_the_ic_cmb_model_for_the_large-scale-jet_x-ray_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_multi-wavelength_study_of_multiple_spectral_component_jets_in_agn_testing_the_ic_cmb_model_for_the_large-scale-jet_x-ray_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Breiding
Over 150 resolved, kpc-scale X-ray jets hosted by active galactic nuclei have been discovered with the Chandra X-ray Observatory. A significant fraction of these jets have an X-ray spectrum either too high in flux or too hard to be consistent with the high-energy extension of the radio-to-optical synchrotron spectrum, a subtype we identify as Multiple Spectral Component (MSC) X-ray jets. A leading hypothesis for the origin of the X-rays is the inverse-Compton scattering of the cosmic microwave background by the same electron population producing the radio-to-optical synchrotron spectrum (known as the IC/CMB model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Negative Long Lag from the Optical to the UV Continuum in Fairall 9</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_negative_long_lag_from_the_optical_to_the_uv_continuum_in_fairall_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_negative_long_lag_from_the_optical_to_the_uv_continuum_in_fairall_9/</guid>
      <description>First author: Philippe Z. Yao
We report the detection of a long-timescale negative lag, where the blue bands lag the red bands, in the nearby Seyfert 1 galaxy Fairall 9. Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) light curves show variability over a wide range of timescales. By measuring time lags between different wavelengths, the otherwise inaccessible structure and kinematics of the accretion disk can be studied. One common approach, reverberation mapping, quantifies the continuum and line lags moving outwards through the disk at the light-travel time, revealing the size and temperature profile of the disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining cosmic shear data with correlated photo-$z$ uncertainties: constraints from DESY1 and HSC-DR1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/combining_cosmic_shear_data_with_correlated_photo-_z__uncertainties_constraints_from_desy1_and_hsc-dr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/combining_cosmic_shear_data_with_correlated_photo-_z__uncertainties_constraints_from_desy1_and_hsc-dr1/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carlos García-García
An accurate calibration of the source redshift distribution $p(z)$ is a key aspect in the analysis of cosmic shear data. This, one way or another, requires the use of spectroscopic or high-quality photometric samples. However, the difficulty to obtain colour-complete spectroscopic samples matching the depth of weak lensing catalogs means that the analyses of different cosmic shear datasets often use the same samples for redshift calibration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation of the star J004229.87&#43;410551.8 in M31 as a B[e] supergiant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/confirmation_of_the_star_j004229.87&#43;410551.8_in_m31_as_a_be_supergiant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/confirmation_of_the_star_j004229.87&#43;410551.8_in_m31_as_a_be_supergiant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sarkisyan A.
We study the luminous blue variable candidate J004229.87+410551.8 in the Andromeda Galaxy. Earlier, the star displayed a spectral anomaly: although a hot emission spectrum had been detected, it had strong CaII H and K absorption lines. Subsequently the star was assumed to be a hot hypergiant or a B[e] supergiant. For the purpose of clear star classification, we conducted spectroscopic and photometric analysis of the object and its surroundings with the 6-m telescope of SAO RAS, the 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for extended gaseous reservoirs around AGN at cosmic noon from ALMA CO(3-2) observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evidence_for_extended_gaseous_reservoirs_around_agn_at_cosmic_noon_from_alma_co3-2_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evidence_for_extended_gaseous_reservoirs_around_agn_at_cosmic_noon_from_alma_co3-2_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. C. Jones
Gaseous outflows are key phenomena in the evolution of galaxies, as they affect star formation (either positively or negatively), eject gas from the core or disk, and directly cause mixing of pristine and processed material. Active outflows may be detected through searches for broad spectral line emission or high-velocity gas, but it is also possible to determine the presence of past outflows by searching for extended reservoirs of chemically enriched molecular gas in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) around galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Early Afterglow Polarization of GRB 190829A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exploring_the_early_afterglow_polarization_of_grb_190829a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exploring_the_early_afterglow_polarization_of_grb_190829a/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. C. Caligula do E. S. Pedreira
The GRB 190829A has been widely studied due to its nature and the high energy emission presented. Due to the detection of a very-high-energy component by the High Energy Stereoscopic System and the event&amp;rsquo;s atypically middling luminosity, it has been categorized in a select, limited group of bursts bordering classic GRBs and nearby sub-energetic events. Given the range of models utilized to adequately characterize the afterglow of this burst, it has proven challenging to identify the most probable explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-precision abundances of first population stars in NGC 2808: confirmation of a metallicity spread</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-precision_abundances_of_first_population_stars_in_ngc_2808_confirmation_of_a_metallicity_spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-precision_abundances_of_first_population_stars_in_ngc_2808_confirmation_of_a_metallicity_spread/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Lardo
Photometric investigations have revealed that Galactic globular clusters exhibit internal metallicity variations amongst the so-called first-population stars, until now considered to have a homogeneous initial chemical composition. This is not fully supported by the sparse spectroscopic evidence, which so far gives conflicting results. Here, we present a high-resolution re-analysis of five stars in the Galactic globular cluster NGC 2808 taken from the literature. Target stars are bright red giants with nearly identical atmospheric parameters belonging to the first population according to their identification in the chromosome map of the cluster, and we have measured precise differential abundances for Fe, Si, Ca, Ti, and Ni to the ~0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holographic energy density, dark energy sound speed, and tensions in cosmological parameters: $H_0$ and $S_8$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/holographic_energy_density_dark_energy_sound_speed_and_tensions_in_cosmological_parameters__h_0__and__s_8_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/holographic_energy_density_dark_energy_sound_speed_and_tensions_in_cosmological_parameters__h_0__and__s_8_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wilmar Cardona
Interesting discrepancies in cosmological parameters are challenging the success of the $\Lambda$CDM model. Direct measurements of the Hubble constant $H_0$ using Cepheid variables and supernovae turn out to be higher than inferred from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB). Weak galaxy lensing surveys consistently report values of the strength of matter clustering $\sigma_8$ lower than values derived from the CMB in the context of $\Lambda$CDM. In this paper we address these discrepancies in cosmological parameters by considering Dark Energy (DE) as a fluid with evolving equation of state $w_{\mathrm{de}}(z)$, constant sound speed squared $\hat{c}{\mathrm{s}}^{2}$, and vanishing anisotropic stress $\sigma$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is jet re-orientation the elusive trigger for star formation suppression in radio galaxies?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/is_jet_re-orientation_the_elusive_trigger_for_star_formation_suppression_in_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/is_jet_re-orientation_the_elusive_trigger_for_star_formation_suppression_in_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Garofalo
Jet re-orientation associated with the time evolution of radio quasars explains the formation of X-shaped radio galaxies and their preference for isolated environments. But since X-shaped radio galaxies are generally not found in dense environments (e.g. groups/clusters), the jet re-orientation phenomenon for radio galaxies in groups and clusters has been ignored. We take a closer look at the re-orientation of FRI jets with respect to FRII jets, and find that it may constitute the as-yet unidentified trigger for star formation suppression in radio galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Li-rich and super Li-rich giants produced by element diffusion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/li-rich_and_super_li-rich_giants_produced_by_element_diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/li-rich_and_super_li-rich_giants_produced_by_element_diffusion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jun Gao
Context. About 0.2-2% of giant stars are Li-rich, whose lithium abundance (A(Li)) is higher than 1.5 dex. Among them, near 6% are super Li-rich with A(Li) exceeding 3.2 dex. Meanwhile, the formation mechanism of these Li-rich and super Li-rich giants is still under debate. Aims. Considering the compact He core of red giants, attention is paid to the effect of element diffusion on A(Li). In particular, when the He core flash occurs, the element diffusion makes the thermohaline mixing zone extend inward and connect to the inner convection region of stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living on the edge of the Central Molecular Zone: G1.3 is the more likely candidate for gas accretion into the CMZ</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/living_on_the_edge_of_the_central_molecular_zone_g1.3_is_the_more_likely_candidate_for_gas_accretion_into_the_cmz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/living_on_the_edge_of_the_central_molecular_zone_g1.3_is_the_more_likely_candidate_for_gas_accretion_into_the_cmz/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura A. Busch
The 1.3deg (G1.3) and 1.6deg (G1.6) cloud complexes in the Central Molecular Zone (CMZ) of our Galaxy have been proposed to possibly reside at the intersection region of the X1 and X2 orbits for several reasons. This includes the detection of co-spatial low- and high-velocity clouds, high velocity dispersion, high fractional molecular abundances of shock-tracing molecules, and kinetic temperatures that are higher than for usual CMZ clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement of the ~ 10^{-16} Gauss inter-galactic magnetic field with high energy emission of GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/measurement_of_the___sim_10-16_~gauss_inter-galactic_magnetic_field_with_high_energy_emission_of_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/measurement_of_the___sim_10-16_~gauss_inter-galactic_magnetic_field_with_high_energy_emission_of_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zi-Qing Xia
The fast evolving TeV-PeV transients and their delayed GeV-TeV cascade emission in principle server as an ideal probe of the inter-galactic magnetic fields which are hard to be measured by other methods. Very recently, LHASSO has detected the very high energy emission of the extraordinary powerful GRB 221009A up to $\sim 18$ TeV within $\sim 2000$ s after the burst trigger. Here we report the detection of a $\sim 400$ GeV photon, without accompanying prominent $\gamma$ rays down to $\sim 2$ GeV, by Fermi-LAT in the direction of GRB 221009A at about 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Photon Rings with the ngEHT</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/measuring_photon_rings_with_the_ngeht/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/measuring_photon_rings_with_the_ngeht/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paul Tiede
General relativity predicts that images of optically thin accretion flows around black holes should generically have a photon ring,&#39;&#39; composed of a series of increasingly sharp subrings that correspond to increasingly strongly lensed emission near the black hole. Because the effects of lensing are determined by the spacetime curvature, the photon ring provides a pathway to precise measurements of the black hole properties and tests of the Kerr metric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Ellipticity of M 87* Images</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/measuring_the_ellipticity_of_m_87_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/measuring_the_ellipticity_of_m_87_images/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paul Tiede
The Event Horizon Telescope (EHT) images of the supermassive black hole at the center of the galaxy M 87 provided the first image of the accretion environment on horizon scales. General relativity predicts that the image of the shadow should be nearly circular, given the inclination angle of the black hole M 87*. A robust detection of ellipticity in the image reconstructions of M 87* could signal new gravitational physics on horizon scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microlensing of gravitational waves by dark matter structures</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/microlensing_of_gravitational_waves_by_dark_matter_structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/microlensing_of_gravitational_waves_by_dark_matter_structures/</guid>
      <description>First author: Malcolm Fairbairn
Gravitational lensing of gravitational waves provides a potential new probe of dark matter structures. In this work, we consider the microlensing effect on gravitational wave signals from black hole binaries induced by low-mass dark matter halos that do not retain enough baryonic matter to hold stars. We clarify systematically when this microlensing effect is relevant and study in detail its detectability by future gravitational wave observatories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monster radiative shocks in the perturbed magnetospheres of neutron stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/monster_radiative_shocks_in_the_perturbed_magnetospheres_of_neutron_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/monster_radiative_shocks_in_the_perturbed_magnetospheres_of_neutron_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrei M. Beloborodov
Magnetospheres of neutron stars can be perturbed by star quakes or interaction in a binary system. The perturbations are typically in the kHz band and excite magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) waves. We show that compressive magnetospheric waves steepen into monster shocks mediated by radiation reaction, different from normal collisionless shocks. The shocks admit a simple analytical description. They expand through the magnetosphere with radiative losses, and then a blast wave is launched into the neutron-star wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Merger Rate of Primordial Black Holes in Cosmic Voids</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_merger_rate_of_primordial_black_holes_in_cosmic_voids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_merger_rate_of_primordial_black_holes_in_cosmic_voids/</guid>
      <description>First author: Saeed Fakhry
Cosmic voids are known as underdense substructures of the cosmic web that cover a large volume of the Universe. It is known that cosmic voids contain a small number of dark matter halos, so the existence of primordial black holes (PBHs) in these secluded regions of the Universe is not unlikely. In this work, we calculate the merger rate of PBHs in dark matter halos structured in cosmic voids and determine their contribution to gravitational wave events resulting from black hole mergers recorded by the Advanced Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory (aLIGO)-Advanced Virgo (aVirgo) detectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of radio experiments for UHE cosmic particles detection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/overview_of_radio_experiments_for_uhe_cosmic_particles_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/overview_of_radio_experiments_for_uhe_cosmic_particles_detection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Chiche
Radio-detection is a mature technique that has gained large momentum over the past decades. Its physical detection principle is mainly driven by the electromagnetic part of the shower, and is therefore not too sensitive to uncertainties on hadronic interactions. Furthermore its technical detection principle allows for a 100% duty cycle, and large surface coverage thanks to the low cost of antennas. Various detection methods of UHE particles now rely on the radio signal as main observable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarization Calibration of a Microwave Polarimeter with Near-Infrared Up-Conversion for Optical Correlation and Detection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polarization_calibration_of_a_microwave_polarimeter_with_near-infrared_up-conversion_for_optical_correlation_and_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polarization_calibration_of_a_microwave_polarimeter_with_near-infrared_up-conversion_for_optical_correlation_and_detection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francisco J. Casas
This paper presents a polarization calibration method applied to a microwave polarimeter demonstrator based on a near-infrared (NIR) frequency up-conversion stage that allows both optical correlation and signal detection at a wavelength of 1550 nm. The instrument was designed to measure the polarization of cosmic microwave background (CMB) radiation from the sky, obtaining the Stokes parameters of the incoming signal simultaneously, in a frequency range from 10 to 20 GHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prograde and Retrograde Gas Flow around Disk-embedded Companions: Dependence on Eccentricity, Mass and Disk Properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prograde_and_retrograde_gas_flow_around_disk-embedded_companions_dependence_on_eccentricity_mass_and_disk_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prograde_and_retrograde_gas_flow_around_disk-embedded_companions_dependence_on_eccentricity_mass_and_disk_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yi-Xian Chen
We apply 3D hydrodynamical simulations to study the rotational aspect of gas flow patterns around eccentric companions embedded in an accretion disk around its primary host. We sample a wide range of companion mass ratio q and disk aspect ratio h, and confirm a generic transition from prograde (steady tidal interaction dominated) to retrograde (background Keplerian shear dominated) circum-companion flow when orbital eccentricity exceeds a critical value et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propagation of a Strong Fast Magnetosonic Wave in the Magnetosphere of a Neutron Star</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/propagation_of_a_strong_fast_magnetosonic_wave_in_the_magnetosphere_of_a_neutron_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/propagation_of_a_strong_fast_magnetosonic_wave_in_the_magnetosphere_of_a_neutron_star/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexander Y. Chen
We study the propagation of a strong, low frequency, linearly polarized fast magnetosonic wave inside the magnetosphere of a neutron star. The relative strength $\delta B/B$ of the wave grows as a function of radius before it reaches the light cylinder, and what starts as a small perturbation can grow to become nonlinear before it escapes the magnetosphere. Using first-principles Particle-in-Cell (PIC) simulations, we study in detail the evolution of the wave as it becomes nonlinear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quasi-spherical superclusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/quasi-spherical_superclusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/quasi-spherical_superclusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pekka Heinämäki
Generally the dynamical state of superclusters is poorly known. We study properties of superclusters and select a sample of quasi-spherical superclusters, the dynamics of which can be studied using the $\Lambda$ significance diagram. We extracted our supercluster sample with an adaptive local threshold density method from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Data Release 7 (SDSS DR7) data and estimated their masses using the dynamical masses for member galaxies and groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation of ionization electrons: the key role of their 2-pt function of velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/radiation_of_ionization_electrons_the_key_role_of_their_2-pt_function_of_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/radiation_of_ionization_electrons_the_key_role_of_their_2-pt_function_of_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Olivier Deligny
Several attempts to detect extensive air showers (EAS) induced by ultra-high energy cosmic rays have been conducted in the last decade based on the molecular Bremsstrahlung radiation (MBR) at GHz frequencies from quasi-elastic collisions of ionisation electrons left in the atmosphere after the passage of the cascade of particles. These attempts have led to the detection of a handful of signals only, all of them forward-directed along the shower axis and hence suggestive of originating from geomagnetic and Askaryan emissions extending into GHz frequencies close to the Cherenkov angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiatively driven evaporation from magnetar&#39;s surface</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/radiatively_driven_evaporation_from_magnetars_surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/radiatively_driven_evaporation_from_magnetars_surface/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivan Demidov
The luminosity of the Soft Gamma Repeater (SGR) flares significantly exceeds the Eddington luminosity. This is because they emit mainly in the E-mode, for which the radiative cross-sections are strongly suppressed. The energy is released in the magnetosphere forming a magnetically trapped pair fireball, and the surface of the star is illuminated by the powerful radiation from the fireball. We study the ablation of the matter from the surface by this radiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio-bright vs. Radio-dark Gamma-ray Bursts -- More Evidence for Distinct Progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/radio-bright_vs._radio-dark_gamma-ray_bursts_--_more_evidence_for_distinct_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/radio-bright_vs._radio-dark_gamma-ray_bursts_--_more_evidence_for_distinct_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Angana Chakraborty
We analyze two distinct samples of GRBs, with and without radio afterglow emission. We use a sample of 211 GRBs which is an update of the previous sample from arXiv:1902.01974, and find, in agreement with previous results (although with a sample that is almost twice as large) as the intrinsic gamma-ray duration (Tint) and isotropic equivalent energy (Eiso) distributions between these two populations appear to differ significantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searches for Ultra-High-Energy Photons at the Pierre Auger Observatory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/searches_for_ultra-high-energy_photons_at_the_pierre_auger_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/searches_for_ultra-high-energy_photons_at_the_pierre_auger_observatory/</guid>
      <description>First author: The Pierre Auger Collaboration
The Pierre Auger Observatory, being the largest air-shower experiment in the world, offers an unprecedented exposure to neutral particles at the highest energies. Since the start of data taking more than 18 years ago, various searches for ultra-high-energy (UHE, $E\gtrsim10^{17},\text{eV}$) photons have been performed: either for a diffuse flux of UHE photons, for point sources of UHE photons or for UHE photons associated with transient events like gravitational wave events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for neutrinos from solar flares across solar cycles 23 and 24 with the Super-Kamiokande detector</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/searching_for_neutrinos_from_solar_flares_across_solar_cycles_23_and_24_with_the_super-kamiokande_detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/searching_for_neutrinos_from_solar_flares_across_solar_cycles_23_and_24_with_the_super-kamiokande_detector/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. Okamoto
Neutrinos associated with solar flares (solar-flare neutrinos) provide information on particle acceleration mechanisms during the impulsive phase of solar flares. We searched using the Super-Kamiokande detector for neutrinos from solar flares that occurred during solar cycles $23$ and $24$, including the largest solar flare (X28.0) on November 4th, 2003. In order to minimize the background rate we searched for neutrino interactions within narrow time windows coincident with $\gamma$-rays and soft X-rays recorded by satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopy of High Redshift Galaxies with the ngVLA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spectroscopy_of_high_redshift_galaxies_with_the_ngvla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spectroscopy_of_high_redshift_galaxies_with_the_ngvla/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. L. Carilli
We present simulations of the capabilities of the ngVLA to image at $\sim 0.75$ kpc resolution ($0.085&amp;quot;$), molecular line emission from star forming disk galaxies at high redshift. The results are compared to the current capabilities of ALMA. ALMA can detect the integrated emission, and determine the velocity gradient and size across the brighter emission regions of the galaxy. The ngVLA is a factor $\sim 6$ more sensitive at the adopted spatial and velocity resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying the properties of compressible MHD turbulence by synchrotron fluctuation statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/studying_the_properties_of_compressible_mhd_turbulence_by_synchrotron_fluctuation_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/studying_the_properties_of_compressible_mhd_turbulence_by_synchrotron_fluctuation_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ru-Yue Wang
We study the observable properties of compressible MHD turbulence covering different turbulence regimes, based on synthetic synchrotron observations arising from 3D MHD numerical simulations. Using the synchrotron emissivity and intensity, we first explore how the cosmic ray spectral indices affect the measurements of turbulence properties by employing normalized correlation functions. We then study how the anisotropy of synchrotron total and polarization intensities arising from three fundamental MHD modes vary with the viewing angle, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super-resolution simulation of the Fuzzy Dark Matter cosmological model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/super-resolution_simulation_of_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_cosmological_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/super-resolution_simulation_of_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_cosmological_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Meris Sipp
AI super-resolution, combining deep learning and N-body simulations has been shown to successfully reproduce the large scale structure and halo abundances in the Lambda Cold Dark Matter cosmological model. Here, we extend its use to models with a different dark matter content, in this case Fuzzy Dark Matter (FDM), in the approximation that the difference is encoded in the initial power spectrum. We focus on redshift z = 2, with simulations that model smaller scales and lower masses, the latter by two orders of magnitude, than has been done in previous AI super-resolution work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The environment of AGN dwarf galaxies at z ~ 0.7 from the VIPERS survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_environment_of_agn_dwarf_galaxies_at_z__sim_0.7_from_the_vipers_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_environment_of_agn_dwarf_galaxies_at_z__sim_0.7_from_the_vipers_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Siudek
Dwarf galaxies are ideal laboratories to study the relationship between the environment and AGN activity. However, the type of environments in which dwarf galaxies hosting AGN reside is still unclear and limited to low-redshift studies (z &amp;lt; 0.5). We use the VIMOS Public Extragalactic Redshift Survey (VIPERS) to investigate, for the first time, their environments at 0.5 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.9. We select a sample of 12,942 low-mass ($\rm{log}(M_\mathrm{*}/M_{\odot})\leq10$) galaxies and use the emission-line diagnostic diagram to identify AGN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolving cluster cores: Putting together the pieces of the puzzle</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_evolving_cluster_cores_putting_together_the_pieces_of_the_puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_evolving_cluster_cores_putting_together_the_pieces_of_the_puzzle/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Molendi
In this work we address the issue of whether the division of clusters in cool cores (CCs) and non-cool cores (NCCs) is due to a primordial difference or to how clusters evolve across cosmic time. Our first goal is to establish if spectra from the central regions of a subclass of NCCs known as cool core remnants (CCRs) are consistent with having a small but significant amount of short cooling time gas, thereby allowing a transformation to CC systems on a timescale of a giga year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Galaxies and the Effect of Heterogeneous Enrichment from Primordial Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_first_galaxies_and_the_effect_of_heterogeneous_enrichment_from_primordial_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_first_galaxies_and_the_effect_of_heterogeneous_enrichment_from_primordial_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Azton I. Wells
We incorporate new scale-intelligent models of metal-enriched star formation (\starss) with surrogate models of primordial stellar feedback (\starnet) into the astrophysics simulation code \enzo to analyze the impact of heterogeneous metal enrichment on the first galaxies. Our study includes the earliest generations of stars and the protogalaxies ($10^6 \lesssim M_v/M_\odot \lesssim 10^8$) containing them. We compare results obtained with the new methods to two common paradigms of metallicity initial conditions in simulations: ignoring the metallicity initial condition and assuming a uniform metallicity floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intermediate Polar FO Aquarii Has Not Been the Same Since Recovering from a Series of Low States</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_intermediate_polar_fo_aquarii_has_not_been_the_same_since_recovering_from_a_series_of_low_states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_intermediate_polar_fo_aquarii_has_not_been_the_same_since_recovering_from_a_series_of_low_states/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Garnavich
FO Aqr is a bright intermediate polar that has long displayed large amplitude photometric variations corresponding to the 20.9 min spin period of its white dwarf. Between 2016 and 2020, the system suffered a series of unprecedented low-states, but recent data shows that it has now recovered to its normal optical luminosity. We compare the light curves obtained by K2/Kepler in 2014 with photometry from the TESS mission obtained in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three regimes of atmospheric evaporation for super-Earths and sub-Neptunes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_three_regimes_of_atmospheric_evaporation_for_super-earths_and_sub-neptunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_three_regimes_of_atmospheric_evaporation_for_super-earths_and_sub-neptunes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Darius Modirrousta-Galian
A significant fraction of super-Earths and sub-Neptunes are thought to experience an extreme loss of volatiles because of atmospheric evaporation in the early stages of their life. Though the mechanisms behind the extreme mass loss are not fully understood, two contenders have been widely discussed: photoevaporation from X-ray and ultraviolet irradiation and core powered mass loss. Here, it is shown that both mechanisms occur but with different timescales, and that atmospheric loss can take place over three regimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultrahigh-energy cosmic-ray signature in GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/ultrahigh-energy_cosmic-ray_signature_in_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/ultrahigh-energy_cosmic-ray_signature_in_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Saikat Das
The brightest long gamma-ray burst detected so far by the Swift-BAT and Fermi-GBM telescopes, GRB~221009A provides an unprecedented opportunity for understanding the high-energy processes in extreme transient phenomena. We find that the conventional leptonic models, synchrotron and synchrotron-self-Compton, for the afterglow emission from this source is unable to explain observation of $\gamma$ rays, by the LHAASO detector, extending up to 18 TeV energies. We model $\gamma$-ray spectrum estimated in the energy range 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antenna source of radio-frequency emission in ion-proton pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/antenna_source_of_radio-frequency_emission_in_ion-proton_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/antenna_source_of_radio-frequency_emission_in_ion-proton_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: P B Jones
The growth of a longitudinal or quasi-longitudinal Langmuir mode in the outward-moving beam of ions and protons that forms the open sector of an ion-proton pulsar magnetosphere radiates as an analogue of an end-fed high-impedance horizontal straight-wire antenna an integral number of half-waves in length. The radiation has, broadly, the energy flux, linear polarization and spectral index that are widely observed: also, the notch phenomenon seen in some integrated pulse profiles occurs naturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Information in Skew Spectra of Biased Tracers in Redshift Space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmological_information_in_skew_spectra_of_biased_tracers_in_redshift_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmological_information_in_skew_spectra_of_biased_tracers_in_redshift_space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiamin Hou
Extracting the non-Gaussian information encoded in the higher-order clustering statistics of the large-scale structure is key to fully realizing the potential of upcoming galaxy surveys. We investigate the information content of the redshift-space {\it weighted skew spectra} of biased tracers as efficient estimators for 3-point clustering statistics. The skew spectra are constructed by correlating the observed galaxy field with an appropriately-weighted square of it. We perform numerical Fisher forecasts using two synthetic datasets; the halo catalogs from the Quijote N-body simulations and the galaxy catalogs from the Molino suite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover Your Basis: Comprehensive Data-Driven Characterization of the Binary Black Hole Population</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cover_your_basis_comprehensive_data-driven_characterization_of_the_binary_black_hole_population/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cover_your_basis_comprehensive_data-driven_characterization_of_the_binary_black_hole_population/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bruce Edelman
We introduce the first complete non-parametric model for the astrophysical distribution of the binary black hole (BBH) population. Constructed from basis splines, we use these models to conduct the most comprehensive data-driven investigation of the BBH population to date, simultaneously fitting non-parametric models for the BBH mass ratio, spin magnitude and misalignment, and redshift distributions for the first time. Using the BBHs in GWTC-3, we report the same features recovered with similarly flexible models of the mass distribution, most notably the peaks in merger rates at primary masses of ${\sim}10,M_\odot$ and ${\sim}35,M_\odot$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf galaxy formation with and without dark matter-baryon streaming velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf_galaxy_formation_with_and_without_dark_matter-baryon_streaming_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf_galaxy_formation_with_and_without_dark_matter-baryon_streaming_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna T. P. Schauer
We study how supersonic streaming velocities of baryons relative to dark matter &amp;ndash; a large-scale effect imprinted at recombination and coherent over $\sim 3$ Mpc scales &amp;ndash; affects the formation of dwarf galaxies at $z \gtrsim 5$. We perform cosmological hydrodynamic simulations, including and excluding streaming velocities, in regions centered on halos with $M_{\rm vir}(z=0) \approx 10^{10}$ M${\odot}$; the simulations are part of the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project and run with FIRE-3 physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of direct impact accretion in degenerate binary systems</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dynamics_of_direct_impact_accretion_in_degenerate_binary_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dynamics_of_direct_impact_accretion_in_degenerate_binary_systems/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nikita Kramarev
We consider the gas dynamics in an accreting binary system of degenerate stars within the framework of the Newtonian approximation. In such a system, the accretion stream can impact the surface of a white dwarf (WD) or neutron star (NS) as a result of the very compact orbit. This causes a loss of angular momentumfrom the orbit and spin-up of the accretor. We construct approximations for the specific angular momentum of the accreting matter which goes to spin up the accretor and some other parameters of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/fermi_gamma-ray_space_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/fermi_gamma-ray_space_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: David J. Thompson
The Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope, a key mission in multiwavelength and multimessenger studies, has been surveying the gamma-ray sky from its low-Earth orbit since 2008. Its two scientific instruments, the Gamma-ray Burst Monitor (GBM) and the Large Area Telescope (LAT), cover 8 orders of magnitude in photon energy. The GBM consists of 12 Sodium Iodide detectors and 2 Bismuth Germinate detectors, covering the 10 keV - 40 MeV energy range, arrayed on two sides of the spacecraft so as to view the entire sky that is not occulted by the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRB 221009A: a potential source of ultra-high-energy cosmic rays</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/grb_221009a_a_potential_source_of_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_rays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/grb_221009a_a_potential_source_of_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_rays/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rafael Alves Batista
Recently an extraordinarily bright gamma-ray burst, GRB 221009A, was observed by several facilities covering the whole electromagnetic spectrum. Gamma rays with energies up to 18 TeV were detected, as well as a photon with 251 TeV. Such energetic events are not expected because they would be attenuated by pair-production interactions with the extragalactic background light. This tension is, however, only apparent, and does not call for any unconventional explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implication of photon-ALP interactions in sub-PeV neutrino source TXS 0506&#43;056</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/implication_of_photon-alp_interactions_in_sub-pev_neutrino_source_txs_0506&#43;056/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/implication_of_photon-alp_interactions_in_sub-pev_neutrino_source_txs_0506&#43;056/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bhanu Prakash Pant
We investigate the effect of photon-ALP oscillations on the gamma-ray spectra of TXS 0506+056 using observations by Fermi Large Area Telescope (FERMI-LAT) and Major Atmospheric Gamma Imaging Cherenkov Telescopes (MAGIC) data. We individually used both the quiescent and the two VHE flaring phases around IC170922-A and additionally, the 2014 neutrino flare phase for the source to study the ALP effect at sub-PeV energies.
arxiv link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L 363-38 b: a planet newly discovered with ESPRESSO orbiting a nearby M dwarf star</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/l_363-38_b_a_planet_newly_discovered_with_espresso_orbiting_a_nearby_m_dwarf_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/l_363-38_b_a_planet_newly_discovered_with_espresso_orbiting_a_nearby_m_dwarf_star/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lia F. Sartori
Context. Planets around stars in the solar neighbourhood will be prime targets for characterisation with upcoming large space- and ground-based facilities. Since large-scale exoplanet searches will not be feasible with such telescopes, it is crucial to use currently available data and instruments to find possible target planets before next generation facilities come online. Aims. We aim at detecting new extrasolar planets around stars in the solar neighbourhood by blind radial velocity (RV) search with ESPRESSO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New continuum and polarization observations of the Cygnus Loop with FAST II. Images and analyses</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/new_continuum_and_polarization_observations_of_the_cygnus_loop_with_fast_ii._images_and_analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/new_continuum_and_polarization_observations_of_the_cygnus_loop_with_fast_ii._images_and_analyses/</guid>
      <description>First author: X. H. Sun
We present total-intensity and polarized-intensity images of the Cygnus Loop supernova remnant (SNR) observed by the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope (FAST). The high angular-resolution and high-sensitivity images enable us to thoroughly compare the properties of the northern part with the southern part of the SNR. The central filament in the northern part and the southern part have a similar foreground rotation measure, meaning their distances are likely similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Fourier-Filtering WFS to reach sensitivity close to the fundamental limit</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/optimizing_fourier-filtering_wfs_to_reach_sensitivity_close_to_the_fundamental_limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/optimizing_fourier-filtering_wfs_to_reach_sensitivity_close_to_the_fundamental_limit/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vincent Chambouleyron
To reach the full potential of the new generation of ground based telescopes, an extremely fine adjustment of the phase is required. Wavefront control and correction before detection has therefore become one of the cornerstones of instruments to achieve targeted performance, especially for high-contrast imaging. A crucial feature of accurate wavefront control leans on the wavefront sensor (WFS). We present a strategy to design new Fourier-Filtering WFS that encode the phase close from the fundamental photon efficiency limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for spatial coincidence between IceCube neutrinos and radio pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/search_for_spatial_coincidence_between_icecube_neutrinos_and_radio_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/search_for_spatial_coincidence_between_icecube_neutrinos_and_radio_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vibhavasu Pasumarti
We search for a spatial association between radio pulsars and ultra-high energy neutrinos using the publicly available IceCube point source neutrino events catalog. For this purpose we use the unbinned maximum likelihood method to search for a statistically significant excess from each of the pulsars in the ATNF catalog. We do not find any pulsars with detection significance much higher than that expected from a Gaussian distribution, Therefore, we conclude that none of the currently known pulsars contribute to the diffuse neutrino flux detected by IceCube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Active Galactic Nuclei in the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy Experiment Survey (HETDEX) III. A red quasar with extremely high equivalent widths showing powerful outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_active_galactic_nuclei_in_the_hobby-eberly_telescope_dark_energy_experiment_survey_hetdex_iii._a_red_quasar_with_extremely_high_equivalent_widths_showing_powerful_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_active_galactic_nuclei_in_the_hobby-eberly_telescope_dark_energy_experiment_survey_hetdex_iii._a_red_quasar_with_extremely_high_equivalent_widths_showing_powerful_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chenxu Liu
We report an Active Galactic Nucleus (AGN) with extremely high equivalent width (EW), EW(LyA+NV,rest)&amp;gt;921 AA in the rest-frame, at z~2.24 in the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy Experiment Survey (HETDEX) as a representative case of the high EW AGN population. The continuum level is a non-detection in the HETDEX spectrum, thus the measured EW is a lower limit. The source is detected with significant emission lines (&amp;gt;7sigma) at LyA+NV, CIV, and moderate emission line (~4sigma) at HeII within the wavelength coverage of HETDEX (3500 AA - 5500 AA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mantis Network III: A titanium cold-trap on the ultra-hot Jupiter WASP-121 b</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_mantis_network_iii_a_titanium_cold-trap_on_the_ultra-hot_jupiter_wasp-121_b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_mantis_network_iii_a_titanium_cold-trap_on_the_ultra-hot_jupiter_wasp-121_b/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. J. Hoeijmakers
Observations of WASP-121 b have suggested an under-abundance of titanium and titanium-oxide from its terminator region. In this study, we aim to determine whether this depletion is global by investigating the day-side emission spectrum. We analyse 8 epochs of high-resolution spectra obtained with the ESPRESSO spectrograph at optical wavelengths, targeting orbital phases when the day-side is in view. We use a cross-correlation method to search for various atoms, TiO and VO and compare to models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidally excited gravity waves in the cores of solar-type stars: resonances and critical-layer formation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/tidally_excited_gravity_waves_in_the_cores_of_solar-type_stars_resonances_and_critical-layer_formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/tidally_excited_gravity_waves_in_the_cores_of_solar-type_stars_resonances_and_critical-layer_formation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhao Guo
We simulate the propagation and dissipation of tidally induced nonlinear gravity waves in the cores of solar-type stars. We perform hydrodynamical simulations of a previously developed Boussinesq model using a spectral-element code to study the stellar core as a wave cavity that is periodically forced at the outer boundary with a given azimuthal wavenumber and an adjustable frequency. For low-amplitude forcing, the system exhibits resonances with standing g-modes at particular frequencies, corresponding to a situation in which the tidal torque is highly frequency-dependent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomographic Alcock-Paczynski Method with Redshift Errors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/tomographic_alcock-paczynski_method_with_redshift_errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/tomographic_alcock-paczynski_method_with_redshift_errors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liang Xiao
The tomographic Alcock-Paczynski (AP) method is a promising method that uses the redshift evolution of the anisotropic clustering in redshift space to calibrate cosmology. It extends the applicable range of AP method to substantially nonlinear scales, yielding very tight cosmological constraints. For future stage-IV slitless spectroscopic surveys, the non-negligible redshift errors might reduce the advantage of the tomographic AP method by suppressing the resolution of the nonlinear structure along the line of sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray Emission from the Interstellar and Circumgalactic Medium of Elliptical Galaxies based on MACER simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/x-ray_emission_from_the_interstellar_and_circumgalactic_medium_of_elliptical_galaxies_based_on_macer_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/x-ray_emission_from_the_interstellar_and_circumgalactic_medium_of_elliptical_galaxies_based_on_macer_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aditi Vijayan
Interstellar (ISM) and circumgalactic medium (CGM) around galaxies are linked to several physical processes that drive galaxy evolution. For example, the X-ray emission from the CGM gas around ellipticals has been linked to the AGN feedback occurring in the host. Upcoming telescopes such as HUBS, with ~ 1 eV resolution, can provide us with deep insights about the hot gas properties of such galaxies thus constrain these processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XSLIDE (X-Ray Spectral Line IDentifier and Explorer): a quick-look tool for XRISM</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/xslide_x-ray_spectral_line_identifier_and_explorer_a_quick-look_tool_for_xrism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/xslide_x-ray_spectral_line_identifier_and_explorer_a_quick-look_tool_for_xrism/</guid>
      <description>First author: Efrem Braun
We present XSLIDE (X-Ray Spectral Line IDentifier and Explorer), a graphical user interface that has been designed as a quick-look tool for the upcoming X-Ray Imaging and Spectroscopy Mission (XRISM). XSLIDE is a simple and user-friendly application that allows for the interactive plotting of spectra from XRISM&amp;rsquo;s Resolve instrument without requiring the selection of models for forward-fitting. XSLIDE performs common tasks such as rebinning, continuum fitting, automatically detecting lines, assigning detected lines to known atomic transitions, spectral diagnostics, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolved eclipsing binary systems in the Galactic bulge: Precise physical and orbital parameters of OGLE-BLG-ECL-305487 and OGLE-BLG-ECL-116218</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evolved_eclipsing_binary_systems_in_the_galactic_bulge_precise_physical_and_orbital_parameters_of_ogle-blg-ecl-305487_and_ogle-blg-ecl-116218/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evolved_eclipsing_binary_systems_in_the_galactic_bulge_precise_physical_and_orbital_parameters_of_ogle-blg-ecl-305487_and_ogle-blg-ecl-116218/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. Suchomska
Our goal is to determine, with high accuracy, the physical and orbital parameters of two double-lined eclipsing binary systems, where the components are two giant stars. We also aim to study the evolutionary status of the binaries, to derive the distances towards them by using a surface brightness-colour relation, and to compare these measurements with the measurements presented by the Gaia mission. In order to measure the physical and orbital parameters of the systems, we analysed the light curves and radial-velocity curves with the Wilson-Devinney code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ExoMol line lists -- XLV. Rovibronic molecular line lists of calcium monohydride (CaH) and magnesium monohydride (MgH)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlv._rovibronic_molecular_line_lists_of_calcium_monohydride_cah_and_magnesium_monohydride_mgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlv._rovibronic_molecular_line_lists_of_calcium_monohydride_cah_and_magnesium_monohydride_mgh/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alec Owens
New molecular line lists for calcium monohydride ($^{40}$Ca$^{1}$H) and magnesium monohydride ($^{24}$Mg$^{1}$H) and its minor isotopologues ($^{25}$Mg$^{1}$H and $^{26}$Mg$^{1}$H) are presented. The rotation-vibration-electronic (rovibronic) line lists, named \texttt{XAB}, consider transitions involving the \X, \A, and \BBp\ electronic states in the 0&amp;ndash;30,000~cm$^{-1}$ region (wavelengths $\lambda &amp;gt; 0.33$~$\mu$m) and are suitable for temperatures up to 5000 K. A comprehensive analysis of the published spectroscopic literature on CaH and MgH is used to obtain new extensive datasets of accurate rovibronic energy levels with measurement uncertainties and consistent quantum number labelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ExoMol line lists -- XLVII. Rovibronic molecular line list of the calcium monohydroxide radical (CaOH)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlvii._rovibronic_molecular_line_list_of_the_calcium_monohydroxide_radical_caoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlvii._rovibronic_molecular_line_list_of_the_calcium_monohydroxide_radical_caoh/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alec Owens
Any future detection of the calcium monohydroxide radical (CaOH) in stellar and exoplanetary atmospheres will rely on accurate molecular opacity data. Here, we present the first comprehensive molecular line list of CaOH covering the \A&amp;ndash;\X\ rotation-vibration-electronic and \X&amp;ndash;\X\ rotation-vibration bands. The newly computed OYT6 line list contains over 24.2 billion transitions between 3.2 million energy levels with rotational excitation up to $J=175.5$. It is applicable to temperatures up to $T=3000$~K and covers the 0,&amp;ndash;,35,000~cm$^{-1}$ range (wavelengths $\lambda &amp;gt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast On-orbit Pulse Phase Estimation of X-ray Crab Pulsar for XNAV Flight Experiments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/fast_on-orbit_pulse_phase_estimation_of_x-ray_crab_pulsar_for_xnav_flight_experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/fast_on-orbit_pulse_phase_estimation_of_x-ray_crab_pulsar_for_xnav_flight_experiments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yidi Wang
The recent flight experiments with Neutron Star Interior Composition Explorer (\textit{NICER}) and \textit{Insight}-Hard X-ray Modulation Telescope (\textit{Insight}-HXMT) have demonstrated the feasibility of X-ray pulsar-based navigation (XNAV) in the space. However, the current pulse phase estimation and navigation methods employed in the above flight experiments are computationally too expensive for handling the Crab pulsar data. To solve this problem, this paper proposes a fast algorithm of on-orbit estimating the pulse phase of Crab pulsar called X-ray pulsar navigaTion usIng on-orbiT pulsAr timiNg (XTITAN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How magnetic field and stellar radiative feedback influences the collapse and the stellar mass spectrum of a massive star forming clump</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/how_magnetic_field_and_stellar_radiative_feedback_influences_the_collapse_and_the_stellar_mass_spectrum_of_a_massive_star_forming_clump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/how_magnetic_field_and_stellar_radiative_feedback_influences_the_collapse_and_the_stellar_mass_spectrum_of_a_massive_star_forming_clump/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick Hennebelle
In spite of decades of theoretical efforts, the physical origin of the stellar initial mass function (IMF) is still debated. We aim at understanding the influence of various physical processes such as radiative stellar feedback, magnetic field and non-ideal magneto-hydrodynamics on the IMF. We present a series of numerical simulations of collapsing 1000 M$\odot$ clumps taking into account radiative feedback and magnetic field with spatial resolution down to 1 AU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of water vapor seeing on mid-infrared high-contrast imaging at ELT scale</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/impact_of_water_vapor_seeing_on_mid-infrared_high-contrast_imaging_at_elt_scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/impact_of_water_vapor_seeing_on_mid-infrared_high-contrast_imaging_at_elt_scale/</guid>
      <description>First author: Olivier Absil
The high-speed variability of the local water vapor content in the Earth atmosphere is a significant contributor to ground-based wavefront quality throughout the infrared domain. Unlike dry air, water vapor is highly chromatic, especially in the mid-infrared. This means that adaptive optics correction in the visible or near-infrared domain does not necessarily ensure a high wavefront quality at longer wavelengths. Here, we use literature measurements of water vapor seeing, and more recent infrared interferometric data from the Very Large Telescope Interferometer (VLTI), to evaluate the wavefront quality that will be delivered to the METIS mid-infrared camera and spectrograph for the Extremely Large Telescope (ELT), operating from 3 to 13 {\mu}m, after single-conjugate adaptive optics correction in the near-infrared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spitzer/IRS full spectral modeling to characterize mineralogical properties of silicate dust in heavily obscured AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spitzer_irs_full_spectral_modeling_to_characterize_mineralogical_properties_of_silicate_dust_in_heavily_obscured_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spitzer_irs_full_spectral_modeling_to_characterize_mineralogical_properties_of_silicate_dust_in_heavily_obscured_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Tsuchikawa
Mid-Infrared (IR) silicate dust bands observed in heavily obscured active galactic nuclei (AGNs) include information on the mineralogical properties of silicate dust. We aim to investigate the mineralogical picture of the circumnuclear region of heavily obscured AGNs to reveal obscured AGN activities through the picture. In our previous study Tsuchikawa et al. (2021), we investigated the properties of silicate dust in heavily obscured AGNs focusing on the mineralogical composition and the crystallinity with Spitzer/IRS 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic KMTNet Planetary Anomaly Search, Paper VII: Complete Sample of $q &lt; 10^{-4}$ Planets from the First Four-Year Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/systematic_kmtnet_planetary_anomaly_search_paper_vii_complete_sample_of__q__10-4__planets_from_the_first_four-year_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/systematic_kmtnet_planetary_anomaly_search_paper_vii_complete_sample_of__q__10-4__planets_from_the_first_four-year_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Weicheng Zang
We present the analysis of seven microlensing planetary events with planet/host mass ratios $q &amp;lt; 10^{-4}$: KMT-2017-BLG-1194, KMT-2017-BLG-0428, KMT-2019-BLG-1806, KMT-2017-BLG-1003, KMT-2019-BLG-1367, OGLE-2017-BLG-1806, and KMT-2016-BLG-1105. They were identified by applying the Korea Microlensing Telescope Network (KMTNet) AnomalyFinder algorithm to 2016&amp;ndash;2019 KMTNet events. A Bayesian analysis indicates that all the lens systems consist of a cold super-Earth orbiting an M or K dwarf. Together with 17 previously published and three that will be published elsewhere, AnomalyFinder has found a total of 27 planets that have solutions with $q &amp;lt; 10^{-4}$ from 2016&amp;ndash;2019 KMTNet events, which lays the foundation for the first statistical analysis of the planetary mass-ratio function based on KMTNet data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pre-Pilot and Pilot Survey: the Tully Fisher Relation in Eridanus, Hydra, Norma and NGC4636 fields</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pre-pilot_and_pilot_survey_the_tully_fisher_relation_in_eridanus_hydra_norma_and_ngc4636_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pre-pilot_and_pilot_survey_the_tully_fisher_relation_in_eridanus_hydra_norma_and_ngc4636_fields/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hélène M. Courtois
The WALLABY pilot survey has been conducted using the Australian SKA Pathfinder (ASKAP). The integrated 21-cm HI line spectra are formed in a very different manner compared to usual single-dish spectra Tully-Fisher measurements. It is thus extremely important to ensure that slight differences (e.g. biases due to missing flux) are quantified and understood in order to maximise the use of the large amount of data becoming available soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
