<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blackhole physics on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/blackhole-physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blackhole physics on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/blackhole-physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spectro-spatial evolution of the CMB II: generalised Boltzmann hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_ii_generalised_boltzmann_hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_ii_generalised_boltzmann_hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jens Chluba
In this paper, we formulate a generalised photon Boltzmann hierarchy that allows us to model the evolution and creation of spectral distortion anisotropies in the early Universe. We directly build on our first paper in this series, extending the thermalisation Green&amp;rsquo;s function treatment to the anisotropic case. We show that the problem can be described with the common Boltzmann hierarchy for the photon field extended by new spectral parameters &amp;ndash; a step that reduces the complexity of the calculation by at least two orders of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of corotation on gradual solar energetic particle event intensity profiles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_impact_of_corotation_on_gradual_solar_energetic_particle_event_intensity_profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_impact_of_corotation_on_gradual_solar_energetic_particle_event_intensity_profiles/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Hutchinson
Corotation of particle-filled magnetic flux tubes is generally thought to have a minor influence on the time-intensity profiles of gradual Solar Energetic Particle (SEP) events. For this reason many models solve the focussed transport equation within the corotating frame, thus neglecting corotation effects. We study the effects of corotation on gradual SEP intensity profiles at a range of observer longitudinal positions relative to the solar source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Task: Deriving Semantic Class Targets for the Physical Sciences</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_task_deriving_semantic_class_targets_for_the_physical_sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_task_deriving_semantic_class_targets_for_the_physical_sciences/</guid>
      <description>First author: Micah Bowles
We define deriving semantic class targets as a novel multi-modal task. By doing so, we aim to improve classification schemes in the physical sciences which can be severely abstracted and obfuscating. We address this task for upcoming radio astronomy surveys and present the derived semantic radio galaxy morphology class targets.
arxiv link
pdf link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies I: Mass-Size Outliers Among the Satellites of Milky Way Analogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/beyond_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_i_mass-size_outliers_among_the_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/beyond_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_i_mass-size_outliers_among_the_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiaxuan Li
Large diffuse galaxies are hard to find, but understanding the environments where they live, their numbers, and ultimately their origins, is of intense interest and importance for galaxy formation and evolution. Using Subaru&amp;rsquo;s Hyper Suprime-Cam Strategic Survey Program, we perform a systematic search for low surface brightness galaxies and present novel and effective methods for detecting and modeling them. As a case study, we surveyed 922 Milky Way analogs in the nearby Universe ($0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar Object Accessibility and Mission Design</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/interstellar_object_accessibility_and_mission_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/interstellar_object_accessibility_and_mission_design/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin P. S. Donitz
Interstellar objects (ISOs) are fascinating and under-explored celestial objects, providing physical laboratories to understand the formation of our solar system and probe the composition and properties of material formed in exoplanetary systems. This paper will discuss the accessibility of and mission design to ISOs with varying characteristics, including a discussion of state covariance estimation over the course of a cruise, handoffs from traditional navigation approaches to novel autonomous navigation for fast flyby regimes, and overall recommendations about preparing for the future in situ exploration of these targets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-Earth Interplanetary Coronal Mass Ejections and Their Association with DH Type II Radio Bursts During Solar Cycles 23 and 24</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/near-earth_interplanetary_coronal_mass_ejections_and_their_association_with_dh_type_ii_radio_bursts_during_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/near-earth_interplanetary_coronal_mass_ejections_and_their_association_with_dh_type_ii_radio_bursts_during_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</guid>
      <description>First author: Binal D. Patel
We analyse the characteristics of interplanetary coronal mass ejections (ICMEs) during Solar Cycles 23 and 24. The present analysis is primarily based on the near-Earth ICME catalogue (Richardson and Cane, 2010). An important aspect of this study is to understand the near-Earth and geoeffective aspects of ICMEs in terms of their association (type II ICMEs) versus absence (non-type II ICMEs) of decameter-hectometer (DH) type II radio bursts, detected by Wind/WAVES and STEREOS/WAVES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a scaling relation between coherent radio emission and physical parameters of hot magnetic stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/testing_a_scaling_relation_between_coherent_radio_emission_and_physical_parameters_of_hot_magnetic_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/testing_a_scaling_relation_between_coherent_radio_emission_and_physical_parameters_of_hot_magnetic_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Barnali Das
Coherent radio emission via electron cyclotron maser emission (ECME) from hot magnetic stars was discovered more than two decades ago, but the physical conditions that make the generation of ECME favourable remain uncertain. Only recently was an empirical relation, connecting ECME luminosity with the stellar magnetic field and temperature, proposed to explain what makes a hot magnetic star capable of producing ECME. This relation was, however, obtained with just fourteen stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of winds on atmospheric layers of red supergiants I. Modelling for interferometric observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_effect_of_winds_on_atmospheric_layers_of_red_supergiants_i._modelling_for_interferometric_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_effect_of_winds_on_atmospheric_layers_of_red_supergiants_i._modelling_for_interferometric_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. González-Torà
Red supergiants (RSGs) are evolved massive stars in a stage preceding core-collapse supernova. The physical processes that trigger mass loss in their atmospheres are still not fully understood. Based on observations of $\alpha$ Ori, a new semi-empirical method to add a wind to hydrostatic model atmospheres of RSGs was recently developed. We use this method of adding a wind to a MARCS model atmosphere to compute synthetic observables, comparing the model to spatially resolved interferometric observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELVES IV: The Satellite Stellar-to-Halo Mass Relation Beyond the Milky-Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iv_the_satellite_stellar-to-halo_mass_relation_beyond_the_milky-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iv_the_satellite_stellar-to-halo_mass_relation_beyond_the_milky-way/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shany Danieli
Quantifying the connection between galaxies and their host dark matter halos has been key for testing cosmological models on various scales. Below $M_\star \sim 10^9,M_\odot$, such studies have primarily relied on the satellite galaxy population orbiting the Milky Way. Here we present new constraints on the connection between satellite galaxies and their host dark matter subhalos using the largest sample of satellite galaxies in the Local Volume ($D \lesssim 12,\mathrm{Mpc}$) to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light pollution and the concentration of anthropogenic photons in the terrestrial atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/light_pollution_and_the_concentration_of_anthropogenic_photons_in_the_terrestrial_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/light_pollution_and_the_concentration_of_anthropogenic_photons_in_the_terrestrial_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Salvador Bará
Light pollution can be rigorously described in terms of the volume concentration of anthropogenic photons (light quanta) in the terrestrial atmosphere. This formulation, consistent with the basic physics of the emission, scattering and absorption of light, allows one to express light pollution levels in terms of particle volume concentrations, in a completely analogous way as it is currently done with other classical pollutants, like particulate matter or molecular contaminants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects and challenges of numerical modelling of the Sun at millimetre wavelengths</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prospects_and_challenges_of_numerical_modelling_of_the_sun_at_millimetre_wavelengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prospects_and_challenges_of_numerical_modelling_of_the_sun_at_millimetre_wavelengths/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sven Wedemeyer
The Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) offers new diagnostic possibilities that complement other commonly used diagnostics for the study of our Sun. In particular, ALMA&amp;rsquo;s ability to serve as an essentially linear thermometer of the chromospheric gas at unprecedented spatial resolution at millimetre wavelengths and future polarisation measurements have great diagnostic potential. Solar ALMA observations are therefore expected to contribute significantly to answering long-standing questions about the structure, dynamics and energy balance of the outer layers of the solar atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What sets the splashback radius of dark matter haloes: accretion history or other properties?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/what_sets_the_splashback_radius_of_dark_matter_haloes_accretion_history_or_other_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/what_sets_the_splashback_radius_of_dark_matter_haloes_accretion_history_or_other_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tae-hyeon Shin
The density profiles of dark matter haloes contain rich information about their growth history and physical properties. One particularly interesting region is the splashback radius, $R_{\rm sp}$, which marks the transition between particles orbiting in the halo and particles undergoing first infall. While the dependence of $R_{\rm sp}$ on the recent accretion rate is well established and theoretically expected, it is not clear exactly what parts of the accretion history $R_{\rm sp}$ responds to, and what other halo properties might additionally influence its position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D modelling of the impact of stellar activity on tidally locked terrestrial exoplanets: atmospheric composition and habitability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/3d_modelling_of_the_impact_of_stellar_activity_on_tidally_locked_terrestrial_exoplanets_atmospheric_composition_and_habitability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/3d_modelling_of_the_impact_of_stellar_activity_on_tidally_locked_terrestrial_exoplanets_atmospheric_composition_and_habitability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Robert J. Ridgway
Stellar flares present challenges to the potential habitability of terrestrial planets orbiting M dwarf stars through inducing changes in the atmospheric composition and irradiating the planet&amp;rsquo;s surface in large amounts of ultraviolet light. To examine their impact, we have coupled a general circulation model with a photochemical kinetics scheme to examine the response and changes of an Earth-like atmosphere to stellar flares and coronal mass ejections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Atmospheric Retrieval of the Brown Dwarf Gliese 229B</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_atmospheric_retrieval_of_the_brown_dwarf_gliese_229b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_atmospheric_retrieval_of_the_brown_dwarf_gliese_229b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emily Calamari
We present results from an atmospheric retrieval analysis of Gl 229B using the BREWSTER retrieval code. We find the best fit model to be cloud-free, consistent with the T dwarf retrieval work of Line et al. 2017, Zalesky et al. 2022 and Gonzales et al. 2020. Fundamental parameters (mass, radius, log(L_{Bol}/L_{Sun}), log(g)) determined from our model agree within 1\sigma to SED-derived values except for T_{eff} where our retrieved T_{eff} is approximately 100 K cooler than the evolutionary model-based SED value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal lensing solutions in the singular perturbative approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/minimal_lensing_solutions_in_the_singular_perturbative_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/minimal_lensing_solutions_in_the_singular_perturbative_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christophe Alard
This paper analyse the properties of minimal solutions for the reconstruction of the lens potential in the singular perturbative approach. These minimal solutions corresponds to an expansion with a minimal degree in Fourier expansion of the perturbative fields. Using these minimal solutions prevent spurious physically meaningless terms in the reconstruction of the fields. In effect a perturbative analysis indicates that a small change in the source model will corresponds to the higher order terms in the expansion of the fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-type Stars Stellar Parameter Estimation Using Recurrent Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/o-type_stars_stellar_parameter_estimation_using_recurrent_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/o-type_stars_stellar_parameter_estimation_using_recurrent_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Miguel Flores R.
In this paper, we present a deep learning system approach to estimating luminosity, effective temperature, and surface gravity of O-type stars using the optical region of the stellar spectra. In previous work, we compare a set of machine learning and deep learning algorithms in order to establish a reliable way to fit a stellar model using two methods: the classification of the stellar spectra models and the estimation of the physical parameters in a regression-type task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ExoMol line lists -- {XLVI}: Empirical rovibronic spectra of silicon mononitrate (SiN) covering the 6 lowest electronic states and 4 isotopologues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlvi_empirical_rovibronic_spectra_of_silicon_mononitrate_sin_covering_the_6_lowest_electronic_states_and_4_isotopologues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlvi_empirical_rovibronic_spectra_of_silicon_mononitrate_sin_covering_the_6_lowest_electronic_states_and_4_isotopologues/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mikhail Semenov
Silicon mononitride ($^{28}$Si$^{14}$N, $^{29}$Si$^{14}$N, $^{30}$Si$^{14}$N, $^{28}$Si$^{15}$N) line lists covering infrared, visible and ultraviolet regions are presented. The \name\ line lists produced by ExoMol include rovibronic transitions between six electronic states: \XS, \AS, \BS, \DS, \asi, \bsi. The \ai\ potential energy and coupling curves, computed at the multireference configuration interaction (MRCI/aug-cc-pVQZ) level of theory, are refined for the observed states by fitting their analytical representations to 1052 experimentally derived SiN energy levels determined from rovibronic bands belonging to the $X$&amp;ndash;$X$, $A$&amp;ndash;$X$ and $B$&amp;ndash;$X$ electronic systems through the MARVEL procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Perpendicular Alignments of Velocity Gradient and Magnetic Field observed in the Molecular Clouds L1478 and L1482</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/parallel_and_perpendicular_alignments_of_velocity_gradient_and_magnetic_field_observed_in_the_molecular_clouds_l1478_and_l1482/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/parallel_and_perpendicular_alignments_of_velocity_gradient_and_magnetic_field_observed_in_the_molecular_clouds_l1478_and_l1482/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tyler Schmaltz
Star formation is a complex process that typically occurs in dense regions of molecular clouds mainly regulated by magnetic fields, magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) turbulence, and self-gravity. However, it remains a challenging endeavor to trace the magnetic field and determine regions of gravitational collapse where the star is forming. Based on the anisotropic properties of MHD turbulence, a new technique termed Velocity Gradient Technique (VGT) has been proposed to address these challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the interior structure of icy moons with a Bayesian approach to magnetic induction measurements</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_the_interior_structure_of_icy_moons_with_a_bayesian_approach_to_magnetic_induction_measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_the_interior_structure_of_icy_moons_with_a_bayesian_approach_to_magnetic_induction_measurements/</guid>
      <description>First author: John B. Biersteker
Some icy moons and small bodies in the solar system are believed to host subsurface liquid water oceans. The interaction of these saline, electrically conductive oceans with time-varying external magnetic fields generates induced magnetic fields. Magnetometry observations of these induced fields in turn enable the detection and characterization of these oceans. We present a framework for characterizing the interiors of icy moons using multi-frequency induction and Bayesian inference applied to magnetometry measurements anticipated from the upcoming Europa Clipper mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of water and electron collisions in the rotational excitation of HF in comets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_water_and_electron_collisions_in_the_rotational_excitation_of_hf_in_comets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_water_and_electron_collisions_in_the_rotational_excitation_of_hf_in_comets/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Loreau
We present the first set of rate coefficients for the rotational excitation of the 7 lowest levels of hydrogen fluoride (HF) induced by collision with water molecules, the dominant collider in cometary comas, in the 5-150 K temperature range. The calculations are performed with a quantum statistical approach from an accurate rigid rotor ab initio interaction potential. Rate coefficients for excitation of HF by electron-impact are also computed, within the Born approximation, in the 10-10,000 K temperature range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Study and Live Catalogue of Multi-Spacecraft 3He-Rich Time Periods over Solar Cycles 23, 24, and 25</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_study_and_live_catalogue_of_multi-spacecraft_3he-rich_time_periods_over_solar_cycles_23_24_and_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_study_and_live_catalogue_of_multi-spacecraft_3he-rich_time_periods_over_solar_cycles_23_24_and_25/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samuel T. Hart
Using ion measurements from Ultra-Low-Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) observations onboard Advanced Composition Explorer (ACE) and Solar Isotope Spectrometer (SIS) observations onboard the Solar Terrestrial Observatory (STEREO)-A and STEREO-B spacecraft, we have identified 854 3He-rich time periods between 1997 September and 2021 March. We include all event types with observed 3He enhancements such as corotating interaction regions (CIRs), gradual solar energetic particle (SEP) events, interplanetary shocks, and impulsive SEP events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
