<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blackhole physics on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/blackhole-physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blackhole physics on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/blackhole-physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Task: Deriving Semantic Class Targets for the Physical Sciences</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_task_deriving_semantic_class_targets_for_the_physical_sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_task_deriving_semantic_class_targets_for_the_physical_sciences/</guid>
      <description>First author: Micah Bowles
We define deriving semantic class targets as a novel multi-modal task. By doing so, we aim to improve classification schemes in the physical sciences which can be severely abstracted and obfuscating. We address this task for upcoming radio astronomy surveys and present the derived semantic radio galaxy morphology class targets.
arxiv link
pdf link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-Earth Interplanetary Coronal Mass Ejections and Their Association with DH Type II Radio Bursts During Solar Cycles 23 and 24</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/near-earth_interplanetary_coronal_mass_ejections_and_their_association_with_dh_type_ii_radio_bursts_during_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/near-earth_interplanetary_coronal_mass_ejections_and_their_association_with_dh_type_ii_radio_bursts_during_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</guid>
      <description>First author: Binal D. Patel
We analyse the characteristics of interplanetary coronal mass ejections (ICMEs) during Solar Cycles 23 and 24. The present analysis is primarily based on the near-Earth ICME catalogue (Richardson and Cane, 2010). An important aspect of this study is to understand the near-Earth and geoeffective aspects of ICMEs in terms of their association (type II ICMEs) versus absence (non-type II ICMEs) of decameter-hectometer (DH) type II radio bursts, detected by Wind/WAVES and STEREOS/WAVES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a scaling relation between coherent radio emission and physical parameters of hot magnetic stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/testing_a_scaling_relation_between_coherent_radio_emission_and_physical_parameters_of_hot_magnetic_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/testing_a_scaling_relation_between_coherent_radio_emission_and_physical_parameters_of_hot_magnetic_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Barnali Das
Coherent radio emission via electron cyclotron maser emission (ECME) from hot magnetic stars was discovered more than two decades ago, but the physical conditions that make the generation of ECME favourable remain uncertain. Only recently was an empirical relation, connecting ECME luminosity with the stellar magnetic field and temperature, proposed to explain what makes a hot magnetic star capable of producing ECME. This relation was, however, obtained with just fourteen stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELVES IV: The Satellite Stellar-to-Halo Mass Relation Beyond the Milky-Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iv_the_satellite_stellar-to-halo_mass_relation_beyond_the_milky-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iv_the_satellite_stellar-to-halo_mass_relation_beyond_the_milky-way/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shany Danieli
Quantifying the connection between galaxies and their host dark matter halos has been key for testing cosmological models on various scales. Below $M_\star \sim 10^9,M_\odot$, such studies have primarily relied on the satellite galaxy population orbiting the Milky Way. Here we present new constraints on the connection between satellite galaxies and their host dark matter subhalos using the largest sample of satellite galaxies in the Local Volume ($D \lesssim 12,\mathrm{Mpc}$) to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light pollution and the concentration of anthropogenic photons in the terrestrial atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/light_pollution_and_the_concentration_of_anthropogenic_photons_in_the_terrestrial_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/light_pollution_and_the_concentration_of_anthropogenic_photons_in_the_terrestrial_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Salvador Bará
Light pollution can be rigorously described in terms of the volume concentration of anthropogenic photons (light quanta) in the terrestrial atmosphere. This formulation, consistent with the basic physics of the emission, scattering and absorption of light, allows one to express light pollution levels in terms of particle volume concentrations, in a completely analogous way as it is currently done with other classical pollutants, like particulate matter or molecular contaminants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects and challenges of numerical modelling of the Sun at millimetre wavelengths</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prospects_and_challenges_of_numerical_modelling_of_the_sun_at_millimetre_wavelengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prospects_and_challenges_of_numerical_modelling_of_the_sun_at_millimetre_wavelengths/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sven Wedemeyer
The Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) offers new diagnostic possibilities that complement other commonly used diagnostics for the study of our Sun. In particular, ALMA&amp;rsquo;s ability to serve as an essentially linear thermometer of the chromospheric gas at unprecedented spatial resolution at millimetre wavelengths and future polarisation measurements have great diagnostic potential. Solar ALMA observations are therefore expected to contribute significantly to answering long-standing questions about the structure, dynamics and energy balance of the outer layers of the solar atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What sets the splashback radius of dark matter haloes: accretion history or other properties?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/what_sets_the_splashback_radius_of_dark_matter_haloes_accretion_history_or_other_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/what_sets_the_splashback_radius_of_dark_matter_haloes_accretion_history_or_other_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tae-hyeon Shin
The density profiles of dark matter haloes contain rich information about their growth history and physical properties. One particularly interesting region is the splashback radius, $R_{\rm sp}$, which marks the transition between particles orbiting in the halo and particles undergoing first infall. While the dependence of $R_{\rm sp}$ on the recent accretion rate is well established and theoretically expected, it is not clear exactly what parts of the accretion history $R_{\rm sp}$ responds to, and what other halo properties might additionally influence its position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D modelling of the impact of stellar activity on tidally locked terrestrial exoplanets: atmospheric composition and habitability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/3d_modelling_of_the_impact_of_stellar_activity_on_tidally_locked_terrestrial_exoplanets_atmospheric_composition_and_habitability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/3d_modelling_of_the_impact_of_stellar_activity_on_tidally_locked_terrestrial_exoplanets_atmospheric_composition_and_habitability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Robert J. Ridgway
Stellar flares present challenges to the potential habitability of terrestrial planets orbiting M dwarf stars through inducing changes in the atmospheric composition and irradiating the planet&amp;rsquo;s surface in large amounts of ultraviolet light. To examine their impact, we have coupled a general circulation model with a photochemical kinetics scheme to examine the response and changes of an Earth-like atmosphere to stellar flares and coronal mass ejections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Atmospheric Retrieval of the Brown Dwarf Gliese 229B</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_atmospheric_retrieval_of_the_brown_dwarf_gliese_229b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_atmospheric_retrieval_of_the_brown_dwarf_gliese_229b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emily Calamari
We present results from an atmospheric retrieval analysis of Gl 229B using the BREWSTER retrieval code. We find the best fit model to be cloud-free, consistent with the T dwarf retrieval work of Line et al. 2017, Zalesky et al. 2022 and Gonzales et al. 2020. Fundamental parameters (mass, radius, log(L_{Bol}/L_{Sun}), log(g)) determined from our model agree within 1\sigma to SED-derived values except for T_{eff} where our retrieved T_{eff} is approximately 100 K cooler than the evolutionary model-based SED value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal lensing solutions in the singular perturbative approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/minimal_lensing_solutions_in_the_singular_perturbative_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/minimal_lensing_solutions_in_the_singular_perturbative_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christophe Alard
This paper analyse the properties of minimal solutions for the reconstruction of the lens potential in the singular perturbative approach. These minimal solutions corresponds to an expansion with a minimal degree in Fourier expansion of the perturbative fields. Using these minimal solutions prevent spurious physically meaningless terms in the reconstruction of the fields. In effect a perturbative analysis indicates that a small change in the source model will corresponds to the higher order terms in the expansion of the fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-type Stars Stellar Parameter Estimation Using Recurrent Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/o-type_stars_stellar_parameter_estimation_using_recurrent_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/o-type_stars_stellar_parameter_estimation_using_recurrent_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Miguel Flores R.
In this paper, we present a deep learning system approach to estimating luminosity, effective temperature, and surface gravity of O-type stars using the optical region of the stellar spectra. In previous work, we compare a set of machine learning and deep learning algorithms in order to establish a reliable way to fit a stellar model using two methods: the classification of the stellar spectra models and the estimation of the physical parameters in a regression-type task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ExoMol line lists -- {XLVI}: Empirical rovibronic spectra of silicon mononitrate (SiN) covering the 6 lowest electronic states and 4 isotopologues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlvi_empirical_rovibronic_spectra_of_silicon_mononitrate_sin_covering_the_6_lowest_electronic_states_and_4_isotopologues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/exomol_line_lists_--_xlvi_empirical_rovibronic_spectra_of_silicon_mononitrate_sin_covering_the_6_lowest_electronic_states_and_4_isotopologues/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mikhail Semenov
Silicon mononitride ($^{28}$Si$^{14}$N, $^{29}$Si$^{14}$N, $^{30}$Si$^{14}$N, $^{28}$Si$^{15}$N) line lists covering infrared, visible and ultraviolet regions are presented. The \name\ line lists produced by ExoMol include rovibronic transitions between six electronic states: \XS, \AS, \BS, \DS, \asi, \bsi. The \ai\ potential energy and coupling curves, computed at the multireference configuration interaction (MRCI/aug-cc-pVQZ) level of theory, are refined for the observed states by fitting their analytical representations to 1052 experimentally derived SiN energy levels determined from rovibronic bands belonging to the $X$&amp;ndash;$X$, $A$&amp;ndash;$X$ and $B$&amp;ndash;$X$ electronic systems through the MARVEL procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Perpendicular Alignments of Velocity Gradient and Magnetic Field observed in the Molecular Clouds L1478 and L1482</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/parallel_and_perpendicular_alignments_of_velocity_gradient_and_magnetic_field_observed_in_the_molecular_clouds_l1478_and_l1482/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/parallel_and_perpendicular_alignments_of_velocity_gradient_and_magnetic_field_observed_in_the_molecular_clouds_l1478_and_l1482/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tyler Schmaltz
Star formation is a complex process that typically occurs in dense regions of molecular clouds mainly regulated by magnetic fields, magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) turbulence, and self-gravity. However, it remains a challenging endeavor to trace the magnetic field and determine regions of gravitational collapse where the star is forming. Based on the anisotropic properties of MHD turbulence, a new technique termed Velocity Gradient Technique (VGT) has been proposed to address these challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for thermal gyro-synchrotron emission from hot stellar coronae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_thermal_gyro-synchrotron_emission_from_hot_stellar_coronae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_thermal_gyro-synchrotron_emission_from_hot_stellar_coronae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Walter Golay
We have searched for thermal gyro-synchrotron radio emission from a sample of five radio-loud stars whose X-ray coronae contain a hot ($T&amp;gt;10^7$ K) thermal component. We used the JVLA to measure Stokes I and V/I spectral energy distributions (SEDs) over the frequency range 15&amp;ndash;45 GHz, determining the best-fitting model parameters using power-law and thermal gyro-synchrotron emission models. The SEDs of the three chromospherically active binaries (Algol, UX Arietis, HR 1099) were well-fit by a power-law gyro-synchrotron model, with no evidence for a thermal component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Interstellar Medium as an Evolutionary Tracer in ALMA-Observed Local Dusty Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cool_interstellar_medium_as_an_evolutionary_tracer_in_alma-observed_local_dusty_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cool_interstellar_medium_as_an_evolutionary_tracer_in_alma-observed_local_dusty_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David H. W. Glass
The content and distribution of cool interstellar medium (ISM, &amp;lt;30K) can indicate the evolutionary mechanisms that transform late type to early type galaxies (ETGs). To investigate this, ALMA observations of 12CO[2-1] line emission were obtained for five dusty ETGs from a complete sample in low-density environments. Four of the ETGs have massive (approximately 10^9 Msolar), extended molecular gas reservoirs with effective radii of approximately 3 to 5 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiency of the top-down PAH-to-fullerene conversion in UV irradiated environments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/efficiency_of_the_top-down_pah-to-fullerene_conversion_in_uv_irradiated_environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/efficiency_of_the_top-down_pah-to-fullerene_conversion_in_uv_irradiated_environments/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. S. Murga
Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) and fullerenes play a major role in the physics and chemistry of the interstellar medium. Based on a number of recent experimental and theoretical investigations we developed a model in which PAHs are subject to photo-dissociation (carbon and hydrogen loss) and hydrogenation. We take into account that dehydrogenated PAHs may fold into closed structures &amp;ndash; fullerenes. Fullerenes, in their turn, can be also hydrogenated, becoming fulleranes, and photo-dissociated, losing carbon and hydrogen atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical turbulence forecast over short timescales using machine learning techniques</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_turbulence_forecast_over_short_timescales_using_machine_learning_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_turbulence_forecast_over_short_timescales_using_machine_learning_techniques/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Turchi
Forecast of optical turbulence and atmospheric parameters relevant for ground-based astronomy is becoming an important goal for telescope planning and AO instruments optimization in several major telescope. Such detailed and accurate forecast is typically performed with numerical atmospheric models. Recently short-term forecasts (a few hours in advance) are also being provided (ALTA project) using a technique based on an autoregression approach, as part of a strategy that aims to increase the forecast accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible Evidence for Lorentz Invariance Violation in Gamma-ray Burst 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/possible_evidence_for_lorentz_invariance_violation_in_gamma-ray_burst_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/possible_evidence_for_lorentz_invariance_violation_in_gamma-ray_burst_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Justin D. Finke
The preliminary detections of the gamma-ray burst 221009A up to 18 TeV by LHAASO and up to 251 TeV by Carpet 2 have been reported through Astronomer&amp;rsquo;s Telegrams and Gamma-ray Coordination Network circulars. Since this burst is at redshift $z=0.15$, these photons may at first seem to have a low probability to avoid pair production off of background radiation fields and survive to reach detectors on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search for the Topology of the Universe Has Just Begun</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_search_for_the_topology_of_the_universe_has_just_begun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_search_for_the_topology_of_the_universe_has_just_begun/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yashar Akrami
Anomalous large-angle cosmic microwave background anisotropies motivate further searches for cosmic topology. We demonstrate that for generic topologies of spatially flat spacetimes, off-diagonal correlations between microwave background harmonic coefficients over a wide range of scales encode significant topological information, even if the topology scale substantially exceeds the diameter of the observable Universe. Observational searches have so far considered only a small subset of testable topologies, and current limits on the topology scale are much weaker than generally understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting the oscillation and propagation of the nascent dynamic solar wind structure at 2.6 solar radii using VLBI radio telescopes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detecting_the_oscillation_and_propagation_of_the_nascent_dynamic_solar_wind_structure_at_2.6_solar_radii_using_vlbi_radio_telescopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detecting_the_oscillation_and_propagation_of_the_nascent_dynamic_solar_wind_structure_at_2.6_solar_radii_using_vlbi_radio_telescopes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maoli Ma
Probing the solar corona is crucial to study the coronal heating and solar wind acceleration. However, the transient and inhomogeneous solar wind flows carry large-amplitude inherent Alfven waves and turbulence, which make detection more difficult. We report the oscillation and propagation of the solar wind at 2.6 solar radii (Rs) by observation of China Tianwen and ESA Mars Express with radio telescopes. The observations were carried out on Oct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequency Agile Solar Radiotelescope: A Next-Generation Radio Telescope for Solar Physics and Space Weather</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/frequency_agile_solar_radiotelescope_a_next-generation_radio_telescope_for_solar_physics_and_space_weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/frequency_agile_solar_radiotelescope_a_next-generation_radio_telescope_for_solar_physics_and_space_weather/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dale E. Gary
The Frequency Agile Solar Radiotelescope (FASR) has been strongly endorsed as a top community priority by both Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics Decadal Surveys and Solar &amp;amp; Space Physics Decadal Surveys in the past two decades. Although it was developed to a high state of readiness in previous years (it went through a CATE analysis and was declared ``doable now&amp;quot;), the NSF has not had the funding mechanisms in place to fund this mid-scale program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOGREEN: a critical assessment of environmental trends in cosmological hydrodynamical simulations at z ~ 1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gogreen_a_critical_assessment_of_environmental_trends_in_cosmological_hydrodynamical_simulations_at_z_~_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gogreen_a_critical_assessment_of_environmental_trends_in_cosmological_hydrodynamical_simulations_at_z_~_1/</guid>
      <description>First author: Egidijus Kukstas
Recent observations have shown that the environmental quenching of galaxies at z ~ 1 is qualitatively different to that in the local Universe. However, the physical origin of these differences has not yet been elucidated. In addition, while low-redshift comparisons between observed environmental trends and the predictions of cosmological hydrodynamical simulations are now routine, there have been relatively few comparisons at higher redshifts to date. Here we confront three state-of-the-art suites of simulations (BAHAMAS+MACSIS, EAGLE+Hydrangea, IllustrisTNG) with state-of-the-art observations of the field and cluster environments from the COSMOS/UltraVISTA and GOGREEN surveys, respectively, at z ~ 1 to assess the realism of the simulations and gain insight into the evolution of environmental quenching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference finds consistency between a neutrino flavor evolution model and Earth-based solar neutrino measurements</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_finds_consistency_between_a_neutrino_flavor_evolution_model_and_earth-based_solar_neutrino_measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_finds_consistency_between_a_neutrino_flavor_evolution_model_and_earth-based_solar_neutrino_measurements/</guid>
      <description>First author: Caroline Laber-Smith
We continue examining statistical data assimilation (SDA), an inference methodology, to infer solutions to neutrino flavor evolution, for the first time using real - rather than simulated - data. The model represents neutrinos streaming from the Sun&amp;rsquo;s center and undergoing a Mikheyev-Smirnov-Wolfenstein (MSW) resonance in flavor space, due to the radially-varying electron number density. The model neutrino energies are chosen to correspond to experimental bins in the Sudbury Neutrino Observatory (SNO) and Borexino experiments, which measure electron-flavor survival probability at Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionisation of inner T Tauri star discs: effects of in-situ energetic particles produced by strong magnetic reconnection events</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ionisation_of_inner_t_tauri_star_discs_effects_of_in-situ_energetic_particles_produced_by_strong_magnetic_reconnection_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ionisation_of_inner_t_tauri_star_discs_effects_of_in-situ_energetic_particles_produced_by_strong_magnetic_reconnection_events/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brunn V
Magnetic reconnection is one of the major particle acceleration processes in space and astrophysical plasmas. Low-energy supra-thermal particles emitted by magnetic reconnection are a source of ionisation for circumstellar discs, influencing their chemical, thermal and dynamical evolution. The aim of this work is to propose a first investigation to evaluate how energetic particles can propagate in the circumstellar disc of a T Tauri star and how they affect the ionisation rate of the disc plasma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconnection-Driven Energy Cascade in Magnetohydrodynamic Turbulence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconnection-driven_energy_cascade_in_magnetohydrodynamic_turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconnection-driven_energy_cascade_in_magnetohydrodynamic_turbulence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chuanfei Dong
Magnetohydrodynamic turbulence regulates the transfer of energy from large to small scales in many astrophysical systems, including the solar atmosphere. We perform three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic simulations with unprecedentedly large magnetic Reynolds number to reveal how rapid reconnection of magnetic field lines changes the classical paradigm of the turbulent energy cascade. By breaking elongated current sheets into chains of small magnetic flux ropes (or plasmoids), magnetic reconnection leads to a new range of turbulent energy cascade, where the rate of energy transfer is controlled by the growth rate of the plasmoids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing ultra-high-energy cosmic ray acceleration with multi-messenger observations of the nearby GRB 980425/SN 1998bw</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_ray_acceleration_with_multi-messenger_observations_of_the_nearby_grb_980425_sn_1998bw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_ray_acceleration_with_multi-messenger_observations_of_the_nearby_grb_980425_sn_1998bw/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nestor Mirabal
The origin of ultra-high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) is one of the most mystifying issues in astroparticle physics. It has been suggested that gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are excellent acceleration sites for cosmic rays. The propagation of UHECRs from the GRB host galaxy to the Earth should generate delayed secondary photons and neutrinos. Here we present a dedicated search for delayed UHECR and neutrino emission centered around the position of nearby GRB 980425/SN 1998bw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation level of turbulence in collapsing gas clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_level_of_turbulence_in_collapsing_gas_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_level_of_turbulence_in_collapsing_gas_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sho Higashi
We investigate the physical mechanism that decides the saturation level of turbulence in collapsing gas clouds. We perform a suite of high-resolution numerical simulations following the collapse of turbulent gas clouds with various effective polytropic exponents $\gamma_{\rm eff}$, initial Mach numbers $\mathcal{M}0$, and initial turbulent seeds. Equating the energy injection rate by gravitational contraction and the dissipation rate of turbulence, we obtain an analytic expression of the saturation level of turbulence, and compare it with the numerical results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Ring Mission: Building a Panorama of the Sun and Inner-heliosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solar_ring_mission_building_a_panorama_of_the_sun_and_inner-heliosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solar_ring_mission_building_a_panorama_of_the_sun_and_inner-heliosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuming Wang
Solar Ring (SOR) is a proposed space science mission to monitor and study the Sun and inner heliosphere from a full 360{\deg} perspective in the ecliptic plane. It will deploy three 120{\deg}-separated spacecraft on the 1-AU orbit. The first spacecraft, S1, locates 30{\deg} upstream of the Earth, the second, S2, 90{\deg} downstream, and the third, S3, completes the configuration. This design with necessary science instruments, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFAW survey II: 6 Newly Validated Planets and 13 Planet Candidates from K2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tfaw_survey_ii_6_newly_validated_planets_and_13_planet_candidates_from_k2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tfaw_survey_ii_6_newly_validated_planets_and_13_planet_candidates_from_k2/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. del Ser
Searching for Earth-sized planets in data from Kepler&amp;rsquo;s extended mission (K2) is a niche that still remains to be fully exploited. The TFAW survey is an ongoing project that aims to re-analyze all light curves in K2 C1-C8 and C12-C18 campaigns with a wavelet-based detrending and denoising method, and the period search algorithm TLS to search for new transit candidates not detected in previous works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Two Years of FLEET: an Active Search for Superluminous Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_first_two_years_of_fleet_an_active_search_for_superluminous_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_first_two_years_of_fleet_an_active_search_for_superluminous_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sebastian Gomez
In November 2019 we began operating FLEET (Finding Luminous and Exotic Extragalactic Transients), a machine learning algorithm designed to photometrically identify Type I superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) in transient alert streams. Using FLEET, we spectroscopically classified 21 of the 50 SLSNe identified worldwide between November 2019 and January 2022. Based on our original algorithm, we anticipated that FLEET would achieve a purity of about 50% for transients with a probability of being a SLSN, \pslsn$&amp;gt;0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The integrated perturbation theory for cosmological tensor fields I: Basic formulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_integrated_perturbation_theory_for_cosmological_tensor_fields_i_basic_formulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_integrated_perturbation_theory_for_cosmological_tensor_fields_i_basic_formulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takahiko Matsubara
In order to extract maximal information about cosmology from the large-scale structure of the Universe, one needs to use every bit of signals that can be observed. Beyond the spatial distributions of astronomical objects, the spatial correlations of tensor fields, such as galaxy spins and shapes, are ones of promising sources that we can access in the era of large surveys in near future. The perturbation theory is a powerful tool to analytically describe the behaviors and evolutions of correlation statistics for a given cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: Semi-analytic galaxy formation models on the past lightcone</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_models_on_the_past_lightcone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_models_on_the_past_lightcone/</guid>
      <description>First author: Monica Barrera
Upcoming large galaxy surveys will subject the standard cosmological model, $\Lambda$CDM, to new precision tests. These can be tightened considerably if theoretical models of galaxy formation are available that can predict galaxy clustering and galaxy-galaxy lensing on the full range of measurable scales throughout volumes as large as those of the surveys and with sufficient flexibility that uncertain aspects of the underlying astrophysics can be marginalised over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of Pop III stars and early black holes in the 21cm signal from Cosmic Dawn</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_role_of_pop_iii_stars_and_early_black_holes_in_the_21cm_signal_from_cosmic_dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_role_of_pop_iii_stars_and_early_black_holes_in_the_21cm_signal_from_cosmic_dawn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emanuele M. Ventura
Modeling the 21cm global signal from the Cosmic Dawn is challenging due to the many poorly constrained physical processes that come into play. We address this problem using the semi-analytical code &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Archaeology Tool&amp;rdquo; (CAT). CAT follows the evolution of dark matter halos tracking their merger history and provides an ab initio description of their baryonic evolution, starting from the formation of the first (Pop III) stars and black holes (BHs) in mini-halos at z &amp;gt; 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional numerical simulations of ambipolar diffusion in NS cores in the one-fluid approximation: instability of poloidal magnetic field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three-dimensional_numerical_simulations_of_ambipolar_diffusion_in_ns_cores_in_the_one-fluid_approximation_instability_of_poloidal_magnetic_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three-dimensional_numerical_simulations_of_ambipolar_diffusion_in_ns_cores_in_the_one-fluid_approximation_instability_of_poloidal_magnetic_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrei P. Igoshev
We numerically model evolution of magnetic fields inside a neutron star under the influence of ambipolar diffusion in the weak-coupling mode in the one-fluid MHD approximation. Our simulations are three-dimensional and performed in spherical coordinates. Our model covers the neutron star core and includes crust where the magnetic field decay is due to Ohmic decay. We discover an instability of poloidal magnetic field under the influence of ambipolar diffusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-Delay Cosmography: Measuring the Hubble Constant and other cosmological parameters with strong gravitational lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-delay_cosmography_measuring_the_hubble_constant_and_other_cosmological_parameters_with_strong_gravitational_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-delay_cosmography_measuring_the_hubble_constant_and_other_cosmological_parameters_with_strong_gravitational_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Birrer
Multiply lensed sources experience a relative time delay in the arrival of photons. This effect can be used to measure absolute distances and the Hubble constant ($H_0$) and is known as time-delay cosmography. The methodology is independent of the local distance ladder and early-universe physics and provides a precise and competitive measurement of $H_0$. With upcoming observatories, time-delay cosmography can provide a 1% precision measurement of $H_0$ and can decisively shed light on the current reported &amp;lsquo;Hubble tension&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-Variable Jet Ejections from RW Aur A, RY Tau and DG Tau</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-variable_jet_ejections_from_rw_aur_a_ry_tau_and_dg_tau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-variable_jet_ejections_from_rw_aur_a_ry_tau_and_dg_tau/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michihiro Takami
We present Gemini-NIFS, VLT-SINFONI and Keck-OSIRIS observations of near-infrared [Fe II] emission associated with the well-studied jets from three active T Tauri stars; RW Aur A, RY Tau and DG Tau taken from 2012-2021. We primarily covered the redshifted jet from RW Aur A, and the blueshifted jets from RY Tau and DG Tau, to investigate long-term time variabilities potentially related to the activities of mass accretion and/or the stellar magnetic fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very High Energy Afterglow Emission of GRB~221009A: Lessons Learned from the Brightest Long Gamma-ray Burst in a Wind Environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/very_high_energy_afterglow_emission_of_grb~221009a_lessons_learned_from_the_brightest_long_gamma-ray_burst_in_a_wind_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/very_high_energy_afterglow_emission_of_grb~221009a_lessons_learned_from_the_brightest_long_gamma-ray_burst_in_a_wind_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jia Ren
In this paper, we modeled the dynamics and radiation physics of the rarity event GRB 221009A afterglow in detail. Based on the analysis results of the {\tt ASGARD} package we developed, the afterglow data of GRB 221009A strongly favors the origin of a relativistic jet propagating in a stellar-wind-dominated environment. Therefore, GRB 221009A is a typical lesson for the very high energy (VHE) afterglow of long gamma-ray burst in a wind environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray galaxies selected from HyperLEDA database</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_galaxies_selected_from_hyperleda_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_galaxies_selected_from_hyperleda_database/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Pulatova
We cross-matched the 4XMM-DR10 catalog with the HyperLEDA database and obtained the new sample of galaxies that contain X-ray sources. Excluding duplicate observations and false matches, we present a total of 7759 galaxies with X-ray sources. In the current work, we present general properties of the sample: namely the distribution in equatorial coordinates, radial velocity distribution, morphological type, and X-ray fluxes. The sample includes morphological classification for 5241 galaxies with X-ray emission, almost half of which, 42%, are elliptical (E, E-S0).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Radiative-Convective Model for Terrestrial Planets with Self-Consistent Patchy Clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_radiative-convective_model_for_terrestrial_planets_with_self-consistent_patchy_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_radiative-convective_model_for_terrestrial_planets_with_self-consistent_patchy_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: James D. Windsor
Clouds are ubiquitous, &amp;ndash; ,they arise for every solar system planet that possesses an atmosphere and have also been suggested as a leading mechanism for obscuring spectral features in exoplanet observations. As exoplanet observations continue to improve, there is a need for efficient and general planetary climate models that appropriately handle the possible cloudy atmospheric environments that arise on these worlds. We generate a new 1D radiative-convective terrestrial planet climate model that self-consistently handles patchy clouds through a parameterized microphysical treatment of condensation and sedimentation processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of flares on giant stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characteristics_of_flares_on_giant_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characteristics_of_flares_on_giant_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Katalin Oláh
Although late-type dwarfs and giant stars are substantially different, their flares are thought to originate in similar physical processes and differ only by a scale factor in the energy levels. We study the validity of this approach. We search for characteristics of flares on active giants, which might be statistically different from those on main-sequence stars. We used nearly 4000 flares of 61 giants and 20 stars of other types that were observed with Kepler in long-cadence mode, which is the only suitable database for this comparative study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Investigation of Neutral Gas Origins (DINGO): HI stacking experiments with early science data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_investigation_of_neutral_gas_origins_dingo_hi_stacking_experiments_with_early_science_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_investigation_of_neutral_gas_origins_dingo_hi_stacking_experiments_with_early_science_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jonghwan Rhee
We present early science results from Deep Investigation of Neutral Gas Origins (DINGO), an HI survey using the Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP). Using ASKAP sub-arrays available during its commissioning phase, DINGO early science data were taken over $\sim$ 60 deg$^{2}$ of the Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) 23 h region with 35.5 hr integration time. We make direct detections of six known and one new sources at $z &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the lockstep growth between black holes and bulges create their mass relation?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_lockstep_growth_between_black_holes_and_bulges_create_their_mass_relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_lockstep_growth_between_black_holes_and_bulges_create_their_mass_relation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guang Yang
Recent studies have revealed a strong relation between sample-averaged black-hole (BH) accretion rate (BHAR) and star formation rate (SFR) among bulge-dominated galaxies, i.e., &amp;ldquo;lockstep&amp;rdquo; BH-bulge growth, in the distant universe. This relation might be closely related to the BH-bulge mass correlation observed in the local universe. To understand further BH-bulge coevolution, we present ALMA CO(2-1) or CO(3-2) observations of 7 star-forming bulge-dominated galaxies at z=0.5-2.5. Using the ALMA data, we detect significant ($&amp;gt;3\sigma$) CO emission from 4 objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAGLE-like simulation models do not solve the entropy core problem in groups and clusters of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eagle-like_simulation_models_do_not_solve_the_entropy_core_problem_in_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eagle-like_simulation_models_do_not_solve_the_entropy_core_problem_in_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Edoardo Altamura
Recent high-resolution cosmological hydrodynamic simulations run with a variety of codes systematically predict large amounts of entropy in the intra-cluster medium at low redshift, leading to flat entropy profiles and a suppressed cool-core population. This prediction is at odds with X-ray observations of groups and clusters. We use a new implementation of the EAGLE galaxy formation model to investigate the sensitivity of the central entropy and the shape of the profiles to changes in the sub-grid model applied to a suite of zoom-in cosmological simulations of a group of mass $M_{500} = 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episodic accretion and mergers during growth of massive protostars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/episodic_accretion_and_mergers_during_growth_of_massive_protostars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/episodic_accretion_and_mergers_during_growth_of_massive_protostars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vardan G. Elbakyan
3D simulations of high mass young stellar object (HMYSO) growth show that their circumstellar discs fragment onto multiple self-gravitating objects. Accretion of these by HMYSO may explain episodic accretion bursts discovered recently. We post-process results of a previous 3D simulation of a HMYSO disc with a 1D code that resolves the disc and object dynamics down to the stellar surface. We find that burst-like deposition of material into the inner disc seen in 3D simulations by itself does not always signify powerful accretion bursts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding high-redshift gamma-ray bursts in tandem near-infrared and optical surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/finding_high-redshift_gamma-ray_bursts_in_tandem_near-infrared_and_optical_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/finding_high-redshift_gamma-ray_bursts_in_tandem_near-infrared_and_optical_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Campana
The race for the most distant object in the Universe has been played by long-duration gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), star-forming galaxies and quasars. GRBs took a temporary lead with the discovery of GRB 090423 at a redshift z=8.2, but now the record-holder is the galaxy GN-z11 at z=11.0. Despite this record, galaxies and quasars are very faint (GN-z11 has a magnitude H=26), hampering the study of the physical properties of the primordial Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal rotation and buoyancy travel time of 60 gamma Doradus stars from uninterrupted TESS light curves spanning 352 days</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/internal_rotation_and_buoyancy_travel_time_of_60_gamma_doradus_stars_from_uninterrupted_tess_light_curves_spanning_352_days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/internal_rotation_and_buoyancy_travel_time_of_60_gamma_doradus_stars_from_uninterrupted_tess_light_curves_spanning_352_days/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stefano Garcia
Context. Gamma Doradus (hereafter $\gamma$~Dor) stars are gravity-mode pulsators whose periods carry information about the internal structure of the star. These periods are especially sensitive to the internal rotation and chemical mixing, two processes that are currently not well constrained in the theory of stellar evolution. Aims. We aim to identify the pulsation modes and deduce the internal rotation and buoyancy travel time for 106 $\gamma$ Dor stars observed by the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission in its southern continuous viewing zone (hereafter S-CVZ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindling the First Stars: I. Dependence of Detectability of the First Stars with JWST on the Pop III Stellar Masses</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kindling_the_first_stars_i._dependence_of_detectability_of_the_first_stars_with_jwst_on_the_pop_iii_stellar_masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kindling_the_first_stars_i._dependence_of_detectability_of_the_first_stars_with_jwst_on_the_pop_iii_stellar_masses/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mia Sauda Bovill
The first Pop III stars formed out of primordial, metal free gas, in minihalos at z&amp;gt;20, and kickstarted the cosmic processes of reionizaton and enrichment. While these stars are likely more massive than their enriched counterparts, the current unknowns of their astrophysics include; when the first Pop III stars ignited, how massive they were, and when and how the era of the first stars ended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MHD turbulence formation in solar flares: 3D simulation and synthetic observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mhd_turbulence_formation_in_solar_flares_3d_simulation_and_synthetic_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mhd_turbulence_formation_in_solar_flares_3d_simulation_and_synthetic_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wenzhi Ruan
Turbulent plasma motion is common in the universe, and invoked in solar flares to drive effective acceleration leading to high energy electrons. Unresolved mass motions are frequently detected in flares from extreme ultraviolet (EUV) observations, which are often regarded as turbulence. However, how this plasma turbulence forms during the flare is still largely a mystery. Here we successfully reproduce observed turbulence in our 3D magnetohydrodynamic simulation where the magnetic reconnection process is included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observational constraints on accelerators of ultra-high energy cosmic rays</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_constraints_on_accelerators_of_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_constraints_on_accelerators_of_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sullivan Marafico
We explore two generic hypotheses for tracing the sources of ultra-high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) in the Universe: star formation rate density or stellar mass density. For each scenario, we infer a set of constraints for the emission mechanisms in the accelerators, for their energetics and for the abundances of elements at escape from their environments. From these constraints, we generate sky maps above 40~EeV expected from a catalog that comprises 410,761 galaxies out to 350 Mpc and provides a near-infrared flux-limited sample to map both stellar mass and star formation rate over the full sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric and spectroscopic studies of the long period low mass ratio deep contact binary KN Per</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_spectroscopic_studies_of_the_long_period_low_mass_ratio_deep_contact_binary_kn_per/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_spectroscopic_studies_of_the_long_period_low_mass_ratio_deep_contact_binary_kn_per/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xin-Yi Gao
The photometric analysis and spectroscopic study of the long period low mass ratio deep contact binary KN Per were executed. The light curves of BV(RI)$c$-band were from the Ningbo Bureau of Education and Xinjiang Observatory Telescope (NEXT) at the Xingming Observatory. Through the analysis of Wilson-Devinney (W-D) program, KN Per was found as an A-type low mass ratio deep contact binary (q=0.236, f=53.4%). A cool spot applied on the primary component was introduced to explain the unequal maxima of the light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planetary system around LTT 1445A unveiled by ESPRESSO: Multiple planets in a triple M-dwarf system</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planetary_system_around_ltt_1445a_unveiled_by_espresso_multiple_planets_in_a_triple_m-dwarf_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planetary_system_around_ltt_1445a_unveiled_by_espresso_multiple_planets_in_a_triple_m-dwarf_system/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Lavie
We present radial velocity follow-up obtained with ESPRESSO of the M-type star LTT 1445A (TOI-455), for which a transiting planet b with an orbital period of~5.4 days was detected by TESS. We report the discovery of a second transiting planet (LTT 1445A c) and a third non-transiting candidate planet (LTT 1445A d) with orbital periods of 3.12 and 24.30 days, respectively. The host star is the main component of a triple M-dwarf system at a distance of 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling solutions of wiggly cosmic strings: II. Time-varying coarse-graining scale solutions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings_ii._time-varying_coarse-graining_scale_solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings_ii._time-varying_coarse-graining_scale_solutions/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Almeida
We continue our exploration of the wiggly generalisation of the Velocity-Dependent One Scale Model for cosmic strings, through the study of its allowed asymptotic scaling solutions. We extend the work of a previous paper [Almeida $&amp;amp;$ Martins, Phys. Rev. D 104 (2021) 043524] by considering the more comprehensive case of a time-varying coarse-graining scale for the string wiggles. The modeling of the evolution of the network therefore relies on three main mechanisms: Hubble expansion, energy transfer mechanisms (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The astorb database at Lowell Observatory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_astorb_database_at_lowell_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_astorb_database_at_lowell_observatory/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicholas A. Moskovitz
The astorb database at Lowell Observatory is an actively curated catalog of all known asteroids in the Solar System. astorb has heritage dating back to the 1970&amp;rsquo;s and has been publicly accessible since the 1990&amp;rsquo;s. Beginning in 2015 work began to modernize the underlying database infrastructure, operational software, and associated web applications. That effort has involved the expansion of astorb to incorporate new data such as physical properties (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The burst mode of accretion in massive star formation with stellar inertia</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_burst_mode_of_accretion_in_massive_star_formation_with_stellar_inertia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_burst_mode_of_accretion_in_massive_star_formation_with_stellar_inertia/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. M. -A. Meyer
The burst mode of accretion in massive star formation is a scenario linking the initial gravitational collapse of parent pre-stellar cores to the properties of their gravitationally unstable discs and of their accretion-driven bursts. In this study, we present a series of high-resolution 3D radiation-hydrodynamics numerical simulations for young massive stars formed out of collapsing 100 Mo molecular cores spinning with several values of the ratio of rotational-to-gravitational energies beta=5%-9%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MilleniumTNG Project: The galaxy population at z ≥ 8</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_milleniumtng_project_the_galaxy_population_at_zgeq8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_milleniumtng_project_the_galaxy_population_at_zgeq8/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rahul Kannan
The early release science results from the $\textit{James Webb Space Telescope (JWST)}$ have yielded an unexpected abundance of high-redshift luminous galaxies that seems to be in tension with current theories of galaxy formation. However, it is currently difficult to draw definitive conclusions form these results as the sources have not yet been spectroscopically confirmed. It is in any case important to establish baseline predictions from current state-of-the-art galaxy formation models that can be compared and contrasted with these new measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: High-precision predictions for matter clustering and halo statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_high-precision_predictions_for_matter_clustering_and_halo_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_high-precision_predictions_for_matter_clustering_and_halo_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: César Hernández-Aguayo
Cosmological inference with large galaxy surveys requires theoretical models that combine precise predictions for large-scale structure with robust and flexible galaxy formation modelling throughout a sufficiently large cosmic volume. Here, we introduce the MillenniumTNG (MTNG) project which combines the hydrodynamical galaxy formation model of IllustrisTNG with the large volume of the Millennium simulation. Our largest hydrodynamic simulation, covering (500 Mpc/h)^3 = (740 Mpc)^3, is complemented by a suite of dark-matter-only simulations with up to 4320^3 dark matter particles (a mass resolution of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: The hydrodynamical full physics simulation and a first look at its galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_hydrodynamical_full_physics_simulation_and_a_first_look_at_its_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_hydrodynamical_full_physics_simulation_and_a_first_look_at_its_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ruediger Pakmor
Cosmological simulations are an important theoretical pillar for understanding nonlinear structure formation in our Universe and for relating it to observations on large scales. In several papers, we introduce our MillenniumTNG (MTNG) project that provides a comprehensive set of high-resolution, large volume simulations of cosmic structure formation aiming to better understand physical processes on large scales and to help interpreting upcoming large-scale galaxy surveys. We here focus on the full physics box MTNG740 that computes a volume of $(740,\mathrm{Mpc})^3$ with a baryonic mass resolution of $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The physical drivers of gas turbulence in simulated disc galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_drivers_of_gas_turbulence_in_simulated_disc_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_drivers_of_gas_turbulence_in_simulated_disc_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Esteban Jiménez
We use the EAGLE cosmological simulations to study the evolution of the vertical velocity dispersion of cold gas, $\sigma_{z}$, in central disc galaxies and its connection to stellar feedback, gravitational instabilities, cosmological gas accretion and galaxy mergers. To isolate the impact of feedback, we analyse runs that turn off stellar and (or) AGN feedback in addition to a run that includes both. The evolution of $\sigma_z$ and its dependence on stellar mass and star formation rate in EAGLE are in good agreement with observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upper limits on the Polarized Isotropic Stochastic Gravitational-Wave Background from Advanced LIGO-Virgo&#39;s First Three Observing Runs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/upper_limits_on_the_polarized_isotropic_stochastic_gravitational-wave_background_from_advanced_ligo-virgos_first_three_observing_runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/upper_limits_on_the_polarized_isotropic_stochastic_gravitational-wave_background_from_advanced_ligo-virgos_first_three_observing_runs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yang Jiang
Parity violation is expected to generate an asymmetry between the amplitude of left and right-handed gravitational-wave modes which leads to a circularly polarized stochastic gravitational-wave background (SGWB). Due to the three independent baselines in the LIGO-Virgo network, we focus on the amplitude difference in strain power characterized by Stokes&amp;rsquo; parameters and do maximum-likelihood estimation to constrain the polarization degree of SGWB. Our results indicate that there is no evidence for the circularly polarized SGWB in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is zero spatial curvature special?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/why_is_zero_spatial_curvature_special/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/why_is_zero_spatial_curvature_special/</guid>
      <description>First author: Raul Jimenez
Evidence for almost spatial flatness of the Universe has been provided from several observational probes, including the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Baryon Acoustic Oscillations (BAO) from galaxy clustering data. However, other than inflation, and in this case only in the limit of infinite time, there is no strong a priori motivation for a spatially flat Universe. Using the renormalization group (RG) technique in curved spacetime, we present in this work a theoretical motivation for spatial flatness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Statistical Comparison of EUV Brightenings Observed by SO/EUI with Simulated Brightenings in Non-potential Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_comparison_of_euv_brightenings_observed_by_so_eui_with_simulated_brightenings_in_non-potential_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_comparison_of_euv_brightenings_observed_by_so_eui_with_simulated_brightenings_in_non-potential_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Krzysztof Barczynski
The High Resolution Imager (HRI_EUV) telescope of the Extreme Ultraviolet Imager (EUI) instrument onboard Solar Orbiter has observed EUV brightenings, so-called campfires, as fine-scale structures at coronal temperatures. The goal of this paper is to compare the basic geometrical (size, orientation) and physical (intensity, lifetime) properties of the EUV brightenings with regions of energy dissipation in a non-potential coronal magnetic field simulation. In the simulation, HMI line-of-sight magnetograms are used as input to drive the evolution of solar coronal magnetic fields and energy dissipation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amplitudes of Solar Gravity Modes: A Review</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/amplitudes_of_solar_gravity_modes_a_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/amplitudes_of_solar_gravity_modes_a_review/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kévin Belkacem
Solar gravity modes are considered as the {\it Rosetta Stone} for probing and subsequently deciphering the physical properties of the solar inner-most layers. Recent claims of positive detection therefore shed some new light on the long-standing issue of estimating solar gravity mode amplitudes. In this article, our objective is to review the theoretical efforts intended to predict solar gravity mode amplitudes. Because most of these studies assumed analogous driving and damping properties to those for the observed acoustic modes, we also provide a short overview of our current knowledge for these modes in the Sun and solar-type stars (which show solar-like oscillations) before diving into the specific problem of solar gravity modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of the HD 108236 system with CHEOPS and TESS. Confirmation of a fifth transiting planet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_the_hd_108236_system_with_cheops_and_tess._confirmation_of_a_fifth_transiting_planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_the_hd_108236_system_with_cheops_and_tess._confirmation_of_a_fifth_transiting_planet/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Hoyer
The HD108236 system was first announced with the detection of four small planets based on TESS data. Shortly after, the transit of an additional planet with a period of 29.54d was serendipitously detected by CHEOPS. In this way, HD108236 (V=9.2) became one of the brightest stars known to host five small transiting planets (R$p$&amp;lt;3R${\oplus}$). We characterize the planetary system by using all the data available from CHEOPS and TESS space missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Estimation of the Binding Energies of POx and HPOx (x=2,3) Species</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/computational_estimation_of_the_binding_energies_of_pox_and_hpox_x23_species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/computational_estimation_of_the_binding_energies_of_pox_and_hpox_x23_species/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elettra L. Piacentino
The distribution of molecules between the gas and solid phase during star and planet formation, determines the trajectory of gas and grain surface chemistry, as well as the delivery of elements to nascent planets. This distribution is primarily set by the binding energies of different molecules to water ice surfaces. We computationally estimated the binding energies of ten astrochemically relevant P-bearing species on water surface, we also validate our method for 20 species with known binding energies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the equation of state of hybrid stars using recent information from multidisciplinary physics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_equation_of_state_of_hybrid_stars_using_recent_information_from_multidisciplinary_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_equation_of_state_of_hybrid_stars_using_recent_information_from_multidisciplinary_physics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Swarnim Shirke
At the ultra-high densities existing in the core of neutron stars, it is expected that a phase transition from baryonic to deconfined quark matter may occur. Such a phase transition would affect the underlying equation of state (EoS) as well as the observable astrophysical properties of neutron stars. Comparison of EoS model predictions with astronomical data from multi-messenger signals then provides us an opportunity to probe the behaviour of dense matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of spectral hardenings in cosmic-ray boron-to-carbon and boron-to-oxygen flux ratios with DAMPE</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_spectral_hardenings_in_cosmic-ray_boron-to-carbon_and_boron-to-oxygen_flux_ratios_with_dampe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_spectral_hardenings_in_cosmic-ray_boron-to-carbon_and_boron-to-oxygen_flux_ratios_with_dampe/</guid>
      <description>First author: DAMPE Collaboration
Boron nuclei in cosmic rays (CRs) are believed to be mainly produced by the fragmentation of heavier nuclei, such as carbon and oxygen, via collisions with the interstellar matter. Therefore, the boron-to-carbon flux ratio (B/C) and the boron-to-oxygen flux ratio (B/O) are very essential probes of the CR propagation. The energy dependence of the B/C ratio from previous balloon-borne and space-based experiments can be well described by a single power-law up to about 1 TeV/n within uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the gamma-ray binary LS I &#43;61 303 harbour a magnetar?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_gamma-ray_binary_ls_i_&#43;61_303_harbour_a_magnetar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_gamma-ray_binary_ls_i_&#43;61_303_harbour_a_magnetar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arthur G. Suvorov
LS I +61{\deg}303 is a high mass X-ray binary that is also catalogued as a gamma-ray binary as a result of frequent outbursts at TeV photon energies. The system has released two soft-gamma flares in the past, suggesting a magnetar interpretation for the compact primary. This inference has recently gained significant traction following the discovery of transient radio pulses, detected in some orbital phases from the system, as the measured rotation and tentative spindown rates imply a polar magnetic field strength of $B_p \gtrsim 10^{14},\mbox{G}$ if the star is decelerating via magnetic dipole braking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Emerging Bipolar Magnetic Regions in Mean-field Dynamo Model of Solar Cycles 23 and 24</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_emerging_bipolar_magnetic_regions_in_mean-field_dynamo_model_of_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_emerging_bipolar_magnetic_regions_in_mean-field_dynamo_model_of_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. V. Pipin
We model the physical parameters of Solar Cycles 23 and 24 using a nonlinear dynamical mean-field dynamo model that includes the formation and evolution of bipolar magnetic regions (BMR). The Parker-type dynamo model consists of a complete MHD system in the mean-field formulation: the 3D magnetic induction equation, and 2D momentum and energy equations in the anelastic approximation. The initialization of BMR is modeled in the framework of Parker&amp;rsquo;s magnetic buoyancy instability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUMES III: Ultraviolet and Optical Variability of M Dwarf Chromospheres</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fumes_iii_ultraviolet_and_optical_variability_of_m_dwarf_chromospheres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fumes_iii_ultraviolet_and_optical_variability_of_m_dwarf_chromospheres/</guid>
      <description>First author: Girish M. Duvvuri
We obtained ultraviolet and optical spectra for 9 M~dwarfs across a range of rotation periods to determine whether they showed stochastic intrinsic variability distinguishable from flares. The ultraviolet spectra were observed during the Far Ultraviolet M~Dwarf Evolution Survey \emph{Hubble~Space~Telescope} program using the Space Telescope Imaging Spectrograph. The optical observations were taken from the Apache Point Observatory 3.5-meter telescope using the Dual Imaging Spectrograph and from the Gemini South Observatory using the Gemini Multi-Object Spectrograph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of updated Multipole Love and f-Love Universal Relations in context of Binary Neutron Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_updated_multipole_love_and_f-love_universal_relations_in_context_of_binary_neutron_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_updated_multipole_love_and_f-love_universal_relations_in_context_of_binary_neutron_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bikram Keshari Pradhan
Neutron star (NS) equation of state (EoS) insensitive relations or universal relations (UR) involving neutron star bulk properties play a crucial role in gravitational-wave astronomy. Considering a wide range of equations of state originating from (i) phenomenological relativistic mean field models, (ii) realistic EoS models based on different physical motivations, and (iii) polytropic EoSs described by spectral decomposition method, we update the EoS-insensitive relations involving NS tidal deformability (Multipole Love relation) and the UR between f-mode frequency and tidal deformability (f-Love relation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint of f(R) gravity in the cosmic magnification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imprint_of_fr_gravity_in_the_cosmic_magnification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imprint_of_fr_gravity_in_the_cosmic_magnification/</guid>
      <description>First author: Didam Duniya
f(R) gravity is one of the simplest viable modifications to General Relativity: it passes local astrophysical tests, predicts both the early-time cosmic inflation and the late-time cosmic acceleration, and also describes dark matter. In this paper, we probe cosmic magnification on large scales in f (R) gravity, using the well-known Hu-Sawicki model as an example. Our results indicate that at redshifts z &amp;lt; 3, values of the model exponent n &amp;gt; 1 lead to inconsistent behaviour in the evolution of scalar perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inconspicuous Solar Polar Coronal X-ray Jets as the Source of Conspicuous Hinode/EUV Imaging Spectrometer (EIS) Doppler Outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inconspicuous_solar_polar_coronal_x-ray_jets_as_the_source_of_conspicuous_hinode_euv_imaging_spectrometer_eis_doppler_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inconspicuous_solar_polar_coronal_x-ray_jets_as_the_source_of_conspicuous_hinode_euv_imaging_spectrometer_eis_doppler_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alphonse C. Sterling
We examine in greater detail five events previously identified as being sources of strong transient coronal outflows in a solar polar region in Hinode/EUV Imaging Spectrometer (EIS) Doppler data. Although relatively compact or faint and inconspicuous in Hinode/Soft X-ray Telescope (XRT) soft-X-ray (SXR) images and in Solar Dynamics Observatory (SDO)/Atmospheric Imaging Assembly (AIA) EUV images, we find that all of these events are consistent with being faint coronal X-ray jets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term Study of the Sun and Its Implications to Solar Dynamo Models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_study_of_the_sun_and_its_implications_to_solar_dynamo_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_study_of_the_sun_and_its_implications_to_solar_dynamo_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bibhuti Kumar Jha
The Sun shows a wide range of temporal variations, from a few seconds to decades and even centuries, broadly classified into two classes short-term and Long-term. The solar dynamo mechanism is believed to be responsible for these global changes happening in the Sun. Hence, many dynamo models have been proposed to explain the observed behaviour of the Sun. This thesis is primarily focused on studying the \lt\ variation of the Sun and provides various inputs to the solar dynamo models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term trends of light pollution assessed from SQM measurements and an empirical atmospheric model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_trends_of_light_pollution_assessed_from_sqm_measurements_and_an_empirical_atmospheric_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_trends_of_light_pollution_assessed_from_sqm_measurements_and_an_empirical_atmospheric_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Johannes Puschnig
We present long-term (4-10 years) trends of light pollution observed at 26 locations, covering rural, intermediate and urban sites, including the three major European metropolitan areas of Stockholm, Berlin and Vienna. Our analysis is based on i) night sky brightness (NSB) measurements obtained with Sky Quality Meters (SQMs) and ii) a rich set of atmospheric data products provided by the European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling lens potentials with continuous neural fields in galaxy-scale strong lenses</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_lens_potentials_with_continuous_neural_fields_in_galaxy-scale_strong_lenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_lens_potentials_with_continuous_neural_fields_in_galaxy-scale_strong_lenses/</guid>
      <description>First author: Luca Biggio
Strong gravitational lensing is a unique observational tool for studying the dark and luminous mass distribution both within and between galaxies. Given the presence of substructures, current strong lensing observations demand more complex mass models than smooth analytical profiles, such as power-law ellipsoids. In this work, we introduce a continuous neural field to predict the lensing potential at any position throughout the image plane, allowing for a nearly model-independent description of the lensing mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planetary nebulae with Wolf-Rayet-type central stars -- IV. NGC 1501 and its mixing layer</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planetary_nebulae_with_wolf-rayet-type_central_stars_--_iv._ngc_1501_and_its_mixing_layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planetary_nebulae_with_wolf-rayet-type_central_stars_--_iv._ngc_1501_and_its_mixing_layer/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Rubio
Theory predicts that the temperature of the X-ray-emitting gas ($\sim$10$^{6}$ K) detected from planetary nebulae (PNe) is a consequence of mixing or thermal conduction when in contact with the ionized outer rim ($\sim$10$^{4}$ K). Gas at intermediate temperatures ($\sim$10$^{5}$ K) can be used to study the physics of the production of X-ray-emitting gas, via C IV, N V and O VI ions. Here we model the stellar atmosphere of the CSPN of NGC 1501 to demonstrate that even this hot H-deficient [WO4]-type star cannot produce these emission lines by photoionization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plasma composition measurements in an active region from Solar Orbiter/SPICE and Hinode/EIS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/plasma_composition_measurements_in_an_active_region_from_solar_orbiter_spice_and_hinode_eis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/plasma_composition_measurements_in_an_active_region_from_solar_orbiter_spice_and_hinode_eis/</guid>
      <description>First author: David H. Brooks
A key goal of the Solar Orbiter mission is to connect elemental abundance measurements of the solar wind enveloping the spacecraft with EUV spectroscopic observations of their solar sources, but this is not an easy exercise. Observations from previous missions have revealed a highly complex picture of spatial and temporal variations of elemental abundances in the solar corona. We have used coordinated observations from Hinode and Solar Orbiter to attempt new abundance measurements with the SPICE (Spectral Imaging of the Coronal Environment) instrument, and benchmark them against standard analyses from EIS (EUV Imaging Spectrometer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak lensing in the blue: a counter-intuitive strategy for stratospheric observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/weak_lensing_in_the_blue_a_counter-intuitive_strategy_for_stratospheric_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/weak_lensing_in_the_blue_a_counter-intuitive_strategy_for_stratospheric_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mohamed M. Shaaban
The statistical power of weak lensing measurements is principally driven by the number of high redshift galaxies whose shapes are resolved. Conventional wisdom and physical intuition suggest this is optimised by deep imaging at long (red or near IR) wavelengths, to avoid losing redshifted Balmer break and Lyman break galaxies. We use the synthetic Emission Line EL-COSMOS catalogue to simulate lensing observations using different filters, from various altitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTEGRAL study of MAXI J1535-571, MAXI J1820&#43;070 and MAXI J1348-630 outbursts -- I. Detection and polarization properties of the high-energy emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/integral_study_of_maxi_j1535-571_maxi_j1820&#43;070_and_maxi_j1348-630_outbursts_--_i._detection_and_polarization_properties_of_the_high-energy_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/integral_study_of_maxi_j1535-571_maxi_j1820&#43;070_and_maxi_j1348-630_outbursts_--_i._detection_and_polarization_properties_of_the_high-energy_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Cangemi
In black hole X-ray binaries, a non-thermal high-energy component is sometimes detected at energies above 200 keV. The origin of this component is debated and distinct spectral modelizations can lead to different interpretations. High-energy polarimetry measurements with INTEGRAL allow new diagnostics on the physics responsible for the MeV spectral component. In this work, we aim to investigate the high-energy behavior of three bright sources discovered by the MAXI: MAXI J1535-571, MAXI J1820+070 and MAXI J1348-630.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature Gas Opacities with AESOPUS 2.0</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-temperature_gas_opacities_with_aesopus_2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-temperature_gas_opacities_with_aesopus_2.0/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paola Marigo
This work introduces new low-temperature gas opacities, in the range 3.2 &amp;lt;= log(T/K) &amp;lt;= 4.5, computed with the AESOPUS code under the assumption of thermodynamic equilibrium (Marigo &amp;amp;_Aringer_2009). In comparison to the previous version AESOPUS 1.0, we updated and expanded molecular absorption to include 80 species, mostly using the recommended line lists currently available from the ExoMol and HITRAN databases. Furthermore, in light of a recent study, we revised the H- photodetachment cross section, added the free-free absorption of other negative ions of atoms and molecules, and updated the collision-induced absorption due to H2/H2, H2/H, H2/He, and H/He pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Solutions of Wiggly Cosmic Strings</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. R. R. Almeida
Cosmic string networks form during cosmological phase transitions as a consequence of the Kibble mechanism. The evolution of the simplest networks is accurately described by the canonical Velocity Dependent One-Scale (VOS) model. However, numerical simulations have demonstrated the existence of significant quantities of short-wavelength propagation modes on the strings, known as wiggles, which motivated the recent development of a wiggly string extension of the VOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Quasi-Periodical Oscillations in Precursors of Short and Long Gamma Ray Bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_quasi-periodical_oscillations_in_precursors_of_short_and_long_gamma_ray_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_quasi-periodical_oscillations_in_precursors_of_short_and_long_gamma_ray_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuo Xiao
The precursors of short and long Gamma Ray Bursts (SGRBs and LGRBs) can serve as probes of their progenitors, as well as shedding light on the physical processes of mergers or core-collapse supernovae. Some models predict the possible existence of Quasi-Periodically Oscillations (QPO) in the precursors of SGRBs. Although many previous studies have performed QPO search in the main emission of SGRBs and LGRBs, so far there was no systematic QPO search in their precursors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard physics is still capable to interpret ~ 18 TeV photons from GRB~221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/standard_physics_is_still_capable_to_interpr18_tev_photons_from_grb~221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/standard_physics_is_still_capable_to_interpr18_tev_photons_from_grb~221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhi-Chao Zhao
It is reported that the Large High Altitude Air Shower Observatory (LHAASO) observed thousands of very-high-energy photons up to $\sim$18 TeV from GRB 221009A. We study the survival rate of these photons by considering the fact that they are absorbed by the extragalactic background light. By performing a set of $10^6$ Monte-Carlo simulations, we explore the parameter space allowed by current observations and find that the probability of predicting that LHAASO observes at least one photons of 18 TeV from GRB 221009A within 2000 seconds is 4&amp;ndash;5%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of collisional neutrino flavor instabilities in spherically symmetric supernova models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_collisional_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_spherically_symmetric_supernova_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_collisional_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_spherically_symmetric_supernova_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zewei Xiong
We implement a multi-group and discrete-ordinate neutrino transport model in spherical symmetry which allows to simulate collective neutrino oscillations by including realistic collisional rates in a self-consistent way. We utilize this innovative model, based on strategic parameter rescaling, to study a recently proposed collisional flavor instability caused by the asymmetry of emission and absorption rates between $\nu_e$ and $\bar\nu_e$ for four different static backgrounds taken from different stages in a core-collapse supernova simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particle Injection and Nonthermal Particle Acceleration in Relativistic Magnetic Reconnection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/particle_injection_and_nonthermal_particle_acceleration_in_relativistic_magnetic_reconnection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/particle_injection_and_nonthermal_particle_acceleration_in_relativistic_magnetic_reconnection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Omar French
Magnetic reconnection in the relativistic regime has been proposed as an important process for the efficient production of nonthermal particles and high-energy emissions. Using fully kinetic particle-in-cell simulations, we investigate how guide-field strength and domain size affect characteristic spectral features and acceleration processes. We study two stages of acceleration: energization up until the injection energy $\gamma_{\rm inj}$ and further acceleration that generates a power-law spectrum. Stronger guide fields increase the power-law index and $\gamma_{\rm inj}$, which suppresses acceleration efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Systems Engineering for sub-CubeSat scale spacecraft</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agile_systems_engineering_for_sub-cubesat_scale_spacecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agile_systems_engineering_for_sub-cubesat_scale_spacecraft/</guid>
      <description>First author: Konstantinos Kanavouras
Space systems miniaturization has been increasingly popular for the past decades, with over 1600 CubeSats and 300 sub-CubeSat sized spacecraft estimated to have been launched since 1998. This trend towards decreasing size enables the execution of unprecedented missions in terms of quantity, cost and development time, allowing for massively distributed satellite networks, and rapid prototyping of space equipment. Pocket-sized spacecraft can be designed in-house in less than a year and can reach weights of less than 10g, reducing the considerable effort typically associated with orbital flight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Saturation of the Bell Instability using Hybrid Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_saturation_of_the_bell_instability_using_hybrid_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_saturation_of_the_bell_instability_using_hybrid_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Georgios Zacharegkas
The nonresonant streaming instability (Bell instability) plays a pivotal role in the acceleration and confinement of cosmic rays (CRs); yet, the exact mechanism responsible for its saturation and the magnitude of the final amplified magnetic field have not been assessed from first-principles. Using a survey of hybrid simulations (with kinetic ions and fluid electrons), we study the evolution of the Bell instability as a function of the parameters of the CR population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the time lag between solar wind dynamic parameters and solar activity UV proxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_time_lag_between_solar_wind_dynamic_parameters_and_solar_activity_uv_proxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_time_lag_between_solar_wind_dynamic_parameters_and_solar_activity_uv_proxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Reda
The solar activity displays variability and periodic behaviours over a wide range of timescales, with the presence of a most prominent cycle with a mean length of 11 years. Such variability is transported within the heliosphere by solar wind, radiation and other processes, affecting the properties of the interplanetary medium. The presence of solar activity-related periodicities is well visible in different solar wind and geomagnetic indices, although with time lags with respect to the solar one, leading to hysteresis cycles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perturbation theory with dispersion and higher cumulants: framework and linear theory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_framework_and_linear_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_framework_and_linear_theory/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mathias Garny
The standard perturbation theory (SPT) approach to gravitational clustering is based on a fluid approximation of the underlying Vlasov-Poisson dynamics, taking only the zeroth and first cumulant of the phase-space distribution function into account (density and velocity fields). This assumption breaks down when dark matter particle orbits cross and leads to well-known problems, e.g. an anomalously large backreaction of small-scale modes onto larger scales that compromises predictivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perturbation theory with dispersion and higher cumulants: non-linear regime</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_non-linear_regime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_non-linear_regime/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mathias Garny
We present non-linear solutions of Vlasov Perturbation Theory (VPT), describing gravitational clustering of collisionless dark matter with dispersion and higher cumulants induced by orbit crossing. We show that VPT can be cast into a form that is formally analogous to standard perturbation theory (SPT), but including additional perturbation variables, non-linear interactions, and a more complex propagation. VPT non-linear kernels have a crucial decoupling property: for fixed total momentum, the kernels becomes strongly suppressed when any of the individual momenta cross the dispersion scale into the non-linear regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photochemistry and Heating/Cooling of the Multiphase Interstellar Medium with UV Radiative Transfer for Magnetohydrodynamic Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photochemistry_and_heating_cooling_of_the_multiphase_interstellar_medium_with_uv_radiative_transfer_for_magnetohydrodynamic_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photochemistry_and_heating_cooling_of_the_multiphase_interstellar_medium_with_uv_radiative_transfer_for_magnetohydrodynamic_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeong-Gyu Kim
We present an efficient heating/cooling method coupled with chemistry and ultraviolet (UV) radiative transfer, which can be applied to numerical simulations of the interstellar medium (ISM). We follow the time-dependent evolution of hydrogen species (H$_2$, H, H$^+$), assume carbon/oxygen species (C, C$^+$, CO, O, and O$^+$) are in formation-destruction balance given the non-steady hydrogen abundances, and include essential heating/cooling processes needed to capture thermodynamics of all ISM phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-TeV hadronic interaction model differences and their impact on air showers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-tev_hadronic_interaction_model_differences_and_their_impact_on_air_showers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-tev_hadronic_interaction_model_differences_and_their_impact_on_air_showers/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Schmelling
In the sub-TeV regime, the most widely used hadronic interaction models disagree significantly in their predictions of particle spectra from cosmic ray induced air showers. We investigate the nature and impact of model uncertainties, focussing on air shower primaries with energies around the transition between high and low energy hadronic interaction models, where the dissimilarities are largest and which constitute the bulk of the interactions in air showers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PhotoDissociation Region Toolbox: Software and Models for Astrophysical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_photodissociation_region_toolbox_software_and_models_for_astrophysical_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_photodissociation_region_toolbox_software_and_models_for_astrophysical_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marc W. Pound
The PhotoDissociation Region Toolbox provides comprehensive, easy-to-use, public software tools and models that enable an understanding of the interaction of the light of young, luminous, massive stars with the gas and dust in the Milky Way and in other galaxies. It consists of an open-source Python toolkit and photodissociation region models for analysis of infrared and millimeter/submillimeter line and continuum observations obtained by ground-based and sub-orbital telescopes, and astrophysics space missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-179: a young system with a transiting compact Neptune-mass planet and a low-mass companion in outer orbit</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-179_a_young_system_with_a_transiting_compact_neptune-mass_planet_and_a_low-mass_companion_in_outer_orbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-179_a_young_system_with_a_transiting_compact_neptune-mass_planet_and_a_low-mass_companion_in_outer_orbit/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Desidera
Transiting planets around young stars are key benchmarks for our understanding of planetary systems. One of such candidates was identified around the K dwarf HD 18599 by TESS, labeled as TOI-179. We present the confirmation of the transiting planet and the characterization of the host star and of the TOI-179 system over a broad range of angular separations. To this aim, we exploited the TESS photometric time series, intensive radial velocity monitoring performed with HARPS, and deep high-contrast imaging observations obtained with SPHERE and NACO at VLT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
