<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>intergalactic medium on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/intergalactic-medium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in intergalactic medium on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/intergalactic-medium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The THESAN project: Lyman-alpha emitter luminosity function calibration</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/intergalactic-medium/the_thesan_project_lyman-alpha_emitter_luminosity_function_calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/intergalactic-medium/the_thesan_project_lyman-alpha_emitter_luminosity_function_calibration/</guid>
      <description>First author: Clara Xu
The observability of Lyman-alpha emitting galaxies (LAEs) during the Epoch of Reionization can provide a sensitive probe of the evolving neutral hydrogen gas distribution, thus setting valuable constraints to distinguish different reionization models. In this study, we utilize the new THESAN suite of large-volume (95.5 cMpc) cosmological radiation-hydrodynamic simulations to directly model the Ly$\alpha$ emission from individual galaxies and the subsequent transmission through the intergalactic medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Cosmic-ray Transport with Observations of the Circumgalactic Medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/intergalactic-medium/constraining_cosmic-ray_transport_with_observations_of_the_circumgalactic_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/intergalactic-medium/constraining_cosmic-ray_transport_with_observations_of_the_circumgalactic_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iryna S. Butsky
Recent theoretical studies predict that the circumgalactic medium (CGM) around low-redshift, $\sim L_{\ast}$ galaxies could have substantial nonthermal pressure support in the form of cosmic rays. However, these predictions are sensitive to the specific model of cosmic-ray transport employed, which is theoretically and observationally underconstrained. In this work, we propose a novel observational constraint for calculating the lower limit of the radially-averaged, effective cosmic-ray transport rate, $\kappa_{\rm min}^{\rm eff}$.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
