<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AGN on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/agn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AGN on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/agn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hadronuclear interactions in the jet of low TeV luminosity AGN: Implications for the low-state very-high-energy gamma-ray emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hadronuclear_interactions_in_the_jet_of_low_tev_luminosity_agn_implications_for_the_low-state_very-high-energy_gamma-ray_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hadronuclear_interactions_in_the_jet_of_low_tev_luminosity_agn_implications_for_the_low-state_very-high-energy_gamma-ray_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rui Xue
In the study of radiation mechanisms of AGNs&amp;rsquo; jets, hadronuclear (pp) interactions are commonly neglected, because the number density of cold protons in the jet is considered insufficient. Very recently, our previous work proves that pp interactions in the low TeV luminosity AGNs, which have potential to generate detectable very-high-energy (VHE) emission, could be important. Based on this, the one-zone pp model is employed to study low-state quasi-simultaneous spectral energy distributions of a sample of low TeV luminosity AGNs in this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Full Spectral Timing Model for AGN. Untangling the Variability in Fairall 9</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_full_spectral_timing_model_for_agn._untangling_the_variability_in_fairall_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_full_spectral_timing_model_for_agn._untangling_the_variability_in_fairall_9/</guid>
      <description>First author: Scott Hagen
Continuum reverberation mapping of AGN can provide new insight into the nature and geometry of the accretion flow. Some of the X-rays from the central corona irradiating the disc are absorbed, increasing the local disc temperature. This gives an additional re-processed contribution to the spectral energy distribution (SED) which is lagged and smeared relative to the driving X-ray lightcurve. We directly calculate this reverberation from the accretion disc, creating fully time dependent SEDs for a given X-ray light-curve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
