<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AGN on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/agn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AGN on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/agn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NuSTAR Observes Two Bulgeless Galaxies: No Hard X-ray AGN Detected in NGC 4178 or J0851&#43;3926</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan W. Pfeifle
The discovery over the last several decades of moderate luminosity AGNs in disk-dominated galaxies - which show no &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; bulges - suggests that secular mechanisms represent an important growth pathway for supermassive black holes in these systems. We present new follow-up NuSTAR observations of the optically-elusive AGNs in two bulgeless galaxies, NGC 4178 and J0851+3926. NGC 4178 was originally reported as hosting an AGN based on the detection of [Ne V] mid-infrared emission detected by Spitzer, and based on Chandra X-ray imaging it has since been argued to host either a heavily obscured AGN or a supernova remnant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ALPINE-ALMA [CII] survey: double stellar population and AGN activity in a galaxy at $z\sim5.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Barchiesi
GDS J033218.92-275302.7 (here GS-14) is a $z\sim5.5$ galaxy detected in [CII] as part of the ALPINE survey with unusual UV spectral features that have been interpreted as signatures of either a double stellar population or of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We exploited the multi-wavelength coverage of GS-14 to investigate the properties and the origin of its emission. We performed UV-to-NIR SED-fitting, with single/double stellar population and/or AGN component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Optical, Ultraviolet and Soft X-ray excess Emissions in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Nour
Soft X-ray emission (0.5&amp;ndash;2.0 keV) plays a pivotal role in regulating the optical and UV emission in the AGNs. We collected a sample of 1811 AGNs from the SDSS database and obtained various parameters of Balmer lines, optical continuum, MgII line &amp;amp; UV continuum and studied their dependencies on soft X-ray luminosity. Based on the linear regression analysis, we found that FWHM${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ FWHM${\text{H}\beta}^{0.554}$ suggesting that UV emission is arising from a region relatively outside the broad line region (BLR) associated to the H$\beta$ emission and found a strong correlation between optical and UV luminosities (L${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ L${\text{H}\beta}^{0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOJAVE XX. Decade-long linear polarization variability in AGN jets at parsec scales</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. I. Zobnina
We studied the variability properties of the linear polarization of active galactic nucleus (AGN) jets on parsec-scales using stacking. Our sample is drawn from the MOJAVE program and consists of 436 AGNs manifesting core-jet morphology and having at least five VLBA observing epochs at 15 GHz from January 1996 through August 2019, with some additional archival VLBA data reduced by us. We employed a stacking procedure and constructed maps of (i) standard deviation of fractional polarization and electric vector position angle (EVPA) over epochs as the measure of variability, (ii) median polarization degree to quantify typical values in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Fourier-Transformation Model for the Production of Hard and Soft X-Ray Time Lags in AGNs: Application to 1H 0707-495</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</guid>
      <description>First author: David C. Baughman
The variability of the X-ray emission from active galactic nuclei is often characterized using time lags observed between soft and hard energy bands in the detector. The time lags are usually computed using the complex cross spectrum, which is based on the Fourier transforms of the hard and soft time series data. It has been noted that some active galactic nuclei display soft X-ray time lags, in addition to the more ubiquitous hard lags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Herschel observations of the 2Jy sample: assessing the non-thermal and AGN contributions to the far-IR continuum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_herschel_observations_of_the_2jy_sample_assessing_the_non-thermal_and_agn_contributions_to_the_far-ir_continuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_herschel_observations_of_the_2jy_sample_assessing_the_non-thermal_and_agn_contributions_to_the_far-ir_continuum/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Dicken
The far-IR/sub-mm wavelength range contains a wealth of diagnostic information that is important for understanding the role of radio AGN in galaxy evolution. Here we present the results of Herschel PACS and SPIRE observations of a complete sample of 46 powerful 2Jy radio AGN at intermediate redshifts (0.05 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.7), which represent the deepest pointed observations of a major sample of radio AGN undertaken by Herschel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Physical Picture for AGNs Lacking Optical Emission Lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher J. Agostino
In this work, we use ~500 low-redshift (z ~ 0.1) X-ray AGNs observed by XMM-Newton and SDSS to investigate the prevalence and nature of AGNs that apparently lack optical emission lines (optically dull AGNs&#39;&#39;). Although 1/4 of spectra appear absorption-line dominated in visual assessment, line extraction with robust continuum subtraction from the MPA/JHU catalog reveals usable [OIII] measurements in 98% of the sample, allowing us to study [OIII]-underluminous AGNs together with more typical AGNs in the context of the L$_{\mathrm{[OIII]}}$--L$_{X}$ relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the moderate UV/X-ray correlation in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Panagiotou
The UV/optical and X-ray variability of active galactic nuclei (AGN) have long been expected to be well correlated as a result of the X-ray illumination of the accretion disk. Recent monitoring campaigns of nearby AGN, however, found that their X-ray and UV/optical emission are only moderately correlated, challenging the aforementioned paradigm. In this work, we aim to demonstrate that due to the definition of the cross correlation function, a low UV/X-ray correlation is well expected in the case of an X-ray illuminated accretion disk, when the dynamic variability of the X-ray source is taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TPHO: a time-dependent photoionisation model for AGN outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tpho_a_time-dependent_photoionisation_model_for_agn_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tpho_a_time-dependent_photoionisation_model_for_agn_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniele Rogantini
Outflows in active galactic nuclei (AGN) are considered a promising candidate for driving AGN feedback at large scales. However, without information on the density of these outflows, we cannot determine how much kinetic power they are imparting to the surrounding medium. Monitoring the response of the ionisation state of the absorbing outflows to changes in the ionising continuum provides the recombination timescale of the outflow, which is a function of the electron density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the X-ray reflection in low accretion rate AGN using XMM-Newton, NuSTAR and Swift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_x-ray_reflection_in_low_accretion_rate_agn_using_xmm-newton_nustar_and_swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_x-ray_reflection_in_low_accretion_rate_agn_using_xmm-newton_nustar_and_swift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Díaz
An interesting feature in active galactic nuclei (AGN) accreting at low rate is the weakness of the reflection features in their X-ray spectra, which can result from the gradual disappearance of the torus with decreasing accretion rates. It has been suggested that low luminosity AGN (LLAGN) would have a different reflector configuration compared with high luminosity AGN, either covering a smaller fraction of the sky or simply having less material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does absorption against AGN reveal supermassive black hole accretion?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_absorption_against_agn_reveal_supermassive_black_hole_accretion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_absorption_against_agn_reveal_supermassive_black_hole_accretion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tom Rose
Galaxies often contain large reservoirs of molecular gas which shape their evolution. This can be through cooling of the gas &amp;ndash; which leads to star formation, or accretion onto the central supermassive black hole &amp;ndash; which fuels AGN activity and produces powerful feedback. Molecular gas has been detected in early-type galaxies on scales of just a few tens to hundreds of solar masses by searching for absorption against their compact radio cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Wavelength Study of Multiple Spectral Component Jets in AGN: Testing the IC/CMB Model for the Large-Scale-Jet X-ray Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multi-wavelength_study_of_multiple_spectral_component_jets_in_agn_testing_the_ic_cmb_model_for_the_large-scale-jet_x-ray_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multi-wavelength_study_of_multiple_spectral_component_jets_in_agn_testing_the_ic_cmb_model_for_the_large-scale-jet_x-ray_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Breiding
Over 150 resolved, kpc-scale X-ray jets hosted by active galactic nuclei have been discovered with the Chandra X-ray Observatory. A significant fraction of these jets have an X-ray spectrum either too high in flux or too hard to be consistent with the high-energy extension of the radio-to-optical synchrotron spectrum, a subtype we identify as Multiple Spectral Component (MSC) X-ray jets. A leading hypothesis for the origin of the X-rays is the inverse-Compton scattering of the cosmic microwave background by the same electron population producing the radio-to-optical synchrotron spectrum (known as the IC/CMB model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Dynamics in AGN Winds: A New Mechanism For Multiwavelength AGN Variability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_dynamics_in_agn_winds_a_new_mechanism_for_multiwavelength_agn_variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_dynamics_in_agn_winds_a_new_mechanism_for_multiwavelength_agn_variability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nadine H. Soliman
Partial dust obscuration in active galactic nuclei (AGN) has been proposed as a potential explanation for some cases of AGN variability. The dust-gas mixture present in AGN torii is accelerated by radiation pressure leading to the launching of an AGN wind. Dust under these conditions has been shown to be unstable to a generic class of fast growing resonant drag instabilities (RDIs). We present the first set of numerical simulations of radiation driven outflows that include explicit dust dynamics in conditions resembling AGN winds and discuss the implications of the RDIs on the morphology of the AGN torus, AGN variability, and the ability of the radiation to effectively launch a wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for extended gaseous reservoirs around AGN at cosmic noon from ALMA CO(3-2) observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_extended_gaseous_reservoirs_around_agn_at_cosmic_noon_from_alma_co3-2_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_extended_gaseous_reservoirs_around_agn_at_cosmic_noon_from_alma_co3-2_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. C. Jones
Gaseous outflows are key phenomena in the evolution of galaxies, as they affect star formation (either positively or negatively), eject gas from the core or disk, and directly cause mixing of pristine and processed material. Active outflows may be detected through searches for broad spectral line emission or high-velocity gas, but it is also possible to determine the presence of past outflows by searching for extended reservoirs of chemically enriched molecular gas in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) around galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical study of the time-lags due to Comptonization and the constraints on the X-ray corona in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_theoretical_study_of_the_time-lags_due_to_comptonization_and_the_constraints_on_the_x-ray_corona_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_theoretical_study_of_the_time-lags_due_to_comptonization_and_the_constraints_on_the_x-ray_corona_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Zhang
We study the Fourier time-lags due to the Comptonization of disc-emitted photons in a spherical, uniform, and stationary X-ray corona, which located on the rotational axis of the black hole. We use Monk, a general relativistic Monte-Carlo radiative transfer code, to calculate Compton scattering of photons emitted by a thin disc with a Novikov-Thorne temperature profile. We find that the model time-lags due to Comptonization remain constant up to a characteristic frequency and then rapidly decrease to zero at higher frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN Feedback in SDSS-IV MaNGA: AGNs Have Suppressed Central Star-Formation Rates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Caleb Lammers
Despite the importance of feedback from active galactic nuclei (AGN) in models of galaxy evolution, observational constraints on the influence of AGN feedback on star formation remain weak. To this end, we have compared the star formation trends of 279 low-redshift AGN galaxies with 558 non-active control galaxies using integral field unit spectroscopy from the SDSS-IV MaNGA survey. With a Gaussian process-based methodology, we reconstruct non-parametric star formation histories in spatially-resolved spaxels covering the face of each galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf AGNs from Variability for the Origins of Seeds (DAVOS): Optical Variability of Broad-line Dwarf AGNs from the Zwicky Transient Facility</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_agns_from_variability_for_the_origins_of_seeds_davos_optical_variability_of_broad-line_dwarf_agns_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_agns_from_variability_for_the_origins_of_seeds_davos_optical_variability_of_broad-line_dwarf_agns_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</guid>
      <description>First author: Z. Franklin Wang
We study the optical variability of a sample of candidate low-mass (dwarf ang Seyfert) active galactic nuclei (AGNs) using Zwicky Transient Facility g-band light curves. Our sample is compiled from broad-line AGNs in dwarf galaxies reported in the literature with single-epoch virial black hole (BH) masses in the range $M_{\rm{BH}} \sim 10^{4}$&amp;ndash;$10^{8}\ M_{\odot}$. We measure the characteristic ``damping&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; timescale of the optical variability $\tau_{\rm{DRW}}$, beyond which the power spectral density flattens, of a final sample of 79 candidate low-mass AGNs with high-quality light curves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas dynamical friction as a binary formation mechanism in AGN discs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_dynamical_friction_as_a_binary_formation_mechanism_in_agn_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_dynamical_friction_as_a_binary_formation_mechanism_in_agn_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stanislav DeLaurentiis
In this paper, we study how gaseous dynamical friction (DF) affects the motion of fly-by stellar-mass black holes (sBHs) embedded in active galactic nucleus (AGN) discs. We perform 3-body integrations of the interaction of two co-planar sBHs in nearby, initially circular orbits around the supermassive black hole (SMBH). We find that DF can facilitate the formation of gravitationally bound near-Keplerian binaries in AGN discs, and we delineate the discrete ranges of impact parameters and AGN disc parameters for which such captures occur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
