<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AGN on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/agn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AGN on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/agn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Update of the INTEGRAL/IBIS AGN catalogue: deeper on the Galactic plane and wider beyond</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/update_of_the_integral_ibis_agn_catalogue_deeper_on_the_galactic_plane_and_wider_beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/update_of_the_integral_ibis_agn_catalogue_deeper_on_the_galactic_plane_and_wider_beyond/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Malizia
In this work we have updated the list of AGN detected by INTEGRAL taking into account the new objects listed in the last published INTEGRAL/IBIS survey. We have collected 83 new AGN increasing the number of INTEGRAL detected active galaxies (436) by 19%. Half of these new additions are located behind the Galactic plane; for most of them we have full X-ray coverage obtained through archival data from Swift/XRT, XMM-Newton and NuSTAR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Mid-Infrared and X-ray Machine Learning Algorithm to Discover Compton-thick AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_mid-infrared_and_x-ray_machine_learning_algorithm_to_discover_compton-thick_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_mid-infrared_and_x-ray_machine_learning_algorithm_to_discover_compton-thick_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ross Silver
We present a new method to predict the line-of-sight column density (NH) values of active galactic nuclei (AGN) based on mid-infrared (MIR), soft, and hard X-ray data. We developed a multiple linear regression machine learning algorithm trained with WISE colors, Swift-BAT count rates, soft X-ray hardness ratios, and an MIR-soft X-ray flux ratio. Our algorithm was trained off 451 AGN from the Swift-BAT sample with known NH and has the ability to accurately predict NH values for AGN of all levels of obscuration, as evidenced by its Spearman correlation coefficient value of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of AGNs and quasars having significant proper motions according to Gaia data within SRG/eRosita X-Ray sources catalog</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_agns_and_quasars_having_significant_proper_motions_according_to_gaia_data_within_srg_erosita_x-ray_sources_catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_agns_and_quasars_having_significant_proper_motions_according_to_gaia_data_within_srg_erosita_x-ray_sources_catalog/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. M. Khamitov
Based on a comparison of the SRG/eROSITA catalog of X-ray active stars and the Gaia catalog, a sample of 502 peculiar objects was obtained for which Gaia, on one hand, detects statistically significant values of parallax or proper motion and, on the other hand, registers signs of the non zero source extent in the optical band. In the log ($F_X/F_{\rm opt}$) - (G-RP) color diagram these objects are separated from the balk of X-ray active stars and are located in the region typical for the galaxies with active nuclei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SOUX AGN Sample: SDSS-XMM-Newton Optical, Ultraviolet and X-ray selected active galactic nuclei spanning a wide range of parameter space -- Sample definition</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_soux_agn_sample_sdss-xmm-newton_optical_ultraviolet_and_x-ray_selected_active_galactic_nuclei_spanning_a_wide_range_of_parameter_space_--_sample_definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_soux_agn_sample_sdss-xmm-newton_optical_ultraviolet_and_x-ray_selected_active_galactic_nuclei_spanning_a_wide_range_of_parameter_space_--_sample_definition/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Kynoch
We assemble a sample of 696 type 1 AGN up to a redshift of $z=2.5$, all of which have an SDSS spectrum containing at least one broad emission line (H $\alpha$, H $\beta$ or Mg II) and an XMM-Newton X-ray spectrum containing at least 250 counts in addition to simultaneous optical/ultraviolet photometry from the XMM Optical Monitor. Our sample includes quasars and narrow-line Seyfert 1s: thus our AGN span a wide range in luminosity, black hole mass and accretion rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Column Density Variability in a Sample of Local Compton-Thin AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrogen_column_density_variability_in_a_sample_of_local_compton-thin_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrogen_column_density_variability_in_a_sample_of_local_compton-thin_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Torres-Albà
We present the analysis of multiepoch observations of a set of 12 variable, Compton-thin, local (z&amp;lt;0.1) active galactic nuclei (AGN) selected from the 100-month BAT catalog. We analyze all available X-ray data from \chandra, \xmm, and \nustar, adding up to a total of 53 individual observations. This corresponds to between 3 and 7 observations per source, probing variability timescales between a few days and $\sim 20$~yr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength Analysis of a Nearby Heavily Obscured AGN in NGC 449</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_analysis_of_a_nearby_heavily_obscured_agn_in_ngc_449/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_analysis_of_a_nearby_heavily_obscured_agn_in_ngc_449/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaotong Guo
We presented the multiwavelength analysis of a heavily obscured active galactic nucleus (AGN) in NGC 449. We first constructed a broadband X-ray spectrum using the latest NuSTAR and XMM-Newton data. Its column density ($\simeq 10^{24} \rm{cm}^{-2}$) and photon index ($\Gamma\simeq 2.4$) were reliably obtained by analyzing the broadband X-ray spectrum. However, the scattering fraction and the intrinsic X-ray luminosity could not be well constrained. Combined with the information obtained from the mid-infrared (mid-IR) spectrum and spectral energy distribution (SED) fitting, we derived its intrinsic X-ray luminosity ($\simeq 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended Corona Models of X-ray Reverberation in the AGN 1H~0707-495 and IRAS 13224-3809</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extended_corona_models_of_x-ray_reverberation_in_the_agn_1h~0707-495_and_iras_13224-3809/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extended_corona_models_of_x-ray_reverberation_in_the_agn_1h~0707-495_and_iras_13224-3809/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Hancock
We fit a new vertically extended corona model to previously measured reverberation time lags observed by \emph{XMM-Newton} in two extremely variable Narrow Line Seyfert 1 Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN), 1H~0707-495 and IRAS~13224-3809, in a variety of similarly observed flux groups and explore the model in all observations over a 16 year period. The model employs two X-ray sources located along the black hole rotational axis at height, $h_1$ and $h_2$ respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN in post-mergers from the Ultraviolet Near Infrared Optical Northern Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_in_post-mergers_from_the_ultraviolet_near_infrared_optical_northern_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_in_post-mergers_from_the_ultraviolet_near_infrared_optical_northern_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Robert W. Bickley
The kinematic disturbances associated with major galaxy mergers are known to produce gas inflows, which in turn may trigger accretion onto the supermassive black holes (SMBH) of the participant galaxies. While this effect has been studied in galaxy pairs, the frequency of active galactic nuclei (AGN) in fully coalesced post-merger systems is poorly constrained due to the limited size or impurity of extant post-merger samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard X-Ray to Radio Multiwavelength SED Analysis of Local U/LIRGs in GOALS Sample with Self-consistent AGN Model Including Polar-dust Component</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_to_radio_multiwavelength_sed_analysis_of_local_u_lirgs_in_goals_sample_with_self-consistent_agn_model_including_polar-dust_component/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_to_radio_multiwavelength_sed_analysis_of_local_u_lirgs_in_goals_sample_with_self-consistent_agn_model_including_polar-dust_component/</guid>
      <description>First author: Satoshi Yamada
We conduct a hard X-ray to radio multiwavelength spectral energy distribution (SED) decomposition for 57 local luminous and ultraluminous infrared galaxies (U/LIRGs) observed with Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array and/or Swift/Burst Alert Telescope in GOALS (Armus et al. 2009) sample. We modify the latest SED-fitting code X-CIGALE by implementing the infrared (IR) CLUMPY model, allowing the multiwavelength study with the X-ray torus model (XCLUMPY) self-consistently. Adopting the torus parameters obtained by the X-ray fitting (Yamada et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fundamental signature of star formation quenching from AGN feedback: A critical dependence of quiescence on supermassive black hole mass not accretion rate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fundamental_signature_of_star_formation_quenching_from_agn_feedback_a_critical_dependence_of_quiescence_on_supermassive_black_hole_mass_not_accretion_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fundamental_signature_of_star_formation_quenching_from_agn_feedback_a_critical_dependence_of_quiescence_on_supermassive_black_hole_mass_not_accretion_rate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Asa F. L. Bluck
We identify the intrinsic dependence of star formation quenching on a variety of galactic and environmental parameters, utilizing a machine learning approach with Random Forest classification. We have previously demonstrated the power of this technique to isolate causality, not mere correlation, in complex astronomical data. First, we analyze three cosmological hydrodynamical simulations (Eagle, Illustris, and IllustrisTNG), selecting snapshots spanning the bulk of cosmic history from comic noon ($z \sim 2$) to the present epoch, with stellar masses in the range $9 &amp;lt; \log(M_/M_{\odot}) &amp;lt; 12$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New multiple AGN systems with sub-arcsec separation: confirmation of candidates selected via the novel GMP method</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_multiple_agn_systems_with_sub-arcsec_separation_confirmation_of_candidates_selected_via_the_novel_gmp_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_multiple_agn_systems_with_sub-arcsec_separation_confirmation_of_candidates_selected_via_the_novel_gmp_method/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Ciurlo
The existence of multiple active galactic nuclei (AGN) at small projected distances on the sky is due to either the presence of multiple, in-spiraling SMBHs, or to gravitational lensing of a single AGN. Both phenomena allow us to address important astrophysical and cosmological questions. However, few kpc-separation multiple AGN are currently known. Recently, the newly-developed Gaia Multi peak (GMP) method provided numerous new candidate members of these populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOALS-JWST: Pulling Back the Curtain on the AGN and Star Formation in VV 114</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/goals-jwst_pulling_back_the_curtain_on_the_agn_and_star_formation_in_vv_114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/goals-jwst_pulling_back_the_curtain_on_the_agn_and_star_formation_in_vv_114/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Rich
We present results from the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) Director&amp;rsquo;s Discretionary Time Early Release Science (ERS) program 1328 targeting the nearby, Luminous Infrared Galaxy (LIRG), VV 114. We use the MIRI and NIRSpec instruments to obtain integral-field spectroscopy of the heavily obscured Eastern nucleus (V114E) and surrounding regions. The spatially resolved, high-resolution, spectra reveal the physical conditions in the gas and dust over a projected area of 2-3 kpc that includes the two brightest IR sources, the NE and SW cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing AGN outflow and accretion models with CIV and HeII emission line demographics in z=2 quasars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_agn_outflow_and_accretion_models_with_civ_and_heii_emission_line_demographics_in_z2_quasars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_agn_outflow_and_accretion_models_with_civ_and_heii_emission_line_demographics_in_z2_quasars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew J. Temple
Using 190,000 spectra from the seventeenth data release of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, we investigate the ultraviolet emission line properties in z=2 quasars. Specifically, we quantify how the shape of CIV 1549A and the equivalent width (EW) of HeII 1640A depend on the black hole mass and Eddington ratio inferred from MgII 2800A. Above L/L_Edd&amp;gt;0.2, there is a strong mass dependence in both CIV blueshift and HeII EW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practicable estimation of opening angle of dust torus in Type-1.9 AGN with double-peaked broad H$α$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_practicable_estimation_of_opening_angle_of_dust_torus_in_type-1.9_agn_with_double-peaked_broad_h_%CE%B1_/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_practicable_estimation_of_opening_angle_of_dust_torus_in_type-1.9_agn_with_double-peaked_broad_h_%CE%B1_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhang XueGuang
In this manuscript, an independent method is proposed to estimate opening angle of dust torus in AGN, through unique properties of Type-1.9 AGN with double-peaked broad H$\alpha$ (Type-1.9 DPAGN) coming from central accretion disk. Type-1.9 AGN without broad H$\beta$ can be expected by the commonly accepted unified model of AGN, considering central BLRs seriously obscured by dust torus with its upper boundary in the line of sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Method to Determine X-ray Luminosity Functions of AGN and their Evolution with Redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_to_determine_x-ray_luminosity_functions_of_agn_and_their_evolution_with_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_to_determine_x-ray_luminosity_functions_of_agn_and_their_evolution_with_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ahlam Alqasim
Almost all massive galaxies today are understood to contain supermassive black holes (SMBH) at their centers. SMBHs grew by accreting material from their surroundings, emitting X-rays as they did so. X-ray Luminosity Functions (XLFs) of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) have been extensively studied in order to understand the AGN population&amp;rsquo;s cosmological properties and evolution. We present a new fixed rest-frame method to achieve a more accurate study of the AGN XLF evolution over cosmic time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Neural Network Approach to identify Stars and AGNs observed by XMM Newton</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_neural_network_approach_to_identify_stars_and_agns_observed_by_xmm_newton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_neural_network_approach_to_identify_stars_and_agns_observed_by_xmm_newton/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sarvesh Gharat
In today&amp;rsquo;s era, a tremendous amount of data is generated by different observatories and manual classification of data is something which is practically impossible. Hence, to classify and categorize the objects there are multiple machine and deep learning techniques used. However, these predictions are overconfident and won&amp;rsquo;t be able to identify if the data actually belongs to the trained class. To solve this major problem of overconfidence, in this study we propose a novel Bayesian Neural Network which randomly samples weights from a distribution as opposed to the fixed weight vector considered in the frequentist approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Accretion Events: TDEs and Changing-Look AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extreme_accretion_events_tdes_and_changing-look_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extreme_accretion_events_tdes_and_changing-look_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Komossa
We present a review of the topics of X-ray stellar tidal disruption events (TDEs) and changing-look active galactic nuclei (AGN). Stars approaching a supermassive black hole (SMBH) can be tidally disrupted and accreted. TDEs were first discovered in the X-ray regime and appear as luminous, giant-amplitude flares from inactive galaxies. The early X-ray observations with ROSAT also established the extreme X-ray spectral softness of these events with temperatures of order 50-100 eV that continues to be seen in the majority of more recently identified events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of gas accretion and AGN feedback on the scatter of the mass-metallicity relation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_gas_accretion_and_agn_feedback_on_the_scatter_of_the_mass-metallicity_relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_gas_accretion_and_agn_feedback_on_the_scatter_of_the_mass-metallicity_relation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nancy Yang
The gas-phase metallicity of galaxies encodes important information about galaxy evolution processes, in particular star formation, feedback, outflows and gas accretion, the relative importance of which can be extracted from systematic trends in the scatter of the mass-metallicity relation (MZR). Here, we use a sample of low redshift (0.02&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;0.055) galaxies from SDSS to investigate the nature of the scatter around the MZR, the observables and physical processes causing it, and its dependence on galaxy mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost in the Shell: Evidence for Past AGN Activities in NGC 5195 from a Newly Discovered large-scale Ionized Structure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ghost_in_the_shell_evidence_for_past_agn_activities_in_ngc_5195_from_a_newly_discovered_large-scale_ionized_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ghost_in_the_shell_evidence_for_past_agn_activities_in_ngc_5195_from_a_newly_discovered_large-scale_ionized_structure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaoyu Xu
The early-type galaxy NGC 5195 (alternatively known as M51b) possesses extended gas features detected in multi-wavelength, postulated to be associated with previous activities of the central supermassive black hole (SMBH). Using integral field spectroscopic observations from the Canada-France-Hawaii Telescope (CFHT)/SITELLE, we report on the discovery of a new large-scale ionized gas structure traced by $[O III]$, $[N II]$, and H$\alpha$ line emission, extending to $\sim10\rm,kpc$ from the nucleus of NGC 5195.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First detection of the outer edge of an AGN accretion disc: Very fast multiband optical variability of NGC 4395 with GTC/HiPERCAM and LT/IO:O</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_detection_of_the_outer_edge_of_an_agn_accretion_disc_very_fast_multiband_optical_variability_of_ngc_4395_with_gtc_hipercam_and_lt_ioo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_detection_of_the_outer_edge_of_an_agn_accretion_disc_very_fast_multiband_optical_variability_of_ngc_4395_with_gtc_hipercam_and_lt_ioo/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. M. McHardy
We present fast (~200s sampling) ugriz photometry of the low mass AGN NGC 4395 with the Liverpool Telescope, followed by very fast (3s sampling) us, gs, rs, is and zs simultaneous monitoring with HiPERCAM on the 10.4m GTC. These observations provide the fastest ever AGN multiband photometry and very precise lag measurements. Unlike in all other AGN, gs lags us by a large amount, consistent with disc reprocessing but not with reprocessing in the Broad Line Region (BLR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiwavelength study of the ongoing Changing-look AGN AT2021fxu</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multiwavelength_study_of_the_ongoing_changing-look_agn_at2021fxu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multiwavelength_study_of_the_ongoing_changing-look_agn_at2021fxu/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yukta Ajay
We present multiwavelength analyses of an active optical transient AT2021fxu which shows the appearance of previously absent broad emission lines in a recent optical spectrum, suggesting a Changing-look (CL) Active Galactic Nucleus (AGN). During the spectral transition, the brightness in the individual photometric bands increased up to $\approx$0.6 in the optical bands and up to $\approx$1.1 magnitudes in the UV bands. The brightening was accompanied by a blueward shift of the optical spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The outburst of the changing-look AGN IRAS23226-3843 in 2019</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_outburst_of_the_changing-look_agn_iras23226-3843_in_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_outburst_of_the_changing-look_agn_iras23226-3843_in_2019/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wolfram Kollatschny
IRAS23226-3843 has previously been classified as a changing-look AGN based on X-ray and optical spectral variations. In 2019, Swift observations revealed a strong rebrightening in X-ray and UV fluxes in comparison to observations in 2017. We took follow-up Swift, XMM-Newton, and NuSTAR observations together with optical spectra (SALT and SAAO 1.9m telescope) from 2019 until 2021. IRAS23226-3843 showed a strong X-ray and optical outburst in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-situ star formation in accretion disk and explanation for correlation between black hole mass and metallicity in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/in-situ_star_formation_in_accretion_disk_and_explanation_for_correlation_between_black_hole_mass_and_metallicity_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/in-situ_star_formation_in_accretion_disk_and_explanation_for_correlation_between_black_hole_mass_and_metallicity_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiao Fan
Recent observations show that the metallicity of the broad line region ($Z_{\rm BLR}$) in active galactic nuclei (AGNs) is solar-to-supersolar, which is positively correlated with the mass of supermassive black holes ($M_{\rm BH}$) and does not evolve with redshift up to $z \sim 7$. We revisit the $M_{\rm BH}-Z_{\rm BLR}$ correlation with more AGNs with $M_{\rm BH}\sim 10^{6-8} M_{\odot}$ and find that the positive correlation become flat in low-mass range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN cool feedback and analogy with X-ray binaries: from radiation pressure to cosmic ray driven outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_cool_feedback_and_analogy_with_x-ray_binaries_from_radiation_pressure_to_cosmic_ray_driven_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_cool_feedback_and_analogy_with_x-ray_binaries_from_radiation_pressure_to_cosmic_ray_driven_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Ishibashi
Cool outflows are now commonly observed in galaxies, but their physical origin and driving mechanism remain unclear. Active galactic nucleus (AGN) feedback can potentially accelerate cool galactic outflows via cosmic rays (CR) and radiation pressure on dust. Here we investigate the relative importance of CR and radiation feedback in AGNs, and we analyse the physical conditions for outflow launching as a function of the black hole accretion flow mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Hole Binary Formation in AGN Discs: From Isolation to Merger</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_binary_formation_in_agn_discs_from_isolation_to_merger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_binary_formation_in_agn_discs_from_isolation_to_merger/</guid>
      <description>First author: Connar Rowan
Motivated by the increasing number of gravitational wave detections of merging black holes (BHs) by LIGO-VIRGO-KAGRA, BH binary mergers in the discs of active galactic nuclei (AGN) is investigated as a possible merger channel. In this pathway, BHs in the large gas disc are expected to encounter one another, become mutually bound as a BH binary system through interaction with the gas in the disc and subsequently inspiral through gravitational torques induced by the local gas until merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency of Optical/UV parameters on X-ray spectral index in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dependency_of_optical_uv_parameters_on_x-ray_spectral_index_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dependency_of_optical_uv_parameters_on_x-ray_spectral_index_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Nour
The study of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGNs) is vital in order to understand their respective nuclei bounded activity primarily triggered by the accretion disk and the associated corona. The hard X-ray emission characterised by the spectral index $\Gamma$ emitted by these sources in 2-10 keV band ionizes the nearby physical features like disk, BLR, NLR and provides a radiative configuration. However, based on previous studies, there is degeneracy in the evolution of $\Gamma$ across the redshift, wherein few studies display a systematic trend in the evolution and others rule out the systematic variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The X-ray view of optically selected dual AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_x-ray_view_of_optically_selected_dual_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_x-ray_view_of_optically_selected_dual_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alessandra De Rosa
We present a study of optically selected dual AGN with projected separations of 3&amp;ndash;97~kpc. Using multi-wavelength (MWL) information (optical, X-rays, mid-IR), we characterized the intrinsic nuclear properties of this sample and compared them with those of isolated systems. Among the 124 X-ray detected AGN candidates, 52 appear in pairs and 72 as single X-ray sources. Through MWL analysis, we confirmed the presence of the AGN in a fraction &amp;gt;80% of the detected targets in pairs (42 over 52).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuSTAR Observes Two Bulgeless Galaxies: No Hard X-ray AGN Detected in NGC 4178 or J0851&#43;3926</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan W. Pfeifle
The discovery over the last several decades of moderate luminosity AGNs in disk-dominated galaxies - which show no &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; bulges - suggests that secular mechanisms represent an important growth pathway for supermassive black holes in these systems. We present new follow-up NuSTAR observations of the optically-elusive AGNs in two bulgeless galaxies, NGC 4178 and J0851+3926. NGC 4178 was originally reported as hosting an AGN based on the detection of [Ne V] mid-infrared emission detected by Spitzer, and based on Chandra X-ray imaging it has since been argued to host either a heavily obscured AGN or a supernova remnant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ALPINE-ALMA $[CII]$ survey: double stellar population and AGN activity in a galaxy at $z\sim5.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Barchiesi
GDS J033218.92-275302.7 (here GS-14) is a $z\sim5.5$ galaxy detected in $[CII]$ as part of the ALPINE survey with unusual UV spectral features that have been interpreted as signatures of either a double stellar population or of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We exploited the multi-wavelength coverage of GS-14 to investigate the properties and the origin of its emission. We performed UV-to-NIR SED-fitting, with single/double stellar population and/or AGN component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Optical, Ultraviolet and Soft X-ray excess Emissions in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Nour
Soft X-ray emission (0.5&amp;ndash;2.0 keV) plays a pivotal role in regulating the optical and UV emission in the AGNs. We collected a sample of 1811 AGNs from the SDSS database and obtained various parameters of Balmer lines, optical continuum, MgII line &amp;amp; UV continuum and studied their dependencies on soft X-ray luminosity. Based on the linear regression analysis, we found that FWHM${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ FWHM${\text{H}\beta}^{0.554}$ suggesting that UV emission is arising from a region relatively outside the broad line region (BLR) associated to the H$\beta$ emission and found a strong correlation between optical and UV luminosities (L${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ L${\text{H}\beta}^{0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOJAVE XX. Decade-long linear polarization variability in AGN jets at parsec scales</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. I. Zobnina
We studied the variability properties of the linear polarization of active galactic nucleus (AGN) jets on parsec-scales using stacking. Our sample is drawn from the MOJAVE program and consists of 436 AGNs manifesting core-jet morphology and having at least five VLBA observing epochs at 15 GHz from January 1996 through August 2019, with some additional archival VLBA data reduced by us. We employed a stacking procedure and constructed maps of (i) standard deviation of fractional polarization and electric vector position angle (EVPA) over epochs as the measure of variability, (ii) median polarization degree to quantify typical values in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Fourier-Transformation Model for the Production of Hard and Soft X-Ray Time Lags in AGNs: Application to 1H 0707-495</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</guid>
      <description>First author: David C. Baughman
The variability of the X-ray emission from active galactic nuclei is often characterized using time lags observed between soft and hard energy bands in the detector. The time lags are usually computed using the complex cross spectrum, which is based on the Fourier transforms of the hard and soft time series data. It has been noted that some active galactic nuclei display soft X-ray time lags, in addition to the more ubiquitous hard lags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Herschel observations of the 2Jy sample: assessing the non-thermal and AGN contributions to the far-IR continuum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_herschel_observations_of_the_2jy_sample_assessing_the_non-thermal_and_agn_contributions_to_the_far-ir_continuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_herschel_observations_of_the_2jy_sample_assessing_the_non-thermal_and_agn_contributions_to_the_far-ir_continuum/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Dicken
The far-IR/sub-mm wavelength range contains a wealth of diagnostic information that is important for understanding the role of radio AGN in galaxy evolution. Here we present the results of Herschel PACS and SPIRE observations of a complete sample of 46 powerful 2Jy radio AGN at intermediate redshifts (0.05 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.7), which represent the deepest pointed observations of a major sample of radio AGN undertaken by Herschel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Physical Picture for AGNs Lacking Optical Emission Lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher J. Agostino
In this work, we use ~500 low-redshift (z ~ 0.1) X-ray AGNs observed by XMM-Newton and SDSS to investigate the prevalence and nature of AGNs that apparently lack optical emission lines (optically dull AGNs&#39;&#39;). Although 1/4 of spectra appear absorption-line dominated in visual assessment, line extraction with robust continuum subtraction from the MPA/JHU catalog reveals usable [OIII] measurements in 98% of the sample, allowing us to study [OIII]-underluminous AGNs together with more typical AGNs in the context of the L$_{\mathrm{[OIII]}}$--L$_{X}$ relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the moderate UV/X-ray correlation in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Panagiotou
The UV/optical and X-ray variability of active galactic nuclei (AGN) have long been expected to be well correlated as a result of the X-ray illumination of the accretion disk. Recent monitoring campaigns of nearby AGN, however, found that their X-ray and UV/optical emission are only moderately correlated, challenging the aforementioned paradigm. In this work, we aim to demonstrate that due to the definition of the cross correlation function, a low UV/X-ray correlation is well expected in the case of an X-ray illuminated accretion disk, when the dynamic variability of the X-ray source is taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TPHO: a time-dependent photoionisation model for AGN outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tpho_a_time-dependent_photoionisation_model_for_agn_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tpho_a_time-dependent_photoionisation_model_for_agn_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniele Rogantini
Outflows in active galactic nuclei (AGN) are considered a promising candidate for driving AGN feedback at large scales. However, without information on the density of these outflows, we cannot determine how much kinetic power they are imparting to the surrounding medium. Monitoring the response of the ionisation state of the absorbing outflows to changes in the ionising continuum provides the recombination timescale of the outflow, which is a function of the electron density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the X-ray reflection in low accretion rate AGN using XMM-Newton, NuSTAR and Swift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_x-ray_reflection_in_low_accretion_rate_agn_using_xmm-newton_nustar_and_swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_x-ray_reflection_in_low_accretion_rate_agn_using_xmm-newton_nustar_and_swift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Díaz
An interesting feature in active galactic nuclei (AGN) accreting at low rate is the weakness of the reflection features in their X-ray spectra, which can result from the gradual disappearance of the torus with decreasing accretion rates. It has been suggested that low luminosity AGN (LLAGN) would have a different reflector configuration compared with high luminosity AGN, either covering a smaller fraction of the sky or simply having less material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does absorption against AGN reveal supermassive black hole accretion?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_absorption_against_agn_reveal_supermassive_black_hole_accretion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_absorption_against_agn_reveal_supermassive_black_hole_accretion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tom Rose
Galaxies often contain large reservoirs of molecular gas which shape their evolution. This can be through cooling of the gas &amp;ndash; which leads to star formation, or accretion onto the central supermassive black hole &amp;ndash; which fuels AGN activity and produces powerful feedback. Molecular gas has been detected in early-type galaxies on scales of just a few tens to hundreds of solar masses by searching for absorption against their compact radio cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Wavelength Study of Multiple Spectral Component Jets in AGN: Testing the IC/CMB Model for the Large-Scale-Jet X-ray Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multi-wavelength_study_of_multiple_spectral_component_jets_in_agn_testing_the_ic_cmb_model_for_the_large-scale-jet_x-ray_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multi-wavelength_study_of_multiple_spectral_component_jets_in_agn_testing_the_ic_cmb_model_for_the_large-scale-jet_x-ray_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Breiding
Over 150 resolved, kpc-scale X-ray jets hosted by active galactic nuclei have been discovered with the Chandra X-ray Observatory. A significant fraction of these jets have an X-ray spectrum either too high in flux or too hard to be consistent with the high-energy extension of the radio-to-optical synchrotron spectrum, a subtype we identify as Multiple Spectral Component (MSC) X-ray jets. A leading hypothesis for the origin of the X-rays is the inverse-Compton scattering of the cosmic microwave background by the same electron population producing the radio-to-optical synchrotron spectrum (known as the IC/CMB model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Dynamics in AGN Winds: A New Mechanism For Multiwavelength AGN Variability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_dynamics_in_agn_winds_a_new_mechanism_for_multiwavelength_agn_variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_dynamics_in_agn_winds_a_new_mechanism_for_multiwavelength_agn_variability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nadine H. Soliman
Partial dust obscuration in active galactic nuclei (AGN) has been proposed as a potential explanation for some cases of AGN variability. The dust-gas mixture present in AGN torii is accelerated by radiation pressure leading to the launching of an AGN wind. Dust under these conditions has been shown to be unstable to a generic class of fast growing resonant drag instabilities (RDIs). We present the first set of numerical simulations of radiation driven outflows that include explicit dust dynamics in conditions resembling AGN winds and discuss the implications of the RDIs on the morphology of the AGN torus, AGN variability, and the ability of the radiation to effectively launch a wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for extended gaseous reservoirs around AGN at cosmic noon from ALMA CO(3-2) observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_extended_gaseous_reservoirs_around_agn_at_cosmic_noon_from_alma_co3-2_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_extended_gaseous_reservoirs_around_agn_at_cosmic_noon_from_alma_co3-2_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. C. Jones
Gaseous outflows are key phenomena in the evolution of galaxies, as they affect star formation (either positively or negatively), eject gas from the core or disk, and directly cause mixing of pristine and processed material. Active outflows may be detected through searches for broad spectral line emission or high-velocity gas, but it is also possible to determine the presence of past outflows by searching for extended reservoirs of chemically enriched molecular gas in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) around galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical study of the time-lags due to Comptonization and the constraints on the X-ray corona in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_theoretical_study_of_the_time-lags_due_to_comptonization_and_the_constraints_on_the_x-ray_corona_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_theoretical_study_of_the_time-lags_due_to_comptonization_and_the_constraints_on_the_x-ray_corona_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Zhang
We study the Fourier time-lags due to the Comptonization of disc-emitted photons in a spherical, uniform, and stationary X-ray corona, which located on the rotational axis of the black hole. We use Monk, a general relativistic Monte-Carlo radiative transfer code, to calculate Compton scattering of photons emitted by a thin disc with a Novikov-Thorne temperature profile. We find that the model time-lags due to Comptonization remain constant up to a characteristic frequency and then rapidly decrease to zero at higher frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN Feedback in SDSS-IV MaNGA: AGNs Have Suppressed Central Star-Formation Rates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Caleb Lammers
Despite the importance of feedback from active galactic nuclei (AGN) in models of galaxy evolution, observational constraints on the influence of AGN feedback on star formation remain weak. To this end, we have compared the star formation trends of 279 low-redshift AGN galaxies with 558 non-active control galaxies using integral field unit spectroscopy from the SDSS-IV MaNGA survey. With a Gaussian process-based methodology, we reconstruct non-parametric star formation histories in spatially-resolved spaxels covering the face of each galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf AGNs from Variability for the Origins of Seeds (DAVOS): Optical Variability of Broad-line Dwarf AGNs from the Zwicky Transient Facility</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_agns_from_variability_for_the_origins_of_seeds_davos_optical_variability_of_broad-line_dwarf_agns_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_agns_from_variability_for_the_origins_of_seeds_davos_optical_variability_of_broad-line_dwarf_agns_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</guid>
      <description>First author: Z. Franklin Wang
We study the optical variability of a sample of candidate low-mass (dwarf ang Seyfert) active galactic nuclei (AGNs) using Zwicky Transient Facility g-band light curves. Our sample is compiled from broad-line AGNs in dwarf galaxies reported in the literature with single-epoch virial black hole (BH) masses in the range $M_{\rm{BH}} \sim 10^{4}$&amp;ndash;$10^{8}\ M_{\odot}$. We measure the characteristic ``damping&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; timescale of the optical variability $\tau_{\rm{DRW}}$, beyond which the power spectral density flattens, of a final sample of 79 candidate low-mass AGNs with high-quality light curves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for AGN-Regulated Cooling in Clusters at $z \sim 1.4$: A Multi-Wavelength View of SPT-CL J0607-4448</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_agn-regulated_cooling_in_clusters_at__z__sim_1.4__a_multi-wavelength_view_of_spt-cl_j0607-4448/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_agn-regulated_cooling_in_clusters_at__z__sim_1.4__a_multi-wavelength_view_of_spt-cl_j0607-4448/</guid>
      <description>First author: Megan Masterson
We present a multi-wavelength analysis of the galaxy cluster SPT-CL J0607-4448 (SPT0607), which is one of the most distant clusters discovered by the South Pole Telescope (SPT) at $z=1.4010\pm0.0028$. The high-redshift cluster shows clear signs of being relaxed with well-regulated feedback from the active galactic nucleus (AGN) in the brightest cluster galaxy (BCG). Using Chandra X-ray data, we construct thermodynamic profiles and determine the properties of the intracluster medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas dynamical friction as a binary formation mechanism in AGN discs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_dynamical_friction_as_a_binary_formation_mechanism_in_agn_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_dynamical_friction_as_a_binary_formation_mechanism_in_agn_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stanislav DeLaurentiis
In this paper, we study how gaseous dynamical friction (DF) affects the motion of fly-by stellar-mass black holes (sBHs) embedded in active galactic nucleus (AGN) discs. We perform 3-body integrations of the interaction of two co-planar sBHs in nearby, initially circular orbits around the supermassive black hole (SMBH). We find that DF can facilitate the formation of gravitationally bound near-Keplerian binaries in AGN discs, and we delineate the discrete ranges of impact parameters and AGN disc parameters for which such captures occur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
