<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>globular clusterchemical on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/globular-clusterchemical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in globular clusterchemical on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/globular-clusterchemical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optical and X-ray Follow-Up to a Globular Cluster Ultraluminous X-ray Source in NGC 4472</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/optical_and_x-ray_follow-up_to_a_globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_source_in_ngc_4472/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/optical_and_x-ray_follow-up_to_a_globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_source_in_ngc_4472/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wasundara R. Athukoralalage
NGC 4472 is home to five ultraluminous X-ray sources hosted by globular clusters. These sources have been suggested as good black hole candidates in extragalactic globular clusters$-$ a highly sought after population that may provide observational information regarding the progenitors of merging black hole binaries. In this body of work, we present X-ray and optical follow up to one of these sources, CXOUJ1229410+075744 (GCU1). We find no evidence of [OIII] optical emission in GCU1 which indicates a lack of significant evidence for super-Eddington outflows, unlike what is seen in a handful of ULXs in extragalactic GCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Globular Clusters in Galaxy Clusters: Sensitivity from the Formation and Evolution of Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/properties_of_globular_clusters_in_galaxy_clusters_sensitivity_from_the_formation_and_evolution_of_globular_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/properties_of_globular_clusters_in_galaxy_clusters_sensitivity_from_the_formation_and_evolution_of_globular_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: So-Myoung Park
We investigate the properties of globular clusters in a galaxy cluster, using the particle tagging method with a semi-analytical approach in a cosmological context. We assume globular clusters form from dark matter halo mergers and their metallicity is assigned based on the stellar mass of the host dark matter halos and the formation redshift of GCs. Dynamical evolution and disruption of globular clusters are considered using semi-analytical approaches, controlled by several free parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far Ultra-Violet Insights Into NGC 1399&#39;s Globular Cluster Population</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/far_ultra-violet_insights_into_ngc_1399s_globular_cluster_population/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/far_ultra-violet_insights_into_ngc_1399s_globular_cluster_population/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kristen C. Dage
We investigate archival Hubble Space Telescope ACS/SBC F140LP observations of NGC~1399 to search for evidence of multiple stellar populations in extragalactic globular clusters. Enhanced FUV populations are thought to be indicators of He-enhanced second generation populations in globular clusters, specifically extreme/blue horizontal branch stars. Out of 149 globular clusters in the field of view, 58 have far ultraviolet (FUV) counterparts with magnitudes brighter than 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking beneath the precision floor I: metallicity spreads and multiple elemental dispersions in the globular clusters NGC 288 and NGC 362</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/peeking_beneath_the_precision_floor_i_metallicity_spreads_and_multiple_elemental_dispersions_in_the_globular_clusters_ngc_288_and_ngc_362/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/peeking_beneath_the_precision_floor_i_metallicity_spreads_and_multiple_elemental_dispersions_in_the_globular_clusters_ngc_288_and_ngc_362/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stephanie Monty
The view of globular clusters (GCs) as simple systems continues to unravel, revealing complex objects hosting multiple chemical peculiarities. Using differential abundance analysis, we probe the chemistry of the Type I GC, NGC 288 and the Type II GC, NGC 362 at the 2% level for the first time. We measure 20 elements and find differential measurement uncertainties on the order 0.01-0.02 dex in both clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying globular clusters and applying them to estimate the mass of the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: GuangChen Sun
We combine the kinematics of 159 globular clusters (GCs) provided by the Gaia Early Data Release 3 (EDR 3) with other observational data to classify the GCs, and to estimate the mass of Milky Way (MW). We use the age-metallicity relation, integrals of motion, action space and the GC orbits to identify the GCs as either formed in-situ (Bulge and Disk) or ex-situ (via accretion). We find that $45.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Stellar Populations of Globular Clusters From Homogeneous Ca-CN-CH-NH Photometry. VII. Metal-Poor Populations in 47 Tucanae (NGC 104)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/multiple_stellar_populations_of_globular_clusters_from_homogeneous_ca-cn-ch-nh_photometry._vii._metal-poor_populations_in_47_tucanae_ngc_104/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular-clusterchemical/multiple_stellar_populations_of_globular_clusters_from_homogeneous_ca-cn-ch-nh_photometry._vii._metal-poor_populations_in_47_tucanae_ngc_104/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jae-Woo Lee
We present new large field-of-view ($\sim$1\deg$\times$1\deg) Ca-CN photometry of the prototypical metal-rich globular cluster 47 Tucanae (NGC 104). Our results are the following. (1) The populational number ratios of the red giant branch (RGB) and red horizontal branch (RHB) are in excellent agreement: n(CN-w):n(CN-s) = 30:70 ($\pm$1&amp;ndash;2), where the CN-w and CN-s stand for the CN-weak and CN-strong populations, respectively. Both the CN-s RGB and RHB populations are more centrally concentrated than those of CN-w populations are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
