<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cosmology on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/cosmology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cosmology on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/cosmology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Characteristic Functions for Cosmological Cross-Correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/characteristic_functions_for_cosmological_cross-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/characteristic_functions_for_cosmological_cross-correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick C. Breysse
We introduce a novel unbiased, cross-correlation estimator for the one-point statistics of cosmological random fields. One-point statistics are a useful tool for analysis of highly non-Gaussian density fields, while cross-correlations provide a powerful method for combining information from pairs of fields and separating them from noise and systematics. We derive a new Deconvolved Distribution Estimator that combines the useful properties of these two methods into one statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Cosmological Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/complementary_cosmological_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/complementary_cosmological_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gábor Rácz
Cosmic variance limits the accuracy of cosmological N-body simulations, introducing bias in statistics such as the power spectrum, halo mass function, or the cosmic shear. We provide new methods to measure and reduce the effect of cosmic variance in existing and new simulations. We run pairs of simulations using phase shifted initial conditions with matching amplitudes. We set the initial amplitudes of the Fourier modes to ensure that the average power spectrum of the pair is equal to the cosmic mean power spectrum from linear theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spherical collapse of non-top-hat profiles in the presence of dark energy with arbitrary sound speed</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spherical_collapse_of_non-top-hat_profiles_in_the_presence_of_dark_energy_with_arbitrary_sound_speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spherical_collapse_of_non-top-hat_profiles_in_the_presence_of_dark_energy_with_arbitrary_sound_speed/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. C. Batista
We study the spherical collapse of non-top-hat matter fluctuations in the presence of dark energy with arbitrary sound speed. The model is described by a system of partial differential equations solved using a pseudo-spectral method with collocation points. This method can reproduce the known analytical solutions in the linear regime with an accuracy better than $10^{-6}%$ and better than $10^{-2}%$ for the virialization threshold given by the usual spherical collapse model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The deconvolved distribution estimator: enhancing reionisation-era CO line-intensity mapping analyses with a cross-correlation analogue for one-point statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_deconvolved_distribution_estimator_enhancing_reionisation-era_co_line-intensity_mapping_analyses_with_a_cross-correlation_analogue_for_one-point_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_deconvolved_distribution_estimator_enhancing_reionisation-era_co_line-intensity_mapping_analyses_with_a_cross-correlation_analogue_for_one-point_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dongwoo T. Chung
We present the deconvolved distribution estimator (DDE), an extension of the voxel intensity distribution (VID), in the context of future observations proposed as part of the CO Mapping Array Project (COMAP). The DDE exploits the fact that the observed VID is a convolution of correlated signal intensity distributions and uncorrelated noise or interloper intensity distributions. By deconvolving the individual VID of two observables away from their joint VID in a Fourier-space operation, the DDE suppresses sensitivity to interloper emission while maintaining sensitivity to correlated components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global CD/EoR Signal Detection with a Dense Digital Beamforming Array and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/global_cd_eor_signal_detection_with_a_dense_digital_beamforming_array_and_beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/global_cd_eor_signal_detection_with_a_dense_digital_beamforming_array_and_beyond/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junhua Gu
The global neutral hydrogen 21 cm signal extracted from the all-sky averaged radio spectra is one of the signatures of the Cosmic Dawn and Epoch of Reionization (CD/EoR). The frequency-dependency of antenna beam patterns coupled with the strong foreground emission could introduce artificial spectral structures and cause false detection. A digital beamforming array could be potentially employed to form achromatic station beam patterns to overcome this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KaRMMa 2.0 -- Kappa Reconstruction for Mass Mapping</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/karmma_2.0_--_kappa_reconstruction_for_mass_mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/karmma_2.0_--_kappa_reconstruction_for_mass_mapping/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pier Fiedorowicz
We present KaRMMa 2.0, an updated version of the mass map reconstruction code introduced in Fiedorowicz et al. (2022). KaRMMa is a full-sky Bayesian algorithm for reconstructing weak lensing mass maps from shear data. It forward-models the convergence field as a realization of a lognormal field. The corresponding shear map is calculated using the standard Kaiser-Squires transformation, and compared to observations at the field level. The posterior distribution of maps given the shear data is sampled using Hamiltonian Monte Carlo chains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the spin-down limits for the continuous gravitational waves emitted from pulsars as triaxial rotators</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improving_the_spin-down_limits_for_the_continuous_gravitational_waves_emitted_from_pulsars_as_triaxial_rotators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improving_the_spin-down_limits_for_the_continuous_gravitational_waves_emitted_from_pulsars_as_triaxial_rotators/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dhruv Pathak
The spin-down limit of the continuous gravitational wave strain (assuming pulsars as triaxial rotators) depends upon the value of the intrinsic spin frequency derivative of the pulsar, among other parameters. In order to get more accurate intrinsic spin frequency derivative values, dynamical effects contributing to the measured spin frequency derivative values must be estimated via more realistic approaches. In this work, we calculate improved values of the spin-down limit of the gravitational wave strain (assuming pulsars as triaxial rotators) for a set of 237 pulsars for which a targeted search for continuous gravitational waves was carried out by the LVK Collaboration, recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference of gravitational lensing and patchy reionization with future CMB data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_of_gravitational_lensing_and_patchy_reionization_with_future_cmb_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_of_gravitational_lensing_and_patchy_reionization_with_future_cmb_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Federico Bianchini
We develop an optimal Bayesian solution for jointly inferring secondary signals in the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) originating from gravitational lensing and from patchy screening during the epoch of reionization. This method is able to extract full information content from the data, improving upon previously considered quadratic estimators for lensing and screening. We forecast constraints using the Marginal Unbiased Score Expansion (MUSE) method, and show that they are largely dominated by CMB polarization, and depend on the exact details of reionization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New EoR Power Spectrum Limits From MWA Phase II Using the Delay Spectrum Method and Novel Systematic Rejection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_eor_power_spectrum_limits_from_mwa_phase_ii_using_the_delay_spectrum_method_and_novel_systematic_rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_eor_power_spectrum_limits_from_mwa_phase_ii_using_the_delay_spectrum_method_and_novel_systematic_rejection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew Kolopanis
We present an analysis of Epoch of Reionization data from Phase II of the Murchison Widefield Array using the \texttt{simpleDS} delay spectrum pipeline. This analysis is complementary to that presented in Li et al. (2019), which analyzes the same observations using the FHD/$\varepsilon$ppsilon imaging pipeline. This represents the first time that both principal types of 21 cm cosmology power spectrum estimation approaches have been applied to the same data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven Cosmology from Three-dimensional Light Cones</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_cosmology_from_three-dimensional_light_cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_cosmology_from_three-dimensional_light_cones/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yun-Ting Cheng
We present a data-driven technique to analyze multi-frequency images from upcoming cosmological surveys mapping large sky area. Using full information from the data at the two-point level, our method can simultaneously constrain the large-scale structure (LSS), the spectra and redshift distribution of emitting sources, and the noise in observed data without any prior assumptions beyond the homogeneity and isotropy of cosmological perturbations. In particular, the method does not rely on source detection or photometric or spectroscopic redshift estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong lensing constraints on primordial black holes as a dark matter candidate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_lensing_constraints_on_primordial_black_holes_as_a_dark_matter_candidate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_lensing_constraints_on_primordial_black_holes_as_a_dark_matter_candidate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Veronica Dike
Dark matter could comprise, at least in part, primordial black holes (PBH). To test this hypothesis, we present an approach to constrain the PBH mass ($M_{\rm{PBH}}$) and mass fraction ($f_{\rm{PBH}}$) from the flux ratios of quadruply imaged quasars. Our approach uses an approximate Bayesian computation (ABC) forward modeling technique to directly sample the posterior distribution of $M_{\rm{PBH}}$ and $f_{\rm{PBH}}$, while marginalizing over the subhalo mass function amplitude, spatial distribution, and the size of the lensed source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upper limits on the Polarized Isotropic Stochastic Gravitational-Wave Background from Advanced LIGO-Virgo&#39;s First Three Observing Runs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/upper_limits_on_the_polarized_isotropic_stochastic_gravitational-wave_background_from_advanced_ligo-virgos_first_three_observing_runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/upper_limits_on_the_polarized_isotropic_stochastic_gravitational-wave_background_from_advanced_ligo-virgos_first_three_observing_runs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yang Jiang
Parity violation is expected to generate an asymmetry between the amplitude of left and right-handed gravitational-wave modes which leads to a circularly polarized stochastic gravitational-wave background (SGWB). Due to the three independent baselines in the LIGO-Virgo network, we focus on the amplitude difference in strain power characterized by Stokes&amp;rsquo; parameters and do maximum-likelihood estimation to constrain the polarization degree of SGWB. Our results indicate that there is no evidence for the circularly polarized SGWB in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harrison-Zel&#39;dovich spectrum gets back?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/harrison-zeldovich_spectrum_gets_back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/harrison-zeldovich_spectrum_gets_back/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Giarè
The Data Release 4 of the Atacama Cosmology Telescope (ACT) shows an agreement with an Harrison-Zel&amp;rsquo;dovich primordial spectrum ($n_s=1.009 \pm 0.015$), introducing a tension with a significance of $99.3%$ CL with the results from the Planck satellite. The discrepancy on the value of the scalar spectral index is neither alleviated with the addition of large scale structure information nor with the low multipole polarization data. We discuss possible avenues to alleviate the tension relying on either neglecting polarization measurements from ACT or in extending the inflationary sector of the theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inflaton as a pseudo-Nambu-Goldstone boson</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inflaton_as_a_pseudo-nambu-goldstone_boson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inflaton_as_a_pseudo-nambu-goldstone_boson/</guid>
      <description>First author: Noriaki Kitazawa
In the realistic model of cosmic inflation the inflaton potential should be flat and stable under quantum corrections. It is natural to imagine that there is some symmetry behind and an idea of the inflaton as a Nambu-Goldstone boson of spontaneous breaking of some symmetry has been examined. We give a general formulation of this idea using the non-linear realization of Nambu-Goldstone boson in low-energy effective theory with some explicit symmetry breaking to generate non-trivial potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A combinatorial algebraic approach for the modified second-generation time-delay interferometry</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_combinatorial_algebraic_approach_for_the_modified_second-generation_time-delay_interferometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_combinatorial_algebraic_approach_for_the_modified_second-generation_time-delay_interferometry/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhang-Qi Wu
We generalize the combinatorial algebraic approach first proposed by Dhurandhar et al. to construct various classes of modified second-generation time-delay interferometry (TDI) solutions. The main idea behind the algorithm is to enumerate, in a given order, a specific type of commutator between two monomials defined by the products of particular time-displacement operators. On the one hand, the above commutators can be systematically rewritten as the elements of a left ideal, defined by the l.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMB Delensing with Neural Network Based Lensing Reconstruction in the Presence of Primordial Tensor Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cmb_delensing_with_neural_network_based_lensing_reconstruction_in_the_presence_of_primordial_tensor_perturbations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cmb_delensing_with_neural_network_based_lensing_reconstruction_in_the_presence_of_primordial_tensor_perturbations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chen Heinrich
The next-generation CMB experiments are expected to constrain the tensor-to-scalar ratio $r$ with high precision. Delensing is an important process as the observed CMB $B$-mode polarization that contains the primordial tensor perturbation signal is dominated by a much larger contribution due to gravitational lensing. To do so successfully, it is useful to explore methods for lensing reconstruction beyond the traditional quadratic estimator (QE) (which will become suboptimal for the next-generation experiments), and the maximum a posterior estimator (which is still currently under development).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring line-of-sight shear with Einstein rings: a proof of concept</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/measuring_line-of-sight_shear_with_einstein_rings_a_proof_of_concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/measuring_line-of-sight_shear_with_einstein_rings_a_proof_of_concept/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalie B. Hogg
Line-of-sight effects in strong gravitational lensing have long been treated as a nuisance. However, it was recently proposed that the line-of-sight shear could be a cosmological observable in its own right, if it is not degenerate with lens model parameters. Using the formalism introduced by Fleury et al. (2021a), we firstly demonstrate that the line-of-sight shear can be accurately measured from a simple simulated strong lensing image with percent precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SKYSURF-4: Panchromatic Full Sky Surface Brightness Measurement Methods and Results</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/skysurf-4_panchromatic_full_sky_surface_brightness_measurement_methods_and_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/skysurf-4_panchromatic_full_sky_surface_brightness_measurement_methods_and_results/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rosalia O&amp;rsquo;Brien
The diffuse, unresolved sky provides most of the photons that the Hubble Space Telescope (HST) receives, yet remains poorly understood. HST Archival Legacy program SKYSURF aims to measure the 0.2-1.7 $\mu$m sky surface brightness (sky-SB) from over 200,000 HST images. We describe two sky-SB measurement algorithms designed for SKYSURF (the Percentile-clip and ProFound Median methods), that are able to recover the input sky-SB from simulated images to within 1% uncertainty, and present measurements estimated using each algorithm on the entire SKYSURF database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spherical Fast Multipole Method (sFMM) for Gravitational Lensing Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spherical_fast_multipole_method_sfmm_for_gravitational_lensing_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spherical_fast_multipole_method_sfmm_for_gravitational_lensing_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xingpao Suo
In this paper, we present a spherical Fast Multipole Method (sFMM) for ray tracing simulation of gravitational lensing (GL) on a curved sky. The sFMM is a non-trivial extension of the Fast Multiple Method (FMM) to sphere $\mathbb S^2$, and it can accurately solve the Poisson equation with time complexity of $O(N)\log(N)$, where $N$ is the number of particles. It is found that the time complexity of the sFMM is near $O(N)$ and the computational accuracy can reach $10^{-10}$ in our test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorentz invariance violation induced threshold anomaly versus very-high energy cosmic photon emission from GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lorentz_invariance_violation_induced_threshold_anomaly_versus_very-high_energy_cosmic_photon_emission_from_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lorentz_invariance_violation_induced_threshold_anomaly_versus_very-high_energy_cosmic_photon_emission_from_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hao Li
It is reported that the Large High Altitude Air Shower Observatory (LHAASO) observed very high energy photons from GRB 221009A, with the highest energy reaching 18 TeV. We find that observation of such high energy photons is a quite nontrivial fact since extragalactic background light could absorb these photons severely and the flux is too weak to be observed. Therefore we discuss the potential new mechanism for us to observe these photons, and suggest that Lorentz invariance violation induced threshold anomaly of the process (\gamma\gamma\to e^-e^+) provides a candidate to explain this phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-messenger constraints on Abelian-Higgs cosmic string networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-messenger_constraints_on_abelian-higgs_cosmic_string_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-messenger_constraints_on_abelian-higgs_cosmic_string_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mark Hindmarsh
Nielsen-Olesen vortices in the Abelian-Higgs (AH) model are the simplest realisations of cosmic strings in a gauge field theory. Large-scale numerical solutions show that the dominant decay channel of a network of AH strings produced from random initial conditions is classical field radiation. However, they also show that with special initial conditions, loops of string can be created for which classical field radiation is suppressed, and which behave like Nambu-Goto (NG) strings with a dominant decay channel into gravitational radiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the mean field theory of scalar field dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_mean_field_theory_of_scalar_field_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_mean_field_theory_of_scalar_field_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew Eberhardt
Scalar field dark matter offers an interesting alternative to the traditional WIMP dark matter picture. Astrophysical and cosmological simulations are useful to constraining the mass of the dark matter particle in this model. This is particularly true at low mass where the wavelike nature of the dark matter particle manifests on astrophysical scales. These simulations typical use a classical field approximation. In this work, we look at extending these simulations to include quantum corrections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cornering Extended Starobinsky Inflation with CMB and SKA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cornering_extended_starobinsky_inflation_with_cmb_and_ska/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cornering_extended_starobinsky_inflation_with_cmb_and_ska/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tanmoy Modak
Starobinsky inflation is an attractive, fundamental model to explain the Planck measurements, and its higher-order extension may allow us to probe quantum gravity effects. We show that future CMB data combined with the 21cm intensity map from SKA will meaningfully probe such an extended Starobinsky model. A combined analysis will provide a precise measurement and intriguing insight into inflationary dynamics, even accounting for correlations with astrophysical parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even Lighter Particle Dark Matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/even_lighter_particle_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/even_lighter_particle_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alvaro E. Chavarria
We report on recent progress in the search for dark matter particles with masses from 1 MeV to 1 GeV. Several dark matter candidates in this mass range are expected to generate measurable electronic-recoil signals in direct-detection experiments. We focus on dark matter particles scattering with electrons in semiconductor detectors since they have fundamentally the highest sensitivity due to their low ionization threshold. Charge-coupled device (CCD) silicon detectors are the leading technology, with significant progress expected in the coming years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-world CMB lensing quadratic estimator power spectrum response</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/real-world_cmb_lensing_quadratic_estimator_power_spectrum_response/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/real-world_cmb_lensing_quadratic_estimator_power_spectrum_response/</guid>
      <description>First author: Julien Carron
I describe a method to estimate response matrices of Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) lensing power spectra estimators to the true sky power under realistic conditions. Applicable to all lensing reconstruction pipelines based on quadratic estimators (QE), it uses a small number of Gaussian CMB Monte-Carlos and specially designed QE&amp;rsquo;s in order to obtain sufficiently accurate matrices with little computational effort. This method may be used to improve the modelling of CMB lensing band-powers by incorporating at least some of the non-idealities encountered in CMB lensing reconstruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple single-field inflation models with arbitrarily small tensor/scalar ratio</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simple_single-field_inflation_models_with_arbitrarily_small_tensor_scalar_ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simple_single-field_inflation_models_with_arbitrarily_small_tensor_scalar_ratio/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nina K. Stein William H. Kinney
We construct a family of simple single-field inflation models consistent with Planck / BICEP Keck bounds which have a parametrically small tensor amplitude and no running of the scalar spectral index. The construction consists of a constant-roll hilltop inflaton potential with the end of inflation left as a free parameter induced by higher-order operators which become dominant late in inflation. This construction directly demonstrates that there is no lower bound on the tensor/scalar ratio for simple single-field inflation models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of ultra-high energy cosmic rays after more than 15 years of operation of the Pierre Auger Observatory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_science_of_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays_after_more_than_15_years_of_operation_of_the_pierre_auger_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_science_of_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays_after_more_than_15_years_of_operation_of_the_pierre_auger_observatory/</guid>
      <description>First author: Olivier Deligny
The Pierre Auger Observatory has been detecting ultra-high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) for more than fifteen years. An essential feature of the Observatory is its hybrid design: cosmic rays above $100~$PeV are detected through the observation of the associated air showers with different and complementary techniques, from surface detector arrays and fluorescence telescopes to radio antennas. The analyses of the multi-detector data have enabled high-statistics and high-precision studies of the energy spectrum, mass composition and distribution of arrival directions of UHECRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave-optics limit of the stochastic gravitational wave background</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wave-optics_limit_of_the_stochastic_gravitational_wave_background/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wave-optics_limit_of_the_stochastic_gravitational_wave_background/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alice Garoffolo
The stochastic gravitational wave background (SGWB) is a rich resource of cosmological information, encoded both in its source statistics and its anisotropies induced by propagation effects. We provide a theoretical description of it, without employing the Boltzmann equation which is exclusively valid in the geometric optics limit. Our formalism is based on the so-called classical matter approximation and it is able to capture wave-optics effects, such as interference and diffraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultradense dark matter haloes accompanying primordial black holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ultradense_dark_matter_haloes_accompanying_primordial_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ultradense_dark_matter_haloes_accompanying_primordial_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Sten Delos
Primordial black holes (PBHs) form from large-amplitude initial density fluctuations and may comprise some or all of the dark matter. If PBHs have an extended mass spectrum, or in mixed PBH-particle dark matter scenarios, the extreme density fluctuations necessary to produce PBHs also lead to the formation of a much greater abundance of dark matter minihaloes with internal densities potentially of order $10^{12}$ M$_\odot$ pc$^{-3}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Time Dependent Data in Bayesian Global 21cm Foreground and Signal Modelling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/use_of_time_dependent_data_in_bayesian_global_21cm_foreground_and_signal_modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/use_of_time_dependent_data_in_bayesian_global_21cm_foreground_and_signal_modelling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominic Anstey
Global 21cm cosmology aims to investigate the cosmic dawn and epoch of reionisation by measuring the sky averaged HI absorption signal, which requires, accurate modelling of, or correction for, the bright radio foregrounds and distortions arising from chromaticity of the antenna beam. We investigate the effect of improving foreground modelling by fitting data sets from many observation times simultaneously in a single Bayesian analysis, fitting for the same parameter set by performing these fits on simulated data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on primordial curvature spectrum from primordial black holes and scalar-induced gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_primordial_curvature_spectrum_from_primordial_black_holes_and_scalar-induced_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_primordial_curvature_spectrum_from_primordial_black_holes_and_scalar-induced_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhu Yi
The observational data of primordial black holes and scalar-induced gravitational waves can constrain the primordial curvature perturbation at small scales. We parameterize the primordial curvature perturbation by a broken power law form and find that it is consistent with many inflation models that can produce primordial black holes, such as nonminimal derivative coupling inflation, scalar-tensor inflation, Gauss-Bonnet inflation, and K/G inflation. The constraints from primordial black holes on the primordial curvature power spectrum with the broken power law form are obtained, where the fraction of primordial black holes in dark matter is calculated by the peak theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational microlensing by dressed primordial black holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_microlensing_by_dressed_primordial_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_microlensing_by_dressed_primordial_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rong-Gen Cai
The accretion of dark matter around the primordial black holes (PBHs) could lead to the formation of surrounding minihalos, whose mass can be several orders of magnitude higher than the central PBH mass. The gravitational microlensing produced by such dressed PBHs could be quite different from that of the bare PBHs, which may greatly affect the constraints on the PBH abundance. In this paper, we study the gravitational microlensing produced by dressed PBHs in details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale power loss in ground-based CMB mapmaking</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/large-scale_power_loss_in_ground-based_cmb_mapmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/large-scale_power_loss_in_ground-based_cmb_mapmaking/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sigurd Naess
CMB mapmaking relies on a data model to solve for the sky map, and this process is vulnerable to bias if the data model cannot capture the full behavior of the signal. I demonstrate that this bias is not just limited to small-scale effects in high-contrast regions of the sky, but can manifest as $\mathcal{O}(1)$ power loss on large scales in the map under conditions and assumptions realistic for ground-based CMB telescopes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luminosity distribution of fast radio bursts from CHIME/FRB Catalog 1 by means of the updated Macquart relation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/luminosity_distribution_of_fast_radio_bursts_from_chime_frb_catalog_1_by_means_of_the_updated_macquart_relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/luminosity_distribution_of_fast_radio_bursts_from_chime_frb_catalog_1_by_means_of_the_updated_macquart_relation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiang-Han Cui
Fast radio bursts (FRBs) are extremely strong radio flares lasting several micro- to milliseconds and come from unidentified objects at cosmological distances, most of which are only seen once. Based on recently published data in the CHIME/FRB Catalog 1 in the frequency bands 400-800 MHz, we analyze 125 apparently singular FRBs with low dispersion measure (DM) and find that the distribution of their luminosity follows a lognormal form according to statistical tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primordial black holes from stochastic tunnelling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_black_holes_from_stochastic_tunnelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_black_holes_from_stochastic_tunnelling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chiara Animali
If the inflaton gets trapped in a local minimum of its potential shortly before the end of inflation, it escapes by building up quantum fluctuations in a process known as stochastic tunnelling. In this work we study cosmological fluctuations produced in such a scenario, and how likely they are to form Primordial Black Holes (PBHs). This is done by using the stochastic-$\delta N$ formalism, which allows us to reconstruct the highly non-Gaussian tails of the distribution function of the number of $e$-folds spent in the false-vacuum state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for dilaton fields in the Ly$α$ forest</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_dilaton_fields_in_the_ly_%CE%B1__forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_dilaton_fields_in_the_ly_%CE%B1__forest/</guid>
      <description>First author: Louis Hamaide
Dilatons (and moduli) couple to the masses and coupling constants of ordinary matter, and these quantities are fixed by the local value of the dilaton field. If, in addition, the dilaton with mass $m_\phi$ contributes to the cosmic dark matter density, then such quantities oscillate in time at the dilaton Compton frequency. We show how these oscillations lead to broadening and shifting of the Voigt profile of the Ly$\alpha$ forest, in a manner that is correlated with the local dark matter density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spot size estimation of flat-top beams in space-based gravitational wave detectors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spot_size_estimation_of_flat-top_beams_in_space-based_gravitational_wave_detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spot_size_estimation_of_flat-top_beams_in_space-based_gravitational_wave_detectors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhen-Xiang Hao
Motivated by the necessity of a high-quality stray light control in the detection of the gravitational waves in space, the spot size of a flat top beam generated by the clipping of the Gaussian beam (GB) is studied. By adopting the mode expansion method (MEM) approach to simulating the beam, a slight variant of the definition of the mean square deviation (MSD) spot size for the MEM beam is proposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status of QUBIC, the Q&amp;U Bolometer for Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/status_of_qubic_the_qu_bolometer_for_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/status_of_qubic_the_qu_bolometer_for_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Mousset
The Q&amp;amp;U Bolometric Interferometer for Cosmology (QUBIC) is a novel kind of polarimeter optimized for the measurement of the B-mode polarization of the Cosmic Microwave Back-ground (CMB), which is one of the major challenges of observational cosmology. The signal is expected to be of the order of a few tens of nK, prone to instrumental systematic effects and polluted by various astrophysical foregrounds which can only be controlled through multichroic observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Gravitational Lensing Parameter Estimation with Vision Transformer</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_gravitational_lensing_parameter_estimation_with_vision_transformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_gravitational_lensing_parameter_estimation_with_vision_transformer/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kuan-Wei Huang
Quantifying the parameters and corresponding uncertainties of hundreds of strongly lensed quasar systems holds the key to resolving one of the most important scientific questions: the Hubble constant ($H_{0}$) tension. The commonly used Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) method has been too time-consuming to achieve this goal, yet recent work has shown that convolution neural networks (CNNs) can be an alternative with seven orders of magnitude improvement in speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does an interferometer really measure? Including instrument and data characteristics in the reconstruction of the 21cm power spectrum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/what_does_an_interferometer_really_measure_including_instrument_and_data_characteristics_in_the_reconstruction_of_the_21cm_power_spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/what_does_an_interferometer_really_measure_including_instrument_and_data_characteristics_in_the_reconstruction_of_the_21cm_power_spectrum/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adélie Gorce
Combining the visibilities measured by an interferometer to form a cosmological power spectrum is a complicated process in which the window functions play a crucial role. In a delay-based analysis, the mapping between instrumental space, made of per-baseline delay spectra, and cosmological space is not a one-to-one relation. Instead, neighbouring modes contribute to the power measured at one point, with their respective contributions encoded in the window functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
