<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cosmology on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/cosmology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cosmology on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/cosmology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Characteristic Functions for Cosmological Cross-Correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/characteristic_functions_for_cosmological_cross-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/characteristic_functions_for_cosmological_cross-correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick C. Breysse
We introduce a novel unbiased, cross-correlation estimator for the one-point statistics of cosmological random fields. One-point statistics are a useful tool for analysis of highly non-Gaussian density fields, while cross-correlations provide a powerful method for combining information from pairs of fields and separating them from noise and systematics. We derive a new Deconvolved Distribution Estimator that combines the useful properties of these two methods into one statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Cosmological Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/complementary_cosmological_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/complementary_cosmological_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gábor Rácz
Cosmic variance limits the accuracy of cosmological N-body simulations, introducing bias in statistics such as the power spectrum, halo mass function, or the cosmic shear. We provide new methods to measure and reduce the effect of cosmic variance in existing and new simulations. We run pairs of simulations using phase shifted initial conditions with matching amplitudes. We set the initial amplitudes of the Fourier modes to ensure that the average power spectrum of the pair is equal to the cosmic mean power spectrum from linear theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spherical collapse of non-top-hat profiles in the presence of dark energy with arbitrary sound speed</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spherical_collapse_of_non-top-hat_profiles_in_the_presence_of_dark_energy_with_arbitrary_sound_speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spherical_collapse_of_non-top-hat_profiles_in_the_presence_of_dark_energy_with_arbitrary_sound_speed/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. C. Batista
We study the spherical collapse of non-top-hat matter fluctuations in the presence of dark energy with arbitrary sound speed. The model is described by a system of partial differential equations solved using a pseudo-spectral method with collocation points. This method can reproduce the known analytical solutions in the linear regime with an accuracy better than $10^{-6}%$ and better than $10^{-2}%$ for the virialization threshold given by the usual spherical collapse model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The deconvolved distribution estimator: enhancing reionisation-era CO line-intensity mapping analyses with a cross-correlation analogue for one-point statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_deconvolved_distribution_estimator_enhancing_reionisation-era_co_line-intensity_mapping_analyses_with_a_cross-correlation_analogue_for_one-point_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_deconvolved_distribution_estimator_enhancing_reionisation-era_co_line-intensity_mapping_analyses_with_a_cross-correlation_analogue_for_one-point_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dongwoo T. Chung
We present the deconvolved distribution estimator (DDE), an extension of the voxel intensity distribution (VID), in the context of future observations proposed as part of the CO Mapping Array Project (COMAP). The DDE exploits the fact that the observed VID is a convolution of correlated signal intensity distributions and uncorrelated noise or interloper intensity distributions. By deconvolving the individual VID of two observables away from their joint VID in a Fourier-space operation, the DDE suppresses sensitivity to interloper emission while maintaining sensitivity to correlated components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global CD/EoR Signal Detection with a Dense Digital Beamforming Array and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/global_cd_eor_signal_detection_with_a_dense_digital_beamforming_array_and_beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/global_cd_eor_signal_detection_with_a_dense_digital_beamforming_array_and_beyond/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junhua Gu
The global neutral hydrogen 21 cm signal extracted from the all-sky averaged radio spectra is one of the signatures of the Cosmic Dawn and Epoch of Reionization (CD/EoR). The frequency-dependency of antenna beam patterns coupled with the strong foreground emission could introduce artificial spectral structures and cause false detection. A digital beamforming array could be potentially employed to form achromatic station beam patterns to overcome this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
