<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cosmology on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/cosmology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cosmology on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/cosmology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Non-Gaussianity in the cosmic microwave background from loop quantum cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussianity_in_the_cosmic_microwave_background_from_loop_quantum_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussianity_in_the_cosmic_microwave_background_from_loop_quantum_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roshna K
Primordial non-Gaussianity has set strong constraints on models of the early universe. Studies have shown that Loop Quantum Cosmology (LQC), which is an attempt to extend inflationary scenario to planck scales, leads to a strongly scale dependent and oscillatory non-Gaussianity. In particular, the non-Gaussianity function $f_{_{\rm NL}}(k_1,, k_2,, k_3)$ generated in LQC, though similar to that generated during slow roll inflation at small scales, is highly scale dependent and oscillatory at large wavelengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological-Scale HI Distribution Around Galaxies and AGN Probed with the HETDEX and SDSS Spectroscopic Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological-scale_hi_distribution_around_galaxies_and_agn_probed_with_the_hetdex_and_sdss_spectroscopic_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological-scale_hi_distribution_around_galaxies_and_agn_probed_with_the_hetdex_and_sdss_spectroscopic_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dongsheng Sun
We present cosmological-scale 3-dimensional (3D) neutral hydrogen ({\sc Hi}) tomographic maps at $z=2-3$ over a total of 837 deg$^2$ in two blank fields that are developed with Ly$\alpha$ forest absorptions of 14,736 background Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) quasars at $z$=2.08-3.67. Using the tomographic maps, we investigate the large-scale ($\gtrsim 10$ $h^{-1}$cMpc) average {\sc Hi} radial profiles and two-direction profiles of the line-of-sight (LoS) and transverse (TS) directions around galaxies and AGN at $z=2-3$ identified by the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy eXperiment (HETDEX) and SDSS surveys, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of the Probability of Interaction of Globular Clusters with Each Other and with the Galactic Center on the Cosmological Time Scale According to Gaia DR2 Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_analysis_of_the_probability_of_interaction_of_globular_clusters_with_each_other_and_with_the_galactic_center_on_the_cosmological_time_scale_according_to_gaia_dr2_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_analysis_of_the_probability_of_interaction_of_globular_clusters_with_each_other_and_with_the_galactic_center_on_the_cosmological_time_scale_according_to_gaia_dr2_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maryna Ishchenko
This study is aimed at investigating the dynamic evolution of the orbits of stellar globular clusters (GCs). To integrate the orbits backward in time, the authors use models of the time-varying potentials derived from cosmological simulations, which are closest to the potential of the Galaxy. This allows for estimating the probability of close passages (collisions) of GCs with respect to each other and the Galactic center (GalC) in the Galaxy undergoing dynamic changes in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining cosmological parameters from N-body simulations with Variational Bayesian Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_cosmological_parameters_from_n-body_simulations_with_variational_bayesian_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_cosmological_parameters_from_n-body_simulations_with_variational_bayesian_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Héctor J. Hortúa
Methods based on Deep Learning have recently been applied on astrophysical parameter recovery thanks to their ability to capture information from complex data. One of these methods is the approximate Bayesian Neural Networks (BNNs) which have demonstrated to yield consistent posterior distribution into the parameter space, helpful for uncertainty quantification. However, as any modern neural networks, they tend to produce overly confident uncertainty estimates and can introduce bias when BNNs are applied to data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cosmological Simulation Code OpenGadget3 -- Implementation of Meshless Finite Mass</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cosmological_simulation_code_opengadget3_--_implementation_of_meshless_finite_mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cosmological_simulation_code_opengadget3_--_implementation_of_meshless_finite_mass/</guid>
      <description>First author: Frederick Groth
Subsonic turbulence plays a major role in determining properties of the intra cluster medium (ICM). We introduce a new Meshless Finite Mass (MFM) implementation in OpenGadget3 and apply it to this specific problem. To this end, we present a set of test cases to validate our implementation of the MFM framework in our code. These include but are not limited to: the soundwave and Kepler disk as smooth situations to probe the stability, a Rayleigh-Taylor and Kelvin-Helmholtz instability as popular mixing instabilities, a blob test as more complex example including both mixing and shocks, shock tubes with various Mach numbers, a Sedov blast wave, different tests including self-gravity such as gravitational freefall, a hydrostatic sphere, the Zeldovich-pancake, and the nifty cluster as cosmological application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing Cosmology beyond $Λ$CDM using the SKA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_cosmology_beyond__%CE%BB_cdm_using_the_ska/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_cosmology_beyond__%CE%BB_cdm_using_the_ska/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shamik Ghosh
The cosmological principle states that the Universe is statistically homogeneous and isotropic at large distance scales. There currently exist many observations which indicate a departure from this principle. It has been shown that many of these observations can be explained by invoking superhorizon cosmological perturbations and may be consistent with the Big Bang paradigm. Remarkably, these modes simultaneously explain the observed Hubble tension, i.e., the discrepancy between the direct and indirect measurements of the Hubble parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observational constraints of diffusive dark-fluid cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_constraints_of_diffusive_dark-fluid_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_constraints_of_diffusive_dark-fluid_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Remudin Reshid Mekuria
In this work, we consider an interacting dark-fluid cosmological model in which energy exchange between dark matter and dark energy occurs through diffusion. After solving the background expansion history for a late-time universe, we attempt to constrain the cosmological parameters by comparing simulated values of the model against Supernovae Type 1A data. We consider four different cases and compare them against the LCDM model as the &amp;ldquo;true model&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Fisher forecasts for next-generation spectroscopic surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_fisher_forecasts_for_next-generation_spectroscopic_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_fisher_forecasts_for_next-generation_spectroscopic_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: William d&amp;rsquo;Assignies D.
Next-generation spectroscopic surveys such as the MegaMapper, MUltiplexed Survey Telescope (MUST), MaunaKea Spectroscopic Explorer (MSE), and Wide Spectroscopic Telescope (WST) are foreseen to increase the number of galaxy/quasar redshifts by an order of magnitude, with hundred millions of spectra that will be measured at $z&amp;gt;2$. We perform a Fisher matrix analysis for these surveys on the baryonic acoustic oscillation (BAO), the redshift-space distortion (RSD) measurement, the non-Gaussianity amplitude $f_{\rm NL}$, and the total neutrino mass $M_\nu$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Simulations of Two-Component Wave Dark Matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_simulations_of_two-component_wave_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_simulations_of_two-component_wave_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hsinhao Huang
Wave (fuzzy) dark matter consists of ultralight bosons ($m \sim 10^{-22} \textrm{&amp;ndash;} 10^{-20},{\rm eV}$), featuring a compact solitonic core at the centre of a granular halo. Here we extend this model to a two-component wave dark matter, with distinct particle masses and coupled only through gravity, and investigate the resulting soliton-halo structure via cosmological simulations. Specifically, we assume wave dark matter contains $75$ per cent major component and $25$ per cent minor component, fix the major-component particle mass to $m_{\rm major}=1\times10^{-22},{\rm eV}$, and explore two different minor-component particle masses with $m_{\rm major}:m_{\rm minor}=3:1$ and $1:3$, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New description of the scaling evolution of the cosmological magneto-hydrodynamic system</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_description_of_the_scaling_evolution_of_the_cosmological_magneto-hydrodynamic_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_description_of_the_scaling_evolution_of_the_cosmological_magneto-hydrodynamic_system/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fumio Uchida
We present a new description of cosmological evolution of the primordial magnetic field under the condition that it is non-helical and its energy density is larger than the kinetic energy density. We argue that the evolution can be described by four different regimes, according to whether the decay dynamics is linear or not, and whether the dominant dissipation term is the shear viscosity or the drag force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel model-marginalized cosmological bound on the QCD axion mass</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_novel_model-marginalized_cosmological_bound_on_the_qcd_axion_mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_novel_model-marginalized_cosmological_bound_on_the_qcd_axion_mass/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eleonora Di Valentino
We present strong model-marginalized limits on mixed hot dark matter scenarios, which consider both thermal neutrinos and thermal QCD axions. A novel aspect of our analyses is the inclusion of small-scale Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) observations from the Atacama Cosmology Telescope (ACT) and the South Pole Telescope (SPT), together with those from the Planck satellite and Baryon Acoustic Oscillation (BAO) data. After marginalizing over a number of well-motivated non-minimal background cosmologies, the tightest $95%$ CL upper bound we obtain is $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CosmoDRAGoN simulations -- I. Dynamics and observable signatures of radio jets in cosmological environments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmodragon_simulations_--_i._dynamics_and_observable_signatures_of_radio_jets_in_cosmological_environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmodragon_simulations_--_i._dynamics_and_observable_signatures_of_radio_jets_in_cosmological_environments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick M. Yates-Jones
We present the Cosmological Double Radio Active Galactic Nuclei (CosmoDRAGoN) project: a large suite of simulated AGN jets in cosmological environments. These environments sample the intra-cluster media of galaxy clusters that form in cosmological smooth particle hydrodynamics (SPH) simulations, which we then use as inputs for grid-based hydrodynamic simulations of radio jets. Initially conical jets are injected with a range of jet powers, speeds (both relativistic and non-relativistic), and opening angles; we follow their collimation and propagation on scales of tens to hundreds of kiloparsecs, and calculate spatially-resolved synthetic radio spectra in post-processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the spatial curvature with cosmic expansion history in a cosmological model with a non-standard sound horizon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_spatial_curvature_with_cosmic_expansion_history_in_a_cosmological_model_with_a_non-standard_sound_horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_spatial_curvature_with_cosmic_expansion_history_in_a_cosmological_model_with_a_non-standard_sound_horizon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jordan Stevens
Spatial curvature is one of the most fundamental parameters in our current concordance flat $\Lambda$CDM model of the Universe. The goal of this work is to investigate how the constraint on the spatial curvature is affected by an assumption on the sound horizon scale. The sound horizon is an essential quantity to use the standard ruler from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Baryon Acoustic Oscillations (BAOs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renormalizing one-point probability distribution function for cosmological counts in cells</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/renormalizing_one-point_probability_distribution_function_for_cosmological_counts_in_cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/renormalizing_one-point_probability_distribution_function_for_cosmological_counts_in_cells/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anton Chudaykin
We study the one-point probability distribution function (PDF) for matter density averaged over spherical cells. The leading part to the PDF is defined by the dynamics of the spherical collapse whereas the next-to-leading part comes from the integration over fluctuations around the saddle-point solution. The latter calculation receives sizable contributions from unphysical short modes and must be renormalized. We propose a new approach to renormalization by modeling the effective stress-energy tensor for short perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The catalog-to-cosmology framework for weak lensing and galaxy clustering for LSST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_catalog-to-cosmology_framework_for_weak_lensing_and_galaxy_clustering_for_lsst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_catalog-to-cosmology_framework_for_weak_lensing_and_galaxy_clustering_for_lsst/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Prat
We present TXPipe, a modular, automated and reproducible pipeline for generating data vectors in cosmology analyses. The pipeline is developed within the Rubin Observatory Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST) Dark Energy Science Collaboration (DESC), and designed for cosmology analyses using LSST data. In this paper, we present the pipeline for the so-called 3$\times$2pt analysis - a combination of three two-point functions that measure the auto- and cross-correlation between galaxy density and shapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25,000 optical fiber positioning robots for next-generation cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/25000_optical_fiber_positioning_robots_for_next-generation_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/25000_optical_fiber_positioning_robots_for_next-generation_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph H. Silber
Massively parallel multi-object spectrographs are on the leading edge of cosmology instrumentation. The highly successful Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI) which begun survey operations in May 2021, for example, has 5,000 robotically-actuated multimode fibers, which deliver light from thousands of individual galaxies and quasars simultaneously to an array of high-resolution spectrographs off-telescope. The redshifts are individually measured, thus providing 3D maps of the Universe in unprecedented detail, and enabling precise measurement of dark energy expansion and other key cosmological parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-redshift cosmological probes of helium reionization at the cosmic (fore)noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-redshift_cosmological_probes_of_helium_reionization_at_the_cosmic_forenoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-redshift_cosmological_probes_of_helium_reionization_at_the_cosmic_forenoon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Selim C. Hotinli
Joint analysis of CMB and large-scale structure at high redshifts provide new and unique windows into unexplored epochs of early structure formation. Here, we demonstrate how cosmic infrared background and high-redshift galaxies can be jointly analysed with CMB to probe the epoch of helium reionization ($2&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4$) on the light cone using kinetic Sunyaev Zel&amp;rsquo;dovich tomography. Characterising this epoch has great potential significance for understanding astrophysics of galaxy formation, quasar activity and formation of the super-massive black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Cosmological Principle with CatWISE Quasars: A Bayesian Analysis of the Number-Count Dipole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_cosmological_principle_with_catwise_quasars_a_bayesian_analysis_of_the_number-count_dipole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_cosmological_principle_with_catwise_quasars_a_bayesian_analysis_of_the_number-count_dipole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lawrence Dam
The Cosmological Principle, that the Universe is homogeneous and isotropic on sufficiently large scales, underpins the standard model of cosmology. However, a recent analysis of 1.36 million infrared-selected quasars has identified a significant tension in the amplitude of the number-count dipole compared to that derived from the CMB, thus challenging the Cosmological Principle. Here we present a Bayesian analysis of the same quasar sample, testing various hypotheses using the Bayesian evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voids fill us in on rising cosmology tensions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/voids_fill_us_in_on_rising_cosmology_tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/voids_fill_us_in_on_rising_cosmology_tensions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sofia Contarini
We investigate the main tensions within the current standard model of cosmology from the perspective of the void size function in BOSS DR12 data. For this purpose, we present the first cosmological constraints on the parameters $S_8\equiv \sigma_8\sqrt{\Omega_{\rm m}/0.3}$ and $H_0$ obtained from voids as a stand-alone probe. We rely on an extension of the popular volume-conserving model for the void size function, tailored to the application on data, including geometric and dynamic distortions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology with cosmic web environments II. Redshift-space auto and cross power spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_with_cosmic_web_environments_ii._redshift-space_auto_and_cross_power_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_with_cosmic_web_environments_ii._redshift-space_auto_and_cross_power_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tony Bonnaire
Degeneracies among parameters of the cosmological model are known to drastically limit the information contained in the matter distribution. In the first paper of this series, we shown that the cosmic web environments; namely the voids, walls, filaments and nodes; can be used as a leverage to improve the real-space constraints on a set of six cosmological parameters, including the summed neutrino mass. Following-upon these results, we propose to study the achievable constraints of environment-dependent power spectra in redshift space where the velocities add up information to the standard two-point statistics by breaking the isotropy of the matter density field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guess the cheese flavour by the size of its holes: A cosmological test using the abundance of Popcorn voids</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/guess_the_cheese_flavour_by_the_size_of_its_holes_a_cosmological_test_using_the_abundance_of_popcorn_voids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/guess_the_cheese_flavour_by_the_size_of_its_holes_a_cosmological_test_using_the_abundance_of_popcorn_voids/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dante J. Paz
We present a new definition of cosmic void and a publicly available code with the algorithm that implements it. In this void finder, underdense regions are defined as free-form objects, called popcorn voids, made from the union of spheres of maximum volume with a given joint integrated underdensity contrast. This provides, for the first time, a definition of a void in the matter field whose abundance can be faithfully reproduced by excursion set theory, in particular using the Vdn model without any adjustment or cleaning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning cosmology from void properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/machine_learning_cosmology_from_void_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/machine_learning_cosmology_from_void_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bonny Y. Wang
Cosmic voids are the largest and most underdense structures in the Universe. Their properties have been shown to encode precious information about the laws and constituents of the Universe. We show that machine learning techniques can unlock the information in void features for cosmological parameter inference. We rely on thousands of void catalogs from the GIGANTES dataset, where every catalog contains an average of 11,000 voids from a volume of $1~(h^{-1}{\rm Gpc})^3$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision cosmology with primordial GW backgrounds in presence of astrophysical foregrounds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/precision_cosmology_with_primordial_gw_backgrounds_in_presence_of_astrophysical_foregrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/precision_cosmology_with_primordial_gw_backgrounds_in_presence_of_astrophysical_foregrounds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Davide Racco
The era of Gravitational-Wave (GW) astronomy will grant the detection of the astrophysical GW background from unresolved mergers of binary black holes, and the prospect of probing the presence of primordial GW backgrounds. In particular, the low-frequency tail of the GW spectrum for causally-generated primordial signals (like a phase transition) offers an excellent opportunity to measure unambiguously cosmological parameters as the equation of state of the universe, or free-streaming particles at epochs well before recombination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propagating Uncertainties in the SALT3 Model Training Process to Cosmological Constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/propagating_uncertainties_in_the_salt3_model_training_process_to_cosmological_constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/propagating_uncertainties_in_the_salt3_model_training_process_to_cosmological_constraints/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Dai
Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are standardizable candles that must be modeled empirically to yield cosmological constraints. To understand the robustness of this modeling to variations in the model training procedure, we build an end-to-end pipeline to test the recently developed SALT3 model. We explore the consequences of removing pre-2000s low-$z$ or poorly calibrated $U$-band data, adjusting the amount and fidelity of SN Ia spectra, and using a model-independent framework to simulate the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Measurement of the CMB Temperature Power Spectrum and Constraints on Cosmology from the SPT-3G 2018 TT/TE/EE Data Set</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_measurement_of_the_cmb_temperature_power_spectrum_and_constraints_on_cosmology_from_the_spt-3g_2018_tt_te_ee_data_set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_measurement_of_the_cmb_temperature_power_spectrum_and_constraints_on_cosmology_from_the_spt-3g_2018_tt_te_ee_data_set/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Balkenhol
We present a sample-variance-limited measurement of the temperature power spectrum ($TT$) of the cosmic microwave background (CMB) using observations of a $\sim! 1500 ,\mathrm{deg}^2$ field made by SPT-3G in 2018. We report multifrequency power spectrum measurements at 95, 150, and 220GHz covering the angular multipole range $750 \leq \ell &amp;lt; 3000$. We combine this $TT$ measurement with the published polarization power spectrum measurements from the 2018 observing season and update their associated covariance matrix to complete the SPT-3G 2018 $TT/TE/EE$ data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the bispectrum from bouncing cosmologies with Planck</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_bispectrum_from_bouncing_cosmologies_with_planck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_bispectrum_from_bouncing_cosmologies_with_planck/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bartjan van Tent
Bouncing models of cosmology, as they arise e.g. in loop quantum cosmology, can generate close-to-scale-invariant fluctuation spectra as observed in the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB). However, they are typically not Gaussian and also generate a bispectrum. It was proposed that these models can help to mitigate the large-scale anomalies of the CMB by considering large non-Gaussianities on very large scales, which decay exponentially on sub-horizon scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Model Tests with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_model_tests_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_model_tests_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nikita Lovyagin
The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), which has recently become operational, is capable of detecting objects at record-breaking redshifts, $z \gtrsim 15$. This is a crucial advance for observational cosmology, as at these redshifts the differences between alternative cosmological models manifest themselves in the most obvious way. In recent years, some observational hints have emerged indicating that the Standard Cosmological Model could require correcting. One of these hints is related to the discovery of remote galaxies whose redshifts correspond to the very young Universe (less than one billion years after the Big Bang) but which are similar to nearby galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Cosmology with Double Source Lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_cosmology_with_double_source_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_cosmology_with_double_source_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Divij Sharma
Double source lensing provides a dimensionless ratio of distance ratios, a &amp;ldquo;remote viewing&amp;rdquo; of cosmology through distances relative to the gravitational lens, beyond the observer. We use this to test the cosmological framework, particularly with respect to spatial curvature and the distance duality relation. We derive a consistency equation for constant spatial curvature, allowing not only the investigation of flat vs curved but of the Friedmann-Lema^itre-Robertson-Walker framework itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of a Relativistic Jet Following the Disruption of a Star by a Cosmological Black Hole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_birth_of_a_relativistic_jet_following_the_disruption_of_a_star_by_a_cosmological_black_hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_birth_of_a_relativistic_jet_following_the_disruption_of_a_star_by_a_cosmological_black_hole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dheeraj R. Pasham
A black hole can launch a powerful relativistic jet after it tidally disrupts a star. If this jet fortuitously aligns with our line of sight, the overall brightness is Doppler boosted by several orders of magnitude. Consequently, such on-axis relativistic tidal disruption events (TDEs) have the potential to unveil cosmological (redshift $z&amp;gt;$1) quiescent black holes and are ideal test beds to understand the radiative mechanisms operating in super-Eddington jets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-noising non-Gaussian fields in cosmology with normalizing flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/de-noising_non-gaussian_fields_in_cosmology_with_normalizing_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/de-noising_non-gaussian_fields_in_cosmology_with_normalizing_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Rouhiainen
Fields in cosmology, such as the matter distribution, are observed by experiments up to experimental noise. The first step in cosmological data analysis is usually to de-noise the observed field using an analytic or simulation driven prior. On large enough scales, such fields are Gaussian, and the de-noising step is known as Wiener filtering. However, on smaller scales probed by upcoming experiments, a Gaussian prior is substantially sub-optimal because the true field distribution is very non-Gaussian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology from Galaxy Redshift Surveys with PointNet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_from_galaxy_redshift_surveys_with_pointnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_from_galaxy_redshift_surveys_with_pointnet/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sotiris Anagnostidis
In recent years, deep learning approaches have achieved state-of-the-art results in the analysis of point cloud data. In cosmology, galaxy redshift surveys resemble such a permutation invariant collection of positions in space. These surveys have so far mostly been analysed with two-point statistics, such as power spectra and correlation functions. The usage of these summary statistics is best justified on large scales, where the density field is linear and Gaussian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid: Modelling massive neutrinos in cosmology -- a code comparison</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_modelling_massive_neutrinos_in_cosmology_--_a_code_comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_modelling_massive_neutrinos_in_cosmology_--_a_code_comparison/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Adamek
The measurement of the absolute neutrino mass scale from cosmological large-scale clustering data is one of the key science goals of the Euclid mission. Such a measurement relies on precise modelling of the impact of neutrinos on structure formation, which can be studied with $N$-body simulations. Here we present the results from a major code comparison effort to establish the maturity and reliability of numerical methods for treating massive neutrinos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid: performance on main cosmological parameter science</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_performance_on_main_cosmological_parameter_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_performance_on_main_cosmological_parameter_science/</guid>
      <description>First author: Isaac Tutusaus
Euclid will observe 15 000 deg$^2$ of the darkest sky, in regions free of contamination by light from our Galaxy and our Solar System. Three &amp;ldquo;Euclid Deep Fields&amp;rdquo; surveys covering around 40 deg$^2$ in total will extend the scientific scope of the mission to the high-redshift Universe. The complete survey will be constituted by hundreds of thousands of images and several tens of petabytes of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tilt Instability in the Cosmological Principle</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_tilt_instability_in_the_cosmological_principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_tilt_instability_in_the_cosmological_principle/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chethan Krishnan
We show that the Friedmann-Lema^{i}tre-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) framework has an instability towards the growth of fluid flow anisotropies, even if the Universe is accelerating. This flow (tilt) instability in the matter sector is invisible to Cosmic No-Hair Theorem-like arguments, which typically only flag shear anisotropies in the metric. We illustrate our claims in the setting of ``dipole cosmology&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;, the maximally Copernican generalization of FLRW that can accommodate a flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lagrangian displacement field estimators in cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lagrangian_displacement_field_estimators_in_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lagrangian_displacement_field_estimators_in_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Atsuhisa Ota
The nonlinear Lagrangian displacement field and initial linear density field are highly correlated. Therefore, reconstructing the nonlinear displacement field could better extract the primordial cosmological information from the late time density field. Continuing from Ref. [1], we investigate to what extent the iterative displacement reconstruction in Ref. [2] can recover the true displacement field with a particular emphasis on improving the numerical discreteness effect and improving the perturbation theory model for the postreconstructed field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints on unimodular gravity models with diffusion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_on_unimodular_gravity_models_with_diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_on_unimodular_gravity_models_with_diffusion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Susana J. Landau
A discrete space-time structure lying at about the Planck scale may become manifest in the form of very small violations of the conservation of the matter energy-momentum tensor. In order to include such kind of violations, forbidden within the General Relativity framework, the theory of unimodular gravity seems as the simplest option to describe the gravitational interaction. In the cosmological context, a direct consequence of such violation of energy conservation might be heuristically viewed a &amp;ldquo;diffusion process of matter (both dark and ordinary)&amp;rdquo; into an effective dark energy term in Einstein&amp;rsquo;s equations, which leads under natural assumptions to an adequate estimate for the value of the cosmological constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fisher Forecasting for Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_fisher_forecasting_for_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_fisher_forecasting_for_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph Ryan
The planning and design of future experiments rely heavily on forecasting to assess the potential scientific value provided by a hypothetical set of measurements. The Fisher information matrix, due to its convenient properties and low computational cost, provides an especially useful forecasting tool. However, the Fisher matrix only provides a reasonable approximation to the true likelihood when data are nearly Gaussian distributed and observables have nearly linear dependence on the parameters of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating cosmological growth functions with B-Splines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_cosmological_growth_functions_with_b-splines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_cosmological_growth_functions_with_b-splines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ngai Pok Kwan
In the light of GPU accelerations, sequential operations such as solving ordinary differential equations can be bottlenecks for gradient evaluations and hinder potential speed gains. In this work, we focus on growth functions and their time derivatives in cosmological particle mesh simulations and show that these are the majority time cost when using gradient based inference algorithms. We propose to construct novel conditional B-spline emulators which directly learn an interpolating function for the growth factor as a function of time, conditioned on the cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic voids as cosmological laboratories</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_voids_as_cosmological_laboratories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_voids_as_cosmological_laboratories/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carlos Mauricio Correa
Cosmic voids are promising cosmological laboratories for studying the dark energy phenomenon and alternative gravity theories. They are receiving special attention nowadays in view of the new generation of galaxy spectroscopic surveys, which are covering an unprecedented volume and redshift range. There are two primary statistics in void studies: (i) the void size function, which characterises the abundance of voids, and (ii) the void-galaxy cross-correlation function, which contains information about the density and velocity fields in these regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Beam Variations on Power Spectrum Estimation for 21-cm Cosmology I: Simulations of Foreground Contamination for HERA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_beam_variations_on_power_spectrum_estimation_for_21-cm_cosmology_i_simulations_of_foreground_contamination_for_hera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_beam_variations_on_power_spectrum_estimation_for_21-cm_cosmology_i_simulations_of_foreground_contamination_for_hera/</guid>
      <description>First author: Honggeun Kim
Detecting cosmological signals from the Epoch of Reionization (EoR) requires high-precision calibration to isolate the cosmological signals from foreground emission. In radio interferometery, perturbed primary beams of antenna elements can disrupt the precise calibration, which results in contaminating the foreground-free region, or the EoR window, in the cylindrically averaged power spectrum. For Hydrogen Epoch of Reionization Array (HERA), we simulate and characterize the perturbed primary beams induced by feed motions such as axial, lateral, and tilting motions, above the 14-meter dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristic Functions for Cosmological Cross-Correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characteristic_functions_for_cosmological_cross-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characteristic_functions_for_cosmological_cross-correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick C. Breysse
We introduce a novel unbiased, cross-correlation estimator for the one-point statistics of cosmological random fields. One-point statistics are a useful tool for analysis of highly non-Gaussian density fields, while cross-correlations provide a powerful method for combining information from pairs of fields and separating them from noise and systematics. We derive a new Deconvolved Distribution Estimator that combines the useful properties of these two methods into one statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Cosmological Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/complementary_cosmological_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/complementary_cosmological_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gábor Rácz
Cosmic variance limits the accuracy of cosmological N-body simulations, introducing bias in statistics such as the power spectrum, halo mass function, or the cosmic shear. We provide new methods to measure and reduce the effect of cosmic variance in existing and new simulations. We run pairs of simulations using phase shifted initial conditions with matching amplitudes. We set the initial amplitudes of the Fourier modes to ensure that the average power spectrum of the pair is equal to the cosmic mean power spectrum from linear theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological inference from the EFTofLSS: the eBOSS QSO full-shape analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_inference_from_the_eftoflss_the_eboss_qso_full-shape_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_inference_from_the_eftoflss_the_eboss_qso_full-shape_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Théo Simon
We present cosmological results inferred from the effective-field theory (EFT) analysis of the full-shape of eBOSS quasars (QSO) power spectrum. We validate our analysis pipeline against simulations, and find overall good agreement between the analyses in Fourier and configuration space. Keeping the baryon abundance and the spectral tilt fixed, we reconstruct at $68%$ CL the fractional matter abundance $\Omega_m$, the reduced Hubble constant $h$, and the clustering amplitude $\sigma_8$, to respectively $\Omega_m=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting dark matter to dark radiation does not solve cosmological tensions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/converting_dark_matter_to_dark_radiation_does_not_solve_cosmological_tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/converting_dark_matter_to_dark_radiation_does_not_solve_cosmological_tensions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fiona McCarthy
Tensions between cosmological parameters (in particular the local expansion rate $H_0$ and the amplitude of matter clustering $S_8$) inferred from low-redshift data and data from the cosmic microwave background (CMB) and large-scale structure (LSS) experiments have inspired many extensions to the standard cosmological model, $\Lambda$CDM. Models which simultaneously lessen both tensions are of particular interest. We consider one scenario with the potential for such a resolution, in which some fraction of the dark matter has converted into dark radiation since the release of the CMB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dispersion measure of Fast Radio Bursts host galaxies: estimation from cosmological simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts_host_galaxies_estimation_from_cosmological_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts_host_galaxies_estimation_from_cosmological_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jian-Feng Mo
The dispersion measure(DM) of fast radio burst encodes important information such as its distance, properties of intervening medium. Based on simulations in the Illustris and IllustrisTNG projects, we analyze the DM of FRBs contributed by the interstellar medium and circumgalactic medium in the hosts, $\rm{DM_{host}}$. We explore two population models - tracing the star formation rate (SFR), and the stellar mass, i.e. young and old progenitors respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holographic energy density, dark energy sound speed, and tensions in cosmological parameters: $H_0$ and $S_8$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/holographic_energy_density_dark_energy_sound_speed_and_tensions_in_cosmological_parameters__h_0__and__s_8_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/holographic_energy_density_dark_energy_sound_speed_and_tensions_in_cosmological_parameters__h_0__and__s_8_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wilmar Cardona
Interesting discrepancies in cosmological parameters are challenging the success of the $\Lambda$CDM model. Direct measurements of the Hubble constant $H_0$ using Cepheid variables and supernovae turn out to be higher than inferred from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB). Weak galaxy lensing surveys consistently report values of the strength of matter clustering $\sigma_8$ lower than values derived from the CMB in the context of $\Lambda$CDM. In this paper we address these discrepancies in cosmological parameters by considering Dark Energy (DE) as a fluid with evolving equation of state $w_{\mathrm{de}}(z)$, constant sound speed squared $\hat{c}{\mathrm{s}}^{2}$, and vanishing anisotropic stress $\sigma$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super-resolution simulation of the Fuzzy Dark Matter cosmological model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/super-resolution_simulation_of_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_cosmological_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/super-resolution_simulation_of_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_cosmological_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Meris Sipp
AI super-resolution, combining deep learning and N-body simulations has been shown to successfully reproduce the large scale structure and halo abundances in the Lambda Cold Dark Matter cosmological model. Here, we extend its use to models with a different dark matter content, in this case Fuzzy Dark Matter (FDM), in the approximation that the difference is encoded in the initial power spectrum. We focus on redshift z = 2, with simulations that model smaller scales and lower masses, the latter by two orders of magnitude, than has been done in previous AI super-resolution work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Information in Skew Spectra of Biased Tracers in Redshift Space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_information_in_skew_spectra_of_biased_tracers_in_redshift_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_information_in_skew_spectra_of_biased_tracers_in_redshift_space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiamin Hou
Extracting the non-Gaussian information encoded in the higher-order clustering statistics of the large-scale structure is key to fully realizing the potential of upcoming galaxy surveys. We investigate the information content of the redshift-space {\it weighted skew spectra} of biased tracers as efficient estimators for 3-point clustering statistics. The skew spectra are constructed by correlating the observed galaxy field with an appropriately-weighted square of it. We perform numerical Fisher forecasts using two synthetic datasets; the halo catalogs from the Quijote N-body simulations and the galaxy catalogs from the Molino suite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cosmological Fireball with Sixteen-Percent Gamma-Ray Radiative Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_cosmological_fireball_with_sixteen-percent_gamma-ray_radiative_efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_cosmological_fireball_with_sixteen-percent_gamma-ray_radiative_efficiency/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liang Li
Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are the most powerful explosions in the universe. The standard model invokes a relativistic fireball with a bright photosphere emission component. How efficiently the jet converts its energy to radiation is a long-standing problem and it is poorly constrained. A definitive diagnosis of GRB radiation components and measurement of GRB radiative efficiency requires prompt emission and afterglow data with high-resolution and wide-band coverage in time and energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A General Framework for Removing Point Spread Function Additive Systematics in Cosmological Weak Lensing Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_general_framework_for_removing_point_spread_function_additive_systematics_in_cosmological_weak_lensing_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_general_framework_for_removing_point_spread_function_additive_systematics_in_cosmological_weak_lensing_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tianqing Zhang
Cosmological weak lensing measurements rely on a precise measurement of the shear two-point correlation function (2PCF) along with a deep understanding of systematics that affect it. In this work, we demonstrate a general framework for describing the impact of PSF systematics on the cosmic shear 2PCF, and mitigating its impact on cosmological analysis. Our framework can describe leakage and modeling error from all spin-2 quantities contributed by the PSF second and higher moments, rather than just the second moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A roadmap to cosmological parameter analysis with third-order shear statistics II: Analytic covariance estimate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_roadmap_to_cosmological_parameter_analysis_with_third-order_shear_statistics_ii_analytic_covariance_estimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_roadmap_to_cosmological_parameter_analysis_with_third-order_shear_statistics_ii_analytic_covariance_estimate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laila Linke
Third-order weak lensing statistics are a promising tool for cosmological analyses since they extract cosmological information in the non-Gaussianity of the cosmic large-scale structure. However, such analyses require precise and accurate models for the covariance. In this second paper of a series on third-order weak lensing statistics, we derive and validate an analytic model for the covariance of the third-order aperture statistics $\langle M_\mathrm{ap}^3\rangle$. We derive the covariance model from a real-space estimator for $\langle M_\mathrm{ap}^3\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Cosmological Tensions by Non-Local Gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/addressing_cosmological_tensions_by_non-local_gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/addressing_cosmological_tensions_by_non-local_gravity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Filippo Bouchè
Alternative cosmological models have been under deep scrutiny in recent years, aiming to address the main shortcomings of the $\Lambda$CDM model. Moreover, as the accuracy of cosmological surveys improved, new tensions have risen between the model-dependent analysis of the Cosmic Microwave Background and lower redshift probes. Within this framework, we review two quantum-inspired non-locally extended theories of gravity, whose main cosmological feature is a geometrically driven accelerated expansion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can high-redshift Hubble diagrams rule out the standard model of cosmology in the context of cosmographic method?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_high-redshift_hubble_diagrams_rule_out_the_standard_model_of_cosmology_in_the_context_of_cosmographic_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_high-redshift_hubble_diagrams_rule_out_the_standard_model_of_cosmology_in_the_context_of_cosmographic_method/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Pourojaghi
Using mock data for the Hubble diagrams of type Ia supernovae (SNIa) and quasars (QSOs) generated based on the standard model of cosmology, and using the least-squares method based on the Markov-Chain-Monte-Carlo (MCMC) algorithm, we first put constraints on the cosmographic parameters in the context of the various model-independent cosmographic methods reconstructed from the Taylor $4^{th}$ and $5^{th}$ order expansions and the Pade (2,2) and (3,2) polynomials of the Hubble parameter, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints from HSC survey first-year data using deep learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_hsc_survey_first-year_data_using_deep_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_hsc_survey_first-year_data_using_deep_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tianhuan Lu
We present cosmological constraints from the Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) first-year weak lensing shear catalogue using convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and conventional summary statistics. We crop 19 $3\times3,\mathrm{{deg}^2}$ sub-fields from the first-year area, divide the galaxies with redshift $0.3\le z\le1.5$ into four equally-spaced redshift bins, and perform tomographic analyses. We develop a pipeline to generate simulated convergence maps from cosmological $N$-body simulations, where we account for effects such as intrinsic alignments (IAs), baryons, photometric redshift errors, and point spread function errors, to match characteristics of the real catalogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints from the BOSS DR12 void size function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_the_boss_dr12_void_size_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_the_boss_dr12_void_size_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sofia Contarini
We present the first cosmological constraints derived from the analysis of the void size function. This work relies on the final BOSS DR12 data set, a large spectroscopic galaxy catalog, ideal for the identification of cosmic voids. We extract a sample of voids from the distribution of galaxies and we apply a cleaning procedure aimed at reaching high levels of purity and completeness. We model the void size function by means of an extension of the popular volume-conserving model, based on two additional nuisance parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f(T) cosmology against the cosmographic method: A new study using mock and observational data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ft_cosmology_against_the_cosmographic_method_a_new_study_using_mock_and_observational_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ft_cosmology_against_the_cosmographic_method_a_new_study_using_mock_and_observational_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Sabiee
In this paper, we study the power-law $f(T)$ model using Hubble diagrams of type Ia supernovae (SNIa), quasars (QSOs), Gamma Ray Bursts (GRBs) and the measurements from baryonic acoustic oscillations (BAO) in the framework of the cosmographic method. Using mock data for SNIa, QSOs and GRBs generated based on the power-law $f(T)$ model, we show whether different cosmographic methods are suitable to reconstruct the distance modulus or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From dark matter halos to pre-stellar cores: High resolution follow-up of cosmological Lyman-Werner simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_dark_matter_halos_to_pre-stellar_cores_high_resolution_follow-up_of_cosmological_lyman-werner_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_dark_matter_halos_to_pre-stellar_cores_high_resolution_follow-up_of_cosmological_lyman-werner_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lewis R. Prole
Molecular hydrogen allows cooling in primordial gas, facilitating its collapse into Population III stars within primordial halos. Lyman-Werner (LW) radiation from these stars can escape the halo and delay further star formation by destroying H$2$ in other halos. As cosmological simulations show that increasing the background LW field strength increases the average halo mass required for star formation, we perform follow-up simulations of selected halos to investigate the knock-on effects this has on the Population III IMF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-sky performance of new 90 GHz detectors for the Cosmology Large Angular Scale Surveyor (CLASS)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on-sky_performance_of_new_90_ghz_detectors_for_the_cosmology_large_angular_scale_surveyor_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on-sky_performance_of_new_90_ghz_detectors_for_the_cosmology_large_angular_scale_surveyor_class/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carolina Núñez
The Cosmology Large Angular Scale Surveyor (CLASS) is a polarization-sensitive telescope array located at an altitude of 5,200 m in the Chilean Atacama Desert and designed to measure the polarized Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) over large angular scales. The CLASS array is currently observing with three telescopes covering four frequency bands: one at 40 GHz (Q); one at 90 GHz (W1); and one dichroic system at 150/220 GHz (HF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The formation of the brightest cluster galaxy and intracluster light in cosmological N-body simulations with the Galaxy Replacement Technique</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_formation_of_the_brightest_cluster_galaxy_and_intracluster_light_in_cosmological_n-body_simulations_with_the_galaxy_replacement_technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_formation_of_the_brightest_cluster_galaxy_and_intracluster_light_in_cosmological_n-body_simulations_with_the_galaxy_replacement_technique/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyungwon Chun
We investigate the formation channels of the intracluster light (ICL) and the brightest cluster galaxy (BCG) in clusters at $z=0$. For this, we perform multi-resolution cosmological N-body simulations using the &amp;ldquo;Galaxy Replacement Technique&amp;rdquo; (GRT). We study the formation channels of the ICL and BCG as a function of distance from the cluster center and the dynamical state of the clusters at $z=0$. To do this, we trace back the stars of the ICL and BCG, and identify the stellar components in which they existed when they first fell into the clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The N5K Challenge: Non-Limber Integration for LSST Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_n5k_challenge_non-limber_integration_for_lsst_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_n5k_challenge_non-limber_integration_for_lsst_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. D. Leonard
The rapidly increasing statistical power of cosmological imaging surveys requires us to reassess the regime of validity for various approximations that accelerate the calculation of relevant theoretical predictions. In this paper, we present the results of the &amp;lsquo;N5K non-Limber integration challenge&amp;rsquo;, the goal of which was to quantify the performance of different approaches to calculating the angular power spectrum of galaxy number counts and cosmic shear data without invoking the so-called &amp;lsquo;Limber approximation&amp;rsquo;, in the context of the Rubin Observatory Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What it takes to solve the Hubble tension through modifications of cosmological recombination</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/what_it_takes_to_solve_the_hubble_tension_through_modifications_of_cosmological_recombination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/what_it_takes_to_solve_the_hubble_tension_through_modifications_of_cosmological_recombination/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nanoom Lee
We develop a novel general formalism allowing us to obtain values of the Hubble constant in agreement with late-time observables without degrading the fit to Cosmic Microwave Background data, considering perturbative modifications around a fiducial $\Lambda$CDM cosmology. Taking as proof-of-principle the case of a time-varying electron mass and fine structure constant, we demonstrate that a modified recombination can solve the Hubble tension and lower $S_8$ to match weak lensing measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
