<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chemical on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chemical on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Laboratory and astronomical discovery of magnesium dicarbide, MgC$_2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/laboratory_and_astronomical_discovery_of_magnesium_dicarbide_mgc__2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/laboratory_and_astronomical_discovery_of_magnesium_dicarbide_mgc__2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. B. Changala
We report the detection of magnesium dicarbide, MgC$_2$, in the laboratory at centimeter wavelengths and assign $^{24}$MgC$_2$, $^{25}$MgC$_2$, and $^{26}$MgC$_2$ to 14 unidentified lines in the radio spectrum of the circumstellar envelope of the evolved carbon star IRC+10216. The structure of MgC$_2$ is found to be T-shaped with a highly ionic bond between the metal atom and the C$_2$ unit, analogous to other dicarbides containing electropositive elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chemical Modelling Roadmap Linking Protoplanetary Disks and Exoplanet Atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_chemical_modelling_roadmap_linking_protoplanetary_disks_and_exoplanet_atmospheres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_chemical_modelling_roadmap_linking_protoplanetary_disks_and_exoplanet_atmospheres/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christian Eistrup
[Abridged] This review paper discussed which chemical effects may be at play in a planet-forming disk midplane, which effects are relevant under different conditions, and which tools are available for modelling chemical kinetics in a disk midplane. The review goes on to discuss some important efforts in the planet formation modelling community to treat chemical evolution, and, vice versa, efforts in the chemical modelling community to implement more physical effects related to planet formation into the chemical modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
