<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chemical on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chemical on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The physical and chemical processes in protoplanetary disks: constraints on the composition of comets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_and_chemical_processes_in_protoplanetary_disks_constraints_on_the_composition_of_comets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_and_chemical_processes_in_protoplanetary_disks_constraints_on_the_composition_of_comets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuri Aikawa
We review the recent observations of protoplanetary disks together with relevant theoretical studies with an emphasis on the evolution of volatiles. In the last several years Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) provided evidence of grain growth, gas-dust decoupling, and sub-structures such as rings and gaps in the dust continuum. Molecular line observations revealed radial and vertical distributions of molecular abundances and also provided significant constraints on the gas dynamics such as turbulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 3-Dimension Model of Volcanism Volatiles Contribution on Atmospheric Chemical Abundance of Habitable Planets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_3-dimension_model_of_volcanism_volatiles_contribution_on_atmospheric_chemical_abundance_of_habitable_planets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_3-dimension_model_of_volcanism_volatiles_contribution_on_atmospheric_chemical_abundance_of_habitable_planets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zihan Huang
The volcanism plays an important part in mass exchange circle to bring matter from core of planet to atmosphere. Thus, it is a possible method to research the change of elements abundance in atmosphere by modeling the process of volatiles from volcanism get through and mix in atmosphere, which is the focused point of this article. This article penetrates from the generation of volatiles, talks the species, mass, and mole fractions of different typical elements in magma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Formation and Chemical Enrichment in Protoclusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_and_chemical_enrichment_in_protoclusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_and_chemical_enrichment_in_protoclusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keita Fukushima
We examine star formation and chemical enrichment in protoclusters (PCs) using cosmological zoom-in hydrodynamic simulations. We find that the total star formation rate (SFR) in all PC ($&amp;gt;10^{14.4},h^{-1}$~M$\odot$) reaches $&amp;gt;10^4,\mathrm{M}\odot \mathrm{yr}^{-1}$, at $z=3$, equivalent to the observed PCs. The SFR in the Core region accounts for about $30%$ of the total star formation in the PC at $z\gtrsim1$, suggesting the importance of the outer regions to reveal the evolution of galaxy clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical modeling of Orion Nebula Cluster disks: evidence for massive, compact gas disks with ISM-like gas-to-dust ratios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_modeling_of_orion_nebula_cluster_disks_evidence_for_massive_compact_gas_disks_with_ism-like_gas-to-dust_ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_modeling_of_orion_nebula_cluster_disks_evidence_for_massive_compact_gas_disks_with_ism-like_gas-to-dust_ratios/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan D. Boyden
The stellar cluster environment is expected to play a central role in the evolution of circumstellar disks. We use thermochemical modeling to constrain the dust and gas masses, disk sizes, UV and X-ray radiation fields, viewing geometries, and central stellar masses of 20 Class II disks in the Orion Nebula Cluster (ONC). We fit a large grid of disk models to $350$ GHz continuum, CO $J=3-2$, and HCO$^+$ $J=4-3$ ALMA observations of each target, and we introduce a procedure for modeling interferometric observations of gas disks detected in absorption against a bright molecular cloud background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of Chemical Propellant Thruster to Deorbit Nano satellite: StudSat II</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/design_of_chemical_propellant_thruster_to_deorbit_nano_satellite_studsat_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/design_of_chemical_propellant_thruster_to_deorbit_nano_satellite_studsat_ii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Prabin Sherpaili
An increase in satellite application has skyrocketed the number of satellites, especially in the low earth orbit (LEO). The major concern today is that these satellites become debris after the end of life, negatively affecting the space environment. As per the International Guidelines of the European Space Agency, it is mandatory to deorbit the satellite within 25 years of its end of life. This paper is aimed to design the solid chemical propellant thruster to deorbit the StudSat II from its original orbit to the lower orbit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determination of the Cosmic-Ray Chemical Composition: Open Issues and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/determination_of_the_cosmic-ray_chemical_composition_open_issues_and_prospects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/determination_of_the_cosmic-ray_chemical_composition_open_issues_and_prospects/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. D. Supanitsky
Cosmic rays are relativistic particles that come to the Earth from outer space. Despite a great effort made in both experimental and theoretical research, their origin is still unknown. One of the main keys to understand their nature is the determination of its chemical composition as a function of primary energy. In this paper, we review the measurements of the mass composition above $10^{15}$ eV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking the dust and chemical evolution: Taurus and Perseus -- New collisional rates for HCN, HNC, and their C, N, and H isotopologues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/linking_the_dust_and_chemical_evolution_taurus_and_perseus_--_new_collisional_rates_for_hcn_hnc_and_their_c_n_and_h_isotopologues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/linking_the_dust_and_chemical_evolution_taurus_and_perseus_--_new_collisional_rates_for_hcn_hnc_and_their_c_n_and_h_isotopologues/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Navarro-Almaida
HCN, HNC, and their isotopologues are ubiquitous molecules that can serve as chemical thermometers and evolutionary tracers to characterize star-forming regions. Despite their importance in carrying information that is vital to studies of the chemistry and evolution of star-forming regions, the collision rates of some of these molecules have not been available for rigorous studies in the past. We perform an up-to-date gas and dust chemical characterization of two different star-forming regions, TMC 1-C and NGC 1333-C7, using new collisional rates of HCN, HNC, and their isotopologues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical abundances in the dwarf galaxy NGC 4163 based on the nebular and auroral emission lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_abundances_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4163_based_on_the_nebular_and_auroral_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_abundances_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4163_based_on_the_nebular_and_auroral_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. A. Zinchenko
We constructed an oxygen abundance map and N/O ratio map of the unusually low excitation dwarf irregular galaxy NGC 4163 based on publicly available spectroscopy obtained by the MaNGA survey. We detected auroral emission line [OII]$\lambda\lambda$7320,7330 which allows us to measure chemical abundance by direct T$_e$ method. We found that the scatter of the oxygen abundance derived by the strong line method is large. The oxygen abundances 12 + log(O/H) derived by strong line method vary from ~7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential contributions of Pop III and intermediate-mass Pop II stars to cosmic chemical enrichment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_contributions_of_pop_iii_and_intermediate-mass_pop_ii_stars_to_cosmic_chemical_enrichment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_contributions_of_pop_iii_and_intermediate-mass_pop_ii_stars_to_cosmic_chemical_enrichment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lia C. Corazza
We propose a semi-analytic model that is developed to understand the cosmological evolution of the mean metallicity in the Universe. In particular, we study the contributions of Population III (Pop III) and Population II (Pop II) stars to the production of $\mathrm{Fe,~Si,~Zn, ~Ni,~P, ~Mg, ~Al, ~S, ~C, ~N}$, and $\mathrm{~O}$. We aim to quantify the roles of two different models in the chemical enrichment of the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in chemical evolution between isolated and embedded prestellar cores</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/differences_in_chemical_evolution_between_isolated_and_embedded_prestellar_cores/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/differences_in_chemical_evolution_between_isolated_and_embedded_prestellar_cores/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. D. Priestley
Models of prestellar cores often assume that the cores are isolated from their environment - material outside the core boundary plays no role in the subsequent evolution. This is unlikely to be the case in reality, where cores are located within hierarchically substructured molecular clouds. We investigate the dynamical and chemical evolution of prestellar cores, modelled as Bonnor-Ebert spheres, and show that the density of the ambient medium has a large impact on the resulting chemical properties of the cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Galactic Chemical Evolution to Cosmic Supernova Rates Synchronized with Core-Collapse Supernovae Limited to the Narrow Progenitor Mass Range</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_galactic_chemical_evolution_to_cosmic_supernova_rates_synchronized_with_core-collapse_supernovae_limited_to_the_narrow_progenitor_mass_range/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_galactic_chemical_evolution_to_cosmic_supernova_rates_synchronized_with_core-collapse_supernovae_limited_to_the_narrow_progenitor_mass_range/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takuji Tsujimoto
Massive ($\geq$8 $M_\odot$) stars perish via one of two fates: core-collapse supernovae (CCSNe), which release synthesized heavy elements, or failed supernovae, thereby forming black holes. In the conventional Galactic chemical evolution (GCE) scheme, a substantial portion of massive stars, e.g., all stars in the mass range of 8-100 $M_{\odot},$ are assumed to enrich the Galaxy with their nucleosynthetic products. However, this hypothesis conflicts with the observations, namely, few CCSNe whose progenitor stars are more massive than $\sim$18 $M_{\odot}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution spectroscopic analysis of four new chemically peculiar stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectroscopic_analysis_of_four_new_chemically_peculiar_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectroscopic_analysis_of_four_new_chemically_peculiar_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. P. Roriz
We present detailed chemical compositions of four stars on the first-ascent red giant branch that are classified as chemically peculiar, but lack comprehensive analyses at high spectral resolution. For BD+03{\deg}2688, HE 0457-1805, HE 1255-2324, and HE 2207-1746, we derived metallicities [Fe/H] $=-1.21$, $-0.19$, $-0.31$, and $-0.55$, respectively, indicating a range in Galactic population membership. In addition to atmospheric parameters, we extracted elemental abundances for 28 elements, including the evolutionary-sensitive CNO group and $^{12}$C/$^{13}$C ratios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laboratory and astronomical discovery of magnesium dicarbide, MgC$_2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/laboratory_and_astronomical_discovery_of_magnesium_dicarbide_mgc__2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/laboratory_and_astronomical_discovery_of_magnesium_dicarbide_mgc__2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. B. Changala
We report the detection of magnesium dicarbide, MgC$_2$, in the laboratory at centimeter wavelengths and assign $^{24}$MgC$_2$, $^{25}$MgC$_2$, and $^{26}$MgC$_2$ to 14 unidentified lines in the radio spectrum of the circumstellar envelope of the evolved carbon star IRC+10216. The structure of MgC$_2$ is found to be T-shaped with a highly ionic bond between the metal atom and the C$_2$ unit, analogous to other dicarbides containing electropositive elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chemical Modelling Roadmap Linking Protoplanetary Disks and Exoplanet Atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_chemical_modelling_roadmap_linking_protoplanetary_disks_and_exoplanet_atmospheres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_chemical_modelling_roadmap_linking_protoplanetary_disks_and_exoplanet_atmospheres/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christian Eistrup
[Abridged] This review paper discussed which chemical effects may be at play in a planet-forming disk midplane, which effects are relevant under different conditions, and which tools are available for modelling chemical kinetics in a disk midplane. The review goes on to discuss some important efforts in the planet formation modelling community to treat chemical evolution, and, vice versa, efforts in the chemical modelling community to implement more physical effects related to planet formation into the chemical modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Analysis of the Chemical Compositions of Gaia-Enceladus/Sausage and Milky Way Satellites using APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_comparative_analysis_of_the_chemical_compositions_of_gaia-enceladus_sausage_and_milky_way_satellites_using_apogee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_comparative_analysis_of_the_chemical_compositions_of_gaia-enceladus_sausage_and_milky_way_satellites_using_apogee/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Fernandes
We use data from the 17th data release of the Apache Point Observatory Galactic Evolution Experiment (APOGEE 2) to contrast the chemical composition of the recently discovered Gaia Enceladus/Sausage system (GE/S) to those of ten Milky Way (MW) dwarf satellite galaxies: LMC, SMC, Bo&amp;quot;otes I, Carina, Draco, Fornax, Sagittarius, Sculptor, Sextans and Ursa Minor. Our main focus is on the distributions of the stellar populations of those systems in the $[Mg/Fe]$-$[Fe/H]$ and $[Mg/Mn]$-$[Al/Fe]$ planes, which are commonly employed in the literature for chemical diagnosis and where dwarf galaxies can be distinguished from in situ populations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
