<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SMBH on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/smbh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SMBH on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/smbh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy and precision of triaxial orbit models I: SMBH mass, stellar mass and dark-matter halo</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accuracy_and_precision_of_triaxial_orbit_models_i_smbh_mass_stellar_mass_and_dark-matter_halo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accuracy_and_precision_of_triaxial_orbit_models_i_smbh_mass_stellar_mass_and_dark-matter_halo/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Neureiter
We investigate the accuracy and precision of triaxial dynamical orbit models by fitting two dimensional mock observations of a realistic N-body merger simulation resembling a massive early-type galaxy with a supermassive black hole (SMBH). We show that we can reproduce the triaxial N-body merger remnant&amp;rsquo;s correct black hole mass, stellar mass-to-light ratio and total enclosed mass (inside the half-light radius) for several different tested orientations with an unprecedented accuracy of 5-10%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Reconstructed Images of Jets Launched by SANE Super-Eddington Accretion Flows Around SMBHs with the ngEHT</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_reconstructed_images_of_jets_launched_by_sane_super-eddington_accretion_flows_around_smbhs_with_the_ngeht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_reconstructed_images_of_jets_launched_by_sane_super-eddington_accretion_flows_around_smbhs_with_the_ngeht/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brandon Curd
Tidal disruption events (TDEs) around super massive black holes (SMBHs) are a potential laboratory to study super-Eddington accretion disks and sometimes result in powerful jets or outflows which may shine in the radio and sub millimeter bands. In this work, we model the thermal synchrotron emission of jets from general relativistic radiation magneto-hydrodynamics (GRRMHD) simulations of a BH accretion disk/jet system which assumes the TDE resulted in a magnetized accretion disk around a BH accreting at $\sim 12-25$ times the Eddington accretion rate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
