<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SMBH on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/smbh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SMBH on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/smbh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eccentricity to the rescue! Detecting Accelerating Eccentric Binaries in the LISA Band</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eccentricity_to_the_rescue_detecting_accelerating_eccentric_binaries_in_the_lisa_band/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eccentricity_to_the_rescue_detecting_accelerating_eccentric_binaries_in_the_lisa_band/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zeyuan Xuan
Many gravitational wave (GW) sources in the LISA band are expected to have non-negligible eccentricity. Furthermore, many of them can undergo acceleration because they reside in the presence of a tertiary. Here we develop analytical and numerical methods to quantify how the compact binary&amp;rsquo;s eccentricity enhances the detection of its peculiar acceleration. We show that the general relativistic precession pattern can disentangle the binary&amp;rsquo;s acceleration-induced frequency shift from the chirp-mass-induced frequency shift in GW template fitting, thus relaxing the signal-to-noise ratio requirement for distinguishing the acceleration by a factor of $10\sim100$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stars Crushed by Black Holes. III. Mild Compression of Radiative Stars by Supermassive Black Holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stars_crushed_by_black_holes._iii._mild_compression_of_radiative_stars_by_supermassive_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stars_crushed_by_black_holes._iii._mild_compression_of_radiative_stars_by_supermassive_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suman Kumar Kundu
A tidal disruption event (TDE) occurs when the gravitational field of a supermassive black hole (SMBH) destroys a star. For TDEs in which the star enters deep within the tidal radius, such that the ratio of the tidal radius to the pericenter distance $\beta$ satisfies $\beta \gg 1$, the star is tidally compressed and heated. It was predicted that the maximum density and temperature attained during deep TDEs scale as $\propto \beta^3$ and $\propto \beta^2$, respectively, and nuclear detonation triggered by $\beta \gtrsim 5$, but these predictions have been debated over the last four decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Past and Future of Mid-Infrared Studies of AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_past_and_future_of_mid-infrared_studies_of_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_past_and_future_of_mid-infrared_studies_of_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Sajina
Observational studies of AGN in the mid-infrared regime are crucial to our understanding of AGN and their role in the evolution of galaxies. Mid-IR-based selection of AGN is complementary to more traditional techniques allowing for a more complete census of AGN activity across cosmic time. Mid-IR observations including time variability and spatially resolved imaging have given us unique insights into the nature of the obscuring structures around AGN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
