<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>most recent update (Sat Mar 25 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-sat-mar-25-2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in most recent update (Sat Mar 25 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-sat-mar-25-2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of rotating massive stars with new hydrodynamic wind models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_massive_stars_with_new_hydrodynamic_wind_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_massive_stars_with_new_hydrodynamic_wind_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex Camilo Gormaz-Matamala
Mass loss due to line-driven winds is central to our understanding of the evolution of massive stars. We extend the evolution models introduced in Paper I, where the mass loss recipe is based on the simultaneous calculation of the wind hydrodynamics and the line-acceleration, by incorporating the effects of stellar rotation. We introduce a grid of self-consistent line-force parameters for a set of standard evolutionary tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A LOFAR sample of luminous compact sources coincident with nearby dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lofar_sample_of_luminous_compact_sources_coincident_with_nearby_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lofar_sample_of_luminous_compact_sources_coincident_with_nearby_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Vohl
The vast majority of extragalactic, compact continuum radio sources are associated with star formation or jets from (super)massive black holes and, as such, are more likely to be found in association with starburst galaxies or early type galaxies. Recently, two new populations of radio sources have been identified: (a) compact and persistent sources (PRS) associated with fast radio bursts (FRB) in dwarf galaxies and (b) compact sources in dwarf galaxies that could belong to the long-sought population of intermediate-mass black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A long-duration gamma-ray burst of dynamical origin from the nucleus of an ancient galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_long-duration_gamma-ray_burst_of_dynamical_origin_from_the_nucleus_of_an_ancient_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_long-duration_gamma-ray_burst_of_dynamical_origin_from_the_nucleus_of_an_ancient_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew J. Levan
The majority of long duration ($&amp;gt;2$ s) gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are believed to arise from the collapse of massive stars \cite{Hjorth+03}, with a small proportion created from the merger of compact objects. Most of these systems are likely formed via standard stellar evolution pathways. However, it has long been thought that a fraction of GRBs may instead be an outcome of dynamical interactions in dense environments, channels which could also contribute significantly to the samples of compact object mergers detected as gravitational wave sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sensitive Search for Supernova Emission Associated with the Extremely Energetic and Nearby GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sensitive_search_for_supernova_emission_associated_with_the_extremely_energetic_and_nearby_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sensitive_search_for_supernova_emission_associated_with_the_extremely_energetic_and_nearby_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gokul P. Srinivasaragavan
We report observations of the optical counterpart of the long gamma-ray burst (LGRB) GRB 221009A. Due to the extreme rarity of being both nearby ($z = 0.151$) and highly energetic ($E_{\gamma,\mathrm{iso}} \geq 10^{54}$ erg), GRB 221009A offers a unique opportunity to probe the connection between massive star core collapse and relativistic jet formation. Adopting a phenomenological power-law model for the afterglow and host galaxy estimates from high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging, we use Bayesian model comparison techniques to determine the likelihood of an associated SN contributing excess flux to the optical light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of invariance of dark matter halo surface density using multiwavelength mock galaxy catalogues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_invariance_of_dark_matter_halo_surface_density_using_multiwavelength_mock_galaxy_catalogues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_invariance_of_dark_matter_halo_surface_density_using_multiwavelength_mock_galaxy_catalogues/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gopika K.
A large number of observations have shown that the dark matter halo surface density, given by the product of halo core radius and core density is nearly constant for a diverse suite of galaxies. Although this invariance of the halo surface density is violated at galaxy cluster and group scales, it is still an open question on whether the aforementioned constancy on galactic scales can be explained within $\Lambda$CDM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulgeless disks, dark galaxies, inverted color gradients, and other expected phenomena at higher z. The chromatic surface brightness modulation (CMOD) effect</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bulgeless_disks_dark_galaxies_inverted_color_gradients_and_other_expected_phenomena_at_higher_z._the_chromatic_surface_brightness_modulation_cmod_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bulgeless_disks_dark_galaxies_inverted_color_gradients_and_other_expected_phenomena_at_higher_z._the_chromatic_surface_brightness_modulation_cmod_effect/</guid>
      <description>First author: Polychronis Papaderos
Since the k correction depends on the spectral energy distribution (SED) of a galaxy, any high-z galaxy with a spatially non-homogeneous SED will experience a spatially varying relative dimming or brightening in addition to the pure distance effect. The morphology of galaxies will therefore change with z. For instance, an early spiral galaxy observed in the V band would show a prominent bulge at z=0, whereas, if at z=1, the V filter probes the rest-frame near-UV where the bulge is faint and the disk relatively brighter, thus the galaxy may appear as bulgeless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining f(Q) Cosmology with Standard Sirens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_fq_cosmology_with_standard_sirens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_fq_cosmology_with_standard_sirens/</guid>
      <description>First author: José Ferreira
In this dissertation, we study two cosmological models based on $f(Q)$ gravity. We resort to mock catalogs of standard siren (SS) events to see whether data from future gravitational wave (GWs) observatories will be able to distinguish these models from $\Lambda$CDM. The first model is the most general $f(Q)$ formulation that replicates a $\Lambda$CDM background, with deviations appearing only at the perturbative level. It has one additional free parameter compared to $\Lambda$CDM, $\alpha$, which when set to zero falls back to $\Lambda$CDM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological studies with VLBI</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_studies_with_vlbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_studies_with_vlbi/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Spingola
Current cosmological controversies can be solved if a sufficient level of precision is achieved by observations. Future surveys with the next generation of telescopes will offer significantly improved depth and angular resolution with respect to existing observations, opening the so-called &amp;ldquo;era of precision cosmology&amp;rdquo;. But, that era can be considered already started at the radio wavelengths with Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI). In this paper, we give an overview on how VLBI is contributing to some open questions in contemporary cosmology by reaching simultaneously the largest distances and the smallest scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMPRESS. XII. Statistics on the Dynamics and Gas Mass Fraction of Extremely-Metal Poor Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/empress._xii._statistics_on_the_dynamics_and_gas_mass_fraction_of_extremely-metal_poor_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/empress._xii._statistics_on_the_dynamics_and_gas_mass_fraction_of_extremely-metal_poor_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yi Xu
We present demography of the dynamics and gas-mass fraction of 33 extremely metal-poor galaxies (EMPGs) with metallicities of $0.015-0.195~Z_\odot$ and low stellar masses of $10^4-10^8~M_\odot$ in the local universe. We conduct deep optical integral-field spectroscopy (IFS) for the low-mass EMPGs with the medium high resolution ($R=7500$) grism of the 8m-Subaru FOCAS IFU instrument by the EMPRESS 3D survey, and investigate H$\alpha$ emission of the EMPGs. Exploiting the resolution high enough for the low-mass galaxies, we derive gas dynamics with the H$\alpha$ lines by the fitting of 3-dimensional disk models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of binary stars in the early evolutionary phases of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_binary_stars_in_the_early_evolutionary_phases_of_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_binary_stars_in_the_early_evolutionary_phases_of_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexander R. Livernois
The dynamics of binary stars provides a unique avenue to gather insight into the study of the structure and dynamics of star clusters and galaxies. In this paper, we present the results of a set of $N$-body simulations aimed at exploring the evolution of binary stars during the early evolutionary phases of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies (UFD). In our simulations, we assume that the stellar component of the UFD is initially dynamically cold and evolves towards its final equilibrium after undergoing the violent relaxation phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRB 191019A: a short gamma-ray burst in disguise from the disk of an active galactic nucleus</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12935/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12935/</guid>
      <description>Davide Lazzati
Long and short gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), canonically separated at around 2 seconds duration, are associated with different progenitors: the collapse of a massive star and the merger of two compact objects, respectively. GRB 191019A was a long GRB ($T_{90}\sim64$ s). Despite the relatively small redshift z=0.248 and HST followup observations, an accompanying supernova was not detected. In addition, the host galaxy did not have significant star formation activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferring the progenitor mass-kinetic energy relation of stripped-envelope core-collapse supernovae from nebular spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_the_progenitor_mass-kinetic_energy_relation_of_stripped-envelope_core-collapse_supernovae_from_nebular_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_the_progenitor_mass-kinetic_energy_relation_of_stripped-envelope_core-collapse_supernovae_from_nebular_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qiliang Fang
The relation between the progenitor mass and the kinetic energy of the explosion is a key toward revealing the explosion mechanism of stripped-envelope (SE) core-collapse (CC) supernovae (SNe). Here, we present a method to derive this relation using the nebular spectra of SESNe, based on the correlation between the $[O~I]$/$[Ca~II]$, which is an indicator of the progenitor mass, and the width of $[O~I]$, which measures the expansion velocity of the oxygen-rich material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared galaxies detected by the Atacama Cosmology Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_galaxies_detected_by_the_atacama_cosmology_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_galaxies_detected_by_the_atacama_cosmology_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ece Kilerci
We report on 167 infrared (IR) galaxies selected by AKARI and IRAS and detected in the Atacama Cosmology Telescope (ACT) Data Release 5 (DR5) sky maps at the 98, 150 and 220 GHz frequency bands. Of these detections, 134 (80%) of the millimeter counterparts are first-time identifications with ACT. We expand the previous ACT extragalactic source catalogs, by including new 98 GHz detections and measurements from ACT DR5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhomogeneous Galactic Chemical Evolution: Modelling Ultra-Faint Dwarf Galaxies of the Large Magellanic Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_galactic_chemical_evolution_modelling_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_galactic_chemical_evolution_modelling_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan K. Alexander
Ultra-faint dwarf galaxies are among the oldest and most metal-poor galaxies in the cosmos, observed to contain no traces of gas at the present time and a high dark matter mass fraction. Understanding the chemical abundance dispersion in such extreme environments could shed light on the properties of the first generations of stars in the cosmos. We present a novel inhomogeneous chemical evolution model, i-GEtool, that we apply to two ultra-faint dwarf galaxies, Carina II (Car II) and Reticulum II (Ret II), which are satellites of the Large Magellanic Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing of materials in magnetised core-collapse supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mixing_of_materials_in_magnetised_core-collapse_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mixing_of_materials_in_magnetised_core-collapse_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Meyer D. M. -A.
Core-collapse supernova remnants are structures of the interstellar medium (ISM) left behind the explosive death of most massive stars (smaller or equal to 40 Mo). Since they result in the expansion of the supernova shock wave into the gaseous environment shaped by the star wind history, their morphology constitutes an insight into the past evolution of their progenitor star. Particularly, fast-moving massive stars can produce asymmetric core-collapse supernova remnants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleosynthesis in jet-driven and jet-associated supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_jet-driven_and_jet-associated_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_jet-driven_and_jet-associated_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Obergaulinger
In contrast to regular core-collapse supernovae, explosions of rapidly rotating massive stars can develop jets, fast collimated outflows directed along the rotational axis. Depending on the rate of rotation and the magnetic field strength before collapse as well as on possible mechanisms amplifying the magnetic field, such a core can explode magnetorotationally rather than via the standard supernova mechanism based on neutrino heating. This scenario can explain the highest kinetic energies observed in the class of hypernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar cluster formation in a Milky Way-sized galaxy at z&gt;4 -- II. A hybrid formation scenario for the nuclear star cluster and its connection to the nuclear stellar ring</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_cluster_formation_in_a_milky_way-sized_galaxy_at_z4_--_ii._a_hybrid_formation_scenario_for_the_nuclear_star_cluster_and_its_connection_to_the_nuclear_stellar_ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_cluster_formation_in_a_milky_way-sized_galaxy_at_z4_--_ii._a_hybrid_formation_scenario_for_the_nuclear_star_cluster_and_its_connection_to_the_nuclear_stellar_ring/</guid>
      <description>First author: Floor van Donkelaar
Nuclear star clusters (NSCs) are massive star clusters found in the innermost region of the majority of galaxies. While recent studies suggest that low-mass NSCs in dwarf galaxies form largely out of the merger of globular clusters and NSCs in massive galaxies have assembled most of their mass through central star formation, the formation channel of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s NSC is still uncertain. In this work, we use GigaEris, a very high resolution $N$-body hydrodynamical cosmological zoom-in&#39;&#39; simulation, to investigate NSC formation in the progenitor of a Milky Way-sized galaxy, as well as its relation to the assembly and evolution of the galactic nuclear region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The formation of globular clusters with top-heavy initial mass functions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12405/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12405/</guid>
      <description>Hajime Fukushima
We study the formation of globular clusters in massive compact clouds with the low-metallicity of $Z=10^{-3}~Z_{\odot}$ by performing three-dimensional radiative-hydrodynamics simulations. Considering the uncertainty of the initial mass function (IMF) of stars formed in low-metallicity and high-density clouds, we investigate the impacts of the IMF on the cloud condition for the GC formation with the range of the power-law index of IMF as $γ= 1-2.35$. We find that the threshold surface density ($Σ_{\rm thr}$) for the GC formation increases from $800~M_{\odot} \; {\rm pc^{-2}}$ at $γ= 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of AGN-driven winds on physical and observable galaxy sizes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_agn-driven_winds_on_physical_and_observable_galaxy_sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_agn-driven_winds_on_physical_and_observable_galaxy_sizes/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. K. Cochrane
Without AGN feedback, simulated massive, star-forming galaxies become too compact relative to observed galaxies at z&amp;lt;2. In this paper, we perform high-resolution re-simulations of a massive (M*~10^11M_sol) galaxy at z~2, drawn from the FIRE project. In the simulation without AGN feedback, the galaxy experiences a rapid starburst and shrinking of its half-mass radius at z~2.3. In this paper, we experiment with driving mechanical AGN winds using a state-of-the-art hyper-Lagrangian refinement technique to increase particle resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the geometry of the hot X-ray corona in the Seyfert galaxy NGC4151 with IXPE</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/uncovering_the_geometry_of_the_hot_x-ray_corona_in_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc4151_with_ixpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/uncovering_the_geometry_of_the_hot_x-ray_corona_in_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc4151_with_ixpe/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. E. Gianolli
We present an X-ray spectro-polarimetric analysis of the bright Seyfert galaxy NGC4151. The source has been observed with the Imaging X-ray Polarimetry Explorer (IXPE) for 700 ks, complemented with simultaneous XMM-Newton (50 ks) and NuSTAR (100 ks) pointings. A polarization degree ${\Pi} = 4.9 {\pm} 1.1 %$ and angle ${\Psi}= 86{\deg} {\pm} 7{\deg}$ east of north ($68%$ confidence level) are measured in the 2-8 keV energy range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Radiation-Hydrodynamic Simulations Resolving Interior of Rapidly Accreting Primordial Protostar</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation-hydrodynamic_simulations_resolving_interior_of_rapidly_accreting_primordial_protostar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation-hydrodynamic_simulations_resolving_interior_of_rapidly_accreting_primordial_protostar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kazutaka Kimura
Direct collapse of supermassive stars is a possible pathway to form supermassive black hole seeds at high redshifts. Whereas previous three-dimensional (3D) simulations demonstrate that supermassive stars form via rapid mass accretion, those resolving the stellar interior have been limited. We here report 3D radiation-hydrodynamic (RHD) simulations following the evolution of rapidly accreting protostars resolving the stellar interior. We use an adaptive mesh refinement code with our newly developed RHD solver employing an explicit M1 closure method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barrow nearly-extensive Gibbs-like entropy favoured by the full dynamical and geometrical data set in cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/barrow_nearly-extensive_gibbs-like_entropy_favoured_by_the_full_dynamical_and_geometrical_data_set_in_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/barrow_nearly-extensive_gibbs-like_entropy_favoured_by_the_full_dynamical_and_geometrical_data_set_in_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tomasz Denkiewicz
We apply the full set of most update dynamical and geometrical data in cosmology to the nonextensive Barrow entropic holographic dark energy. We show that the data point towards an extensive Gibbs-like entropic behaviour for the cosmological horizons, which is the extreme case of the Barrow entropy, with the entropy parameter being $\Delta &amp;gt; 0.86$, close to the maximum threshold of $\Delta =1$ where the fractal dimension of the area-horizon becomes almost or just the volume and the intensivity is recovered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzard to Cardinal: Improved Mock Catalogs for Large Galaxy Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/buzzard_to_cardinal_improved_mock_catalogs_for_large_galaxy_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/buzzard_to_cardinal_improved_mock_catalogs_for_large_galaxy_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chun-Hao To
We present the Cardinal mock galaxy catalogs, a new version of the Buzzard simulation that has been updated to support ongoing and future cosmological surveys, including DES, DESI, and LSST. These catalogs are based on a one-quarter sky simulation populated with galaxies out to a redshift of $z=2.35$ to a depth of $m_{\rm{r}}=27$. Compared to the Buzzard mocks, the Cardinal mocks include an updated subhalo abundance matching (SHAM) model that considers orphan galaxies and includes mass-dependent scatter between galaxy luminosity and halo properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Polarized Radiative Transfer Codes used by the EHT Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12004/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12004/</guid>
      <description>Ben S. Prather
Interpretation of resolved polarized images of black holes by the Event Horizon Telescope (EHT) requires predictions of the polarized emission observable by an Earth-based instrument for a particular model of the black hole accretion system. Such predictions are generated by general relativistic radiative transfer (GRRT) codes, which integrate the equations of polarized radiative transfer in curved spacetime. A selection of ray-tracing GRRT codes used within the EHT collaboration is evaluated for accuracy and consistency in producing a selection of test images, demonstrating that the various methods and implementations of radiative transfer calculations are highly consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating radiation transport on cosmological scale using a denoising Unet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_radiation_transport_on_cosmological_scale_using_a_denoising_unet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_radiation_transport_on_cosmological_scale_using_a_denoising_unet/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mosima P. Masipa
Semi-numerical simulations are the leading candidates for evolving reionization on cosmological scales. These semi-numerical models are efficient in generating large-scale maps of the 21cm signal, but they are too slow to enable inference at the field level. We present different strategies to train a U-Net to accelerate these simulations. We derive the ionization field directly from the initial density field without using the ionizing sources&amp;rsquo; location, and hence emulating the radiative transfer process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical Evolution of Black-Hole Binaries Embedded in AGN Discs: III. The Effects of Viscosity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_evolution_of_black-hole_binaries_embedded_in_agn_discs_iii._the_effects_of_viscosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_evolution_of_black-hole_binaries_embedded_in_agn_discs_iii._the_effects_of_viscosity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rixin Li
Stellar-mass binary black holes (BBHs) embedded in active galactic nucleus (AGN) discs offer a distinct dynamical channel to produce black hole mergers detected in gravitational waves by LIGO/Virgo. To understand their orbital evolution through interactions with the disc gas, we perform a suite of 2D high-resolution, local shearing box, viscous hydrodynamical simulations of equal-mass binaries. We find that viscosity not only smooths the flow structure around prograde circular binaries, but also greatly raises their accretion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of a small X-ray flaring event in NLS1 galaxy NGC 4051</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigation_of_a_small_x-ray_flaring_event_in_nls1_galaxy_ngc_4051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigation_of_a_small_x-ray_flaring_event_in_nls1_galaxy_ngc_4051/</guid>
      <description>First author: Neeraj Kumari
We performed a detailed broadband spectral and timing analysis of a small flaring event of ~120 ks in a narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy NGC 4051 using simultaneous XMM-Newton and NuSTAR observations. The ~300 ks long NuSTAR observation and the overlapping XMM-Newton exposure were segregated into pre-flare, flare, and post-flare segments. During the flare, the NuSTAR count rate peaked at 2.5 times the mean count rate before the flare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST/NIRSpec First Census of Broad-Line AGNs at z=4-7: Detection of 10 Faint AGNs with M_BH~10^6-10^7 M_sun and Their Host Galaxy Properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_first_census_of_broad-line_agns_at_z4-7_detection_of_10_faint_agns_with_m_bh~106-107_m_sun_and_their_host_galaxy_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_first_census_of_broad-line_agns_at_z4-7_detection_of_10_faint_agns_with_m_bh~106-107_m_sun_and_their_host_galaxy_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuichi Harikane
We present a first statistical sample of faint type-1 AGNs at $z&amp;gt;4$ identified by JWST/NIRSpec deep spectroscopy. Among the 185 galaxies at $z_\mathrm{spec}=3.8-8.9$ confirmed with NIRSpec, our systematic search for broad-line emission reveals 10 type-1 AGNs at $z=4.015-6.936$ whose broad component is only seen in the permitted H$\alpha$ line and not in the forbidden $[OIII]$$\lambda$5007 line that is detected with greater significance than H$\alpha$. The broad H$\alpha$ line widths of $\mathrm{FWHM}\simeq1000-6000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for FRB persistent radio source counterparts in dwarf galaxies using LOFAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_frb_persistent_radio_source_counterparts_in_dwarf_galaxies_using_lofar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_frb_persistent_radio_source_counterparts_in_dwarf_galaxies_using_lofar/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Vohl
The repeating FRB 20121102A was localized to a star-forming region in a dwarf galaxy and found to be co-located with a persistent radio source (PRS). FRB 20190520B is only the second known source sharing phenomenology akin to FRB 20121102A&amp;rsquo;s, with similar burst activity, host galaxy properties, as well as being associated with a PRS. PRS emission is potentially a calorimeter, allowing us to estimate the energy output of the central FRB engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 300 parsec resolution imaging of a z = 8.31 galaxy: Turbulent ionized gas and potential stellar feedback 600 million years after the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_300_parsec_resolution_imaging_of_a_z__8.31_galaxy_turbulent_ionized_gas_and_potential_stellar_feedback_600_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_300_parsec_resolution_imaging_of_a_z__8.31_galaxy_turbulent_ionized_gas_and_potential_stellar_feedback_600_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yoichi Tamura
We present the results of 300 pc resolution ALMA imaging of the $[OIII]$ 88 $\mu$m line and dust continuum emission from a $z = 8.312$ Lyman break galaxy MACS0416_Y1. The velocity-integrated $[OIII]$ emission has three peaks which are likely associated with three young stellar clumps of MACS0416_Y1, while the channel map shows a complicated velocity structure with little indication of a global velocity gradient unlike what was found in $[CII]$ 158 $\mu$m at a larger scale, suggesting random bulk motion of ionized gas clouds inside the galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gas Mass Reservoir of Quiescent Galaxies at Cosmic Noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gas_mass_reservoir_of_quiescent_galaxies_at_cosmic_noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gas_mass_reservoir_of_quiescent_galaxies_at_cosmic_noon/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Blánquez-Sesé
We present a 1.1mm stacking analysis of moderately massive (log($M_{}$/$M_{\odot}$) = 10.7 $\pm$ 0.2) quiescent galaxies (QGs) at $\langle z\rangle \sim1.5$, searching for cold dust continuum emission, an excellent tracer of dust and gas mass. Using both the recent GOODS-ALMA survey as well as the full suite of ALMA Band-6 ancillary data in the GOODS-S field, we report the tentative detection of dust continuum equivalent of dust mass log($M_{dust}$/$M_{\odot}$) = 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interplay between radio AGN activity and their host galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_radio_agn_activity_and_their_host_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_radio_agn_activity_and_their_host_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guilherme S. Couto
Radio activity in AGN (Active Galactic Nuclei) produce feedback on the host galaxy via the impact of the relativistic jets on the circumnuclear gas. Although radio jets can reach up to several times the optical radius of the host galaxy, in this review we focus on the observation of the feedback deposited locally in the central region of the host galaxies, in the form of outflows due to the jet-gas interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIMP cross-section limits from LOFAR observations of dwarf spheroidal galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wimp_cross-section_limits_from_lofar_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wimp_cross-section_limits_from_lofar_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Gajović
Weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs) can self-annihilate and thus provide us with the possibility for an indirect detection of Dark Matter (DM). Dwarf spheroidal (dSph) galaxies are excellent places to search for annihilation signals because they are rich in DM and background emission is low. If magnetic fields in dSph exist, the particles produced in DM annihilation emit synchrotron radiation. We use the non-detection of 150 MHz radio continuum emission from dSph galaxies with the LOw Frequency ARray (LOFAR) to derive constraints on the annihilation cross-section of WIMPs into electron-positron pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Approach To The Halo-Galaxy-SMBH Connection Through Cosmic Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_approach_to_the_halo-galaxy-smbh_connection_through_cosmic_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_approach_to_the_halo-galaxy-smbh_connection_through_cosmic_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher Boettner
We study the co-evolution of dark matter halos, galaxies and supermassive black holes using an empirical galaxy evolution model from $z=0$ &amp;ndash; $10$. We demonstrate that by connecting dark matter structure evolution with simple empirical prescriptions for baryonic processes, we are able to faithfully reproduce key observations in the relation between galaxies and their supermassive black holes. By assuming a physically-motivated, direct relationship between the galaxy and supermassive black hole properties to the mass of their host halo, we construct expressions for the galaxy stellar mass function, galaxy UV luminosity function, active black hole mass function and quasar bolometric luminosity function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A JWST/NIRSpec Exploration of the Connection between Ionization Parameter, Electron Density, and Star-Formation-Rate Surface Density in z=2.7-6.3 Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_nirspec_exploration_of_the_connection_between_ionization_parameter_electron_density_and_star-formation-rate_surface_density_in_z2.7-6.3_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_nirspec_exploration_of_the_connection_between_ionization_parameter_electron_density_and_star-formation-rate_surface_density_in_z2.7-6.3_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Naveen A. Reddy
We conduct a statistical analysis of the factors responsible for the variation in the ionization parameter (U) of high-redshift star-forming galaxies based on medium resolution JWST/NIRSpec observations obtained by the Cosmic Evolution Early Release Science (CEERS) survey. The sample consists of 48 galaxies with spectroscopic redshifts z=2.7-6.3 which are largely representative of typical star-forming galaxies at these redshifts. The $[SII]$ 6718, 6733 doublet is used to estimate electron densities (n_e), and dust-corrected Ha luminosities are used to compute total ionizing photon rates (Q).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trail of the Invisible: Blue Globular Clusters Trace the Radial Density Distribution of the Dark Matter -- Case Study of NGC 4278</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02292/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02292/</guid>
      <description>Matthias Kluge
We present new, deep optical observations of the early-type galaxy NGC 4278, which is located in a small loose group. We find that the galaxy lacks fine substructure, i.e., it appears relaxed, out to a radius of $\sim$70 kpc. Our $g$- and $i$-band surface brightness profiles are uniform down to our deepest levels of $\sim$28 mag arcsec$^{-2}$. This spans an extremely large radial range of more than 14 half-mass radii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A young white dwarf orbiting PSR J1835-3259B in the bulge globular cluster NGC 6652</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11263/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11263/</guid>
      <description>J. Chen
We report on the discovery of the companion star to the millisecond pulsar PSR J1835-3259B in the Galactic globular cluster NGC 6652. Taking advantage of deep photometric archival observations acquired through the Hubble Space Telescope in near-ultraviolet and optical bands, we identified a bright and blue object at a position compatible with that of the radio pulsar. The companion is located along the helium-core white dwarf cooling sequence and the comparison with binary evolution models provides a mass of $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An extremely compact, low-mass post-starburst galaxy at $z=5.2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extremely_compact_low-mass_post-starburst_galaxy_at__z5.2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extremely_compact_low-mass_post-starburst_galaxy_at__z5.2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Victoria Strait
We report the discovery of a low-mass $z=5.200\pm 0.002$ galaxy that is in the process of ceasing its star formation. The galaxy, MACS0417-z5PSB, is multiply imaged with magnification factors $\sim40$ by the galaxy cluster MACS J0417.5-1154, observed as part of the CAnadian NIRISS Unbiased Cluster Survey (CANUCS). Using observations of MACS0417-z5PSB with a JWST/NIRSpec Prism spectrum and NIRCam imaging, we investigate the mechanism responsible for the cessation of star formation of the galaxy, and speculate about possibilities for its future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Symmetric Objects: A Distinct Population of Jetted Active Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/compact_symmetric_objects_a_distinct_population_of_jetted_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/compact_symmetric_objects_a_distinct_population_of_jetted_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Kiehlmann
Compact Symmetric Objects (CSOs) are a class of compact, jetted Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) whose jet axes are not aligned close to the line of sight, and whose observed emission is not predominantly relativistically boosted towards us. Using complete samples of CSOs, we present three independent lines of evidence, based on their relative numbers, their redshift distributions, and their size distributions, which show conclusively that most CSOs do not evolve into larger-scale radio sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeMMINGs. V. Nuclear activity and bulge properties: a detailed multi-component decomposition of $e$-MERLIN Palomar galaxies with $HST$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lemmings._v._nuclear_activity_and_bulge_properties_a_detailed_multi-component_decomposition_of__e_-merlin_palomar_galaxies_with__hst_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lemmings._v._nuclear_activity_and_bulge_properties_a_detailed_multi-component_decomposition_of__e_-merlin_palomar_galaxies_with__hst_/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. T. Dullo
We use high-resolution $HST$ imaging and $e$-MERLIN 1.5-GHz observations of galaxy cores from the LeMMINGs survey to investigate the relation between optical structural properties and nuclear radio emission for a large sample of galaxies. We perform accurate, multi-component decompositions of new surface brightness profiles extracted from $HST$ images for 163 LeMMINGs galaxies and fit up to six galaxy components (e.g., bulges, discs, AGN, bars, rings, spiral arms, and nuclear star clusters) simultaneously with S&#39;ersic and/or core-S&#39;ersic models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Metallicity Relationship of SDSS Star Forming Galaxies: Population Synthesis Analysis and Effects of Star Burst Length, Extinction Law, Initial Mass Function and Star Formation Rate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_metallicity_relationship_of_sdss_star_forming_galaxies_population_synthesis_analysis_and_effects_of_star_burst_length_extinction_law_initial_mass_function_and_star_formation_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_metallicity_relationship_of_sdss_star_forming_galaxies_population_synthesis_analysis_and_effects_of_star_burst_length_extinction_law_initial_mass_function_and_star_formation_rate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eva Sextl
We investigate the mass-metallicity relationship of star forming galaxies by analysing the absorption line spectra of $\sim$200,000 galaxies in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. The galaxy spectra are stacked in bins of stellar mass and a population synthesis technique is applied yielding metallicities, ages and star formation history of the young and old stellar population together with interstellar reddening and extinction. We adopt different lengths of the initial starbursts and different initial mass functions for the calculation of model spectra of the single stellar populations contributing to the total integrated spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Reionization-Era Globular Cluster in Low-Mass Galaxy Eridanus II</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11348/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11348/</guid>
      <description>Daniel R. Weisz
Using color-magnitude diagrams from deep archival Hubble Space Telescope imaging, we self-consistently measure the star formation history of Eridanus II (Eri II), the lowest-mass galaxy ($M_{\star}(z=0) \sim 10^5 M_{\odot}$) known to host a globular cluster (GC), and the age, mass, and metallicity of its GC. The GC ($\sim13.2\pm0.4$ Gyr, $\langle[Fe/H]\rangle = -2.75\pm0.2$ dex) and field (mean age $\sim13.5\pm0.3$ Gyr, $\langle[Fe/H]\rangle = -2.6\pm0.15$ dex) have similar ages and metallicities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio and infrared study of the supernova remnant candidate HESS J1912&#43;101</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_infrared_study_of_the_supernova_remnant_candidate_hess_j1912&#43;101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_infrared_study_of_the_supernova_remnant_candidate_hess_j1912&#43;101/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Duvidovich
Aims: We provide new insights into the gamma-ray emission from HESS J1912+101, a TeV supernova remnant candidate probably associated with the radio pulsar PSR J1913+1011. Methods: We obtained new observations at 1.5 GHz using the VLA in the D configuration, with the purpose of detecting the radio shell of the putative remnant. In addition, we observed a single pointing at 6.0 GHz toward PSR J1913+1011 to look for a radio pulsar wind nebula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-lived radioisotope enrichment in star-forming regions from stellar winds and supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radioisotope_enrichment_in_star-forming_regions_from_stellar_winds_and_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radioisotope_enrichment_in_star-forming_regions_from_stellar_winds_and_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Richard J. Parker
The abundance of the short-lived radioisotopes 26-Al and 60-Fe in the early Solar system is usually explained by the Sun either forming from pre-enriched material, or the Sun&amp;rsquo;s protosolar disc being polluted by a nearby supernova explosion from a massive star. Both hypotheses suffer from significant drawbacks: the former does not account for the dynamical evolution of star-forming regions, while in the latter the time for massive stars to explode as supernovae can be similar to, or even longer than, the lifetime of protoplanetary discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical anisotropy in galaxy ellipticity correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_anisotropy_in_galaxy_ellipticity_correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_anisotropy_in_galaxy_ellipticity_correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maresuke Shiraishi
As well as the galaxy number density and peculiar velocity, the galaxy intrinsic alignment can be used to test the cosmic isotropy. We study distinctive impacts of the isotropy breaking on the configuration-space two-point correlation functions (2PCFs) composed of the spin-2 galaxy ellipticity field. For this purpose, we build a methodology to efficiently compute general types of the isotropy-violating 2PCFs by generalizing the polypolar spherical harmonic decomposition approach to the spin-weighted version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bar rotation rate as a diagnostic of dark matter content in the centre of disc galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_bar_rotation_rate_as_a_diagnostic_of_dark_matter_content_in_the_centre_of_disc_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_bar_rotation_rate_as_a_diagnostic_of_dark_matter_content_in_the_centre_of_disc_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Buttitta
We investigate the link between the bar rotation rate and dark matter content in barred galaxies by concentrating on the cases of the lenticular galaxies NGC4264 and NGC4277. These two gas-poor galaxies have similar morphologies, sizes, and luminosities. But, NGC4264 hosts a fast bar, which extends to nearly the corotation, while the bar embedded in NGC4277 is slow and falls short of corotation. We derive the fraction of dark matter $f_{\rm DM, bar}$ within the bar region from Jeans axisymmetric dynamical models by matching the stellar kinematics obtained with the MUSE integral-field spectrograph and using SDSS images to recover the stellar mass distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The massive relic galaxy NGC 1277 is dark matter deficient. From dynamical models of integral-field stellar kinematics out to five effective radii</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_massive_relic_galaxy_ngc_1277_is_dark_matter_deficient._from_dynamical_models_of_integral-field_stellar_kinematics_out_to_five_effective_radii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_massive_relic_galaxy_ngc_1277_is_dark_matter_deficient._from_dynamical_models_of_integral-field_stellar_kinematics_out_to_five_effective_radii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sébastien Comerón
According to the $\Lambda$CDM cosmology, present-day massive galaxies should contain a sizable fraction of dark matter within their stellar body. Models indicate that in massive early-type galaxies (ETGs) with $M_\star\approx1.5\times10^{11},{\rm M}\odot$ dark matter should account for $\sim60%$ of the dynamical mass within five effective radii ($5,R{\rm e}$). Most massive ETGs have been shaped through a two-phase process: the rapid growth of a compact core was followed by the accretion of an extended envelope through mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrophysical and Cosmological Searches for Lorentz Invariance Violation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/astrophysical_and_cosmological_searches_for_lorentz_invariance_violation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/astrophysical_and_cosmological_searches_for_lorentz_invariance_violation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shantanu Desai
Lorentz invariance is one of the fundamental tenets of Special Relativity, and has been extensively tested with laboratory and astrophysical observations. However, many quantum gravity models and theories beyond the Standard Model of Particle Physics predict a violation of Lorentz invariance at energies close to Planck scale. This article reviews observational and experimental tests of Lorentz invariance violation (LIV) with photons, neutrinos and gravitational waves. Most astrophysical tests of LIV using photons are based on searching for a correlation of the spectral lag data with redshift and energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints with the linear point from the BOSS survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_with_the_linear_point_from_the_boss_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_with_the_linear_point_from_the_boss_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mengfan He
The {\it Linear Point} (LP), defined as the midpoint between the BAO peak and the associated left dip of the two-point correlation function (2PCF), $\xi(s)$, is proposed as a new standard ruler which is insensitive to nonlinear effects. In this paper, we use a Bayesian sampler to measure the LP and estimate the corresponding statistical uncertainty, and then perform cosmological parameter constraints with LP measurements. Using the Patchy mock catalogues, we find that the measured LPs are consistent with theoretical predictions at 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark siren cosmology with binary black holes in the era of third-generation gravitational wave detectors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_siren_cosmology_with_binary_black_holes_in_the_era_of_third-generation_gravitational_wave_detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_siren_cosmology_with_binary_black_holes_in_the_era_of_third-generation_gravitational_wave_detectors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Niccolò Muttoni
Third-generation (3G) gravitational wave detectors, in particular Einstein Telescope (ET) and Cosmic Explorer (CE), will explore unprecedented cosmic volumes in search for compact binary mergers, providing us with tens of thousands of detections per year. In this study, we simulate and employ binary black holes detected by 3G interferometers as dark sirens, to extract and infer cosmological parameters by cross-matching gravitational wave data with electromagnetic information retrieved from a simulated galaxy catalog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind Search of The Solar Neighborhood Galactic Disk within 5kpc: 1,179 new Star clusters found in Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.10380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.10380/</guid>
      <description>Huanbin Chi
Studying open clusters (OCs) is essential for a comprehensive understanding of the structure and evolution of the Milky Way. Many previous studies have systematically searched for OCs near the solar system within 1.2 kpc or 20 degrees of galactic latitude. However, few studies searched for OCs at higher galactic latitudes and deeper distances. In this study, based on a hybrid unsupervised clustering algorithm (Friends-of-Friends and pyUPMASK) and a binary classification algorithm (Random Forest), we extended the search region (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-rising Type II supernovae resembling supernova 1987A -- I. A comparative study through scaling relations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-rising_type_ii_supernovae_resembling_supernova_1987a_--_i._a_comparative_study_through_scaling_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-rising_type_ii_supernovae_resembling_supernova_1987a_--_i._a_comparative_study_through_scaling_relations/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. L. Pumo
With the aim of improving our knowledge about their nature, we conduct a comparative study on a sample of long-rising Type II supernovae (SNe) resembling SN 1987A. To do so, we deduce various scaling relations from different analytic models of H-rich SNe, discussing their robustness and feasibility. Then we use the best relations in terms of accuracy to infer the SN progenitor&amp;rsquo;s physical properties at the explosion for the selected sample of SN 1987A-like objects, deriving energies of $\sim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Gaussian assembly bias from a semi-analytic galaxy formation model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussian_assembly_bias_from_a_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussian_assembly_bias_from_a_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Marinucci
We use $z=1$ mock galaxy catalogues produced with the semi-analytic code GALACTICUS to study the dependence of the non-Gaussian bias parameter $b_\phi$ on the mass assembly history of the host halos. We generate large sets of merger trees and measure the non-Gaussian assembly bias $\Delta b_\phi$ for galaxies selected by color magnitude and emission line luminosities. For galaxies selected by $g-r$ color, we find a large assembly bias consistent with the analysis of Barreira et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The H$α$ broadband photometric reverberation mapping of four Seyfert 1 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__broadband_photometric_reverberation_mapping_of_four_seyfert_1_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__broadband_photometric_reverberation_mapping_of_four_seyfert_1_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qinchun Ma
Broadband photometric reverberation mapping (PRM) have been investigated for AGNs in recent years, but mostly on accretion disk continuum RM. Due to the small fraction of broad emission lines in the broadband, PRM for emission lines is very challenging. Here we present an ICCF-Cut method for broadband PRM to obtain the H$\alpha$ broad line lag and apply it to four Seyfert 1 galaxies, MCG+08-11-011, NGC 2617, 3C 120 and NGC 5548.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamics simulations of core convection in supermassive main-sequence stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_core_convection_in_supermassive_main-sequence_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_core_convection_in_supermassive_main-sequence_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Blouin
Supermassive stars are Population III stars with masses exceeding $10^4,M_{\odot}$ that could be the progenitors of the first supermassive black holes. Their interiors are in a regime where radiation pressure dominates the equation of state. In this work, we use the explicit gas dynamics code PPMstar to simulate the hydrogen-burning core of a $10^4,M_{\odot}$ supermassive main-sequence star. These are the first 3D hydrodynamics simulations of core convection in supermassive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An HI story of galaxies in Abell 2626 and beyond</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_hi_story_of_galaxies_in_abell_2626_and_beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_hi_story_of_galaxies_in_abell_2626_and_beyond/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Deb
Context: To study the effects of environment on galaxies we use HI observations of galaxies in and around the cluster A2626. The cluster can effectively be divided in three different environments: the cluster itself, a group environment in the periphery of the cluster (we call it the Swarm) and substructure in the cluster itself. We use these to study the dependence of galaxy properties on environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology inference at the field level from biased tracers in redshift-space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_inference_at_the_field_level_from_biased_tracers_in_redshift-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_inference_at_the_field_level_from_biased_tracers_in_redshift-space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Julia Stadler
Cosmology inference of galaxy clustering at the field level with the EFT likelihood in principle allows for extracting all non-Gaussian information from quasi-linear scales, while robustly marginalizing over any astrophysical uncertainties. A pipeline in this spirit is implemented in the \texttt{LEFTfield} code, which we extend in this work to describe the clustering of galaxies in redshift space. Our main additions are: the computation of the velocity field in the LPT gravity model, the fully nonlinear displacement of the evolved, biased density field to redshift space, and a systematic expansion of velocity bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA): Bulge-disk decomposition of KiDS and VIKING data in the nearby universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_bulge-disk_decomposition_of_kids_and_viking_data_in_the_nearby_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_bulge-disk_decomposition_of_kids_and_viking_data_in_the_nearby_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sarah Casura
In this thesis, we derive a catalogue of robust structural parameters for the components of a large sample of nearby GAMA galaxies while at the same time contributing to the advancement of image analysis, surface brightness fitting and post-processing routines for quality assurance in the context of automated large-scale bulge-disk decomposition studies. The sample consists of 13096 galaxies at redshifts z &amp;lt; 0.08 with imaging data from the Kilo-Degree Survey and the VISTA Kilo-Degree INfrared Galaxy survey spanning the optical and near-infrared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPT-CL J2215-3537: A Massive Starburst at the Center of the Most Distant Relaxed Galaxy Cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spt-cl_j2215-3537_a_massive_starburst_at_the_center_of_the_most_distant_relaxed_galaxy_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spt-cl_j2215-3537_a_massive_starburst_at_the_center_of_the_most_distant_relaxed_galaxy_cluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael S. Calzadilla
We present the discovery of the most distant, dynamically relaxed cool core cluster, SPT-CL J2215-3537 (SPT2215) and its central brightest cluster galaxy (BCG) at z=1.16. Using new X-ray observations, we demonstrate that SPT2215 harbors a strong cool core, with a central cooling time of 200 Myr (at 10 kpc) and a maximal intracluster medium cooling rate of 1900+/-400 Msun/yr. This prodigious cooling may be responsible for fueling extended, star-forming filaments observed in Hubble Space Telescope imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emergence of Brightest Cluster Galaxy in the Most Massive Protocluster Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_emergence_of_brightest_cluster_galaxy_in_the_most_massive_protocluster_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_emergence_of_brightest_cluster_galaxy_in_the_most_massive_protocluster_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dongdong Shi
Distant protoclusters of galaxies, as the progenitors of massive galaxy clusters in the present day, are expected to host brightest cluster galaxies (BCGs) at their early formation stage. It remains unclear whether the assembly of (some) BCGs is essential to the formation of a mature cluster core or vice versa. Here we report the detection of a pair of massive quiescent galaxies likely in the process of merging at the centre of the spectroscopically confirmed, extremely massive protocluster BOSS1244 at a look-back time of 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pantheon Sample analysis of cosmological constraints under new models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pantheon_sample_analysis_of_cosmological_constraints_under_new_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pantheon_sample_analysis_of_cosmological_constraints_under_new_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peifeng Peng
In this project, the cosmological parameters are determined by applying six cosmological models to fit the magnitude-redshift relation of the Pantheon Sample consisting of 1048 Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) in the range of $0.01 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 2.26$. Apart from the well-known flat $\Lambda$CDM model as well as other models that have been broadly studied, this project includes two new models, which are the $\textit{o}\textit{w}$CDM model and the $\textit{o}\textit{w}0\textit{w}a$CDM model, to fully evaluate the correlations between the cosmological parameters by performing the MCMC algorithm and to explore the geometry and mass content of the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
