<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>most recent update (Thu Mar 2 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-thu-mar-2-2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in most recent update (Thu Mar 2 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-thu-mar-2-2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A universal equation to predict $Ω_{\rm m}$ from halo and galaxy catalogues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_universal_equation_to_predict__%CF%89__rm_m__from_halo_and_galaxy_catalogues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_universal_equation_to_predict__%CF%89__rm_m__from_halo_and_galaxy_catalogues/</guid>
      <description>First author: Helen Shao
We discover analytic equations that can infer the value of $\Omega_{\rm m}$ from the positions and velocity moduli of halo and galaxy catalogues. The equations are derived by combining a tailored graph neural network (GNN) architecture with symbolic regression. We first train the GNN on dark matter halos from Gadget N-body simulations to perform field-level likelihood-free inference, and show that our model can infer $\Omega_{\rm m}$ with $\sim6%$ accuracy from halo catalogues of thousands of N-body simulations run with six different codes: Abacus, CUBEP$^3$M, Gadget, Enzo, PKDGrav3, and Ramses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Synoptic Array science: A massive elliptical host among two galaxy-cluster fast radio bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_a_massive_elliptical_host_among_two_galaxy-cluster_fast_radio_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_a_massive_elliptical_host_among_two_galaxy-cluster_fast_radio_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kritti Sharma
The stellar population environments associated with fast radio burst (FRB) sources provide important insights for developing their progenitor theories. We expand the diversity of known FRB host environments by reporting two FRBs in massive galaxy clusters discovered by the Deep Synoptic Array (DSA-110) during its commissioning observations. FRB 20220914A has been localized to a star-forming, late-type galaxy at a redshift of 0.1139 with multiple starbursts at lookback times less than $\sim$3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Synoptic Array science: Two fast radio burst sources in massive galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_two_fast_radio_burst_sources_in_massive_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_two_fast_radio_burst_sources_in_massive_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liam Connor
The hot gas that constitutes the intracluster medium (ICM) has been studied at X-ray and millimeter/sub-millimeter wavelengths (Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect) for decades. Fast radio bursts (FRBs) offer an additional method of directly measuring the ICM and gas surrounding clusters, via observables such as dispersion measure (DM) and Faraday rotation measure (RM). We report the discovery of two FRB sources detected with the Deep Synoptic Array (DSA-110) whose host galaxies belong to massive galaxy clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the rapid formation of black holes and their galaxy hosts in QSOs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_rapid_formation_of_black_holes_and_their_galaxy_hosts_in_qsos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_rapid_formation_of_black_holes_and_their_galaxy_hosts_in_qsos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Karla Alejandra Cutiva-Alvarez
Using the modelling code X-CIGALE, we reproduced the SEDs of 1,359 SDSS QSOs within the redshift range 0 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 4, for which we have NIR/MIR fluxes with the highest quality and spectral data characterizing their SMBHs. Consistent with a rapid formation of the host galaxies, the star formation histories (SFHs) have small e-folding, at most 750 Myrs using an SFH function for Spiral or 1000 Myrs using one for Elliptical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Curvature from Super-Hubble Cosmological Fluctuations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spatial_curvature_from_super-hubble_cosmological_fluctuations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spatial_curvature_from_super-hubble_cosmological_fluctuations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Baptiste Blachier
We revisit how super-Hubble cosmological fluctuations induce, at any time in the cosmic history, a non-vanishing spatial curvature of the local background metric. The random nature of these fluctuations promotes the curvature density parameter to a stochastic quantity for which we derive novel non-perturbative expressions for its mean, variance, higher moments and full probability distribution. For scale-invariant Gaussian perturbations, such as those favored by cosmological observations, we find that the most probable value for the curvature density parameter $\Omega_\mathrm{K}$ today is $-10^{-9}$, that its mean is $+10^{-9}$, both being overwhelmed by a standard deviation of order $10^{-5}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JCMT Nearby Galaxies Legacy Survey: SCUBA-2 observations of nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jcmt_nearby_galaxies_legacy_survey_scuba-2_observations_of_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jcmt_nearby_galaxies_legacy_survey_scuba-2_observations_of_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kate Pattle
We present 850$\mu$m observations of a sample of 8 nearby spiral galaxies, made using the SCUBA-2 camera on the James Clerk Maxwell Telescope (JCMT) as part of the JCMT Nearby Galaxies Legacy Survey (NGLS). We corrected our data for the presence of the $^{12}$CO $J=3\to 2$ line in the SCUBA-2 850$\mu$m bandwidth using NGLS HARP data, finding a typical $^{12}$CO contribution of $\sim 20$%. We measured dust column densities, temperatures and opacity indices by fitting spectral energy distributions constructed from SCUBA-2 and archival Herschel observations, and used archival GALEX and Spitzer data to make maps of surface density of star formation ($\Sigma_{\rm SFR}$).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The restframe ultraviolet of superluminous supernovae -- I. Potential as cosmological probes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_restframe_ultraviolet_of_superluminous_supernovae_--_i._potential_as_cosmological_probes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_restframe_ultraviolet_of_superluminous_supernovae_--_i._potential_as_cosmological_probes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nandita Khetan
Superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) have been detected to $z\sim4$ and can be detected to $z\gtrsim15$ using current and upcoming facilities. SLSNe are extremely UV luminous, and hence objects at $z\gtrsim7$ are detected exclusively via their rest-frame UV using optical and infrared facilities. SLSNe have great utility in multiple areas of stellar and galactic evolution. Here, we explore the potential use of SLSNe type-I as high-redshift cosmological distance indicators in their rest-frame UV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A possible signature of the influence of tidal perturbations in dwarf galaxy scaling relations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_signature_of_the_influence_of_tidal_perturbations_in_dwarf_galaxy_scaling_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_signature_of_the_influence_of_tidal_perturbations_in_dwarf_galaxy_scaling_relations/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. E. Watkins
Dwarf galaxies are excellent cosmological probes, because their shallow potential wells make them very sensitive to the key processes that drive galaxy evolution, including baryonic feedback, tidal interactions, and ram pressure stripping. However, some of the key parameters of dwarf galaxies, which help trace the effects of these processes, are still debated, including the relationship between their sizes and masses. We re-examine the Fornax Cluster dwarf population from the point of view of isomass-radius&amp;ndash;stellar mass relations (IRSMRs) using the Fornax Deep Survey Dwarf galaxy Catalogue, with the centrally located (among dwarfs) $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies II: Environmental Quenching of Mass-Size Outliers Among the Satellites of Milky Way Analogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_ii_environmental_quenching_of_mass-size_outliers_among_the_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_ii_environmental_quenching_of_mass-size_outliers_among_the_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiaxuan Li
Recent observations have reignited interest in a population of dwarf galaxies that are large and diffuse for their mass, often called ultra-diffuse galaxies. However, the origin and evolution of these mass-size outliers and the role of environment are still unclear. Using the exquisitely deep and wide Hyper Suprime-Cam Strategic Survey images, we search for ultra-puffy galaxies, defined as being $1.5\sigma$ larger than the average size for their mass, around Milky-Way&amp;ndash;like galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a quiescent galaxy at z=7.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_quiescent_galaxy_at_z7.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_quiescent_galaxy_at_z7.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tobias J. Looser
Local galaxies are known to broadly follow a bimodal distribution: actively star forming and quiescent system (i.e. galaxies with no or negligible star formation activity at the epoch of observation). Why, when and how such bimodality was established, and whether it has been associated with different processes at different cosmic epochs, is still a key open question in extragalactic astrophysics. Directly observing early quiescent galaxies in the primordial Universe is therefore of utmost importance to constraining models of galaxy formation and transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution X-Ray Spectroscopy of Supernova Remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_x-ray_spectroscopy_of_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_x-ray_spectroscopy_of_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Satoru Katsuda
Thermal X-ray spectra from supernova remnants (SNRs) are dominated by a number of line emission from various elements. Resolving the individual lines is critically important for a variety of scientific topics such as diagnosing high-temperature and low-density non-equilibrium plasmas, identifying spectral features like charge exchange and resonance line scattering, revealing kinematics and elemental abundances of SN ejecta and the circumstellar medium, and studying the interstellar medium or planets&amp;rsquo; atmospheres from extinction features seen in X-ray spectra of very bright SNRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass bias and cosmological constraints from Planck cluster clustering</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_bias_and_cosmological_constraints_from_planck_cluster_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_bias_and_cosmological_constraints_from_planck_cluster_clustering/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. F. Lesci
We analysed the 3D clustering of the Planck sample of Sunyaev-Zeldovich (SZ) selected galaxy clusters, focusing on the redshift-space two-point correlation function (2PCF). We compared our measurements to theoretical predictions of the standard $\Lambda$ cold dark matter ($\Lambda$CDM) cosmological model, deriving an estimate of the Planck mass bias, $b_{\mathrm SZ}$, and cosmological parameters. We measured the 2PCF of the sample in the cluster-centric radial range $r\in[10,150]$ $h^{-1}$Mpc, considering 920 galaxy clusters with redshift $z\leq0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-Independent Determination of $H_0$ and $Ω_{K,0}$ using Time-Delay Galaxy Lenses and Gamma-Ray Bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/model-independent_determination_of__h_0__and__%CF%89_k0__using_time-delay_galaxy_lenses_and_gamma-ray_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/model-independent_determination_of__h_0__and__%CF%89_k0__using_time-delay_galaxy_lenses_and_gamma-ray_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shen-Shi Du
Combining the `time-delay distance&amp;rsquo; ($D_{\Delta t}$) measurements from galaxy lenses and other distance indicators provides model-independent determinations of the Hubble constant ($H_0$) and spatial curvature ($\Omega_{K,0}$), only based on the validity of the Friedmann-Lema^itre-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) metric and geometrical optics. To take the full merit of combining $D_{\Delta t}$ measurements in constraining $H_0$, we use gamma-ray burst (GRB) distances to extend the redshift coverage of lensing systems much higher than that of Type Ia Supernovae (SNe Ia) and even higher than quasars, whilst the general cosmography with a curvature component is implemented for the GRB distance parametrizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear and electromagnetic cascades induced by ultrahigh-energy cosmic rays in radio galaxies: implications for Centaurus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_and_electromagnetic_cascades_induced_by_ultrahigh-energy_cosmic_rays_in_radio_galaxies_implications_for_centaurus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_and_electromagnetic_cascades_induced_by_ultrahigh-energy_cosmic_rays_in_radio_galaxies_implications_for_centaurus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Theodore Zhang
Very-high-energy (VHE) $\gamma$-rays ($\gtrsim 0.1\rm~TeV$) and neutrinos are crucial for identifying accelerators of ultrahigh-energy cosmic rays (UHECRs), but this is challenging especially for UHECR nuclei. In this work, we develop a numerical code to solve the transport equation for UHECRs and their secondaries, where both nuclear and electromagnetic cascades are taken into account self-consistently, considering steady UHECR accelerators such as radio galaxies. In particular, we focus on Centaurus A, which has been proposed as one of the most promising UHECR sources in the local universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust field-level likelihood-free inference with galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robust_field-level_likelihood-free_inference_with_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robust_field-level_likelihood-free_inference_with_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalí S. M. de Santi
We train graph neural networks to perform field-level likelihood-free inference using galaxy catalogs from state-of-the-art hydrodynamic simulations of the CAMELS project. Our models are rotationally, translationally, and permutation invariant and have no scale cutoff. By training on galaxy catalogs that only contain the 3D positions and radial velocities of approximately $1,000$ galaxies in tiny volumes of $(25~h^{-1}{\rm Mpc})^3$, our models achieve a precision of approximately $12$% when inferring the value of $\Omega_{\rm m}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lyman $α$ Reference Sample XIV: Lyman $α$ imaging of 45 low redshift star-forming galaxies and inferences on global emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_lyman__%CE%B1__reference_sample_xiv_lyman__%CE%B1__imaging_of_45_low_redshift_star-forming_galaxies_and_inferences_on_global_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_lyman__%CE%B1__reference_sample_xiv_lyman__%CE%B1__imaging_of_45_low_redshift_star-forming_galaxies_and_inferences_on_global_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jens Melinder
We present Ly $\alpha$ imaging of 45 low redshift star-forming galaxies observed with the Hubble Space Telescope. The galaxies have been selected to have moderate to high star formation rates using far-ultraviolet (FUV) luminosity and \ha equivalent width criteria, but no constraints on Ly $\alpha$ luminosity. We employ a pixel stellar continuum fitting code to obtain accurate continuum subtracted Ly $\alpha$, H $\alpha$ and H $\beta$ maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DESI survey validation data in the COSMOS/HSC field: Cool gas trace main sequence star-forming galaxies at the cosmic noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/desi_survey_validation_data_in_the_cosmos_hsc_field_cool_gas_trace_main_sequence_star-forming_galaxies_at_the_cosmic_noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/desi_survey_validation_data_in_the_cosmos_hsc_field_cool_gas_trace_main_sequence_star-forming_galaxies_at_the_cosmic_noon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Siwei Zou
We present the first result in exploring the gaseous halo and galaxy correlation using the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI) survey validation data in the Cosmic Evolution Survey (COSMOS) and Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) field. We obtain the multiphase gaseous halo properties in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) by using 115 quasar spectra (S/N &amp;gt; 3). We detect MgII absorption at redshift 0.6 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 2.5, CIV absorption at 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proximate molecular quasar absorbers: Chemical enrichment and kinematics of the neutral gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/proximate_molecular_quasar_absorbers_chemical_enrichment_and_kinematics_of_the_neutral_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/proximate_molecular_quasar_absorbers_chemical_enrichment_and_kinematics_of_the_neutral_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Noterdaeme
Proximate molecular quasar absorbers (PH2) are an intriguing population of absorption systems recently uncovered through strong H2 absorption at small velocity separation from the background quasars. We performed a multi-wavelength spectroscopic follow-up of thirteen such systems with VLT/X-Shooter. Here, we present the observations and study the overall chemical enrichment measured from the HI, H2 and metal lines. We combine this with an investigation of the neutral gas kinematics with respect to the quasar host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study of GeV Gamma-ray Emission toward Supernova Remnant G51.26&#43;0.11 and Its Molecular Environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_study_of_gev_gamma-ray_emission_toward_supernova_remnant_g51.26&#43;0.11_and_its_molecular_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_study_of_gev_gamma-ray_emission_toward_supernova_remnant_g51.26&#43;0.11_and_its_molecular_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wen-Juan Zhong
We reanalyze the Fermi-LAT GeV $\gamma$-ray emission in the region of supernova remnant (SNR) G51.26+0.11 and investigate its interstellar molecular environment with the CO-line data. At GeV energies, based on 13.2 years of Fermi-LAT data, the extended $\gamma$-ray emission observed in this region is resolved into a uniform-disk source (&amp;lsquo;Src A&amp;rsquo;) with a significance of 19.5$\sigma$ and a point source (4FGL J1924.3+1628) with a significance of 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN STORM 2. III. A NICER view of the variable X-ray obscurer in Mrk 817</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_storm_2._iii._a_nicer_view_of_the_variable_x-ray_obscurer_in_mrk_817/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_storm_2._iii._a_nicer_view_of_the_variable_x-ray_obscurer_in_mrk_817/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ethan R. Partington
The AGN STORM 2 collaboration targeted the Seyfert 1 galaxy Mrk 817 for a year-long multiwavelength, coordinated reverberation mapping campaign including HST, Swift, XMM-Newton, NICER, and ground-based observatories. Early observations with NICER and XMM revealed an X-ray state ten times fainter than historical observations, consistent with the presence of a new dust-free, ionized obscurer. The following analysis of NICER spectra attributes variability in the observed X-ray flux to changes in both the column density of the obscurer by at least one order of magnitude ($N_\mathrm{H}$ ranges from $2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing model-based carbon and oxygen abundance derivation from ultraviolet emission lines in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/assessing_model-based_carbon_and_oxygen_abundance_derivation_from_ultraviolet_emission_lines_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/assessing_model-based_carbon_and_oxygen_abundance_derivation_from_ultraviolet_emission_lines_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Enrique Pérez-Montero
We present an adapted version of the code HII-CHI-Mistry-UV (P&#39;erez-Montero &amp;amp; Amor&#39;in 2017) to derive chemical abundances from emission lines in the ultraviolet, for use in narrow line regions (NLR) of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN). We evaluate different ultraviolet emission line ratios and how different assumptions about the models, including the presence of dust grains, the shape of the incident spectral energy distribution, or the thickness of the gas envelope around the central source, may affect the final estimates as a function of the set of emission lines used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical abundances in Seyfert galaxies X. Sulphur abundance estimates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_abundances_in_seyfert_galaxies_x._sulphur_abundance_estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_abundances_in_seyfert_galaxies_x._sulphur_abundance_estimates/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. L. Dors
For the first time, the sulphur abundance relative to hydrogen (S/H) in the Narrow Line Regions of a sample of Seyfert 2 nuclei (Sy 2s) has been derived via direct estimation of the electron temperature. Narrow emission line intensities from the SDSS DR17 [in the wavelength range 3000 &amp;lt; $\lambda$ &amp;lt; 9100] and from the literature for a sample of 45 nearby ($z$ &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMB constraints on the early universe independent of late time cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cmb_constraints_on_the_early_universe_independent_of_late_time_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cmb_constraints_on_the_early_universe_independent_of_late_time_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pablo Lemos
The CMB is a powerful probe of early-universe physics but is only observed after passing through large-scale structure, which changes the observed spectra in important model-dependent ways. This is of particular concern given recent claims of significant discrepancies with low redshift data sets when a standard $\Lambda$CDM model is assumed. By using empirical measurements of the CMB lensing reconstruction, combined with weak priors on the smoothness of the lensing spectrum, foregrounds, and shape of any additional integrated Sachs-Wolfe effect, we show how the early-universe parameters can be constrained from CMB observations almost independently of the late-time evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining AGN Torus Sizes with Optical and Mid-Infrared Ensemble Structure Functions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_agn_torus_sizes_with_optical_and_mid-infrared_ensemble_structure_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_agn_torus_sizes_with_optical_and_mid-infrared_ensemble_structure_functions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junyao Li
We propose a new method to constrain the size of the dusty torus in broad-line active galactic nuclei (AGNs) using optical and mid-infrared (MIR) ensemble structure functions (SFs). Because of the geometric dilution of the torus, the mid-infrared response to optical continuum variations has suppressed variability with respect to the optical that depends on the geometry (e.g., size, orientation and opening angle) of the torus. More extended tori have steeper MIR SFs with respect to the optical SF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on the Cosmological Coupling of Black Holes from the Globular Cluster NGC 3201</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_cosmological_coupling_of_black_holes_from_the_globular_cluster_ngc_3201/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_cosmological_coupling_of_black_holes_from_the_globular_cluster_ngc_3201/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carl L. Rodriguez
Globular clusters are among the oldest stellar populations in the Milky Way; consequently, they also host some of the oldest known stellar-mass black holes, providing insight into black hole formation and evolution in the early ($z\gtrsim 2$) Universe. Recent observations of supermassive black holes in elliptical galaxies have been invoked to suggest the possibility of a cosmological coupling between astrophysical black holes and the surrounding expanding Universe, offering a mechanism for black holes to grow over cosmic time, and potentially explaining the origin of dark energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDGE: The shape of dark matter haloes in the faintest galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/edge_the_shape_of_dark_matter_haloes_in_the_faintest_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/edge_the_shape_of_dark_matter_haloes_in_the_faintest_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew D. A. Orkney
Purely collisionless Dark Matter Only (DMO) structure formation simulations predict that Dark Matter (DM) haloes are typically prolate in their centres and spheroidal towards their outskirts. The addition of gas cooling transforms the central DM shape to be rounder and more oblate. It is not clear, however, whether such shape transformations occur in `ultra-faint&amp;rsquo; dwarfs, which have extremely low baryon fractions. We present the first study of the shape and velocity anisotropy of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies that have gas mass fractions of $f_{\rm gas}(r&amp;lt;R_{\rm half}) &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galactic bulge-black hole co-evolution, feeding and feedback of AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galactic_bulge-black_hole_co-evolution_feeding_and_feedback_of_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galactic_bulge-black_hole_co-evolution_feeding_and_feedback_of_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francoise Combes
Since the 1990s, we have known that there is a super-massive black hole in every galaxy, and that its mass is proportional to the mass of the bulge. To better understand how these black holes were formed, in symbiosis with their galaxies, we will look at their demography, the scaling relations between properties of black holes and host galaxies, and their evolution in a Hubble time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Clustering in the Mira-Titan Universe I: Emulators for the redshift space galaxy correlation function and galaxy-galaxy lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_clustering_in_the_mira-titan_universe_i_emulators_for_the_redshift_space_galaxy_correlation_function_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_clustering_in_the_mira-titan_universe_i_emulators_for_the_redshift_space_galaxy_correlation_function_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Juliana Kwan
We construct accurate emulators for the projected and redshift space galaxy correlation functions and excess surface density as measured by galaxy-galaxy lensing, based on Halo Occupation Distribution (HOD) modeling. Using the complete Mira-Titan suite of 111 $N$-body simulations, our emulators vary over eight cosmological parameters and include the effects of neutrino mass and dynamical dark energy. We demonstrate that our emulators are sufficiently accurate for the analysis of the BOSS DR12 CMASS galaxy sample over the range 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEAR-RT: Towards Exa-Scale Moment Based Radiative Transfer For Cosmological Simulations Using Task-Based Parallelism And Dynamic Sub-Cycling with SWIFT</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gear-rt_towards_exa-scale_moment_based_radiative_transfer_for_cosmological_simulations_using_task-based_parallelism_and_dynamic_sub-cycling_with_swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gear-rt_towards_exa-scale_moment_based_radiative_transfer_for_cosmological_simulations_using_task-based_parallelism_and_dynamic_sub-cycling_with_swift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mladen Ivkovic
The development and implementation of GEAR-RT, a radiative transfer solver using the M1 closure in the open source code SWIFT, is presented, and validated using standard tests for radiative transfer. GEAR-RT is modeled after RAMSES-RT (Rosdahl et al. 2013) with some key differences. Firstly, while RAMSES-RT uses Finite Volume methods and an Adaptive Mesh Refinement (AMR) strategy, GEAR-RT employs particles as discretization elements and solves the equations using a Finite Volume Particle Method (FVPM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Flash and Spectral Formation of Type Ia Supernovae with An Envelope: Applications to Over-luminous SNe Ia</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/initial_flash_and_spectral_formation_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_an_envelope_applications_to_over-luminous_sne_ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/initial_flash_and_spectral_formation_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_an_envelope_applications_to_over-luminous_sne_ia/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Over-luminous type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) show peculiar observational features, for which an explosion of a super-massive white dwarf (WD) beyond the classical Chandrasekhar-limiting mass has been suggested, largely based on their high luminosities and slow light-curve evolution. However, their observational features are diverse, with a few extremely peculiar features whose origins have not been clarified; strong and persisting C II lines, late-time accelerated luminosity decline and red spectra, and a sub-day time-scale initial flash clearly identified so far at least for three over-luminous SNe Ia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JADES: Discovery of extremely high equivalent width Lyman-alpha emission from a faint galaxy within an ionized bubble at z=7.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jades_discovery_of_extremely_high_equivalent_width_lyman-alpha_emission_from_a_faint_galaxy_within_an_ionized_bubble_at_z7.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jades_discovery_of_extremely_high_equivalent_width_lyman-alpha_emission_from_a_faint_galaxy_within_an_ionized_bubble_at_z7.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aayush Saxena
We report the discovery of a remarkable Ly$\alpha$ emitting galaxy at $z=7.278$, JADES-GS+53.16746-27.7720 (shortened to JADES-GS-z7-LA), with EW$0$(Ly$\alpha$) $\approx400 \pm 90$A and UV magnitude $-16.7$. The spectroscopic redshift is confirmed via rest-frame optical lines $[O II]$, H$\beta$ and $[O III]$ in its JWST/NIRSpec Micro-Shutter Assembly (MSA) spectrum. The Ly$\alpha$ line is detected in both lower resolution ($R\sim100$) PRISM as well as medium resolution ($R\sim1000$) G140M grating spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jets in FR0 radio galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jets_in_fr0_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jets_in_fr0_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Giovannini
The local radio-loud AGN population is dominated by compact sources named FR0s. These sources show features, for example the host type, the mass of the supermassive black hole (SMBH), and the multi-band nuclear characteristics, that are similar to those of FRI radio galaxies. However, in the radio band, while FR0 and FRI share the same nuclear properties, the kiloparsec-scale diffuse component dominant in FRI is missing in FR0s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francoise Combes
Our vision of galaxies has changed significantly since the era of large galaxy surveys like the Sloan, which gave us extensive statistics with millions of galaxies. The Hubble sequence classification described in Chapter 1 still remains very widely used but has been enriched with broad categories based on color that indicate the recent formation of stars: the red sequence of passive galaxies, consisting solely of old stars, and the blue cloud of galaxies with active star formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of central light distribution in nearby early-type galaxies hosting nuclear star clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_central_light_distribution_in_nearby_early-type_galaxies_hosting_nuclear_star_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_central_light_distribution_in_nearby_early-type_galaxies_hosting_nuclear_star_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. Sruthi
We present analysis of 63 nearby ($&amp;lt;$ 44 Mpc) early-type galaxies hosting nuclear star clusters using the recently discovered parameter Central Intensity Ratio (CIR$_I$) determined from near-infra-red (3.6 $\mu$m) observations with the Infra-red-array-camera of \emph{Spitzer} space telescope. The CIR$_I$, when combined with filters involving age and $B-K$ colour of host galaxies, helps identify two distinct classes of galaxies hosting nuclear star clusters. This is independently verified using Gaussian Mixture Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The eROSITA Final Equatorial-Depth Survey (eFEDS): Host-galaxy Demographics of X-ray AGNs with Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_erosita_final_equatorial-depth_survey_efeds_host-galaxy_demographics_of_x-ray_agns_with_subaru_hyper_suprime-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_erosita_final_equatorial-depth_survey_efeds_host-galaxy_demographics_of_x-ray_agns_with_subaru_hyper_suprime-cam/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junyao Li
We investigate the physical properties, such as star-forming activity, disk vs. bulge nature, galaxy size, and obscuration of 3796 X-ray selected AGNs at $0.2&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;0.8$ in the eFEDS field. Using Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam imaging data in the $grizy$ bands for SRG/eROSITA-detected AGNs, we measure the structural parameters for AGN host galaxies by performing a 2D AGN-host image decomposition. We then conduct spectral energy distribution fitting to derive stellar mass and rest-frame colors for AGN hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interplay between accretion, galaxy downsizing and the formation of box/peanut bulges in TNG50</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_accretion_galaxy_downsizing_and_the_formation_of_box_peanut_bulges_in_tng50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_accretion_galaxy_downsizing_and_the_formation_of_box_peanut_bulges_in_tng50/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stuart Robert Anderson
From the TNG50 cosmological simulation we build a sample of 191 well-resolved barred galaxies with a stellar mass $\logMstar &amp;gt; 10$ at $z=0$. We search for box/peanut bulges (BPs) in this sample, finding them in 55% of cases. We compute $\fbp$, the BP probability for barred galaxies as a function of $\Mstar$, and find that this rises to a plateau, as found in observations of nearby galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wide-angle effects in the galaxy bispectrum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wide-angle_effects_in_the_galaxy_bispectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wide-angle_effects_in_the_galaxy_bispectrum/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kevin Pardede
Primordial non-Gaussianities (PNG) leave unique signatures in the bispectrum of the large-scale structure. With upcoming galaxy surveys set to improve PNG constraints by at least one order of magnitude, it is important to account for any potential contamination. In our work we show how to include wide-angle effects into the 3-dimensional observed galaxy bispectrum. We compute the leading wide-angle corrections to the monopole, finding that they could mimic local PNG with an amplitude of $f_{\rm NL} = \mathcal{O}\left( 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN feedback in an infant galaxy cluster: the LOFAR-Chandra view of the giant FRII radio galaxy J103025&#43;052430 at z=1.7</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_an_infant_galaxy_cluster_the_lofar-chandra_view_of_the_giant_frii_radio_galaxy_j103025&#43;052430_at_z1.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_an_infant_galaxy_cluster_the_lofar-chandra_view_of_the_giant_frii_radio_galaxy_j103025&#43;052430_at_z1.7/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Brienza
In the nearby universe jets from AGN are observed to have a dramatic impact on their surrounding extragalactic environment. Their effect at the cosmic noon&#39; (z&amp;gt;1.5), the epoch when star formation and AGN activity peak, is instead much less constrained. Here we present a study of the giant (750 kpc) radio galaxy 103025+052430 located at the centre of a protocluster at redshift z=1.7, with a focus on its interaction with the external medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension of General Relativity with MOND limit predicts novel orbital structure in and around galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extension_of_general_relativity_with_mond_limit_predicts_novel_orbital_structure_in_and_around_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extension_of_general_relativity_with_mond_limit_predicts_novel_orbital_structure_in_and_around_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Claudio Llinares
Detailed knowledge of the different classes of stellar orbits that can be accommodated in a given galactic potential is a prerequisite when building self-consistent models using for instance the Schwazschild technique. Furthermore, observational properties of galaxies depend on what these classes of orbits are and on the presence of chaos in the systems. In the realistic case in which the starting point for modeling is not a gravitational potential, but an observed density distribution, we will require a gravitational theory to make the connection between the stars that we see and the movement these stars may be having.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDSS-IV MaNGA: The effect of stellar mass and halo mass on the assembly histories of satellite galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss-iv_manga_the_effect_of_stellar_mass_and_halo_mass_on_the_assembly_histories_of_satellite_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss-iv_manga_the_effect_of_stellar_mass_and_halo_mass_on_the_assembly_histories_of_satellite_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Grecco A. Oyarzun
We combine an unprecedented MaNGA sample of over 3,000 passive galaxies in the stellar mass range 10^{9}-10^{12} Msun with the Sloan Digital Sky Survey group catalog by Tinker to quantify how central and satellite formation, quantified by radial profiles in stellar age, $[Fe/H]$, and $[Mg/Fe]$, depends on the stellar mass of the galaxy (M*) and the mass of the host halo (Mh). After controlling for M* and Mh, the stacked spectra of centrals and satellites beyond the effective radius (r_e) show small, yet significant differences in multiple spectral features at the 1% level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Formation Laws and Efficiencies across 80 Nearby Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_laws_and_efficiencies_across_80_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_laws_and_efficiencies_across_80_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiayi Sun
We measure empirical relationships between the local star formation rate (SFR) and properties of the star-forming molecular gas on 1.5 kpc scales across 80 nearby galaxies. These relationships, commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;star formation laws,&amp;rdquo; aim at predicting the local SFR surface density from various combinations of molecular gas surface density, galactic orbital time, molecular cloud free-fall time, and the interstellar medium dynamical equilibrium pressure. Leveraging a multiwavelength database built for the PHANGS survey, we measure these quantities consistently across all galaxies and quantify systematic uncertainties stemming from choices of SFR calibrations and the CO-to-H$_2$ conversion factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of Central Intensity Ratio of Seyfert Galaxies in nearby Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_central_intensity_ratio_of_seyfert_galaxies_in_nearby_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_central_intensity_ratio_of_seyfert_galaxies_in_nearby_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: K T Vinod
We use the recently discovered simple photometric parameter Central Intensity Ratio (CIR, Aswathy &amp;amp; Ravikumar 2018) determined for a sample of 57 nearby (z &amp;lt; 0.02) Seyfert galaxies to explore the central features of galaxies and their possible connection with galaxy evolution. The sample of galaxies shows strong anti-correlation between CIR and mass of their central supermassive black holes (SMBH). The SMBH masses of ellipticals are systematically higher for a given CIR value than that for lenticulars and spirals in the sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intrinsic Alignment of Red Galaxies in DES Y1 redMaPPer Galaxy Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_intrinsic_alignment_of_red_galaxies_in_des_y1_redmapper_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_intrinsic_alignment_of_red_galaxies_in_des_y1_redmapper_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Zhou
Clusters of galaxies are sensitive to the most nonlinear peaks in the cosmic density field. The weak gravitational lensing of background galaxies by clusters can allow us to infer their masses. However, galaxies associated with the local environment of the cluster can also be intrinsically aligned due to the local tidal gradient, contaminating any cosmology derived from the lensing signal. We measure this intrinsic alignment in Dark Energy Survey (DES) Year 1 redMaPPer clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MeerKAT Fornax Survey -- I. Survey description and first evidence of ram pressure in the Fornax galaxy cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_meerkat_fornax_survey_--_i._survey_description_and_first_evidence_of_ram_pressure_in_the_fornax_galaxy_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_meerkat_fornax_survey_--_i._survey_description_and_first_evidence_of_ram_pressure_in_the_fornax_galaxy_cluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Serra
The MeerKAT Fornax Survey maps the distribution and kinematics of atomic neutral hydrogen gas (HI) in the nearby Fornax galaxy cluster using the MeerKAT telescope. The 12 deg^2 survey footprint covers the central region of the cluster out to ~ Rvir and stretches out to ~ 2 Rvir towards south west to include the NGC 1316 galaxy group. The HI column density sensitivity (3 sigma over 25 km/s) ranges from 5e+19/cm^2 at a resolution of ~ 10&amp;quot; (~ 1 kpc at the 20 Mpc distance of Fornax) down to ~ 1e+18/cm^2 at ~ 1&amp;rsquo; (~ 6 kpc), and slightly below this level at the lowest resolution of ~ 100&amp;quot; (~ 10 kpc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wet Compaction to a Blue Nugget: a Critical Phase in Galaxy Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wet_compaction_to_a_blue_nugget_a_critical_phase_in_galaxy_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wet_compaction_to_a_blue_nugget_a_critical_phase_in_galaxy_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sharon Lapiner
We utilize high-resolution cosmological simulations to reveal that high-redshift galaxies tend to undergo a robust wet compaction&#39; event when near a golden&amp;rsquo; stellar mass of $\sim 10^{10} M_{\odot}$. This is a gaseous shrinkage to a compact star-forming phase, a blue nugget&#39; (BN), followed by central quenching of star formation to a compact passive stellar bulge, a red nugget&amp;rsquo; (RN), and a buildup of an extended gaseous disc and ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for transients in the Reionization Lensing Cluster Survey (RELICS): Three new supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_transients_in_the_reionization_lensing_cluster_survey_relics_three_new_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_transients_in_the_reionization_lensing_cluster_survey_relics_three_new_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Miriam Golubchik
The Reionization Cluster Survey (RELICS) imaged 41 galaxy clusters with the Hubble Space Telescope (HST), in order to detect lensed and high-redshift galaxies. Each cluster was imaged to about 26.5 AB mag in three optical and four near-infrared bands, taken in two distinct visits separated by varying time intervals. We make use of the multiple near-infrared epochs to search for transient sources in the cluster fields, with the primary motivation of building statistics for bright caustic crossing events in gravitational arcs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absence of the predicted 2022 October outburst of OJ 287 and implications for binary SMBH scenarios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/absence_of_the_predicted_2022_october_outburst_of_oj_287_and_implications_for_binary_smbh_scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/absence_of_the_predicted_2022_october_outburst_of_oj_287_and_implications_for_binary_smbh_scenarios/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Komossa
The project MOMO (Multiwavelength Observations and Modelling of OJ 287) was set up to test predictions of binary supermassive black hole (SMBH) scenarios and to understand disk-jet physics of the blazar OJ 287. After a correction, the precessing binary (PB) SMBH model predicted the next main outburst of OJ 287 in 2022 October, no longer in July, making the outburst well observable and the model testable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN STORM 2: II. Ultraviolet Observations of Mrk817 with the Cosmic Origins Spectrograph on the Hubble Space Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_storm_2_ii._ultraviolet_observations_of_mrk817_with_the_cosmic_origins_spectrograph_on_the_hubble_space_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_storm_2_ii._ultraviolet_observations_of_mrk817_with_the_cosmic_origins_spectrograph_on_the_hubble_space_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Homayouni
We present reverberation mapping measurements for the prominent ultraviolet broad emission lines of the active galactic nucleus Mrk817 using 165 spectra obtained with the Cosmic Origins Spectrograph on the Hubble Space Telescope. Our ultraviolet observations are accompanied by X-ray, optical, and near-infrared observations as part of the AGN Space Telescope and Optical Reverberation Mapping Program 2 (AGN STORM 2). Using the cross-correlation lag analysis method, we find significant correlated variations in the continuum and emission-line light curves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the Conditional Galaxy Property Distribution using Gaussian Mixture Models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_the_conditional_galaxy_property_distribution_using_gaussian_mixture_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_the_conditional_galaxy_property_distribution_using_gaussian_mixture_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yucheng Zhang
Line-intensity mapping (LIM) is a promising technique to constrain the global distribution of galaxy properties. To combine LIM experiments probing different tracers with traditional galaxy surveys and fully exploit the scientific potential of these observations, it is necessary to have a physically motivated modeling framework. As part of developing such a framework, in this work we introduce and model the conditional galaxy property distribution (CGPD), i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Supernova Physics through Gravitational-Wave Observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_supernova_physics_through_gravitational-wave_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_supernova_physics_through_gravitational-wave_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gergely Dálya
We examine the potential for using the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA network of gravitational-wave detectors to provide constraints on the physical properties of core-collapse supernovae through the observation of their gravitational radiation. We use waveforms generated by 14 of the latest 3D hydrodynamic core-collapse supernova simulations, which are added to noise samples based on the predicted sensitivities of the GW detectors during the O5 observing run. Then we use the BayesWave algorithm to model-independently reconstruct the gravitational-wave waveforms, which are used as input for various machine learning algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curvature of the spectral energy distribution, Compton dominance and synchrotron peak frequency in jetted AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/curvature_of_the_spectral_energy_distribution_compton_dominance_and_synchrotron_peak_frequency_in_jetted_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/curvature_of_the_spectral_energy_distribution_compton_dominance_and_synchrotron_peak_frequency_in_jetted_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chen Yongyun
We collect a large sample with a reliable redshift detected by the Fermi satellite after 10 years of data (4FGL-DR2), including blazars, $\gamma$-ray Narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxies ($\gamma$NLS1s), and radio galaxies. The spectral energy distributions (SEDs) of these Fermi sources are fitted by using a second-degree polynomial, and some important parameters including spectral curvature, synchrotron peak frequency, and peak luminosity are obtained. Based on those parameters, we discuss the Fermi blazar sequence and the particle acceleration mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Buried Compact Sources in the Dwarf Galaxy NGC 4449</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_buried_compact_sources_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4449/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_buried_compact_sources_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4449/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniela Calzetti
Multi-wavelength images from the Hubble Space Telescope covering the wavelength range 0.27-1.6 $\mu$m show that the central area of the nearby dwarf galaxy NGC4449 contains several tens of compact sources that are emitting in the hydrogen recombination line Pa$\beta$ (1.2818 $\mu$m) but are only marginally detected in H$\alpha$ (0.6563 $\mu$m) and undetected at wavelengths $\lambda\le$0.55 $\mu$m. An analysis of the spectral energy distributions (SEDs) of these sources indicates that they are likely relatively young star clusters heavily attenuated by dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Morphologies of High Redshift Galaxies with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_morphologies_of_high_redshift_galaxies_with_machine_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_morphologies_of_high_redshift_galaxies_with_machine_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Clár-Bríd Tohill
The morphology of a galaxy has been shown to encode the evolutionary history and correlates strongly with physical properties such as stellar mass, star formation rates and past merger events. While the majority of galaxies in the local universe can be classified on the Hubble sequence, little is known about the different types of galaxies we observe at high redshift. The irregular morphology of these galaxies makes visual classifications difficult, and with the future of astronomy consisting of many &amp;ldquo;Big Data&amp;rdquo; surveys we need an efficient, and unbiased classification system in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling gas around galaxy pairs and groups using the Q0107 quasar triplet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_gas_around_galaxy_pairs_and_groups_using_the_q0107_quasar_triplet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_gas_around_galaxy_pairs_and_groups_using_the_q0107_quasar_triplet/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexander Beckett
We examine to what extent disk and outflow models can reproduce observations of H I gas within a few virial radii of galaxies in pairs and groups. Using highly-sensitive HST/COS and FOS spectra of the Q0107 quasar triplet covering Ly$\alpha$ for z$\lesssim$1, as well as a deep galaxy redshift survey including VIMOS, DEIMOS, GMOS and MUSE data, we test simple disk and outflow models against the H I absorption along three lines-of-sight (separated by 200-500 kpc) through nine galaxy groups in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitfalls of AI classification of rare objects: Galaxy Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pitfalls_of_ai_classification_of_rare_objects_galaxy_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pitfalls_of_ai_classification_of_rare_objects_galaxy_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. J. Pearson
Galaxy mergers are hugely important in our current dark matter cosmology. These powerful events cause the disruption of the merging galaxies, pushing the gas, stars and dust of the galaxies resulting in changes to morphologies. This disruption can also cause more extreme events inside the galaxies: periods of extreme star formation rates and the rapid increase in active galactic nuclei activity. Hence, to better understand what goes on in these rare events, we need to be able to identify statistically large samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The AGNIFS survey: spatially resolved observations of hot molecular and ionised outflows in nearby active galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_agnifs_survey_spatially_resolved_observations_of_hot_molecular_and_ionised_outflows_in_nearby_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_agnifs_survey_spatially_resolved_observations_of_hot_molecular_and_ionised_outflows_in_nearby_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. A. Riffel
We present the hot molecular and warm ionised gas kinematics for 33 nearby ($0.001\lesssim z\lesssim0.056$) X-ray selected active galaxies using the H$2 2.1218 \mu$m and Br$\gamma$ emission lines observed in the K-band with the Gemini Near-Infrared Field Spectrograph (NIFS). The observations cover the inner 0.04$-$2 kpc of each AGN at spatial resolutions of 4$-$250 pc with a velocity resolution of $\sigma{\rm inst}\approx$20 ${\rm km s^{-1}}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carnegie Supernova Project-I. Optical spectroscopy of stripped-envelope supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._optical_spectroscopy_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._optical_spectroscopy_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. D. Stritzinger
We present 170 optical spectra of 35 low-redshift stripped-envelope core-collapse supernovae observed by the Carnegie Supernova Project-I between 2004 and 2009. The data extend from as early as -19 days (d) prior to the epoch of B-band maximum to +322 d, with the vast majority obtained during the so-called photospheric phase covering the weeks around peak luminosity. In addition to histogram plots characterizing the red-shift distribution, number of spectra per object, and the phase distribution of the sample, spectroscopic classification is also provided following standard criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carnegie Supernova Project-I. Spectroscopic analysis of stripped-envelope supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._spectroscopic_analysis_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._spectroscopic_analysis_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Holmbo
An analysis leveraging 170 optical spectra of 35 stripped-envelope (SE) core-collapse supernovae observed by the Carnegie Supernova Project-I and published in a companion paper is presented. Mean template spectra are constructed for the SNe IIb, Ib and Ic sub-types and parent ions associated with designated spectral features are identified with the aid of the spectral synthesis code SYNAPPS. Our modeled mean spectra suggest the ~6150~\AA\ feature in SNe~IIb may have an underlying contribution due to silicon, while the same feature in some SNe Ib may have an underlying contribution due to hydrogen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Halo Mass-Temperature Relation for Clusters, Groups, and Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_halo_mass-temperature_relation_for_clusters_groups_and_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_halo_mass-temperature_relation_for_clusters_groups_and_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iurii Babyk
The halo mass-temperature relation for a sample of 216 galaxy clusters, groups, and individual galaxies observed by $Chandra$ X-ray Observatory is presented. Using accurate spectral measurements of their hot atmospheres, we derive the $M-T$ relation for systems with temperatures ranging between 0.4-15.0 keV. We measure the total mass of clusters, groups, and galaxies at radius $R_{2500}$, finding that the $M_{2500} \propto T^{\alpha}$ relation follows a power-law with $\alpha$ = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
