<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>globular cluster on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/globular-cluster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in globular cluster on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/globular-cluster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolved Eclipsing Binaries and the Age of the Open Cluster NGC 752</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolved_eclipsing_binaries_and_the_age_of_the_open_cluster_ngc_752/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolved_eclipsing_binaries_and_the_age_of_the_open_cluster_ngc_752/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eric L. Sandquist
We present analyses of improved photometric and spectroscopic observations for two detached eclipsing binaries at the turnoff of the open cluster NGC 752: the 1.01 day binary DS And and the 15.53 d BD $+$37 410. For DS And, we find $M_1 = 1.692\pm0.004\pm0.010 M_\odot$, $R_1 = 2.185\pm0.004\pm0.008 R_\odot$, $M_2 = 1.184\pm0.001\pm0.003 M_\odot$, and $R_2 = 1.200\pm0.003\pm0.005 R_\odot$. We either confirm or newly identify unusual characteristics of both stars in the binary: the primary star is found to be slightly hotter than the main sequence turn off and there is a more substantial discrepancy in its luminosity compared to models (model luminosities are too large by about 40%), while the secondary star is oversized and cooler compared to other main sequence stars in the same cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational scattering of the sterile neutrino halo dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_scattering_of_the_sterile_neutrino_halo_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_scattering_of_the_sterile_neutrino_halo_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Man Ho Chan
A recent study shows that gravitational scattering of dark matter, in the form of massive objects with mass $m \sim 10^3-10^4M_{\odot}$, could provide a possible solution to alleviate the small-scale structure problems of cold dark matter. The scattering cross section is velocity-dependent so that this scenario can explain why self-interaction of dark matter is significant in dwarf galaxies, but not in massive galaxies and galaxy clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HST and HSC Weak-lensing Study of the Equal-mass Dissociative Merger CIZA J0107.7&#43;5408</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_and_hsc_weak-lensing_study_of_the_equal-mass_dissociative_merger_ciza_j0107.7&#43;5408/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_and_hsc_weak-lensing_study_of_the_equal-mass_dissociative_merger_ciza_j0107.7&#43;5408/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyle Finner
A dissociative merger is formed by the interplay of ram pressure and gravitational forces, which can lead to a spatial displacement of the dark matter and baryonic components of the recently collided subclusters. CIZA J0107.7+5408 is a nearby (z=0.105) dissociative merger that hosts two X-ray brightness peaks and a bimodal galaxy distribution. Analyzing MMT/Hectospec observations, we investigate the line-of-sight and spatial distribution of cluster galaxies. Utilizing deep, high-resolution \textit{Hubble} Space Telescope Advanced Camera for Surveys imaging and large field-of-view Subaru Hyper-Suprime-Cam observations, we perform a weak-lensing analysis of CIZA J0107.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal-THINGS: The association and optical characterization of SNRs with HI holes in NGC 6946</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/metal-things_the_association_and_optical_characterization_of_snrs_with_hi_holes_in_ngc_6946/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/metal-things_the_association_and_optical_characterization_of_snrs_with_hi_holes_in_ngc_6946/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. A. Lara-Lopez
NGC~6946, also known as the `Fireworks&amp;rsquo; galaxy, is an unusual galaxy that hosts a total of 225 supernova remnant (SNR) candidates, including 147 optically identified with high [SII]/Ha line ratios. In addition, this galaxy shows prominent HI holes, which were analyzed in previous studies. Indeed, the connection between SNRs and HI holes together with their physical implications in the surrounding gas is worth of attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star formation in IC1396: Kinematics and subcluster structure revealed by Gaia</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_in_ic1396_kinematics_and_subcluster_structure_revealed_by_gaia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_in_ic1396_kinematics_and_subcluster_structure_revealed_by_gaia/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mara E. Pelayo-Baldárrago
We investigate the star formation history of the IC1396 region by studying its kinematics and completing the population census. We use multiwavelength data, combining optical spectroscopy (to identify and classify new members), near-infrared photometry (to trace shocks, jets, and outflows and the interactions between the cluster members and the cloud), along with Gaia EDR3 to identify new potential members in the multidimensional proper motion/parallax space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subhalo abundance matching using progenitor mass</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/subhalo_abundance_matching_using_progenitor_mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/subhalo_abundance_matching_using_progenitor_mass/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shogo Masaki
We propose a novel subhalo abundance matching (SHAM) model that uses the virial mass of the main progenitor of each (sub)halo $M_{\rm prog}$ as a proxy of the galaxy stellar mass $M_$ at the time of observation. This $M_{\rm prog}$ model predicts the two-point correlation functions depending on the choice of the epoch $z_{\rm prog}$ at which $M_\mathrm{prog}$ is measured. With $z_{\rm prog}$ as a fitting parameter, we apply the $M_{\rm prog}$ model to the latest observed angular correlation functions of galaxy samples at $z\simeq0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indirect Measurements of Gas Velocities in Galaxy Clusters: Effects of Ellipticity and Cluster Dynamic State</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/indirect_measurements_of_gas_velocities_in_galaxy_clusters_effects_of_ellipticity_and_cluster_dynamic_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/indirect_measurements_of_gas_velocities_in_galaxy_clusters_effects_of_ellipticity_and_cluster_dynamic_state/</guid>
      <description>First author: Irina Zhuravleva
While awaiting direct velocity measurement of gas motions in the hot intracluster medium, we rely on indirect probes, including gas perturbations in galaxy clusters. Using a sample of $\sim 80$ clusters in different dynamic states from Omega500 cosmological simulations, we examine scaling relations between the fluctuation amplitudes of gas density, $\delta\rho/\rho$, pressure, $\delta P/P$, X-ray surface brightness, Sunyaev-Zeldovich (SZ) y-parameter, and the characteristic Mach number of gas motions, $M_{\rm 1d}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Prestellar Cores in Radiation-magneto-turbulent Simulations of Molecular Clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/massive_prestellar_cores_in_radiation-magneto-turbulent_simulations_of_molecular_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/massive_prestellar_cores_in_radiation-magneto-turbulent_simulations_of_molecular_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chong-Chong He
We simulate the formation and collapse of prestellar cores at few-AU resolution in a set of radiation-magneto-hydrodynamic simulations of giant molecular clouds (GMCs) using the grid-based code RAMSES-RT. We adopt, for the first time to our best knowledge, realistic initial/boundary conditions by zooming-in onto individual massive prestellar cores within the GMC. We identify two distinct modes of fragmentation: &amp;ldquo;quasi-spherical&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;filamentary&amp;rdquo;. In both modes the fragments eventually become embedded in a quasi-steady accretion disk or toroid with radii ~ 500-5000 AU and opening angles $H/R \sim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New applications of Graph Neural Networks in Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_applications_of_graph_neural_networks_in_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_applications_of_graph_neural_networks_in_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Farida Farsian
Upcoming cosmological surveys will provide unprecedented amount of data, which will require innovative statistical methods to maximize the scientific exploitation. Standard cosmological analyses based on abundances, two-point and higher-order statistics of cosmic tracers have been widely used to investigate the properties of the cosmic web and Large Scale Structure. However, these statistics can only exploit a subset of the entire information content available. Our goal is thus to implement new data analysis techniques based on machine learning to extract cosmological information through forward modelling, by directly exploiting the spatial coordinates and other observed properties of galaxies and galaxy clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Outskirts of Dark Matter Haloes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_outskirts_of_dark_matter_haloes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_outskirts_of_dark_matter_haloes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alice Chen
Halo Models of large scale structure provide powerful and indispensable tools for phenomenological understanding of the clustering of matter in the Universe. While the halo model builds structures out of the superposition of haloes, defining halo profiles in their outskirts - beyond their virial radii - becomes increasingly ambiguous, as one cannot assign matter to individual haloes in a clear way. In this paper, we tackle this question by using numerical N-body simulations to find a systematic definition of mean halo profile that can be extended to large radii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the accuracy of likelihoods for cluster abundance cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_accuracy_of_likelihoods_for_cluster_abundance_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_accuracy_of_likelihoods_for_cluster_abundance_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Constantin Payerne
The abundance of galaxy clusters is a sensitive probe to the amplitude of matter density fluctuations, the total amount of matter in the Universe as well as its expansion history. Inferring correct values and accurate uncertainties of cosmological parameters requires accurate knowledge of cluster abundance statistics, encoded in the likelihood function. In this paper, we test the accuracy of cluster abundance likelihoods used in the literature, namely the Poisson and Gaussian likelihoods as well as the more complete description of the Gauss-Poisson Compound likelihood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death at watersheds: galaxy quenching in low-density environments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/death_at_watersheds_galaxy_quenching_in_low-density_environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/death_at_watersheds_galaxy_quenching_in_low-density_environments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maret Einasto
Our aim is to understand the effect of environment to galaxy quenching in various local and global environments. We focus on galaxies with very old stellar populations (VO galaxies), typically found in the centers of clusters and groups, and search for such galaxies in the lowest global density environments, watersheds between superclusters. We use the Sloan Digital Sky Survey MAIN galaxy sample to calculate the luminosity-density field and get global density field, to determine groups and filaments, and to obtain data on galaxy properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOGREEN: a critical assessment of environmental trends in cosmological hydrodynamical simulations at z ~ 1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gogreen_a_critical_assessment_of_environmental_trends_in_cosmological_hydrodynamical_simulations_at_z_~_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gogreen_a_critical_assessment_of_environmental_trends_in_cosmological_hydrodynamical_simulations_at_z_~_1/</guid>
      <description>First author: Egidijus Kukstas
Recent observations have shown that the environmental quenching of galaxies at z ~ 1 is qualitatively different to that in the local Universe. However, the physical origin of these differences has not yet been elucidated. In addition, while low-redshift comparisons between observed environmental trends and the predictions of cosmological hydrodynamical simulations are now routine, there have been relatively few comparisons at higher redshifts to date. Here we confront three state-of-the-art suites of simulations (BAHAMAS+MACSIS, EAGLE+Hydrangea, IllustrisTNG) with state-of-the-art observations of the field and cluster environments from the COSMOS/UltraVISTA and GOGREEN surveys, respectively, at z ~ 1 to assess the realism of the simulations and gain insight into the evolution of environmental quenching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Lemaitre-Tolman model and the mass and turn-around radius in group of galaxies II: the role of dark energy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improved_lemaitre-tolman_model_and_the_mass_and_turn-around_radius_in_group_of_galaxies_ii_the_role_of_dark_energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improved_lemaitre-tolman_model_and_the_mass_and_turn-around_radius_in_group_of_galaxies_ii_the_role_of_dark_energy/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Del Popolo
In this paper, we extend our previous study \cite{DelPopolo2021} on the Lemaitre-Tolman (LT) model showing how the prediction of the model changes when the equation of state parameter ($w$) of dark energy is modified. In the previous study, it was considered that dark energy was merely constituted by the cosmological constant. In this paper, as in the previous study, we also took into account the effect of angular momentum and dynamical friction ($J\eta$ LT model) that modifies the evolution of a perturbation, initially moving with the Hubble flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the giant radio galaxy length distribution with the LoTSS DR2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/measuring_the_giant_radio_galaxy_length_distribution_with_the_lotss_dr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/measuring_the_giant_radio_galaxy_length_distribution_with_the_lotss_dr2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martijn S. S. L. Oei
Radio galaxies are luminous structures created by the jets of supermassive black holes, and consist of atomic nuclei, relativistic electrons, and magnetic fields. In exceptional cases, radio galaxies attain cosmological, megaparsec extents - and thus turn into giants. Giants embody the most extreme known mechanism through which galaxies can impact the Cosmic Web around them. The triggers of giant growth remain a mystery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation pressure-driven outflows from dusty AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation_pressure-driven_outflows_from_dusty_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation_pressure-driven_outflows_from_dusty_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Arakawa
Radiation pressure-driven outflows from luminous accreting supermassive black holes are an important part of active galactic nucleus (AGN) feedback. The effective Eddington limit, based on absorption of radiation by dust, not electron scattering, is revealed in the plane of AGN absorption column density $N_{\mathrm{H}}$ as a function of Eddington fraction $\lambda_{\mathrm{Edd}} = L_{\mathrm{bol}}/L_{\mathrm{Edd}}$, where a lack of objects is seen in the region where the effective limit is exceeded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing ultra-high-energy cosmic ray acceleration with multi-messenger observations of the nearby GRB 980425/SN 1998bw</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_ray_acceleration_with_multi-messenger_observations_of_the_nearby_grb_980425_sn_1998bw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_ray_acceleration_with_multi-messenger_observations_of_the_nearby_grb_980425_sn_1998bw/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nestor Mirabal
The origin of ultra-high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) is one of the most mystifying issues in astroparticle physics. It has been suggested that gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are excellent acceleration sites for cosmic rays. The propagation of UHECRs from the GRB host galaxy to the Earth should generate delayed secondary photons and neutrinos. Here we present a dedicated search for delayed UHECR and neutrino emission centered around the position of nearby GRB 980425/SN 1998bw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic Confirmation of Two X-ray Diffuse and Massive Galaxy Clusters at Low Redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopic_confirmation_of_two_x-ray_diffuse_and_massive_galaxy_clusters_at_low_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopic_confirmation_of_two_x-ray_diffuse_and_massive_galaxy_clusters_at_low_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kaiyuan Chen
We present MMT spectroscopic observations of two massive galaxy cluster candidates at redshift $z\sim0.07$ that show extended and diffuse X-ray emission in the ROSAT All Sky Survey (RASS) images. The targets were selected from a previous catalog of 303 newly-identified cluster candidates with the similar properties using the intra-cluster medium emission. Using the new MMT Hectospec data and SDSS archival spectra, we identify a number of member galaxies for the two targets and confirm that they are galaxy clusters at $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: Semi-analytic galaxy formation models on the past lightcone</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_models_on_the_past_lightcone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_models_on_the_past_lightcone/</guid>
      <description>First author: Monica Barrera
Upcoming large galaxy surveys will subject the standard cosmological model, $\Lambda$CDM, to new precision tests. These can be tightened considerably if theoretical models of galaxy formation are available that can predict galaxy clustering and galaxy-galaxy lensing on the full range of measurable scales throughout volumes as large as those of the surveys and with sufficient flexibility that uncertain aspects of the underlying astrophysics can be marginalised over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Cosmological Parameters using the Cluster Mass-Richness Relation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_cosmological_parameters_using_the_cluster_mass-richness_relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_cosmological_parameters_using_the_cluster_mass-richness_relation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mohamed H. Abdullah
The cluster mass-richness relation (MRR) is an observationally efficient and potentially powerful cosmological tool for constraining the mean matter density of the universe and the amplitude of fluctuations using the cluster abundance technique. We derive the MRR relation using GalWCat19, a publicly available galaxy cluster catalog we created from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey-DR13 spectroscopic dataset. The MRR shows a tail at the low-richness end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the origin of stellar binary black hole mergers by detections of their lensed host galaxies and gravitational wave signals</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_origin_of_stellar_binary_black_hole_mergers_by_detections_of_their_lensed_host_galaxies_and_gravitational_wave_signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_origin_of_stellar_binary_black_hole_mergers_by_detections_of_their_lensed_host_galaxies_and_gravitational_wave_signals/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhiwei Chen
A significant number of stellar binary black hole (sBBH) mergers may be lensed and detected by the third generation gravitational wave (GW) detectors. Their lensed host galaxies may be detectable, which thus helps to accurately localize these sources and provide a new approach to study the origin of sBBHs. In this paper, we investigate the detectability of the lensed host galaxies for the lensed sBBH mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Metallicity of Cool Supergiant Formation. I. Effects on Stellar Mass Loss and Feedback</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/critical_metallicity_of_cool_supergiant_formation._i._effects_on_stellar_mass_loss_and_feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/critical_metallicity_of_cool_supergiant_formation._i._effects_on_stellar_mass_loss_and_feedback/</guid>
      <description>First author: Po-Sheng Ou
This paper systematically studies the relation between metallicity and mass loss of massive stars. We perform one-dimensional stellar evolution simulations and build a grid of $\sim$2000 models with initial masses ranging between 11 and 60 $M_{\odot}$ and absolute metallicities $Z$ between 0.00001 and 0.02. Steady-state winds, comprising hot main-sequence winds and cool supergiant winds, are the main drivers of the mass loss of massive stars in our models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAGLE-like simulation models do not solve the entropy core problem in groups and clusters of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eagle-like_simulation_models_do_not_solve_the_entropy_core_problem_in_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eagle-like_simulation_models_do_not_solve_the_entropy_core_problem_in_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Edoardo Altamura
Recent high-resolution cosmological hydrodynamic simulations run with a variety of codes systematically predict large amounts of entropy in the intra-cluster medium at low redshift, leading to flat entropy profiles and a suppressed cool-core population. This prediction is at odds with X-ray observations of groups and clusters. We use a new implementation of the EAGLE galaxy formation model to investigate the sensitivity of the central entropy and the shape of the profiles to changes in the sub-grid model applied to a suite of zoom-in cosmological simulations of a group of mass $M_{500} = 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First results from the JWST Early Release Science Program Q3D: Turbulent times in the life of a $z \sim 3$ extremely red quasar revealed by NIRSpec IFU</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_results_from_the_jwst_early_release_science_program_q3d_turbulent_times_in_the_life_of_a__z__sim_3__extremely_red_quasar_revealed_by_nirspec_ifu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_results_from_the_jwst_early_release_science_program_q3d_turbulent_times_in_the_life_of_a__z__sim_3__extremely_red_quasar_revealed_by_nirspec_ifu/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominika Wylezalek
Extremely red quasars, with bolometric luminosities exceeding $10^{47}$ erg s$^{-1}$, are a fascinating high-redshift population that is absent in the local universe. They are the best candidates for supermassive black holes accreting at rates at or above the Eddington limit, and they are associated with the most rapid and powerful outflows of ionized gas known to date. They are also hosted by massive galaxies. Here we present the first integral field unit (IFU) observations of a high-redshift quasar obtained by the Near Infrared Spectrograph (NIRSpec) on board the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), which targeted SDSSJ165202.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inflationary and phase-transitional primordial magnetic fields in galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inflationary_and_phase-transitional_primordial_magnetic_fields_in_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inflationary_and_phase-transitional_primordial_magnetic_fields_in_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Salome Mtchedlidze
Primordial magnetic fields (PMFs) are possible candidates for explaining the observed magnetic fields in galaxy clusters. Two competing scenarios of primordial magnetogenesis have been discussed in the literature: inflationary and phase-transitional. We study the amplification of both large- and small-scale correlated magnetic fields corresponding to inflation- and phase-transition-generated PMFs in a massive galaxy cluster. We employ high-resolution magnetohydrodynamic cosmological zoom-in simulations to resolve turbulent motions in the intracluster medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindling the First Stars: I. Dependence of Detectability of the First Stars with JWST on the Pop III Stellar Masses</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kindling_the_first_stars_i._dependence_of_detectability_of_the_first_stars_with_jwst_on_the_pop_iii_stellar_masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kindling_the_first_stars_i._dependence_of_detectability_of_the_first_stars_with_jwst_on_the_pop_iii_stellar_masses/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mia Sauda Bovill
The first Pop III stars formed out of primordial, metal free gas, in minihalos at z&amp;gt;20, and kickstarted the cosmic processes of reionizaton and enrichment. While these stars are likely more massive than their enriched counterparts, the current unknowns of their astrophysics include; when the first Pop III stars ignited, how massive they were, and when and how the era of the first stars ended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observational constraints on accelerators of ultra-high energy cosmic rays</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_constraints_on_accelerators_of_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_constraints_on_accelerators_of_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sullivan Marafico
We explore two generic hypotheses for tracing the sources of ultra-high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) in the Universe: star formation rate density or stellar mass density. For each scenario, we infer a set of constraints for the emission mechanisms in the accelerators, for their energetics and for the abundances of elements at escape from their environments. From these constraints, we generate sky maps above 40~EeV expected from a catalog that comprises 410,761 galaxies out to 350 Mpc and provides a near-infrared flux-limited sample to map both stellar mass and star formation rate over the full sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapster: a fast code for dynamical formation of black-hole binaries in dense star clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapster_a_fast_code_for_dynamical_formation_of_black-hole_binaries_in_dense_star_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapster_a_fast_code_for_dynamical_formation_of_black-hole_binaries_in_dense_star_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Konstantinos Kritos
Gravitational-wave observations have just started probing the properties of black-hole binary merger populations. The observation of binaries with very massive black holes and small mass ratios motivates the study of dense star clusters as astrophysical environments which can produce such events dynamically. In this paper we present Rapster (for &amp;ldquo;Rapid cluster evolution&amp;rdquo;), a new code designed to rapidly model binary black hole population synthesis and the evolution of star clusters based on simple, yet realistic prescriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading the tea leaves in the $M_{\rm bh}$-$M_{\rm *,sph}$ and $M_{\rm bh}$-$R_{\rm e,sph}$ diagrams: dry and gaseous mergers with remnant angular momentum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reading_the_tea_leaves_in_the__m__rm_bh_-_m__rm_sph__and__m__rm_bh_-_r__rm_esph__diagrams_dry_and_gaseous_mergers_with_remnant_angular_momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reading_the_tea_leaves_in_the__m__rm_bh_-_m__rm_sph__and__m__rm_bh_-_r__rm_esph__diagrams_dry_and_gaseous_mergers_with_remnant_angular_momentum/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alister W. Graham
We recently revealed that bulges and elliptical galaxies broadly define distinct, super-linear relations in the $M_{\rm bh}$-$M_{\rm *,sph}$ diagram, with the order-of-magnitude lower $M_{\rm bh}/M_{\rm *,sph}$ ratios in the elliptical galaxies due to major (disc-destroying, elliptical-building) dry mergers. Building on this, here we present a more nuanced picture. Galaxy mergers, in which the net orbital angular momentum does not cancel, can lead to systems with a rotating disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Disk Population in a Distant Massive Protocluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disk_population_in_a_distant_massive_protocluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disk_population_in_a_distant_massive_protocluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yu Cheng
The unprecedented angular resolution and sensitivity of ALMA makes it possible to unveil disk populations in distant ($&amp;gt;$2 kpc), embedded young cluster environments. We have conducted an observation towards the central region of the massive protocluster G286.21+0.16 at 1.3 mm. With a spatial resolution of 23 mas and a sensitivity of 15 $\rm \mu Jy~beam^{-1}$, we detect a total of 38 protostellar disks. These disks have dust masses ranging from about 53 to 1825 $M_\oplus$, assuming a dust temperature of 20 K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: An improved two-halo model for the galaxy-halo connection of red and blue galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_an_improved_two-halo_model_for_the_galaxy-halo_connection_of_red_and_blue_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_an_improved_two-halo_model_for_the_galaxy-halo_connection_of_red_and_blue_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Boryana Hadzhiyska
Approximate methods to populate dark matter halos with galaxies are of great utility to large galaxy surveys. However, the limitations of simple halo occupation models (HODs) preclude a full use of small-scale galaxy clustering data and call for more sophisticated models. We study two galaxy populations, luminous red galaxies (LRGs) and star-forming emission-line galaxies (ELGs), at two epochs, $z=1$ and $z=0$, in the large volume, high-resolution hydrodynamical simulation of the MillenniumTNG project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: High-precision predictions for matter clustering and halo statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_high-precision_predictions_for_matter_clustering_and_halo_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_high-precision_predictions_for_matter_clustering_and_halo_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: César Hernández-Aguayo
Cosmological inference with large galaxy surveys requires theoretical models that combine precise predictions for large-scale structure with robust and flexible galaxy formation modelling throughout a sufficiently large cosmic volume. Here, we introduce the MillenniumTNG (MTNG) project which combines the hydrodynamical galaxy formation model of IllustrisTNG with the large volume of the Millennium simulation. Our largest hydrodynamic simulation, covering (500 Mpc/h)^3 = (740 Mpc)^3, is complemented by a suite of dark-matter-only simulations with up to 4320^3 dark matter particles (a mass resolution of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: Inferring cosmology from galaxy clustering with accelerated N-body scaling and subhalo abundance matching</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_inferring_cosmology_from_galaxy_clustering_with_accelerated_n-body_scaling_and_subhalo_abundance_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_inferring_cosmology_from_galaxy_clustering_with_accelerated_n-body_scaling_and_subhalo_abundance_matching/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergio Contreras
We introduce a novel technique for constraining cosmological parameters and galaxy assembly bias using non-linear redshift-space clustering of galaxies. We scale cosmological N-body simulations and insert galaxies with the SubHalo Abundance Matching extended (SHAMe) empirical model to generate over 175,000 clustering measurements spanning all relevant cosmological and SHAMe parameter values. We then build an emulator capable of reproducing the projected galaxy correlation function at the monopole, quadrupole and hexadecapole level for separations between $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: Refining the one-halo model of red and blue galaxies at different redshifts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_refining_the_one-halo_model_of_red_and_blue_galaxies_at_different_redshifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_refining_the_one-halo_model_of_red_and_blue_galaxies_at_different_redshifts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Boryana Hadzhiyska
Luminous red galaxies (LRGs) and blue star-forming emission-line galaxies (ELGs) are key tracers of large-scale structure used by cosmological surveys. Theoretical predictions for such data are often done via simplistic models for the galaxy-halo connection. In this work, we use the large, high-fidelity hydrodynamical simulation of the MillenniumTNG project (MTNG) to inform a new phenomenological approach for obtaining an accurate and flexible galaxy-halo model on small scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: The hydrodynamical full physics simulation and a first look at its galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_hydrodynamical_full_physics_simulation_and_a_first_look_at_its_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_hydrodynamical_full_physics_simulation_and_a_first_look_at_its_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ruediger Pakmor
Cosmological simulations are an important theoretical pillar for understanding nonlinear structure formation in our Universe and for relating it to observations on large scales. In several papers, we introduce our MillenniumTNG (MTNG) project that provides a comprehensive set of high-resolution, large volume simulations of cosmic structure formation aiming to better understand physical processes on large scales and to help interpreting upcoming large-scale galaxy surveys. We here focus on the full physics box MTNG740 that computes a volume of $(740,\mathrm{Mpc})^3$ with a baryonic mass resolution of $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: The large-scale clustering of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_large-scale_clustering_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_large-scale_clustering_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sownak Bose
Modern redshift surveys are tasked with mapping out the galaxy distribution over enormous distance scales. Existing hydrodynamical simulations, however, do not reach the volumes needed to match upcoming surveys. We present results for the clustering of galaxies using a new, large volume hydrodynamical simulation as part of the MillenniumTNG (MTNG) project. With a computational volume that is $\approx15$ times larger than the next largest such simulation currently available, we show that MTNG is able to accurately reproduce the observed clustering of galaxies as a function of stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is zero spatial curvature special?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/why_is_zero_spatial_curvature_special/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/why_is_zero_spatial_curvature_special/</guid>
      <description>First author: Raul Jimenez
Evidence for almost spatial flatness of the Universe has been provided from several observational probes, including the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Baryon Acoustic Oscillations (BAO) from galaxy clustering data. However, other than inflation, and in this case only in the limit of infinite time, there is no strong a priori motivation for a spatially flat Universe. Using the renormalization group (RG) technique in curved spacetime, we present in this work a theoretical motivation for spatial flatness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic infall in the outskirst of clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/anisotropic_infall_in_the_outskirst_of_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/anisotropic_infall_in_the_outskirst_of_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Juan Manuel Salerno
We analyse the connection between the star formation quenching of galaxies and their location in theoutskirts of clusters in the redshift range $z=[0,2]$ by estimating the fraction of red galaxies. More specifically, we focus on galaxies that infall isotropically from those that are infalling alongside filaments. We use a sample of galaxies obtained from the semi-analytic model of galaxy formation SAG applied to the MultiDark simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemically Peculiar Stars in the Open Cluster Stock 2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemically_peculiar_stars_in_the_open_cluster_stock_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemically_peculiar_stars_in_the_open_cluster_stock_2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laia Casamiquela
The recently re-discovered open cluster Stock 2, located roughly 375 pc away and about 400 Myr old, has the potential to be an exciting new testbed for our understanding of stellar evolution. We present results from a spectroscopic campaign to characterize stars near the cluster&amp;rsquo;s main-sequence turnoff; our goal is to identify candidate chemically peculiar stars among the cluster&amp;rsquo;s A stars. We obtained echelle spectra for 64 cluster members with ESPaDOnS on the 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO($J$=1-0) mapping survey of 64 galaxies in the Fornax cluster with the ALMA Morita array</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co_j_1-0_mapping_survey_of_64_galaxies_in_the_fornax_cluster_with_the_alma_morita_array/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co_j_1-0_mapping_survey_of_64_galaxies_in_the_fornax_cluster_with_the_alma_morita_array/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kana Morokuma-Matsui
We conduct a $^{12}$C$^{16}$O($J$=1-0) (hereafter CO) mapping survey of 64 galaxies in the Fornax cluster using the ALMA Morita array in cycle 5. CO emission is detected from 23 out of the 64 galaxies. Our sample includes dwarf, spiral and elliptical galaxies with stellar masses of $M_{\rm star}\sim10^{6.3-11.6}$~M$\odot$. The achieved beam size and sensitivity are $15&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;\times8&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;$ and $\sim12$~mJy~beam$^{-1}$ at the velocity resolution of $\sim10$~km~s$^{-1}$, respectively. We study the cold-gas (molecular- and atomic-gas) properties of 38 subsamples with $M{\rm star}&amp;gt;10^9$~M$_\odot$ combined with literature HI data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Estimation of the Binding Energies of POx and HPOx (x=2,3) Species</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/computational_estimation_of_the_binding_energies_of_pox_and_hpox_x23_species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/computational_estimation_of_the_binding_energies_of_pox_and_hpox_x23_species/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elettra L. Piacentino
The distribution of molecules between the gas and solid phase during star and planet formation, determines the trajectory of gas and grain surface chemistry, as well as the delivery of elements to nascent planets. This distribution is primarily set by the binding energies of different molecules to water ice surfaces. We computationally estimated the binding energies of ten astrochemically relevant P-bearing species on water surface, we also validate our method for 20 species with known binding energies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Four: A Neural Network&#39;s Search For Polar Spring-time Fans On Mars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planet_four_a_neural_networks_search_for_polar_spring-time_fans_on_mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planet_four_a_neural_networks_search_for_polar_spring-time_fans_on_mars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mark D. McDonnell
Dark deposits visible from orbit appear in the Martian south polar region during the springtime. These are thought to form from explosive jets of carbon dioxide gas breaking through the thawing seasonal ice cap, carrying dust and dirt which is then deposited onto the ice as dark &amp;lsquo;blotches&amp;rsquo;, or blown by the surface winds into streaks or &amp;lsquo;fans&amp;rsquo;. We investigate machine learning (ML) methods for automatically identifying these seasonal features in High Resolution Imaging Science Experiment (HiRISE) satellite imagery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchrotron emission from virial shocks around stacked OVRO-LWA galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synchrotron_emission_from_virial_shocks_around_stacked_ovro-lwa_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synchrotron_emission_from_virial_shocks_around_stacked_ovro-lwa_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kuan-Chou Hou
Galaxy clusters accrete mass through large scale, strong, structure-formation shocks. Such a virial shock is thought to deposit fractions $\xi_e$ and $\xi_B$ of the thermal energy in cosmic-ray electrons (CREs) and magnetic fields, respectively, thus generating a leptonic virial ring. However, the expected synchrotron signal was not convincingly established until now. We stack low-frequency radio data from the OVRO-LWA around the 44 most massive, high latitude, extended MCXC clusters, enhancing the ring sensitivity by rescaling clusters to their characteristic, $R_{500}$ radii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Host Galaxies of Hybrid Morphology Radio Sources</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_host_galaxies_of_hybrid_morphology_radio_sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_host_galaxies_of_hybrid_morphology_radio_sources/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andra Stroe
Based on their differing radio morphologies, powerful radio galaxies can be separated into the Fanaroff-Riley I (FR-I) and II (FR-II) classes. Hybrid morphology radio sources (HyMoRS) contain morphologies consistent with each type of jet on either side: a powerful, highly relativistic FR-II-like jet terminating in a hotspot on one side and an FRI-like plume on the other. HyMoRS present a unique opportunity to study the conditions which give rise to the dichotomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second set of pulsar discoveries by CHIME/FRB/Pulsar: 14 Rotating Radio Transients and 7 pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_second_set_of_pulsar_discoveries_by_chime_frb_pulsar_14_rotating_radio_transients_and_7_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_second_set_of_pulsar_discoveries_by_chime_frb_pulsar_14_rotating_radio_transients_and_7_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fengqiu Adam Dong
The Canadian Hydrogen Mapping Experiment (CHIME) is a radio telescope located in British Columbia, Canada. The large field of view (FOV) of $\sim$ 200 square degrees has enabled the CHIME/FRB instrument to produce the largest FRB catalog to date. The large FOV also allows CHIME/FRB to be an exceptional pulsar and Rotating Radio Transient (RRAT) finding machine, despite saving only the metadata information of incoming Galactic events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gaia-ESO Survey: old super metal-rich visitors from the inner Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gaia-eso_survey_old_super_metal-rich_visitors_from_the_inner_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gaia-eso_survey_old_super_metal-rich_visitors_from_the_inner_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. L. L. Dantas
We report the identification of a set of old super metal-rich dwarf stars with orbits of low eccentricity that reach a maximum height from the Galactic plane between ~0.5-1.5 kpc. We discuss their properties to understand their origins. We use data from the internal data release 6 of the Gaia-ESO Survey. We selected stars observed at high resolution with abundances of 21 species of 18 individual elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving a merger in a hyper-luminous submillimeter galaxy at z=2.82</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolving_a_merger_in_a_hyper-luminous_submillimeter_galaxy_at_z2.82/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolving_a_merger_in_a_hyper-luminous_submillimeter_galaxy_at_z2.82/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. W. Perry
We present the resolved properties of the $z=2.82$ Hyper Luminous Infrared Galaxy (HyLIRG) HS170850.1, the brightest 850$\mu$m source found in the SCUBA-2 followup to the Keck Baryonic Structure Survey fields (S${\rm 850 \mu m}=$19.5 mJy), and amongst the most luminous starbursts known at any redshift. Using the IRAM-NOEMA interferometer in the highest resolution A-configuration, we resolve the source into two components separated by $\sim$8 kpc, visible as blue shifted and red shifted $^{12}$CO(5-4) lines, exhibiting the expected kinematic properties of a major merger between two gas-rich galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dense mini-Neptune orbiting the bright young star HD 18599</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_dense_mini-neptune_orbiting_the_bright_young_star_hd_18599/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_dense_mini-neptune_orbiting_the_bright_young_star_hd_18599/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jose I. Vines
Very little is known about the young planet population because the detection of small planets orbiting young stars is obscured by the effects of stellar activity and fast rotation which mask planets within radial velocity and transit data sets. The few planets that have been discovered in young clusters generally orbit stars too faint for any detailed follow-up analysis. Here we present the characterization of a new mini-Neptune planet orbiting the bright (V=9) and nearby K2 dwarf star, HD 18599.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An empirical method for mitigating an excess up-scattering mass bias on weak lensing mass estimate for shear-selected cluster samples</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_empirical_method_for_mitigating_an_excess_up-scattering_mass_bias_on_weak_lensing_mass_estimate_for_shear-selected_cluster_samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_empirical_method_for_mitigating_an_excess_up-scattering_mass_bias_on_weak_lensing_mass_estimate_for_shear-selected_cluster_samples/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takashi Hamana
An excess up-scattering mass bias on weak lensing cluster mass estimate is a statistical bias that an observed weak lensing mass ($M_{\rm obs}$) of a cluster of galaxies is, in a statistical sense, larger than its true mass ($M_{\rm true}$) because of a higher chance of up-scattering than that of down-scattering due to random noises in a weak lensing cluster shear profile. This non-symmetric scattering probability is caused by a monotonically decreasing cluster mass function with increasing mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Studies from HSC-SSP Tomographic Weak Lensing Peak Abundances</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_studies_from_hsc-ssp_tomographic_weak_lensing_peak_abundances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_studies_from_hsc-ssp_tomographic_weak_lensing_peak_abundances/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiangkun Liu
We perform weak lensing tomographic peak studies using the first-year shear data from Hyper Suprime-Cam Subaru Strategic Program (HSC-SSP) survey. The effective area used in our analyses after field selection, mask and boundary exclusions is $\sim 58 \deg^2$. The source galaxies are divided into low- and high-redshift bins with $0.2\le z_p\le0.85$ and $0.85\le z_p\le1.5$, respectively. We utilize our halo-based theoretical peak model including the projection effect of large-scale structures to derive cosmological constraints from the observed tomographic high peak abundances with the signal-to-noise ratio in the range of $\nu_{\rm N}=[3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perturbation theory with dispersion and higher cumulants: framework and linear theory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_framework_and_linear_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_framework_and_linear_theory/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mathias Garny
The standard perturbation theory (SPT) approach to gravitational clustering is based on a fluid approximation of the underlying Vlasov-Poisson dynamics, taking only the zeroth and first cumulant of the phase-space distribution function into account (density and velocity fields). This assumption breaks down when dark matter particle orbits cross and leads to well-known problems, e.g. an anomalously large backreaction of small-scale modes onto larger scales that compromises predictivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perturbation theory with dispersion and higher cumulants: non-linear regime</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_non-linear_regime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbation_theory_with_dispersion_and_higher_cumulants_non-linear_regime/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mathias Garny
We present non-linear solutions of Vlasov Perturbation Theory (VPT), describing gravitational clustering of collisionless dark matter with dispersion and higher cumulants induced by orbit crossing. We show that VPT can be cast into a form that is formally analogous to standard perturbation theory (SPT), but including additional perturbation variables, non-linear interactions, and a more complex propagation. VPT non-linear kernels have a crucial decoupling property: for fixed total momentum, the kernels becomes strongly suppressed when any of the individual momenta cross the dispersion scale into the non-linear regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ly$α$, CIV, and HeII nebulae around J1000&#43;0234: a galaxy pair at the center of a galaxy overdensity at $z=4.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_ly_%CE%B1__civ_and_heii_nebulae_around_j1000&#43;0234_a_galaxy_pair_at_the_center_of_a_galaxy_overdensity_at__z4.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_ly_%CE%B1__civ_and_heii_nebulae_around_j1000&#43;0234_a_galaxy_pair_at_the_center_of_a_galaxy_overdensity_at__z4.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. F. Jiménez-Andrade
Ly$\alpha$ emission extending over $\gtrsim,\rm 10,kiloparsec,(kpc)$ around dusty, massive starbursts at $z\gtrsim3$ might represent a short-lived phase in the evolution of present-day, massive quiescent galaxies. To obtain empirical constraints on this emerging scenario, we present Ly$\alpha$, CIV, and HeII observations taken with the Multi Unit Spectroscopic Explorer towards J1000$+$0234: a galaxy pair at $z=4.5$ composed of a low-mass starburst (J1000$+$0234$-$South) neighboring a massive Submillimeter Galaxy (SMG; J1000$+$0234$-$North) that harbors a rotationally supported gas disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond $Λ$CDM constraints from the full shape clustering measurements from BOSS and eBOSS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond__%CE%BB_cdm_constraints_from_the_full_shape_clustering_measurements_from_boss_and_eboss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond__%CE%BB_cdm_constraints_from_the_full_shape_clustering_measurements_from_boss_and_eboss/</guid>
      <description>First author: Agne Semenaite
We analyse the full shape of anisotropic clustering measurements from the extended Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic survey (eBOSS) quasar sample together with the combined galaxy sample from the Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey (BOSS). We obtain constraints on the cosmological parameters independent of the Hubble parameter $h$ for the extensions of the $\Lambda$CDM models, focusing on cosmologies with free dark energy equation of state parameter $w$. We combine the clustering constraints with those from the latest CMB data from Planck to obtain joint constraints for these cosmologies for $w$ and the additional extension parameters - its time evolution $w_{\rm{a}}$, the physical curvature density $\omega_{K}$ and the neutrino mass sum $\sum m_{\nu}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of hot galactic winds launched from non-uniform starburst cores</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_of_hot_galactic_winds_launched_from_non-uniform_starburst_cores/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_of_hot_galactic_winds_launched_from_non-uniform_starburst_cores/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dustin D. Nguyen
The galactic wind model of Chevalier1985 (CC85) assumes $\textit{uniform}$ energy and mass-injection within the starburst galaxy nucleus. However, the structure of nuclear star clusters, bulges, and star-forming knots are inherently non-uniform. We generalize to cases with non-uniform energy/mass injection that scale as $r^{-\Delta}$ within the starburst volume $R$, providing solutions for $\Delta = 0$, 1/2, 1, 3/2, and 2. In marked contrast with the CC85 model ($\Delta=0$), which predicts zero velocity at the center, for a singular isothermal sphere profile ($\Delta=2$), we find that the flow maintains a $\textit{constant}$ Mach number of $\mathcal{M}=\sqrt{3/5} \simeq 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of galaxy intrinsic alignment on weak lensing peak statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_galaxy_intrinsic_alignment_on_weak_lensing_peak_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_galaxy_intrinsic_alignment_on_weak_lensing_peak_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tianyu Zhang
The galaxy intrinsic alignment (IA) is a dominant source of systematics in weak lensing (WL) studies. In this paper, by employing large simulations with semi-analytical galaxy formation, we investigate the IA effects on WL peak statistics. Different simulated source galaxy samples of different redshift distributions are constructed, where both WL shear and IA signals are included. Convergence reconstruction and peak statistics are then performed for these samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the cosmological synergy between galaxy cluster and cosmic void number counts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_cosmological_synergy_between_galaxy_cluster_and_cosmic_void_number_counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_cosmological_synergy_between_galaxy_cluster_and_cosmic_void_number_counts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Davide Pelliciari
Galaxy clusters and cosmic voids are the most extreme objects of our Universe in terms of mass and size, tracing two opposite sides of the large-scale matter density field. By studying their abundance as a function of their mass and radius, respectively, i.e. the halo mass function (HMF) and void size function (VSF), it is possible to achieve fundamental constraints on the cosmological model. While the HMF has already been extensively exploited providing robust constraints on the main cosmological model parameters (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretation of multi-TeV photons from GRB221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpretation_of_multi-tev_photons_from_grb221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpretation_of_multi-tev_photons_from_grb221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ali Baktash
The nearby GRB22109A at redshift $z=0.1505$ has been observed up to a maximum energy of 18 TeV with the LHAASO air shower array. The expected optical depth for a photon with energy $E_\gamma=18$ TeV varies between 9.2 and 27.1 according to existing models of the extra-galactic background light (EBL) in the relevant mid infra-red range. The resulting suppression of the flux in several EBL models makes it unlikely that this photon could have been observed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for compact objects in the single-lined spectroscopic binaries of the young Galactic cluster NGC 6231</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_compact_objects_in_the_single-lined_spectroscopic_binaries_of_the_young_galactic_cluster_ngc_6231/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_compact_objects_in_the_single-lined_spectroscopic_binaries_of_the_young_galactic_cluster_ngc_6231/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Banyard
Recent evolutionary computations predict that a few percent of massive OB stars in binary systems should have a dormant BH companion. Despite several reported X-ray quiet OB+BH systems over the last couple of years, finding them with certainty remains challenging. These have great importance as they can be gravitational wave (GW) source progenitors, and are landmark systems in constraining supernova kick physics. This work aims to characterise the hidden companions to the single-lined spectroscopic binaries (SB1s) in the B star population of the young open Galactic cluster NGC 6231 to find candidate systems for harbouring compact object companions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Planck clusters in the LOFAR sky. III. LoTSS-DR2: Dynamic states and density fluctuations of the intracluster medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_planck_clusters_in_the_lofar_sky._iii._lotss-dr2_dynamic_states_and_density_fluctuations_of_the_intracluster_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_planck_clusters_in_the_lofar_sky._iii._lotss-dr2_dynamic_states_and_density_fluctuations_of_the_intracluster_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: X. Zhang
The footprint of LoTSS-DR2 covers 309 PSZ2 galaxy clusters, 83 of which host a radio halo and 26 host a radio relic(s). It provides us an excellent opportunity to statistically study the properties of extended cluster radio sources, especially their connection with merging activities. We aim to quantify cluster dynamic states to investigate their relation with the occurrence of extended radio sources. We also search for connections between intracluster medium (ICM) turbulence and nonthermal characteristics of radio halos in the LoTSS-DR2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudy with A Chance of Rain: Accretion Braking of Cold Clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cloudy_with_a_chance_of_rain_accretion_braking_of_cold_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cloudy_with_a_chance_of_rain_accretion_braking_of_cold_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brent Tan
Understanding the survival, growth and dynamics of cold gas is fundamental to galaxy formation. While there has been a plethora of work on `wind tunnel&#39; simulations that study such cold gas in winds, the infall of this gas under gravity is at least equally important, and fundamentally different since cold gas can never entrain. Instead, velocity shear increases and remains unrelenting. If these clouds are growing, they can experience a drag force due to the accretion of low momentum gas, which dominates over ram pressure drag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decaying Dark Matter and Lyman-$α$ forest constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/decaying_dark_matter_and_lyman-_%CE%B1__forest_constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/decaying_dark_matter_and_lyman-_%CE%B1__forest_constraints/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lea Fuß
Decaying Cold Dark Matter (DCDM) is a model that is currently under investigation regarding primarily the $S_8$ tension between cosmic microwave background (CMB) and certain large-scale structure measurements. The decay into one massive and one (or more) massless daughter particle(s) leads to a suppression of the power spectrum in the late universe that depends on the relative mass splitting $\epsilon=(1-m^2/M^2)/2$ between the mother and massive daughter particle as well as the lifetime $\tau$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST&#39;s PEARLS: a new lens model for ACT-CL J0102$-$4915, &#34;EL Gordo&#39;&#39;, and the first red supergiant star at cosmological distances discovered by JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwsts_pearls_a_new_lens_model_for_act-cl_j0102_-_4915_el_gordo_and_the_first_red_supergiant_star_at_cosmological_distances_discovered_by_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwsts_pearls_a_new_lens_model_for_act-cl_j0102_-_4915_el_gordo_and_the_first_red_supergiant_star_at_cosmological_distances_discovered_by_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jose M. Diego
The first JWST data on the massive colliding cluster El Gordo confirm 23 known families of multiply lensed images and identify 8 new members of these families. Based on these families, which have been confirmed spectroscopically by MUSE, we derived an initial lens model. This model guided the identification of 37 additional families of multiply lensed galaxies, among which 28 are entirely new systems, and 9 were previously known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Synchronized Globular Cluster Formation over Supra-galactic Scales: A Virgo-Centaurus Group Connection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_synchronized_globular_cluster_formation_over_supra-galactic_scales_a_virgo-centaurus_group_connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_synchronized_globular_cluster_formation_over_supra-galactic_scales_a_virgo-centaurus_group_connection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Juan Carlos Forte
This work reports the detection of a multi peaked colour pattern in the integrated colours distribution of globular clusters associated to the giant elliptical galaxy NGC 4486, using Next Generation Virgo Survey data. This feature is imprinted on the well known bimodal colour distribution of these clusters. Remarkably, the pattern is similar to that found in previous works based on photometry from the HST Advanced Camera Virgo Survey, in less massive Virgo galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAH emission from star-forming galaxies in JWST mid-infrared imaging of the lensing cluster SMACS J0723.3$-$7327</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pah_emission_from_star-forming_galaxies_in_jwst_mid-infrared_imaging_of_the_lensing_cluster_smacs_j0723.3_-_7327/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pah_emission_from_star-forming_galaxies_in_jwst_mid-infrared_imaging_of_the_lensing_cluster_smacs_j0723.3_-_7327/</guid>
      <description>First author: Danial Langeroodi
The mid-infrared spectra of star-forming galaxies (SFGs) are characterized by characteristic broad PAH emission features at 3$-$20 $\mu$m. As these features are redshifted, they are predicted to dominate the flux at specific mid-infrared wavelengths, leading to substantial redshift-dependent color variations in broad-band photometry. The advent of JWST for the first time allows the study of this effect for normal SFGs. Based on spectral energy distribution templates, we here present tracks in mid-infrared (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An innovative and automated method for vortex identification. I. Description of the SWIRL algorithm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_innovative_and_automated_method_for_vortex_identification._i._description_of_the_swirl_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_innovative_and_automated_method_for_vortex_identification._i._description_of_the_swirl_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>First author: José Roberto Canivete Cuissa
Context. A universally accepted definition of what a vortex is has not yet been reached. Therefore, we lack an unambiguous and rigorous method for the identification of vortices in fluid flows. Such a method would be necessary to conduct robust statistical studies on vortices in highly dynamical and turbulent systems, such as the solar atmosphere. Aims. We aim to develop an innovative and robust automated methodology for the identification of vortices based on local and global characteristics of the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clues to the formation of Liller 1 from modeling its complex star formation history</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/clues_to_the_formation_of_liller_1_from_modeling_its_complex_star_formation_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/clues_to_the_formation_of_liller_1_from_modeling_its_complex_star_formation_history/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Dalessandro
Liller 1 and Terzan 5 are two massive systems in the Milky-Way bulge hosting populations characterized by significantly different ages ($\Delta t&amp;gt;7-8$ Gyr) and metallicities ($\Delta$[Fe/H]$\sim1$ dex). Their origin is still strongly debated in the literature and all formation scenarios proposed so far require some level of fine-tuning. The detailed star formation histories (SFHs) of these systems may represent an important piece of information to assess their origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining gravity with synergies between radio and optical cosmological surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_gravity_with_synergies_between_radio_and_optical_cosmological_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_gravity_with_synergies_between_radio_and_optical_cosmological_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Santiago Casas
In this work we present updated forecasts on parameterised modifications of gravity that can capture deviations of the behaviour of cosmological density perturbations beyond $\Lambda$CDM. For these forecasts we adopt the SKA Observatory (SKAO) as a benchmark for future cosmological surveys at radio frequencies, combining a continuum survey for weak lensing and angular galaxy clustering with an HI galaxy survey for spectroscopic galaxy clustering that can detect baryon acoustic oscillations and redshift space distortions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Energy Survey Year 3 Results: Measurement of the Baryon Acoustic Oscillations with Three-dimensional Clustering</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_energy_survey_year_3_results_measurement_of_the_baryon_acoustic_oscillations_with_three-dimensional_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_energy_survey_year_3_results_measurement_of_the_baryon_acoustic_oscillations_with_three-dimensional_clustering/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. C. Chan
The three-dimensional correlation function offers an effective way to summarize the correlation of the large-scale structure even for imaging galaxy surveys. We have applied the projected three-dimensional correlation function, $\xi_{\rm p}$ to measure the Baryonic Acoustic Oscillations (BAO) scale on the first-three years Dark Energy Survey data. The sample consists of about 7 million galaxies in the redshift range $ 0.6 &amp;lt; z_{\rm p } &amp;lt; 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular Cluster UVIT legacy Survey (GlobUleS) III. Omega Centauri in Far-Ultraviolet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_uvit_legacy_survey_globules_iii._omega_centauri_in_far-ultraviolet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_uvit_legacy_survey_globules_iii._omega_centauri_in_far-ultraviolet/</guid>
      <description>First author: Deepthi S. Prabhu
We present the first comprehensive study of the most massive globular cluster Omega Centauri in the far-ultraviolet (FUV) extending from the center to ~ 28% of the tidal radius using the Ultraviolet Imaging Telescope aboard AstroSat. A comparison of the FUV-optical color-magnitude diagrams with available canonical models reveals that the horizontal branch (HB) stars bluer than the knee (hHBs) and the white dwarfs (WDs) are fainter in the FUV by ~ 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOALS-JWST: Revealing the Buried Star Clusters in the Luminous Infrared Galaxy VV 114</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/goals-jwst_revealing_the_buried_star_clusters_in_the_luminous_infrared_galaxy_vv_114/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/goals-jwst_revealing_the_buried_star_clusters_in_the_luminous_infrared_galaxy_vv_114/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sean T. Linden
We present the results of a {\it James Webb Space Telescope} NIRCam investigation into the young massive star cluster (YMC) population in the luminous infrared galaxy VV 114. We identify 374 compact YMC candidates with a $S/N \geq 3$, 5, and 5 at F150W, F200W, and F356W respectively. A direct comparison with our {\it HST} cluster catalog reveals that $\sim 20%$ of these sources are undetected at optical wavelengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational lensing of pulsars as a probe of dark matter halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_lensing_of_pulsars_as_a_probe_of_dark_matter_halos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_lensing_of_pulsars_as_a_probe_of_dark_matter_halos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francesca von Braun-Bates
A particular open problem in cosmology is whether dark matter on small scales is clumpy, forming gravitationally-bound halos distributed within the Galaxy. The practical difficulties inherent in testing this hypothesis stem from the fact that, on astrophysical scales, dark matter is solely observable via its gravitational interaction with other objects. This thesis presents a gravitational-lensing-based solution for the mapping and characterisation of low-mass, dark matter halos via their signature in millisecond pulsar observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing Patchy Reionization with the Void Probability Function of Lyman-$α$ Emitters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_patchy_reionization_with_the_void_probability_function_of_lyman-_%CE%B1__emitters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_patchy_reionization_with_the_void_probability_function_of_lyman-_%CE%B1__emitters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lucia A. Perez
We probe what constraints for the global ionized hydrogen fraction the Void Probability Function (VPF) clustering can give for the Lyman-Alpha Galaxies in the Epoch of Reionization (LAGER) narrowband survey as a function of area. Neutral hydrogen acts like a fog for Lyman-alpha emission, and measuring the drop in the luminosity function of Lyman-$\alpha$ emitters (LAEs) has been used to constrain the ionization fraction in narrowband surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star formation history and transition epoch of cluster galaxies based on the Horizon-AGN simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_history_and_transition_epoch_of_cluster_galaxies_based_on_the_horizon-agn_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_history_and_transition_epoch_of_cluster_galaxies_based_on_the_horizon-agn_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Seyoung Jeon
Cluster galaxies exhibit substantially lower star formation rates than field galaxies today, but it is conceivable that clusters were sites of more active star formation in the early universe. Herein, we present an interpretation of the star formation history (SFH) of group/cluster galaxies based on the large-scale cosmological hydrodynamic simulation, Horizon-AGN. We find that massive galaxies in general have small values of e-folding timescales of star formation decay (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracer-Field Cross-Correlations with $k$-Nearest Neighbor Distributions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer-field_cross-correlations_with__k_-nearest_neighbor_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer-field_cross-correlations_with__k_-nearest_neighbor_distributions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arka Banerjee
In astronomy and cosmology, significant effort is devoted to characterizing and understanding spatial cross-correlations between points - e.g. galaxy positions, high energy neutrino arrival directions, X-ray and AGN sources, and continuous field - e.g. weak lensing and Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) maps. Recently, we introduced the $k$-nearest neighbor formalism to better characterize the clustering of discrete (point) datasets. Here we extend it to the point-field cross-correlation analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERTICO IV: Environmental Effects on the Gas Distribution and Star Formation Efficiency of Virgo Cluster Spirals</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_iv_environmental_effects_on_the_gas_distribution_and_star_formation_efficiency_of_virgo_cluster_spirals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_iv_environmental_effects_on_the_gas_distribution_and_star_formation_efficiency_of_virgo_cluster_spirals/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vicente Villanueva
We measure the molecular-to-atomic gas ratio, $R_{\rm mol}$, and the star formation rate (SFR) per unit molecular gas mass, SFE${\rm mol}$, in 38 nearby galaxies selected from the Virgo Environment Traced in CO (VERTICO) survey. We stack ALMA $^{12}$CO(J=2-1) spectra coherently using \hi\ velocities from the VIVA survey to detect faint CO emission out to galactocentric radii $r{\rm gal} \sim 1.2,r_{25}$. We determine the scale-lengths for the molecular and stellar components, finding a $\sim$3:5 relation between them, and indicating that CO emission tends to be more centrally concentrated than stellar mass in VERTICO galaxies when compared to field galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel generative method for star clusters from hydro-dynamical simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_novel_generative_method_for_star_clusters_from_hydro-dynamical_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_novel_generative_method_for_star_clusters_from_hydro-dynamical_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stefano Torniamenti
Most stars form in clumpy and sub-structured clusters. These properties also emerge in hydro-dynamical simulations of star-forming clouds, which provide a way to generate realistic initial conditions for $N-$body runs of young stellar clusters. However, producing large sets of initial conditions by hydro-dynamical simulations is prohibitively expensive in terms of computational time. We introduce a novel technique for generating new initial conditions from a given sample of hydro-dynamical simulations, at a tiny computational cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Spectral Classification System for Hydrogen-deficient Carbon Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_spectral_classification_system_for_hydrogen-deficient_carbon_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_spectral_classification_system_for_hydrogen-deficient_carbon_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Courtney L. Crawford
Stellar spectral classification, and especially the Yerkes system, has been highly useful in the study of stars. While there is a currently accepted classification system for carbon stars, the subset of Hydrogen-deficient Carbon (HdC) stars has not been well described by such a system, due in part to their rarity and their variability. Here we present a new system for the classification of HdCs based on their spectra, which is made wholly on their observable appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on the contributions to the observed binary black hole population from individual evolutionary pathways in isolated binary evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_contributions_to_the_observed_binary_black_hole_population_from_individual_evolutionary_pathways_in_isolated_binary_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_contributions_to_the_observed_binary_black_hole_population_from_individual_evolutionary_pathways_in_isolated_binary_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Stevenson
Gravitational waves from merging binary black holes can be used to shed light on poorly understood aspects of massive binary stellar evolution, such as the evolution of massive stars (including their mass-loss rates), the common envelope phase, and the rate at which massive stars form throughout the cosmic history of the Universe. In this paper we explore the \emph{correlated} impact of these phases on predictions for the merger rate and chirp mass distribution of merging binary black holes, aiming to identify possible degeneracies between model parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance and age of the massive stellar cluster Westerlund 1. II. The eclipsing binary W36</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/distance_and_age_of_the_massive_stellar_cluster_westerlund_1._ii._the_eclipsing_binary_w36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/distance_and_age_of_the_massive_stellar_cluster_westerlund_1._ii._the_eclipsing_binary_w36/</guid>
      <description>First author: Danilo F. Rocha
Westerlund 1 (Wd 1) is one of the most relevant star clusters in the Milky Way to study massive star formation, although it is still poorly known. Here, we used photometric and spectroscopic data to model the eclipsing binary W36, showing that its spectral type is O6.5 III + O9.5 IV, hotter and more luminous than thought before. Its distance $d_{\rm W36}$ $=$ 4.03$\pm$0.25 kpc agrees, within the errors, with three recent Gaia-EDR3-based distances reported in Paper I, Beasor &amp;amp; Davies, and by Negueruela&amp;rsquo;s group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filament Formation via Collision-induced Magnetic Reconnection -- Formation of a Star Cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/filament_formation_via_collision-induced_magnetic_reconnection_--_formation_of_a_star_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/filament_formation_via_collision-induced_magnetic_reconnection_--_formation_of_a_star_cluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuo Kong
A collision-induced magnetic reconnection (CMR) mechanism was recently proposed to explain the formation of a filament in the Orion A molecular cloud. In this mechanism, a collision between two clouds with antiparallel magnetic fields produces a dense filament due to the magnetic tension of the reconnected fields. The filament contains fiber-like sub-structures and is confined by a helical magnetic field. To show whether the dense filament is capable of forming stars, we use the \textsc{Arepo} code with sink particles to model star formation following the formation of the CMR-filament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Populations of Magnetized Filaments in the Intracluster Medium and the Galactic Center</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/populations_of_magnetized_filaments_in_the_intracluster_medium_and_the_galactic_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/populations_of_magnetized_filaments_in_the_intracluster_medium_and_the_galactic_center/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Yusef-Zadeh
Magnetized radio filaments are found in abundance in the inner few hundred pc of our Galaxy. Progress in understanding this population of filaments has been slow, in part due to a lack of detection elsewhere in the Galaxy or in external galaxies. Recent highly sensitive radio continuum observations of radio galaxies in galaxy clusters have revealed remarkable isolated filamentary structures in the ICM that are linked to radio jets, tails and lobes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects for Detecting Fast Radio Bursts in Globular Clusters of Nearby Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_for_detecting_fast_radio_bursts_in_globular_clusters_of_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_for_detecting_fast_radio_bursts_in_globular_clusters_of_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyle Kremer
The recent detection of a repeating fast radio burst (FRB) in an old globular cluster in M81 challenges traditional FRB formation mechanisms based on magnetic activity in young neutron stars formed recently in core-collapse supernovae. Furthermore, the detection of this repeater in such a nearby galaxy implies a high local universe rate of similar events in globular clusters. Building off the properties inferred from the M81 FRB, we predict the number of FRB sources in nearby ($d \lesssim 20,$Mpc) galaxies with large globular cluster systems known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star-forming site RAFGL 5085: Is a perfect candidate of hub-filament system ?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star-forming_site_rafgl_5085_is_a_perfect_candidate_of_hub-filament_system_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star-forming_site_rafgl_5085_is_a_perfect_candidate_of_hub-filament_system_/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. K. Dewangan
To investigate the star formation process, we present a multi-wavelength study of a massive star-forming site RAFGL 5085, which has been associated with the molecular outflow, HII region, and near-infrared cluster. The continuum images at 12, 250, 350, and 500 $\mu$m show a central region (having M${\rm clump}$ $\sim$225 M${\odot}$) surrounded by five parsec-scale filaments, revealing a hub-filament system (HFS). In the {\it Herschel} column density ($N({{\rm{H}}}{2})$) map, filaments are identified with higher aspect ratios (length/diameter) and lower $N({{\rm{H}}}{2})$ values ($\sim$0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar cluster formation in a Milky Way-sized galaxy at z&gt;4 -- I. The proto-globular cluster population and the imposter amongst us</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_cluster_formation_in_a_milky_way-sized_galaxy_at_z4_--_i._the_proto-globular_cluster_population_and_the_imposter_amongst_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_cluster_formation_in_a_milky_way-sized_galaxy_at_z4_--_i._the_proto-globular_cluster_population_and_the_imposter_amongst_us/</guid>
      <description>First author: Floor van Donkelaar
The formation history of globular clusters (GCs) at redshift $z &amp;gt; 4$ remains an unsolved problem. In this work, we use the cosmological, $N$-body hydrodynamical ``zoom-in&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; simulation GigaEris to study the properties and formation of proto-GC candidates in the region surrounding the progenitor of a Milky Way-sized galaxy. The simulation employs a modern implementation of smoothed-particle hydrodynamics, including metal-line cooling and metal and thermal diffusion and allows to resolve systems at the scale of star clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gaia-ESO Survey: Lithium measurements and new curves of growth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gaia-eso_survey_lithium_measurements_and_new_curves_of_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gaia-eso_survey_lithium_measurements_and_new_curves_of_growth/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Franciosini
The Gaia-ESO Survey (GES) is a large public spectroscopic survey that was carried out using the multi-object FLAMES spectrograph at the Very Large Telescope. The survey provides accurate radial velocities, stellar parameters, and elemental abundances for ~115,000 stars in all Milky Way components. In this paper we describe the method adopted in the final data release to derive lithium equivalent widths (EWs) and abundances. Lithium EWs were measured using two different approaches for FGK and M-type stars, to account for the intrinsic differences in the spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MADPSZ catalogue of Planck clusters over the DES region: extending to lower mass and higher redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_madpsz_catalogue_of_planck_clusters_over_the_des_region_extending_to_lower_mass_and_higher_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_madpsz_catalogue_of_planck_clusters_over_the_des_region_extending_to_lower_mass_and_higher_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Hernández-Lang
We present the first systematic follow-up of Planck Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect (SZE) selected candidates down to signal-to-noise (S/N) of 3 over the 5000 deg$^2$ covered by the Dark Energy Survey. Using the MCMF cluster confirmation algorithm, we identify optical counterparts, determine photometric redshifts and richnesses and assign a parameter, $f_{\rm cont}$, that reflects the probability that each SZE-optical pairing represents a real cluster rather than a random superposition of physically unassociated systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The relation between globular cluster systems and supermassive black holes in spiral galaxies III. The link to the $M_\bullet-M_\ast$ correlation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_relation_between_globular_cluster_systems_and_supermassive_black_holes_in_spiral_galaxies_iii._the_link_to_the__m__bullet-m__ast__correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_relation_between_globular_cluster_systems_and_supermassive_black_holes_in_spiral_galaxies_iii._the_link_to_the__m__bullet-m__ast__correlation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rosa A. González-Lópezlira
We continue to explore the relationship between globular cluster total number, $N_{\rm GC}$, and central black hole mass, $M_\bullet$, in spiral galaxies. We present here results for the Sab galaxies NGC 3368, NGC 4736 (M 94) and NGC 4826 (M 64), and the Sm galaxy NGC 4395. The globular cluster (GC) candidate selection is based on the ($u^*$ - $i^\prime$) versus ($i^\prime$ - $K_s$) color-color diagram, and $i^\prime$-band shape parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A global view on star formation: The GLOSTAR Galactic plane survey. VI. Radio Source Catalog II: $28^\circ &lt; \ell &lt; 36^\circ$ and $|b| &lt; 1^\circ$, VLA B-configuration</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_global_view_on_star_formation_the_glostar_galactic_plane_survey._vi._radio_source_catalog_ii__28_circ___ell__36_circ__and__b__1_circ__vla_b-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_global_view_on_star_formation_the_glostar_galactic_plane_survey._vi._radio_source_catalog_ii__28_circ___ell__36_circ__and__b__1_circ__vla_b-configuration/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. A. Dzib
As part of the GLOSTAR survey we have used the VLA in its B-configuration to observe the part of the Galactic plane between longitudes of 28d and 36d and latitudes from -1d to +1d at the C-band (4&amp;ndash;8 GHz). To reduce the contamination of extended sources that are not well recovered by our coverage of the (u, v)-plane we discarded short baselines that are sensitive to emission on angular scales $&amp;lt;4&amp;quot;$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid spin-states of a 4 Gyr collisional family</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/asteroid_spin-states_of_a_4_gyr_collisional_family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/asteroid_spin-states_of_a_4_gyr_collisional_family/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Athanasopoulos
Families of asteroids generated by the collisional fragmentation of a common parent body have been identified using clustering methods of asteroids in their proper orbital element space. An alternative method has been developed in order to identify collisional families from the correlation between the asteroid fragment sizes and their proper semi-major axis distance from the family centre (V-shape). This method has been shown to be effective in the cases of the very diffuse families that formed billions of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baryonic Effects on Lagrangian Clustering and Angular Momentum Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/baryonic_effects_on_lagrangian_clustering_and_angular_momentum_reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/baryonic_effects_on_lagrangian_clustering_and_angular_momentum_reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ming-Jie Sheng
Recent studies illustrate the correlation between the angular momenta of cosmic structures and their Lagrangian properties. However, only baryons are observable and it is unclear whether they reliably trace the cosmic angular momenta. We study the Lagrangian mass distribution, spin correlation and predictability of dark matter, gas, and stellar components of galaxy-halo systems using IllustrisTNG, and show that the primordial segregations between components are typically small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BIFROST: simulating compact subsystems in star clusters using a hierarchical fourth-order forward symplectic integrator code</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bifrost_simulating_compact_subsystems_in_star_clusters_using_a_hierarchical_fourth-order_forward_symplectic_integrator_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bifrost_simulating_compact_subsystems_in_star_clusters_using_a_hierarchical_fourth-order_forward_symplectic_integrator_code/</guid>
      <description>First author: Antti Rantala
We present BIFROST, an extended version of the GPU-accelerated hierarchical fourth-order forward symplectic integrator code FROST. BIFROST (BInaries in FROST) can efficiently evolve collisional stellar systems with arbitrary binary fractions up to $f_\mathrm{bin}=100%$ by using secular and regularised integration for binaries, triples, multiple systems or small clusters around black holes within the fourth-order forward integrator framework. Post-Newtonian (PN) terms up to order PN3.5 are included in the equations of motion of compact subsystems with optional three-body and spin-dependent terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ca Triplet Metallicities and Velocities for twelve Globular Clusters towards the Galactic Bulge</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ca_triplet_metallicities_and_velocities_for_twelve_globular_clusters_towards_the_galactic_bulge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ca_triplet_metallicities_and_velocities_for_twelve_globular_clusters_towards_the_galactic_bulge/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Geisler
Globular clusters (GCs) are excellent tracers of the formation and early evolution of the Milky Way. The bulge GCs (BGCs) are particularly important because they can reveal vital information about the oldest, in-situ component of the Milky Way. We aim at deriving mean metallicities and radial velocities for 13 GCs that lie towards the bulge and are generally associated with this component. We use near infrared low resolution spectroscopy with the FORS2 instrument on the VLT to measure the wavelengths and equivalent widths of the CaII triplet (CaT) lines for a number of stars per cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibrating the Cepheid Period--Wesenheit Relation in the Gaia Bands using Galactic Open Cluster Cepheids</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/calibrating_the_cepheid_period--wesenheit_relation_in_the_gaia_bands_using_galactic_open_cluster_cepheids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/calibrating_the_cepheid_period--wesenheit_relation_in_the_gaia_bands_using_galactic_open_cluster_cepheids/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zehao Lin
Establishing the period&amp;ndash;Wesenheit relation requires independent and accurate distance measurements of classical Cepheids (DCEPs). The precise distance provided by an associated open cluster independently calibrates the period&amp;ndash;Wesenheit relation of DCEPs. 51 DCEPs associated with open clusters are compiled using the constraints of five-dimensional astrometric information. By directly using Gaia DR3 parallax, the period&amp;ndash;Wesenheit relation in the Gaia $G$ band is calibrated as $W_G = (-3.06 \pm 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep diving off the `Cosmic Cliffs&#39;: previously hidden outflows in NGC 3324 revealed by JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_diving_off_the_cosmic_cliffs_previously_hidden_outflows_in_ngc_3324_revealed_by_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_diving_off_the_cosmic_cliffs_previously_hidden_outflows_in_ngc_3324_revealed_by_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Megan Reiter
We present a detailed analysis of the protostellar outflow activity in the massive star-forming region NGC 3324, as revealed by new Early Release Observations (ERO) from the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). Emission from numerous outflows is revealed in narrow-band images of hydrogen Paschen-$\alpha$ (Pa-$\alpha$) and molecular hydrogen. In particular, we report the discovery of 24 previously unknown outflows based on their H$_2$ emission. We find three candidate driving sources for these H$_2$ flows in published catalogs of young stellar objects (YSOs) and we identify 15 IR point sources in the new JWST images as potential driving protostars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diffuse $γ$-ray emission around the massive star forming region of Carina Nebula Complex</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/diffuse__%CE%B3_-ray_emission_around_the_massive_star_forming_region_of_carina_nebula_complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/diffuse__%CE%B3_-ray_emission_around_the_massive_star_forming_region_of_carina_nebula_complex/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ting-Ting Ge
We report the Fermi Large Area Telescope (Fermi-LAT) detection of the $\gamma$-ray emission toward the massive star forming region of Carina Nebula Complex (CNC). Using the latest source catalog and diffuse background models, we found that the GeV $\gamma$-ray emission in this region can be resolved into three different components. The GeV $\gamma$-ray emission from the central point source is considered to originate from the Eta Carina ($\eta$ Car).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of double BSS sequences in the old Galactic open cluster Berkeley 17</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_double_bss_sequences_in_the_old_galactic_open_cluster_berkeley_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_double_bss_sequences_in_the_old_galactic_open_cluster_berkeley_17/</guid>
      <description>First author: Khushboo K Rao
Blue straggler stars (BSS) are peculiar objects which normally appear as a single broad sequence along the extension of the main sequence. Only four globular clusters (GCs) have been observed to have two distinct and parallel BSS sequences. For the first time for any open cluster (OC), we report double BSS sequences in Berkeley 17. Using the machine-learning based membership algorithm ML-MOC on Gaia EDR3 data, we identify 627 cluster members, including 21 BSS candidates out to 15 arcmin from the cluster center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAST observations of an extremely active episode of FRB 20201124A: I. Burst morphology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_i._burst_morphology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_i._burst_morphology/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. J. Zhou
We report the properties of more than 600 bursts (including cluster-bursts) detected from the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20201124A with the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope (FAST) during an extremely active episode on UTC September 25-28, 2021, in a series of four papers. The observations were carried out in the band of 1.0 - 1.5 GHz by using the center beam of the L-band 19-beam receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First results of the glitching pulsars monitoring program at the Argentine Institute of Radioastronomy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_results_of_the_glitching_pulsars_monitoring_program_at_the_argentine_institute_of_radioastronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_results_of_the_glitching_pulsars_monitoring_program_at_the_argentine_institute_of_radioastronomy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ezequiel Zubieta
We report here on the first results of a systematic monitoring of southern glitching pulsars at the Argentine Institute of Radio astronomy started on the year 2019. We detected a major glitch in the Vela pulsar (PSR J0835$-$4510) and two mini-glitches in PSR J1048$-$5832. For each glitch, we present the measurement of glitch parameters by fitting timing residuals. We then make an individual pulses study of Vela in observations previous and after the glitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragment Dynamics in Active Asteroid 331P/Gibbs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fragment_dynamics_in_active_asteroid_331p_gibbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fragment_dynamics_in_active_asteroid_331p_gibbs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Man-To Hui
We present a dynamical analysis of the fragmented active asteroid 331P/Gibbs. Using archival images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope from 2015 to 2018, we measured the astrometry of the primary and the three brightest (presumably the largest) components. Conventional orbit determination revealed a high-degree of orbital similarity between the components. We then applied a fragmentation model to fit the astrometry, obtaining key parameters including the fragmentation epochs and separation velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy clusters in high definition: a dark matter search</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_clusters_in_high_definition_a_dark_matter_search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_clusters_in_high_definition_a_dark_matter_search/</guid>
      <description>First author: Geoff Beck
Recent radio-frequency probes, with the ATCA and ASKAP telescopes, have proven themselves to be at the forefront of placing indirect limits on the properties of dark matter. The latter being able to substantially exceed the constraining power of Fermi-LAT data. However, these observations were based only on dwarf galaxies, where magnetic field uncertainties are large. Here we re-examine the case for galaxy clusters, often ignored due to substantial diffuse radio backgrounds, by considering the extrapolation of known cluster surface brightness profiles down to scales observable with MeerKAT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamma-hadron Separation in Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes using Quantum Classifiers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-hadron_separation_in_imaging_atmospheric_cherenkov_telescopes_using_quantum_classifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-hadron_separation_in_imaging_atmospheric_cherenkov_telescopes_using_quantum_classifiers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jashwanth S
In this paper we have introduced a novel method for gamma hadron separation in Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes (IACT) using Quantum Machine Learning. IACTs captures images of Extensive Air Showers (EAS) produced from very high energy gamma rays. We have used the QML Algorithms, Quantum Support Vector Classifier (QSVC) and Variational Quantum Classifier (VQC) for binary classification of the events into signals (Gamma) and background(hadron) using the image parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster metallicity distributions in the E-MOSAICS simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_metallicity_distributions_in_the_e-mosaics_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_metallicity_distributions_in_the_e-mosaics_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joel Pfeffer
The metallicity distributions of globular cluster (GC) systems in galaxies are a critical test of any GC formation scenario. In this work, we investigate the predicted GC metallicity distributions of galaxies in the MOdelling Star cluster population Assembly In Cosmological Simulations within EAGLE (E-MOSAICS) simulation of a representative cosmological volume ($L = 34.4$ comoving Mpc). We find that the predicted GC metallicity distributions and median metallicities from the fiducial E-MOSAICS GC formation model agree well the observed distributions, except for galaxies with masses $M_\ast \sim 2 \times 10^{10}$ M$\odot$, which contain an overabundance of metal-rich GCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Redshift Galaxy Candidates at $z = 9-13$ as Revealed by JWST Observations of WHL0137-08</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-redshift_galaxy_candidates_at__z__9-13__as_revealed_by_jwst_observations_of_whl0137-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-redshift_galaxy_candidates_at__z__9-13__as_revealed_by_jwst_observations_of_whl0137-08/</guid>
      <description>First author: Larry D. Bradley
JWST was designed to peer into the distant universe and study galaxies nearer the beginning of time than previously. Here we report the discovery of 12 galaxy candidates observed 300-600 Myr after the Big Bang with photometric redshifts between z ~ 8.5-13 measured using JWST NIRCam imaging of the galaxy cluster WHL0137 observed in 8 filters spanning 0.8-5.0 $\mu$m, plus 9 HST filters spanning 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionising Feedback Effects on Star Formation in Globular Clusters with Multiple Stellar Populations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ionising_feedback_effects_on_star_formation_in_globular_clusters_with_multiple_stellar_populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ionising_feedback_effects_on_star_formation_in_globular_clusters_with_multiple_stellar_populations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Asiyeh Yaghoobi
Using 3D radiation-hydrodynamical simulations, we study the effects of ionising radiation on the formation of second-generation (SG) stars in Globular Clusters (GCs) with multiple stellar populations. In particular, we focus on massive ($10^7 \mathrm{M}_{\odot}$) and young (40-Myr old) GCs. We consider stellar winds from asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars, ram pressure, gas accretion onto the cluster, and photoionisation feedback of binary stars. We find that the stellar luminosity is strong enough to warm and ionise the intracluster medium, but it does not lead to a significant gas expulsion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KiDS-1000: Combined halo-model cosmology constraints from galaxy abundance, galaxy clustering and galaxy-galaxy lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kids-1000_combined_halo-model_cosmology_constraints_from_galaxy_abundance_galaxy_clustering_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kids-1000_combined_halo-model_cosmology_constraints_from_galaxy_abundance_galaxy_clustering_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrej Dvornik
We present constraints on the flat $\Lambda$CDM cosmological model through a joint analysis of galaxy abundance, galaxy clustering and galaxy-galaxy lensing observables with the Kilo-Degree Survey. Our theoretical model combines a flexible conditional stellar mass function, to describe the galaxy-halo connection, with a cosmological N-body simulation-calibrated halo model to describe the non-linear matter field. Our magnitude-limited bright galaxy sample combines 9-band optical-to-near-infrared photometry with an extensive and complete spectroscopic training sample to provide accurate redshift and stellar mass estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life cycle of cosmic-ray electrons in the intracluster medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/life_cycle_of_cosmic-ray_electrons_in_the_intracluster_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/life_cycle_of_cosmic-ray_electrons_in_the_intracluster_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Vazza
We simulate the evolution of relativistic electrons injected into the medium of a small galaxy cluster by a central radio galaxy, studying how the initial jet power affects the dispersal and the emission properties of radio plasma. By coupling passive tracer particles to adaptive-mesh cosmological MHD simulations, we study how cosmic-ray electrons are dispersed as a function of the input jet power. We also investigate how the latter affects the thermal and non-thermal properties of the intracluster medium, with differences discernible up to $\sim$ Gyr after the start of the jet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-density star cluster formation: discovery of a young faint fuzzy on the outskirts of the low-mass spiral galaxy NGC 247</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-density_star_cluster_formation_discovery_of_a_young_faint_fuzzy_on_the_outskirts_of_the_low-mass_spiral_galaxy_ngc_247/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-density_star_cluster_formation_discovery_of_a_young_faint_fuzzy_on_the_outskirts_of_the_low-mass_spiral_galaxy_ngc_247/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aaron J. Romanowsky
The classical globular clusters found in all galaxy types have half-light radii of $r_{\rm h} \sim$ 2-4 pc, which have been tied to formation in the dense cores of giant molecular clouds. Some old star clusters have larger sizes, and it is unclear if these represent a fundamentally different mode of low-density star cluster formation. We report the discovery of a rare, young &amp;ldquo;faint fuzzy&amp;rdquo; star cluster, NGC 247-SC1, on the outskirts of the low-mass spiral galaxy NGC 247 in the nearby Sculptor group, and measure its radial velocity using Keck spectroscopy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Classification of Fast Radio Bursts: II. Unsupervised Methods</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/machine_learning_classification_of_fast_radio_bursts_ii._unsupervised_methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/machine_learning_classification_of_fast_radio_bursts_ii._unsupervised_methods/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jia-Ming Zhu-Ge
Fast radio bursts (FRBs) are one of the most mysterious astronomical transients. Observationally, they can be classified into repeaters and apparently non-repeaters. However, due to the lack of continuous observations, some apparently repeaters may have been incorrectly recognized as non-repeaters. In a series of two papers, we intend to solve such problem with machine learning. In this second paper of the series, we focus on an array of unsupervised machine learning methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass function of a young cluster in a low-metallicity environment. Sh 2-209</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_function_of_a_young_cluster_in_a_low-metallicity_environment._sh_2-209/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_function_of_a_young_cluster_in_a_low-metallicity_environment._sh_2-209/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chikako Yasui
We present deep near-infrared (NIR) imaging of Sh 2-209 (S209), a low-metallicity (${\rm [O/H]} = - 0.5$ dex) HII region in the Galaxy. From the NIR images, combined with astrometric data from Gaia EDR3, we estimate the distance to S209 to be 2.5 kpc. This is close enough to enable us to resolve cluster members clearly ($\simeq$1000 AU separation) down to a mass-detection limit of $\simeq$0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most planets might have more than 5 Myr of time to form</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/most_planets_might_have_more_than_5_myr_of_time_to_form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/most_planets_might_have_more_than_5_myr_of_time_to_form/</guid>
      <description>First author: Susanne Pfalzner
The lifetime of protoplanetary disks is a crucial parameter for planet formation research. Observations of disk fractions in star clusters imply median disk lifetimes of 1 &amp;ndash; 3 Myr. This very short disk lifetime calls for planet formation to occur extremely rapidly. We show that young, distant clusters ($\leq$ 5 Myr, $&amp;gt;$ 200 pc) often dominate these types of studies. Such clusters frequently suffer from limiting magnitudes leading to an over-representation of high-mass stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear star cluster formation in star-forming dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_star_cluster_formation_in_star-forming_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_star_cluster_formation_in_star-forming_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Katja Fahrion
Nuclear star clusters (NSCs) are massive star clusters found in all types of galaxies from dwarfs to massive galaxies. Recent studies show that while low-mass NSCs in dwarf galaxies ($M_\text{gal} &amp;lt; 10^{9} M_\odot$) form predominantly out of the merger of globular clusters (GCs), high-mass NSCs in massive galaxies have assembled most of their mass through central enriched star formation. So far, these results of a transition in the dominant NSC formation channel have been based on studies of early-type galaxies and massive late-type galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the nature of rotation in the Praesepe cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_nature_of_rotation_in_the_praesepe_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_nature_of_rotation_in_the_praesepe_cluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. J. Hao
Although a large number of Galactic open clusters (OCs) have been identified, the internal kinematic properties (e.g., rotation) of almost all the known OCs are still far from clear. With the high-precision astrometric data of Gaia EDR3, we have developed a methodology to unveil the rotational properties of the Praesepe cluster. Statistics of the three-dimensional residual motions of the member stars reveal the presence of Praesepe&amp;rsquo;s rotation and determine its spatial rotation axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open clusters housing classical Cepheids in Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/open_clusters_housing_classical_cepheids_in_gaia_dr3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/open_clusters_housing_classical_cepheids_in_gaia_dr3/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. J. Hao
The latest Gaia Data Release 3 provides an opportunity to expand the census of Galactic open clusters harboring classical Cepheid variables, thereby bolstering the cosmic distance scale. A comprehensive analysis yielded a total of 50 classical Cepheids associated with 45 open clusters, of which 39 open cluster-classical Cepheid pairs are considered probable, with the remaining 11 pairs considered improbable but worth following up. Two previously identified clusters by us possibly host classical Cepheids (OC-0125/V1788 Cyg and OC-0675/OGLE-BLG-CEP-114).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outflows Driven by Direct and Reprocessed Radiation Pressure in Massive Star Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/outflows_driven_by_direct_and_reprocessed_radiation_pressure_in_massive_star_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/outflows_driven_by_direct_and_reprocessed_radiation_pressure_in_massive_star_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shyam H. Menon
We use three-dimensional radiation hydrodynamic (RHD) simulations to study the formation of massive star clusters under the combined effects of direct ultraviolet (UV) and dust-reprocessed infrared (IR) radiation pressure. We explore a broad range of mass surface density $\Sigma \sim 10^2$-$10^5 , \mathrm{M}{\odot} , \mathrm{pc}^{-2}$, spanning values typical of weakly star-forming galaxies to extreme systems such as clouds forming super-star clusters, where radiation pressure is expected to be the dominant feedback mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particle clustering in turbulence: Prediction of spatial and statistical properties with deep learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/particle_clustering_in_turbulence_prediction_of_spatial_and_statistical_properties_with_deep_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/particle_clustering_in_turbulence_prediction_of_spatial_and_statistical_properties_with_deep_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yan-Mong Chan
We demonstrate the utility of deep learning for modeling the clustering of particles that are aerodynamically coupled to turbulent fluids. Using a Lagrangian particle module within the ATHENA++ hydrodynamics code, we simulate the dynamics of particles in the Epstein drag regime within a periodic domain of isotropic forced hydrodynamic turbulence. This setup is an idealized model relevant to the collisional growth of micron to mmsized dust particles in early stage planet formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on the quantity and brightness evolution characteristics of Photospheric Bright Points groups</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/research_on_the_quantity_and_brightness_evolution_characteristics_of_photospheric_bright_points_groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/research_on_the_quantity_and_brightness_evolution_characteristics_of_photospheric_bright_points_groups/</guid>
      <description>First author: HaiCheng Bai
Context. Photospheric bright points (BPs), as the smallest magnetic element of the photosphere and the footpoint tracer of the magnetic flux tube, are of great significance to the study of BPs. Compared with the study of the characteristics and evolution of a few specific BPs, the study of BPs groups can provide us with a better understanding of the characteristics and overall activities of BPs groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing gravity with gravitational waves $\times$ electromagnetic probes cross-correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_gravity_with_gravitational_waves___times__electromagnetic_probes_cross-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_gravity_with_gravitational_waves___times__electromagnetic_probes_cross-correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giulio Scelfo
In a General Relativistic framework, Gravitational Waves (GW) and Electromagnetic (EM) waves are expected to respond in the same way to the effects of matter perturbations between the emitter and the observer. A different behaviour might be a signature of alternative theories of gravity. In this work we study the cross-correlation of resolved GW events (from compact objects mergers detected by the Einstein Telescope, either assuming or excluding the detection of an EM counterpart) and EM signals (coming both from the Intensity Mapping of the neutral hydrogen distribution and resolved galaxies from the SKA Observatory), considering weak lensing, angular clustering and their cross term ($\mathrm{L \times C}$) as observable probes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aemulus Project VI: Emulation of beyond-standard galaxy clustering statistics to improve cosmological constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_aemulus_project_vi_emulation_of_beyond-standard_galaxy_clustering_statistics_to_improve_cosmological_constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_aemulus_project_vi_emulation_of_beyond-standard_galaxy_clustering_statistics_to_improve_cosmological_constraints/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kate Storey-Fisher
There is untapped cosmological information in galaxy redshift surveys in the non-linear regime. In this work, we use the AEMULUS suite of cosmological $N$-body simulations to construct Gaussian process emulators of galaxy clustering statistics at small scales ($0.1-50 : h^{-1},\mathrm{Mpc}$) in order to constrain cosmological and galaxy bias parameters. In addition to standard statistics &amp;ndash; the projected correlation function $w_\mathrm{p}(r_\mathrm{p})$, the redshift-space monopole of the correlation function $\xi_0(s)$, and the quadrupole $\xi_2(s)$ &amp;ndash; we emulate statistics that include information about the local environment, namely the underdensity probability function $P_\mathrm{U}(s)$ and the density-marked correlation function $M(s)$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The breakdown of current gyrochronology as evidenced by old coeval stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_breakdown_of_current_gyrochronology_as_evidenced_by_old_coeval_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_breakdown_of_current_gyrochronology_as_evidenced_by_old_coeval_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joaquín Silva-Beyer
Gyrochronology can yield useful ages for field main-sequence stars, a regime where other techniques are problematic. Typically, gyrochronology relations are calibrated using young ($\lesssim$ 2 Gyr) clusters, but the constraints at older ages are scarce, making them potentially inaccurate and imprecise. In order to test the performance of current gyrochronology relations, we construct samples of stellar pairs with coeval components, for a range of ages and with available rotation periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cross-correlation of galaxies in absorption with the Lyman $α$ forest</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cross-correlation_of_galaxies_in_absorption_with_the_lyman__%CE%B1__forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cross-correlation_of_galaxies_in_absorption_with_the_lyman__%CE%B1__forest/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ignasi Pérez-Ràfols
We present the first clustering measurement of Strong Blended Lyman $\alpha$ (SBLA) absorption systems by measuring their cross-correlation with the Lyman $\alpha$ forest. SBLAs are a new population of absorbers detected within the Lyman $\alpha$ forest. We find a bias of $2.329\pm0.057$, consistent with that of Damped Lyman $\alpha$ absorbers (DLAs). For DLAs, we recover a bias of $2.331\pm0.057$ larger than previously reported (P&#39;erez-R`afols et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The distribution of globular clusters in kinematic spaces does not trace the accretion history of the host galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_distribution_of_globular_clusters_in_kinematic_spaces_does_not_trace_the_accretion_history_of_the_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_distribution_of_globular_clusters_in_kinematic_spaces_does_not_trace_the_accretion_history_of_the_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giulia Pagnini
Reconstructing how all the stellar components of the Galaxy formed and assembled over time, by studying the properties of the stars which make it, is the aim of Galactic archeology. In these last years, thanks to the launch of the ESA Gaia astrometric mission, and the development of many spectroscopic surveys, we are for the first time in the position to delve into the layers of the past of our galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SDSS-Gaia View of the Color-Magnitude Relation for Blue Horizontal-Branch Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sdss-gaia_view_of_the_color-magnitude_relation_for_blue_horizontal-branch_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sdss-gaia_view_of_the_color-magnitude_relation_for_blue_horizontal-branch_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrícia O. Barbosa
We present an updated sample of blue horizontal-branch (BHB) stars selected from the photometric and spectroscopic data from Sloan Digital Sky Survey and its associated project Sloan Extension for Galactic Understanding and Exploration (SEGUE). With this data, we selected candidates for A-type stars in the color-color space and then a mixture modeling technique was implemented in order to distinguish between BHB and main-sequence/blue-straggler stars based on their surface gravity values ($\log \rm{g}$) estimated by the SEGUE Stellar Parameter Pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When and how did early-type galaxies outside of galaxy clusters lose their rotational support?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/when_and_how_did_early-type_galaxies_outside_of_galaxy_clusters_lose_their_rotational_support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/when_and_how_did_early-type_galaxies_outside_of_galaxy_clusters_lose_their_rotational_support/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michal Bílek
Context: Early-type galaxies (ETGs) are divided into slow and fast rotators (FRs and SRs) according to the degree of ordered rotation of their stellar populations. Cosmological hydrodynamical simulations indicate that galaxies are formed as FRs before their rotational support decreases, usually because of mergers. Aims: We aimed to investigate this process observationally for galaxies outside of clusters. Methods: We made use of the fact that different merger types leave different traces that have different lifetimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHIM-hunting through cross-correlation of optical and SZ effect data in the Virgo cluster filaments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/whim-hunting_through_cross-correlation_of_optical_and_sz_effect_data_in_the_virgo_cluster_filaments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/whim-hunting_through_cross-correlation_of_optical_and_sz_effect_data_in_the_virgo_cluster_filaments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Cagri Erciyes
Context. The physical state of most of the baryonic matter in the local universe is unknown, which is commonly referred to as the ``missing baryon problem&amp;quot;. It is theorized that at least half of these missing baryons are in a warm-hot, low-density phase outside of the virialized dark-matter halos. Aims. We make an attempt to find the signature of this warm-hot intergalactic medium (WHIM) phase in the filaments of the nearby Virgo cluster by using optical and Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray analysis of JWST&#39;s first galaxy cluster lens SMACS J0723.3-7327</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_analysis_of_jwsts_first_galaxy_cluster_lens_smacs_j0723.3-7327/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_analysis_of_jwsts_first_galaxy_cluster_lens_smacs_j0723.3-7327/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Liu
SMACS~J0723.3-7327 is the first galaxy cluster lens observed by JWST. Based on the ERO data from JWST, several groups have reported the results on strong lensing analysis and mass distribution of this cluster. However, limited by the angular coverage of the JWST data, the strong lensing models only cover the central region. X-ray analysis on the hot ICM is necessary to obtain a more complete constraint on the mass distribution in this very massive cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMM-Newton view of the shock heating in an early merging cluster, CIZA J1358.9$-$4750</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/xmm-newton_view_of_the_shock_heating_in_an_early_merging_cluster_ciza_j1358.9_-_4750/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/xmm-newton_view_of_the_shock_heating_in_an_early_merging_cluster_ciza_j1358.9_-_4750/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Omiya
CIZA J1358.9-4750 is a nearby galaxy cluster in the early phase of a major merger. The two-dimensional temperature map using XMM-Newton EPIC-PN observation confirms the existence of a high temperature region, which we call the &amp;ldquo;hot region&amp;rdquo;, in the &amp;ldquo;bridge region&amp;rdquo; connecting the two clusters. The ~ 500 kpc wide region between the southeast and northwest boundaries also has higher pseudo pressure compared to the unshocked regions, suggesting the existence of two shocks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
