<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/3month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/3month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of rotating massive stars with new hydrodynamic wind models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_massive_stars_with_new_hydrodynamic_wind_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_massive_stars_with_new_hydrodynamic_wind_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex Camilo Gormaz-Matamala
Mass loss due to line-driven winds is central to our understanding of the evolution of massive stars. We extend the evolution models introduced in Paper I, where the mass loss recipe is based on the simultaneous calculation of the wind hydrodynamics and the line-acceleration, by incorporating the effects of stellar rotation. We introduce a grid of self-consistent line-force parameters for a set of standard evolutionary tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A LOFAR sample of luminous compact sources coincident with nearby dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lofar_sample_of_luminous_compact_sources_coincident_with_nearby_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lofar_sample_of_luminous_compact_sources_coincident_with_nearby_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Vohl
The vast majority of extragalactic, compact continuum radio sources are associated with star formation or jets from (super)massive black holes and, as such, are more likely to be found in association with starburst galaxies or early type galaxies. Recently, two new populations of radio sources have been identified: (a) compact and persistent sources (PRS) associated with fast radio bursts (FRB) in dwarf galaxies and (b) compact sources in dwarf galaxies that could belong to the long-sought population of intermediate-mass black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A long-duration gamma-ray burst of dynamical origin from the nucleus of an ancient galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_long-duration_gamma-ray_burst_of_dynamical_origin_from_the_nucleus_of_an_ancient_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_long-duration_gamma-ray_burst_of_dynamical_origin_from_the_nucleus_of_an_ancient_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew J. Levan
The majority of long duration ($&amp;gt;2$ s) gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are believed to arise from the collapse of massive stars \cite{Hjorth+03}, with a small proportion created from the merger of compact objects. Most of these systems are likely formed via standard stellar evolution pathways. However, it has long been thought that a fraction of GRBs may instead be an outcome of dynamical interactions in dense environments, channels which could also contribute significantly to the samples of compact object mergers detected as gravitational wave sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sensitive Search for Supernova Emission Associated with the Extremely Energetic and Nearby GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sensitive_search_for_supernova_emission_associated_with_the_extremely_energetic_and_nearby_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sensitive_search_for_supernova_emission_associated_with_the_extremely_energetic_and_nearby_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gokul P. Srinivasaragavan
We report observations of the optical counterpart of the long gamma-ray burst (LGRB) GRB 221009A. Due to the extreme rarity of being both nearby ($z = 0.151$) and highly energetic ($E_{\gamma,\mathrm{iso}} \geq 10^{54}$ erg), GRB 221009A offers a unique opportunity to probe the connection between massive star core collapse and relativistic jet formation. Adopting a phenomenological power-law model for the afterglow and host galaxy estimates from high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging, we use Bayesian model comparison techniques to determine the likelihood of an associated SN contributing excess flux to the optical light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of invariance of dark matter halo surface density using multiwavelength mock galaxy catalogues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_invariance_of_dark_matter_halo_surface_density_using_multiwavelength_mock_galaxy_catalogues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_invariance_of_dark_matter_halo_surface_density_using_multiwavelength_mock_galaxy_catalogues/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gopika K.
A large number of observations have shown that the dark matter halo surface density, given by the product of halo core radius and core density is nearly constant for a diverse suite of galaxies. Although this invariance of the halo surface density is violated at galaxy cluster and group scales, it is still an open question on whether the aforementioned constancy on galactic scales can be explained within $\Lambda$CDM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulgeless disks, dark galaxies, inverted color gradients, and other expected phenomena at higher z. The chromatic surface brightness modulation (CMOD) effect</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bulgeless_disks_dark_galaxies_inverted_color_gradients_and_other_expected_phenomena_at_higher_z._the_chromatic_surface_brightness_modulation_cmod_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bulgeless_disks_dark_galaxies_inverted_color_gradients_and_other_expected_phenomena_at_higher_z._the_chromatic_surface_brightness_modulation_cmod_effect/</guid>
      <description>First author: Polychronis Papaderos
Since the k correction depends on the spectral energy distribution (SED) of a galaxy, any high-z galaxy with a spatially non-homogeneous SED will experience a spatially varying relative dimming or brightening in addition to the pure distance effect. The morphology of galaxies will therefore change with z. For instance, an early spiral galaxy observed in the V band would show a prominent bulge at z=0, whereas, if at z=1, the V filter probes the rest-frame near-UV where the bulge is faint and the disk relatively brighter, thus the galaxy may appear as bulgeless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining f(Q) Cosmology with Standard Sirens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_fq_cosmology_with_standard_sirens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_fq_cosmology_with_standard_sirens/</guid>
      <description>First author: José Ferreira
In this dissertation, we study two cosmological models based on $f(Q)$ gravity. We resort to mock catalogs of standard siren (SS) events to see whether data from future gravitational wave (GWs) observatories will be able to distinguish these models from $\Lambda$CDM. The first model is the most general $f(Q)$ formulation that replicates a $\Lambda$CDM background, with deviations appearing only at the perturbative level. It has one additional free parameter compared to $\Lambda$CDM, $\alpha$, which when set to zero falls back to $\Lambda$CDM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological studies with VLBI</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_studies_with_vlbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_studies_with_vlbi/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Spingola
Current cosmological controversies can be solved if a sufficient level of precision is achieved by observations. Future surveys with the next generation of telescopes will offer significantly improved depth and angular resolution with respect to existing observations, opening the so-called &amp;ldquo;era of precision cosmology&amp;rdquo;. But, that era can be considered already started at the radio wavelengths with Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI). In this paper, we give an overview on how VLBI is contributing to some open questions in contemporary cosmology by reaching simultaneously the largest distances and the smallest scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMPRESS. XII. Statistics on the Dynamics and Gas Mass Fraction of Extremely-Metal Poor Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/empress._xii._statistics_on_the_dynamics_and_gas_mass_fraction_of_extremely-metal_poor_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/empress._xii._statistics_on_the_dynamics_and_gas_mass_fraction_of_extremely-metal_poor_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yi Xu
We present demography of the dynamics and gas-mass fraction of 33 extremely metal-poor galaxies (EMPGs) with metallicities of $0.015-0.195~Z_\odot$ and low stellar masses of $10^4-10^8~M_\odot$ in the local universe. We conduct deep optical integral-field spectroscopy (IFS) for the low-mass EMPGs with the medium high resolution ($R=7500$) grism of the 8m-Subaru FOCAS IFU instrument by the EMPRESS 3D survey, and investigate H$\alpha$ emission of the EMPGs. Exploiting the resolution high enough for the low-mass galaxies, we derive gas dynamics with the H$\alpha$ lines by the fitting of 3-dimensional disk models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of binary stars in the early evolutionary phases of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_binary_stars_in_the_early_evolutionary_phases_of_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_binary_stars_in_the_early_evolutionary_phases_of_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexander R. Livernois
The dynamics of binary stars provides a unique avenue to gather insight into the study of the structure and dynamics of star clusters and galaxies. In this paper, we present the results of a set of $N$-body simulations aimed at exploring the evolution of binary stars during the early evolutionary phases of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies (UFD). In our simulations, we assume that the stellar component of the UFD is initially dynamically cold and evolves towards its final equilibrium after undergoing the violent relaxation phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRB 191019A: a short gamma-ray burst in disguise from the disk of an active galactic nucleus</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12935/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12935/</guid>
      <description>Davide Lazzati
Long and short gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), canonically separated at around 2 seconds duration, are associated with different progenitors: the collapse of a massive star and the merger of two compact objects, respectively. GRB 191019A was a long GRB ($T_{90}\sim64$ s). Despite the relatively small redshift z=0.248 and HST followup observations, an accompanying supernova was not detected. In addition, the host galaxy did not have significant star formation activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferring the progenitor mass-kinetic energy relation of stripped-envelope core-collapse supernovae from nebular spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_the_progenitor_mass-kinetic_energy_relation_of_stripped-envelope_core-collapse_supernovae_from_nebular_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_the_progenitor_mass-kinetic_energy_relation_of_stripped-envelope_core-collapse_supernovae_from_nebular_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qiliang Fang
The relation between the progenitor mass and the kinetic energy of the explosion is a key toward revealing the explosion mechanism of stripped-envelope (SE) core-collapse (CC) supernovae (SNe). Here, we present a method to derive this relation using the nebular spectra of SESNe, based on the correlation between the $[O~I]$/$[Ca~II]$, which is an indicator of the progenitor mass, and the width of $[O~I]$, which measures the expansion velocity of the oxygen-rich material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared galaxies detected by the Atacama Cosmology Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_galaxies_detected_by_the_atacama_cosmology_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_galaxies_detected_by_the_atacama_cosmology_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ece Kilerci
We report on 167 infrared (IR) galaxies selected by AKARI and IRAS and detected in the Atacama Cosmology Telescope (ACT) Data Release 5 (DR5) sky maps at the 98, 150 and 220 GHz frequency bands. Of these detections, 134 (80%) of the millimeter counterparts are first-time identifications with ACT. We expand the previous ACT extragalactic source catalogs, by including new 98 GHz detections and measurements from ACT DR5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhomogeneous Galactic Chemical Evolution: Modelling Ultra-Faint Dwarf Galaxies of the Large Magellanic Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_galactic_chemical_evolution_modelling_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_galactic_chemical_evolution_modelling_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan K. Alexander
Ultra-faint dwarf galaxies are among the oldest and most metal-poor galaxies in the cosmos, observed to contain no traces of gas at the present time and a high dark matter mass fraction. Understanding the chemical abundance dispersion in such extreme environments could shed light on the properties of the first generations of stars in the cosmos. We present a novel inhomogeneous chemical evolution model, i-GEtool, that we apply to two ultra-faint dwarf galaxies, Carina II (Car II) and Reticulum II (Ret II), which are satellites of the Large Magellanic Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing of materials in magnetised core-collapse supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mixing_of_materials_in_magnetised_core-collapse_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mixing_of_materials_in_magnetised_core-collapse_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Meyer D. M. -A.
Core-collapse supernova remnants are structures of the interstellar medium (ISM) left behind the explosive death of most massive stars (smaller or equal to 40 Mo). Since they result in the expansion of the supernova shock wave into the gaseous environment shaped by the star wind history, their morphology constitutes an insight into the past evolution of their progenitor star. Particularly, fast-moving massive stars can produce asymmetric core-collapse supernova remnants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleosynthesis in jet-driven and jet-associated supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_jet-driven_and_jet-associated_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_jet-driven_and_jet-associated_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Obergaulinger
In contrast to regular core-collapse supernovae, explosions of rapidly rotating massive stars can develop jets, fast collimated outflows directed along the rotational axis. Depending on the rate of rotation and the magnetic field strength before collapse as well as on possible mechanisms amplifying the magnetic field, such a core can explode magnetorotationally rather than via the standard supernova mechanism based on neutrino heating. This scenario can explain the highest kinetic energies observed in the class of hypernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar cluster formation in a Milky Way-sized galaxy at z&gt;4 -- II. A hybrid formation scenario for the nuclear star cluster and its connection to the nuclear stellar ring</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_cluster_formation_in_a_milky_way-sized_galaxy_at_z4_--_ii._a_hybrid_formation_scenario_for_the_nuclear_star_cluster_and_its_connection_to_the_nuclear_stellar_ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_cluster_formation_in_a_milky_way-sized_galaxy_at_z4_--_ii._a_hybrid_formation_scenario_for_the_nuclear_star_cluster_and_its_connection_to_the_nuclear_stellar_ring/</guid>
      <description>First author: Floor van Donkelaar
Nuclear star clusters (NSCs) are massive star clusters found in the innermost region of the majority of galaxies. While recent studies suggest that low-mass NSCs in dwarf galaxies form largely out of the merger of globular clusters and NSCs in massive galaxies have assembled most of their mass through central star formation, the formation channel of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s NSC is still uncertain. In this work, we use GigaEris, a very high resolution $N$-body hydrodynamical cosmological zoom-in&#39;&#39; simulation, to investigate NSC formation in the progenitor of a Milky Way-sized galaxy, as well as its relation to the assembly and evolution of the galactic nuclear region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The formation of globular clusters with top-heavy initial mass functions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12405/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12405/</guid>
      <description>Hajime Fukushima
We study the formation of globular clusters in massive compact clouds with the low-metallicity of $Z=10^{-3}~Z_{\odot}$ by performing three-dimensional radiative-hydrodynamics simulations. Considering the uncertainty of the initial mass function (IMF) of stars formed in low-metallicity and high-density clouds, we investigate the impacts of the IMF on the cloud condition for the GC formation with the range of the power-law index of IMF as $γ= 1-2.35$. We find that the threshold surface density ($Σ_{\rm thr}$) for the GC formation increases from $800~M_{\odot} \; {\rm pc^{-2}}$ at $γ= 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of AGN-driven winds on physical and observable galaxy sizes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_agn-driven_winds_on_physical_and_observable_galaxy_sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_agn-driven_winds_on_physical_and_observable_galaxy_sizes/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. K. Cochrane
Without AGN feedback, simulated massive, star-forming galaxies become too compact relative to observed galaxies at z&amp;lt;2. In this paper, we perform high-resolution re-simulations of a massive (M*~10^11M_sol) galaxy at z~2, drawn from the FIRE project. In the simulation without AGN feedback, the galaxy experiences a rapid starburst and shrinking of its half-mass radius at z~2.3. In this paper, we experiment with driving mechanical AGN winds using a state-of-the-art hyper-Lagrangian refinement technique to increase particle resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the geometry of the hot X-ray corona in the Seyfert galaxy NGC4151 with IXPE</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/uncovering_the_geometry_of_the_hot_x-ray_corona_in_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc4151_with_ixpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/uncovering_the_geometry_of_the_hot_x-ray_corona_in_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc4151_with_ixpe/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. E. Gianolli
We present an X-ray spectro-polarimetric analysis of the bright Seyfert galaxy NGC4151. The source has been observed with the Imaging X-ray Polarimetry Explorer (IXPE) for 700 ks, complemented with simultaneous XMM-Newton (50 ks) and NuSTAR (100 ks) pointings. A polarization degree ${\Pi} = 4.9 {\pm} 1.1 %$ and angle ${\Psi}= 86{\deg} {\pm} 7{\deg}$ east of north ($68%$ confidence level) are measured in the 2-8 keV energy range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Radiation-Hydrodynamic Simulations Resolving Interior of Rapidly Accreting Primordial Protostar</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation-hydrodynamic_simulations_resolving_interior_of_rapidly_accreting_primordial_protostar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation-hydrodynamic_simulations_resolving_interior_of_rapidly_accreting_primordial_protostar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kazutaka Kimura
Direct collapse of supermassive stars is a possible pathway to form supermassive black hole seeds at high redshifts. Whereas previous three-dimensional (3D) simulations demonstrate that supermassive stars form via rapid mass accretion, those resolving the stellar interior have been limited. We here report 3D radiation-hydrodynamic (RHD) simulations following the evolution of rapidly accreting protostars resolving the stellar interior. We use an adaptive mesh refinement code with our newly developed RHD solver employing an explicit M1 closure method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barrow nearly-extensive Gibbs-like entropy favoured by the full dynamical and geometrical data set in cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/barrow_nearly-extensive_gibbs-like_entropy_favoured_by_the_full_dynamical_and_geometrical_data_set_in_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/barrow_nearly-extensive_gibbs-like_entropy_favoured_by_the_full_dynamical_and_geometrical_data_set_in_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tomasz Denkiewicz
We apply the full set of most update dynamical and geometrical data in cosmology to the nonextensive Barrow entropic holographic dark energy. We show that the data point towards an extensive Gibbs-like entropic behaviour for the cosmological horizons, which is the extreme case of the Barrow entropy, with the entropy parameter being $\Delta &amp;gt; 0.86$, close to the maximum threshold of $\Delta =1$ where the fractal dimension of the area-horizon becomes almost or just the volume and the intensivity is recovered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzard to Cardinal: Improved Mock Catalogs for Large Galaxy Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/buzzard_to_cardinal_improved_mock_catalogs_for_large_galaxy_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/buzzard_to_cardinal_improved_mock_catalogs_for_large_galaxy_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chun-Hao To
We present the Cardinal mock galaxy catalogs, a new version of the Buzzard simulation that has been updated to support ongoing and future cosmological surveys, including DES, DESI, and LSST. These catalogs are based on a one-quarter sky simulation populated with galaxies out to a redshift of $z=2.35$ to a depth of $m_{\rm{r}}=27$. Compared to the Buzzard mocks, the Cardinal mocks include an updated subhalo abundance matching (SHAM) model that considers orphan galaxies and includes mass-dependent scatter between galaxy luminosity and halo properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Polarized Radiative Transfer Codes used by the EHT Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12004/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.12004/</guid>
      <description>Ben S. Prather
Interpretation of resolved polarized images of black holes by the Event Horizon Telescope (EHT) requires predictions of the polarized emission observable by an Earth-based instrument for a particular model of the black hole accretion system. Such predictions are generated by general relativistic radiative transfer (GRRT) codes, which integrate the equations of polarized radiative transfer in curved spacetime. A selection of ray-tracing GRRT codes used within the EHT collaboration is evaluated for accuracy and consistency in producing a selection of test images, demonstrating that the various methods and implementations of radiative transfer calculations are highly consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating radiation transport on cosmological scale using a denoising Unet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_radiation_transport_on_cosmological_scale_using_a_denoising_unet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_radiation_transport_on_cosmological_scale_using_a_denoising_unet/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mosima P. Masipa
Semi-numerical simulations are the leading candidates for evolving reionization on cosmological scales. These semi-numerical models are efficient in generating large-scale maps of the 21cm signal, but they are too slow to enable inference at the field level. We present different strategies to train a U-Net to accelerate these simulations. We derive the ionization field directly from the initial density field without using the ionizing sources&amp;rsquo; location, and hence emulating the radiative transfer process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical Evolution of Black-Hole Binaries Embedded in AGN Discs: III. The Effects of Viscosity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_evolution_of_black-hole_binaries_embedded_in_agn_discs_iii._the_effects_of_viscosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_evolution_of_black-hole_binaries_embedded_in_agn_discs_iii._the_effects_of_viscosity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rixin Li
Stellar-mass binary black holes (BBHs) embedded in active galactic nucleus (AGN) discs offer a distinct dynamical channel to produce black hole mergers detected in gravitational waves by LIGO/Virgo. To understand their orbital evolution through interactions with the disc gas, we perform a suite of 2D high-resolution, local shearing box, viscous hydrodynamical simulations of equal-mass binaries. We find that viscosity not only smooths the flow structure around prograde circular binaries, but also greatly raises their accretion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of a small X-ray flaring event in NLS1 galaxy NGC 4051</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigation_of_a_small_x-ray_flaring_event_in_nls1_galaxy_ngc_4051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigation_of_a_small_x-ray_flaring_event_in_nls1_galaxy_ngc_4051/</guid>
      <description>First author: Neeraj Kumari
We performed a detailed broadband spectral and timing analysis of a small flaring event of ~120 ks in a narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy NGC 4051 using simultaneous XMM-Newton and NuSTAR observations. The ~300 ks long NuSTAR observation and the overlapping XMM-Newton exposure were segregated into pre-flare, flare, and post-flare segments. During the flare, the NuSTAR count rate peaked at 2.5 times the mean count rate before the flare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST/NIRSpec First Census of Broad-Line AGNs at z=4-7: Detection of 10 Faint AGNs with M_BH~10^6-10^7 M_sun and Their Host Galaxy Properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_first_census_of_broad-line_agns_at_z4-7_detection_of_10_faint_agns_with_m_bh~106-107_m_sun_and_their_host_galaxy_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_first_census_of_broad-line_agns_at_z4-7_detection_of_10_faint_agns_with_m_bh~106-107_m_sun_and_their_host_galaxy_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuichi Harikane
We present a first statistical sample of faint type-1 AGNs at $z&amp;gt;4$ identified by JWST/NIRSpec deep spectroscopy. Among the 185 galaxies at $z_\mathrm{spec}=3.8-8.9$ confirmed with NIRSpec, our systematic search for broad-line emission reveals 10 type-1 AGNs at $z=4.015-6.936$ whose broad component is only seen in the permitted H$\alpha$ line and not in the forbidden $[OIII]$$\lambda$5007 line that is detected with greater significance than H$\alpha$. The broad H$\alpha$ line widths of $\mathrm{FWHM}\simeq1000-6000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for FRB persistent radio source counterparts in dwarf galaxies using LOFAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_frb_persistent_radio_source_counterparts_in_dwarf_galaxies_using_lofar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_frb_persistent_radio_source_counterparts_in_dwarf_galaxies_using_lofar/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Vohl
The repeating FRB 20121102A was localized to a star-forming region in a dwarf galaxy and found to be co-located with a persistent radio source (PRS). FRB 20190520B is only the second known source sharing phenomenology akin to FRB 20121102A&amp;rsquo;s, with similar burst activity, host galaxy properties, as well as being associated with a PRS. PRS emission is potentially a calorimeter, allowing us to estimate the energy output of the central FRB engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 300 parsec resolution imaging of a z = 8.31 galaxy: Turbulent ionized gas and potential stellar feedback 600 million years after the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_300_parsec_resolution_imaging_of_a_z__8.31_galaxy_turbulent_ionized_gas_and_potential_stellar_feedback_600_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_300_parsec_resolution_imaging_of_a_z__8.31_galaxy_turbulent_ionized_gas_and_potential_stellar_feedback_600_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yoichi Tamura
We present the results of 300 pc resolution ALMA imaging of the $[OIII]$ 88 $\mu$m line and dust continuum emission from a $z = 8.312$ Lyman break galaxy MACS0416_Y1. The velocity-integrated $[OIII]$ emission has three peaks which are likely associated with three young stellar clumps of MACS0416_Y1, while the channel map shows a complicated velocity structure with little indication of a global velocity gradient unlike what was found in $[CII]$ 158 $\mu$m at a larger scale, suggesting random bulk motion of ionized gas clouds inside the galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gas Mass Reservoir of Quiescent Galaxies at Cosmic Noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gas_mass_reservoir_of_quiescent_galaxies_at_cosmic_noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gas_mass_reservoir_of_quiescent_galaxies_at_cosmic_noon/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Blánquez-Sesé
We present a 1.1mm stacking analysis of moderately massive (log($M_{}$/$M_{\odot}$) = 10.7 $\pm$ 0.2) quiescent galaxies (QGs) at $\langle z\rangle \sim1.5$, searching for cold dust continuum emission, an excellent tracer of dust and gas mass. Using both the recent GOODS-ALMA survey as well as the full suite of ALMA Band-6 ancillary data in the GOODS-S field, we report the tentative detection of dust continuum equivalent of dust mass log($M_{dust}$/$M_{\odot}$) = 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interplay between radio AGN activity and their host galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_radio_agn_activity_and_their_host_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_radio_agn_activity_and_their_host_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guilherme S. Couto
Radio activity in AGN (Active Galactic Nuclei) produce feedback on the host galaxy via the impact of the relativistic jets on the circumnuclear gas. Although radio jets can reach up to several times the optical radius of the host galaxy, in this review we focus on the observation of the feedback deposited locally in the central region of the host galaxies, in the form of outflows due to the jet-gas interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIMP cross-section limits from LOFAR observations of dwarf spheroidal galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wimp_cross-section_limits_from_lofar_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wimp_cross-section_limits_from_lofar_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Gajović
Weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs) can self-annihilate and thus provide us with the possibility for an indirect detection of Dark Matter (DM). Dwarf spheroidal (dSph) galaxies are excellent places to search for annihilation signals because they are rich in DM and background emission is low. If magnetic fields in dSph exist, the particles produced in DM annihilation emit synchrotron radiation. We use the non-detection of 150 MHz radio continuum emission from dSph galaxies with the LOw Frequency ARray (LOFAR) to derive constraints on the annihilation cross-section of WIMPs into electron-positron pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Approach To The Halo-Galaxy-SMBH Connection Through Cosmic Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_approach_to_the_halo-galaxy-smbh_connection_through_cosmic_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_approach_to_the_halo-galaxy-smbh_connection_through_cosmic_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher Boettner
We study the co-evolution of dark matter halos, galaxies and supermassive black holes using an empirical galaxy evolution model from $z=0$ &amp;ndash; $10$. We demonstrate that by connecting dark matter structure evolution with simple empirical prescriptions for baryonic processes, we are able to faithfully reproduce key observations in the relation between galaxies and their supermassive black holes. By assuming a physically-motivated, direct relationship between the galaxy and supermassive black hole properties to the mass of their host halo, we construct expressions for the galaxy stellar mass function, galaxy UV luminosity function, active black hole mass function and quasar bolometric luminosity function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A JWST/NIRSpec Exploration of the Connection between Ionization Parameter, Electron Density, and Star-Formation-Rate Surface Density in z=2.7-6.3 Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_nirspec_exploration_of_the_connection_between_ionization_parameter_electron_density_and_star-formation-rate_surface_density_in_z2.7-6.3_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_nirspec_exploration_of_the_connection_between_ionization_parameter_electron_density_and_star-formation-rate_surface_density_in_z2.7-6.3_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Naveen A. Reddy
We conduct a statistical analysis of the factors responsible for the variation in the ionization parameter (U) of high-redshift star-forming galaxies based on medium resolution JWST/NIRSpec observations obtained by the Cosmic Evolution Early Release Science (CEERS) survey. The sample consists of 48 galaxies with spectroscopic redshifts z=2.7-6.3 which are largely representative of typical star-forming galaxies at these redshifts. The $[SII]$ 6718, 6733 doublet is used to estimate electron densities (n_e), and dust-corrected Ha luminosities are used to compute total ionizing photon rates (Q).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trail of the Invisible: Blue Globular Clusters Trace the Radial Density Distribution of the Dark Matter -- Case Study of NGC 4278</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02292/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02292/</guid>
      <description>Matthias Kluge
We present new, deep optical observations of the early-type galaxy NGC 4278, which is located in a small loose group. We find that the galaxy lacks fine substructure, i.e., it appears relaxed, out to a radius of $\sim$70 kpc. Our $g$- and $i$-band surface brightness profiles are uniform down to our deepest levels of $\sim$28 mag arcsec$^{-2}$. This spans an extremely large radial range of more than 14 half-mass radii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A young white dwarf orbiting PSR J1835-3259B in the bulge globular cluster NGC 6652</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11263/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11263/</guid>
      <description>J. Chen
We report on the discovery of the companion star to the millisecond pulsar PSR J1835-3259B in the Galactic globular cluster NGC 6652. Taking advantage of deep photometric archival observations acquired through the Hubble Space Telescope in near-ultraviolet and optical bands, we identified a bright and blue object at a position compatible with that of the radio pulsar. The companion is located along the helium-core white dwarf cooling sequence and the comparison with binary evolution models provides a mass of $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An extremely compact, low-mass post-starburst galaxy at $z=5.2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extremely_compact_low-mass_post-starburst_galaxy_at__z5.2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extremely_compact_low-mass_post-starburst_galaxy_at__z5.2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Victoria Strait
We report the discovery of a low-mass $z=5.200\pm 0.002$ galaxy that is in the process of ceasing its star formation. The galaxy, MACS0417-z5PSB, is multiply imaged with magnification factors $\sim40$ by the galaxy cluster MACS J0417.5-1154, observed as part of the CAnadian NIRISS Unbiased Cluster Survey (CANUCS). Using observations of MACS0417-z5PSB with a JWST/NIRSpec Prism spectrum and NIRCam imaging, we investigate the mechanism responsible for the cessation of star formation of the galaxy, and speculate about possibilities for its future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Symmetric Objects: A Distinct Population of Jetted Active Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/compact_symmetric_objects_a_distinct_population_of_jetted_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/compact_symmetric_objects_a_distinct_population_of_jetted_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Kiehlmann
Compact Symmetric Objects (CSOs) are a class of compact, jetted Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) whose jet axes are not aligned close to the line of sight, and whose observed emission is not predominantly relativistically boosted towards us. Using complete samples of CSOs, we present three independent lines of evidence, based on their relative numbers, their redshift distributions, and their size distributions, which show conclusively that most CSOs do not evolve into larger-scale radio sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeMMINGs. V. Nuclear activity and bulge properties: a detailed multi-component decomposition of $e$-MERLIN Palomar galaxies with $HST$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lemmings._v._nuclear_activity_and_bulge_properties_a_detailed_multi-component_decomposition_of__e_-merlin_palomar_galaxies_with__hst_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lemmings._v._nuclear_activity_and_bulge_properties_a_detailed_multi-component_decomposition_of__e_-merlin_palomar_galaxies_with__hst_/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. T. Dullo
We use high-resolution $HST$ imaging and $e$-MERLIN 1.5-GHz observations of galaxy cores from the LeMMINGs survey to investigate the relation between optical structural properties and nuclear radio emission for a large sample of galaxies. We perform accurate, multi-component decompositions of new surface brightness profiles extracted from $HST$ images for 163 LeMMINGs galaxies and fit up to six galaxy components (e.g., bulges, discs, AGN, bars, rings, spiral arms, and nuclear star clusters) simultaneously with S&#39;ersic and/or core-S&#39;ersic models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Metallicity Relationship of SDSS Star Forming Galaxies: Population Synthesis Analysis and Effects of Star Burst Length, Extinction Law, Initial Mass Function and Star Formation Rate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_metallicity_relationship_of_sdss_star_forming_galaxies_population_synthesis_analysis_and_effects_of_star_burst_length_extinction_law_initial_mass_function_and_star_formation_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_metallicity_relationship_of_sdss_star_forming_galaxies_population_synthesis_analysis_and_effects_of_star_burst_length_extinction_law_initial_mass_function_and_star_formation_rate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eva Sextl
We investigate the mass-metallicity relationship of star forming galaxies by analysing the absorption line spectra of $\sim$200,000 galaxies in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. The galaxy spectra are stacked in bins of stellar mass and a population synthesis technique is applied yielding metallicities, ages and star formation history of the young and old stellar population together with interstellar reddening and extinction. We adopt different lengths of the initial starbursts and different initial mass functions for the calculation of model spectra of the single stellar populations contributing to the total integrated spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Reionization-Era Globular Cluster in Low-Mass Galaxy Eridanus II</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11348/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.11348/</guid>
      <description>Daniel R. Weisz
Using color-magnitude diagrams from deep archival Hubble Space Telescope imaging, we self-consistently measure the star formation history of Eridanus II (Eri II), the lowest-mass galaxy ($M_{\star}(z=0) \sim 10^5 M_{\odot}$) known to host a globular cluster (GC), and the age, mass, and metallicity of its GC. The GC ($\sim13.2\pm0.4$ Gyr, $\langle[Fe/H]\rangle = -2.75\pm0.2$ dex) and field (mean age $\sim13.5\pm0.3$ Gyr, $\langle[Fe/H]\rangle = -2.6\pm0.15$ dex) have similar ages and metallicities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio and infrared study of the supernova remnant candidate HESS J1912&#43;101</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_infrared_study_of_the_supernova_remnant_candidate_hess_j1912&#43;101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_infrared_study_of_the_supernova_remnant_candidate_hess_j1912&#43;101/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Duvidovich
Aims: We provide new insights into the gamma-ray emission from HESS J1912+101, a TeV supernova remnant candidate probably associated with the radio pulsar PSR J1913+1011. Methods: We obtained new observations at 1.5 GHz using the VLA in the D configuration, with the purpose of detecting the radio shell of the putative remnant. In addition, we observed a single pointing at 6.0 GHz toward PSR J1913+1011 to look for a radio pulsar wind nebula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-lived radioisotope enrichment in star-forming regions from stellar winds and supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radioisotope_enrichment_in_star-forming_regions_from_stellar_winds_and_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radioisotope_enrichment_in_star-forming_regions_from_stellar_winds_and_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Richard J. Parker
The abundance of the short-lived radioisotopes 26-Al and 60-Fe in the early Solar system is usually explained by the Sun either forming from pre-enriched material, or the Sun&amp;rsquo;s protosolar disc being polluted by a nearby supernova explosion from a massive star. Both hypotheses suffer from significant drawbacks: the former does not account for the dynamical evolution of star-forming regions, while in the latter the time for massive stars to explode as supernovae can be similar to, or even longer than, the lifetime of protoplanetary discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical anisotropy in galaxy ellipticity correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_anisotropy_in_galaxy_ellipticity_correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_anisotropy_in_galaxy_ellipticity_correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maresuke Shiraishi
As well as the galaxy number density and peculiar velocity, the galaxy intrinsic alignment can be used to test the cosmic isotropy. We study distinctive impacts of the isotropy breaking on the configuration-space two-point correlation functions (2PCFs) composed of the spin-2 galaxy ellipticity field. For this purpose, we build a methodology to efficiently compute general types of the isotropy-violating 2PCFs by generalizing the polypolar spherical harmonic decomposition approach to the spin-weighted version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bar rotation rate as a diagnostic of dark matter content in the centre of disc galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_bar_rotation_rate_as_a_diagnostic_of_dark_matter_content_in_the_centre_of_disc_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_bar_rotation_rate_as_a_diagnostic_of_dark_matter_content_in_the_centre_of_disc_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Buttitta
We investigate the link between the bar rotation rate and dark matter content in barred galaxies by concentrating on the cases of the lenticular galaxies NGC4264 and NGC4277. These two gas-poor galaxies have similar morphologies, sizes, and luminosities. But, NGC4264 hosts a fast bar, which extends to nearly the corotation, while the bar embedded in NGC4277 is slow and falls short of corotation. We derive the fraction of dark matter $f_{\rm DM, bar}$ within the bar region from Jeans axisymmetric dynamical models by matching the stellar kinematics obtained with the MUSE integral-field spectrograph and using SDSS images to recover the stellar mass distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The massive relic galaxy NGC 1277 is dark matter deficient. From dynamical models of integral-field stellar kinematics out to five effective radii</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_massive_relic_galaxy_ngc_1277_is_dark_matter_deficient._from_dynamical_models_of_integral-field_stellar_kinematics_out_to_five_effective_radii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_massive_relic_galaxy_ngc_1277_is_dark_matter_deficient._from_dynamical_models_of_integral-field_stellar_kinematics_out_to_five_effective_radii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sébastien Comerón
According to the $\Lambda$CDM cosmology, present-day massive galaxies should contain a sizable fraction of dark matter within their stellar body. Models indicate that in massive early-type galaxies (ETGs) with $M_\star\approx1.5\times10^{11},{\rm M}\odot$ dark matter should account for $\sim60%$ of the dynamical mass within five effective radii ($5,R{\rm e}$). Most massive ETGs have been shaped through a two-phase process: the rapid growth of a compact core was followed by the accretion of an extended envelope through mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrophysical and Cosmological Searches for Lorentz Invariance Violation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/astrophysical_and_cosmological_searches_for_lorentz_invariance_violation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/astrophysical_and_cosmological_searches_for_lorentz_invariance_violation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shantanu Desai
Lorentz invariance is one of the fundamental tenets of Special Relativity, and has been extensively tested with laboratory and astrophysical observations. However, many quantum gravity models and theories beyond the Standard Model of Particle Physics predict a violation of Lorentz invariance at energies close to Planck scale. This article reviews observational and experimental tests of Lorentz invariance violation (LIV) with photons, neutrinos and gravitational waves. Most astrophysical tests of LIV using photons are based on searching for a correlation of the spectral lag data with redshift and energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints with the linear point from the BOSS survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_with_the_linear_point_from_the_boss_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_with_the_linear_point_from_the_boss_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mengfan He
The {\it Linear Point} (LP), defined as the midpoint between the BAO peak and the associated left dip of the two-point correlation function (2PCF), $\xi(s)$, is proposed as a new standard ruler which is insensitive to nonlinear effects. In this paper, we use a Bayesian sampler to measure the LP and estimate the corresponding statistical uncertainty, and then perform cosmological parameter constraints with LP measurements. Using the Patchy mock catalogues, we find that the measured LPs are consistent with theoretical predictions at 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark siren cosmology with binary black holes in the era of third-generation gravitational wave detectors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_siren_cosmology_with_binary_black_holes_in_the_era_of_third-generation_gravitational_wave_detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_siren_cosmology_with_binary_black_holes_in_the_era_of_third-generation_gravitational_wave_detectors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Niccolò Muttoni
Third-generation (3G) gravitational wave detectors, in particular Einstein Telescope (ET) and Cosmic Explorer (CE), will explore unprecedented cosmic volumes in search for compact binary mergers, providing us with tens of thousands of detections per year. In this study, we simulate and employ binary black holes detected by 3G interferometers as dark sirens, to extract and infer cosmological parameters by cross-matching gravitational wave data with electromagnetic information retrieved from a simulated galaxy catalog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind Search of The Solar Neighborhood Galactic Disk within 5kpc: 1,179 new Star clusters found in Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.10380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.10380/</guid>
      <description>Huanbin Chi
Studying open clusters (OCs) is essential for a comprehensive understanding of the structure and evolution of the Milky Way. Many previous studies have systematically searched for OCs near the solar system within 1.2 kpc or 20 degrees of galactic latitude. However, few studies searched for OCs at higher galactic latitudes and deeper distances. In this study, based on a hybrid unsupervised clustering algorithm (Friends-of-Friends and pyUPMASK) and a binary classification algorithm (Random Forest), we extended the search region (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-rising Type II supernovae resembling supernova 1987A -- I. A comparative study through scaling relations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-rising_type_ii_supernovae_resembling_supernova_1987a_--_i._a_comparative_study_through_scaling_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-rising_type_ii_supernovae_resembling_supernova_1987a_--_i._a_comparative_study_through_scaling_relations/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. L. Pumo
With the aim of improving our knowledge about their nature, we conduct a comparative study on a sample of long-rising Type II supernovae (SNe) resembling SN 1987A. To do so, we deduce various scaling relations from different analytic models of H-rich SNe, discussing their robustness and feasibility. Then we use the best relations in terms of accuracy to infer the SN progenitor&amp;rsquo;s physical properties at the explosion for the selected sample of SN 1987A-like objects, deriving energies of $\sim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Gaussian assembly bias from a semi-analytic galaxy formation model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussian_assembly_bias_from_a_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussian_assembly_bias_from_a_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Marinucci
We use $z=1$ mock galaxy catalogues produced with the semi-analytic code GALACTICUS to study the dependence of the non-Gaussian bias parameter $b_\phi$ on the mass assembly history of the host halos. We generate large sets of merger trees and measure the non-Gaussian assembly bias $\Delta b_\phi$ for galaxies selected by color magnitude and emission line luminosities. For galaxies selected by $g-r$ color, we find a large assembly bias consistent with the analysis of Barreira et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The H$α$ broadband photometric reverberation mapping of four Seyfert 1 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__broadband_photometric_reverberation_mapping_of_four_seyfert_1_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__broadband_photometric_reverberation_mapping_of_four_seyfert_1_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qinchun Ma
Broadband photometric reverberation mapping (PRM) have been investigated for AGNs in recent years, but mostly on accretion disk continuum RM. Due to the small fraction of broad emission lines in the broadband, PRM for emission lines is very challenging. Here we present an ICCF-Cut method for broadband PRM to obtain the H$\alpha$ broad line lag and apply it to four Seyfert 1 galaxies, MCG+08-11-011, NGC 2617, 3C 120 and NGC 5548.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamics simulations of core convection in supermassive main-sequence stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_core_convection_in_supermassive_main-sequence_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_core_convection_in_supermassive_main-sequence_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Blouin
Supermassive stars are Population III stars with masses exceeding $10^4,M_{\odot}$ that could be the progenitors of the first supermassive black holes. Their interiors are in a regime where radiation pressure dominates the equation of state. In this work, we use the explicit gas dynamics code PPMstar to simulate the hydrogen-burning core of a $10^4,M_{\odot}$ supermassive main-sequence star. These are the first 3D hydrodynamics simulations of core convection in supermassive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An HI story of galaxies in Abell 2626 and beyond</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_hi_story_of_galaxies_in_abell_2626_and_beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_hi_story_of_galaxies_in_abell_2626_and_beyond/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Deb
Context: To study the effects of environment on galaxies we use HI observations of galaxies in and around the cluster A2626. The cluster can effectively be divided in three different environments: the cluster itself, a group environment in the periphery of the cluster (we call it the Swarm) and substructure in the cluster itself. We use these to study the dependence of galaxy properties on environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology inference at the field level from biased tracers in redshift-space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_inference_at_the_field_level_from_biased_tracers_in_redshift-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_inference_at_the_field_level_from_biased_tracers_in_redshift-space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Julia Stadler
Cosmology inference of galaxy clustering at the field level with the EFT likelihood in principle allows for extracting all non-Gaussian information from quasi-linear scales, while robustly marginalizing over any astrophysical uncertainties. A pipeline in this spirit is implemented in the \texttt{LEFTfield} code, which we extend in this work to describe the clustering of galaxies in redshift space. Our main additions are: the computation of the velocity field in the LPT gravity model, the fully nonlinear displacement of the evolved, biased density field to redshift space, and a systematic expansion of velocity bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA): Bulge-disk decomposition of KiDS and VIKING data in the nearby universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_bulge-disk_decomposition_of_kids_and_viking_data_in_the_nearby_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_bulge-disk_decomposition_of_kids_and_viking_data_in_the_nearby_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sarah Casura
In this thesis, we derive a catalogue of robust structural parameters for the components of a large sample of nearby GAMA galaxies while at the same time contributing to the advancement of image analysis, surface brightness fitting and post-processing routines for quality assurance in the context of automated large-scale bulge-disk decomposition studies. The sample consists of 13096 galaxies at redshifts z &amp;lt; 0.08 with imaging data from the Kilo-Degree Survey and the VISTA Kilo-Degree INfrared Galaxy survey spanning the optical and near-infrared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPT-CL J2215-3537: A Massive Starburst at the Center of the Most Distant Relaxed Galaxy Cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spt-cl_j2215-3537_a_massive_starburst_at_the_center_of_the_most_distant_relaxed_galaxy_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spt-cl_j2215-3537_a_massive_starburst_at_the_center_of_the_most_distant_relaxed_galaxy_cluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael S. Calzadilla
We present the discovery of the most distant, dynamically relaxed cool core cluster, SPT-CL J2215-3537 (SPT2215) and its central brightest cluster galaxy (BCG) at z=1.16. Using new X-ray observations, we demonstrate that SPT2215 harbors a strong cool core, with a central cooling time of 200 Myr (at 10 kpc) and a maximal intracluster medium cooling rate of 1900+/-400 Msun/yr. This prodigious cooling may be responsible for fueling extended, star-forming filaments observed in Hubble Space Telescope imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emergence of Brightest Cluster Galaxy in the Most Massive Protocluster Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_emergence_of_brightest_cluster_galaxy_in_the_most_massive_protocluster_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_emergence_of_brightest_cluster_galaxy_in_the_most_massive_protocluster_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dongdong Shi
Distant protoclusters of galaxies, as the progenitors of massive galaxy clusters in the present day, are expected to host brightest cluster galaxies (BCGs) at their early formation stage. It remains unclear whether the assembly of (some) BCGs is essential to the formation of a mature cluster core or vice versa. Here we report the detection of a pair of massive quiescent galaxies likely in the process of merging at the centre of the spectroscopically confirmed, extremely massive protocluster BOSS1244 at a look-back time of 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pantheon Sample analysis of cosmological constraints under new models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pantheon_sample_analysis_of_cosmological_constraints_under_new_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pantheon_sample_analysis_of_cosmological_constraints_under_new_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peifeng Peng
In this project, the cosmological parameters are determined by applying six cosmological models to fit the magnitude-redshift relation of the Pantheon Sample consisting of 1048 Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) in the range of $0.01 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 2.26$. Apart from the well-known flat $\Lambda$CDM model as well as other models that have been broadly studied, this project includes two new models, which are the $\textit{o}\textit{w}$CDM model and the $\textit{o}\textit{w}0\textit{w}a$CDM model, to fully evaluate the correlations between the cosmological parameters by performing the MCMC algorithm and to explore the geometry and mass content of the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIGHTEE-\HI: Possible interactions with the galaxy NGC~895</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mightee-_hi_possible_interactions_with_the_galaxy_ngc~895/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mightee-_hi_possible_interactions_with_the_galaxy_ngc~895/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brenda Namumba
The transformation and evolution of a galaxy is strongly influenced by interactions with its environment. Neutral hydrogen (\HI) is an excellent way to trace these interactions. Here, we present \HI\ observations of the spiral galaxy NGC~895, which was previously thought to be isolated. High-sensitivity \HI\ observations from the MeerKAT large survey project MIGHTEE reveal possible interaction features, such as extended spiral arms, and the two newly discovered \HI\ companions, that drive us to change the narrative that it is an isolated galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular gas in super spiral galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/molecular_gas_in_super_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/molecular_gas_in_super_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ute Lisenfeld
At the highest stellar masses (log(\mstar) $\gtrsim$ 11.5 \msun), only a small fraction of galaxies are disk-like and actively star-forming objects. These so-called `super spirals&amp;rsquo; are ideal objects to better understand how galaxy evolution proceeds and to extend our knowledge about the relation between stars and gas to a higher stellar mass regime. We present new CO(1-0) data for a sample of 46 super spirals and for 18 slightly lower-mass (log(\mstar) $&amp;gt;$ 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleosynthesis in neutrino-heated ejecta and neutrino-driven winds of core-collapse supernovae; neutrino-induced nucleosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_neutrino-heated_ejecta_and_neutrino-driven_winds_of_core-collapse_supernovae_neutrino-induced_nucleosynthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_neutrino-heated_ejecta_and_neutrino-driven_winds_of_core-collapse_supernovae_neutrino-induced_nucleosynthesis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shinya Wanajo
The innermost ejecta of core-collapse supernovae are considered to be the sources of some iron-group and heavier nuclei. The ejecta are predominantly driven by neutrino heating, principally due to neutrino capture on free neutrons and protons. Such neutrino interaction plays a crucial role for setting neutron richness in the ejecta. Recent hydrodynamics work with sophisticated neutrino transport indicates that the ejecta are only mildly neutron rich or even proton rich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric study of the late-time near-infrared plateau in Type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_study_of_the_late-time_near-infrared_plateau_in_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_study_of_the_late-time_near-infrared_plateau_in_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Deckers
We present an in-depth study of the late-time near-infrared plateau in Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia), which occurs between 70-500 d. We double the existing sample of SNe Ia observed during the late-time near-infrared plateau with new observations taken with the Hubble Space Telescope, Gemini, New Technology Telescope, the 3.5m Calar Alto Telescope, and the Nordic Optical Telescope. Our sample consists of 24 nearby SNe Ia at redshift &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly growing primordial black holes as seeds of the massive high-redshift JWST Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapidly_growing_primordial_black_holes_as_seeds_of_the_massive_high-redshift_jwst_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapidly_growing_primordial_black_holes_as_seeds_of_the_massive_high-redshift_jwst_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guan-Wen Yuan
A group of massive galaxies at redshifts of $z\geq 6.5$ have been recently detected by James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), which were unexpected to form at such early times within the standard Big Bang cosmology. In this work we propose that the formation of some $\sim 50~M_\odot$ primordial black holes (PBHs) formed in the early Universe via super-Eddington accretion within the dark matter halo can explain these observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chandra X-ray Survey of Optically Selected Close Galaxy Pairs: Unexpectedly Low Occupation of Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_chandra_x-ray_survey_of_optically_selected_close_galaxy_pairs_unexpectedly_low_occupation_of_active_galactic_nuclei/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_chandra_x-ray_survey_of_optically_selected_close_galaxy_pairs_unexpectedly_low_occupation_of_active_galactic_nuclei/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lin He
High-resolution X-ray observations offer a unique tool for probing the still elusive connection between galaxy mergers and active galactic nuclei (AGNs). We present an analysis of nuclear X-ray emission in an optically selected sample of 92 close galaxy pairs (with projected separations $\lesssim 20$ kpc and line-of-sight velocity offsets $&amp;lt;$ 500 km s$^{-1}$) at low redshift ($\bar{z} \sim 0.07$), based on archival Chandra observations. The parent sample of galaxy pairs is constructed without imposing an optical classification of nuclear activity, thus is largely free of selection effect for or against the presence of an AGN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback in the merging galaxy group NGC6338</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/feedback_in_the_merging_galaxy_group_ngc6338/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/feedback_in_the_merging_galaxy_group_ngc6338/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gerrit Schellenberger
The galaxy group NGC6338 is one of the most violent group-group mergers known to date. While the central dominant galaxies rush at each other at 1400km/s along the line of sight, with dramatic gas heating and shock fronts detected, the central gas in the BCGs remains cool. There are also indications of feedback from active galactic nuclei (AGNs), and neither subcluster core has been disrupted. With our deep radio uGMRT data at 383MHz and 650MHz we clearly detect a set of large, old lobes in the southern BCG coinciding with the X-ray cavities, while the northern, and smaller BCG appears slightly extended in the radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First results from the JWST Early Release Science Program Q3D: The Warm Ionized Gas Outflow in z ~ 1.6 Quasar XID 2028 and its Impact on the Host Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_results_from_the_jwst_early_release_science_program_q3d_the_warm_ionized_gas_outflow_in_z_~_1.6_quasar_xid_2028_and_its_impact_on_the_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_results_from_the_jwst_early_release_science_program_q3d_the_warm_ionized_gas_outflow_in_z_~_1.6_quasar_xid_2028_and_its_impact_on_the_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sylvain Veilleux
Quasar feedback may regulate the growth of supermassive black holes, quench coeval star formation, and impact galaxy morphology and the circumgalactic medium. However, direct evidence for quasar feedback in action at the epoch of peak black hole accretion at z ~ 2 remains elusive. A good case in point is the z = 1.6 quasar WISEA J100211.29+013706.7 (XID 2028) where past analyses of the same ground-based data have come to different conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength monitoring of the nucleus in PBC J2333.9-2343: the giant radio galaxy with a blazar-like core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_monitoring_of_the_nucleus_in_pbc_j2333.9-2343_the_giant_radio_galaxy_with_a_blazar-like_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_monitoring_of_the_nucleus_in_pbc_j2333.9-2343_the_giant_radio_galaxy_with_a_blazar-like_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Hernández-García
PBC J2333.9-2343 is a giant radio galaxy at z = 0.047 with a bright central core associated to a blazar nucleus. If the nuclear blazar jet is a new phase of the jet activity, then the small orientation angle suggest a dramatic change of the jet direction. We present observations obtained between September 2018 and January 2019 (cadence larger than three days) with Effeslberg, SMARTS-1.3m, ZTF, ATLAS, Swift, and Fermi-LAT, and between April-July 2019 (daily cadence) with SMARTS-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Dynamical Heating of Dwarf Galaxies in a Fuzzy Dark Matter Halo</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_dynamical_heating_of_dwarf_galaxies_in_a_fuzzy_dark_matter_halo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_dynamical_heating_of_dwarf_galaxies_in_a_fuzzy_dark_matter_halo/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dhruba Dutta Chowdhury
Fuzzy Dark Matter (FDM), consisting of ultralight bosons, is an intriguing alternative to Cold Dark Matter. Numerical simulations solving the Schr&amp;quot;odinger-Poisson (SP) equation, which governs FDM dynamics, show that FDM halos consist of a central solitonic core (representing the ground state of the SP equation), surrounded by a large envelope of excited states. Wave interference gives rise to order unity density fluctuations throughout the envelope and causes the soliton to undergo density oscillations and execute a confined random walk in the central region of the halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-lived Radionuclides in the Milky Way Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radionuclides_in_the_milky_way_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radionuclides_in_the_milky_way_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tejpreet Kaur
The short-lived radionuclides (SLRs) have a half-life $\leq$ 100 Myr. The $\gamma$-ray observations and excess abundance of their daughter nuclides in various meteoritic phases confirm the existence of SLRs in the Galaxy and early solar system (ESS), respectively. In this work, we have developed Galactic Chemical Evolution (GCE) models for SLRs, $^{26}$Al, and $^{60}$Fe along with $^{36}$Cl, $^{41}$Ca, and $^{53}$Mn. These models predict the temporal and spatial evolution of SLR abundance trends in the Galaxy from 2-18 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of pre-supernova feedback in spherical clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_pre-supernova_feedback_in_spherical_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_pre-supernova_feedback_in_spherical_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michalis Kourniotis
We present a one-dimensional radiation-hydrodynamic model of a spherically symmetric cloud evolving under the influence of the self-gravity and the feedback from a star cluster forming in its centre. On one hand, the model is simple due to its 1D geometry, on the other hand, the feedback includes the ionising radiation, stellar winds and the radiation pressure acting on gas and dust. The star cluster is formed from the gas flowing into the cloud centre and the feedback parameters are determined from stellar evolution models and the cluster star forming history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The e-MANTIS emulator: fast predictions of the non-linear matter power spectrum in $f(R)$CDM cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_e-mantis_emulator_fast_predictions_of_the_non-linear_matter_power_spectrum_in__fr_cdm_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_e-mantis_emulator_fast_predictions_of_the_non-linear_matter_power_spectrum_in__fr_cdm_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iñigo Sáez-Casares
In order to probe modifications of gravity at cosmological scales, one needs accurate theoretical predictions. N-body simulations are required to explore the non-linear regime of structure formation but are very time consuming. In this work, we build an emulator, dubbed e-MANTIS, that performs an accurate and fast interpolation between the predictions of a given set of cosmological simulations, in $f(R)$ modified gravity, run with ECOSMOG. We sample a wide 3D parameter space given by the current background scalar field value $10^{-7} &amp;lt; \left|f_{R_0} \right| &amp;lt; 10^{-4}$, matter density $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The halo model for cosmology: a pedagogical review</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_halo_model_for_cosmology_a_pedagogical_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_halo_model_for_cosmology_a_pedagogical_review/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marika Asgari
We present a pedagogical review of the halo model, a flexible framework that can describe the distribution of matter and its tracers on non-linear scales for both conventional and exotic cosmological models. We start with the premise that the complex structure of the cosmic web can be described by the sum of its individual components: dark matter, gas, and galaxies, all distributed within spherical haloes with a range of masses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LeMMINGs survey: probing sub-kpc radio structures of nearby galaxies with e-MERLIN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_lemmings_survey_probing_sub-kpc_radio_structures_of_nearby_galaxies_with_e-merlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_lemmings_survey_probing_sub-kpc_radio_structures_of_nearby_galaxies_with_e-merlin/</guid>
      <description>First author: David R. A. Williams
The Legacy e-MERLIN Multi-band Imaging of Nearby Galaxies survey (LeMMINGs) is a statistically-complete census of nuclear accretion and star formation processes in the local Universe. The LeMMINGs observations at 1.5 and 5 GHz yield angular resolutions on 10s milliarcsecond-scales, with sensitivities of 10s $\mu$Jy. Awarded 810 hours of observing time, the full statistical sample (at 1.5 GHz) plus several studies of individual objects have now been published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of LoBAL QSOs: II. HST/WFC3 Observations Reveal Host Galaxies Dominated by Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_nature_of_lobal_qsos_ii._hst_wfc3_observations_reveal_host_galaxies_dominated_by_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_nature_of_lobal_qsos_ii._hst_wfc3_observations_reveal_host_galaxies_dominated_by_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mariana S. Lazarova
Low-ionization Broad Absorption Line QSOs (LoBALs) are suspected to be merging systems in which extreme, AGN-driven outflows have been triggered. Whether or not LoBALs are uniquely associated with mergers, however, has yet to be established. To characterize the morphologies of LoBALs, we present the first high-resolution morphological analysis of a volume-limited sample of 22 SDSS-selected LoBALs at 0.5 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.6 from Hubble Space Telescope Wide Field Camera 3 observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Enigmatic Globular Cluster Ultracompact X-ray Binary X1850--087: Extreme Radio Variability in the Hard State</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.08836/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.08836/</guid>
      <description>T. Panurach
The conditions under which accreting neutron stars launch radio-emitting jets and/or outflows are still poorly understood. The ultracompact X-ray binary X1850--087, located in the globular cluster NGC 6712, is a persistent atoll-type X-ray source that has previously shown unusual radio continuum variability. Here we present the results of a pilot radio monitoring program of X1850--087 undertaken with the Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array, with simultaneous or quasi-simultaneous Swift/XRT data obtained at each epoch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Ia supernovae SN 2013bz, PSN J0910&#43;5003 and ASASSN-16ex: similar to 09dc-like?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_sn_2013bz_psn_j0910&#43;5003_and_asassn-16ex_similar_to_09dc-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_sn_2013bz_psn_j0910&#43;5003_and_asassn-16ex_similar_to_09dc-like/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Tiwari
We present optical photometric and spectroscopic studies of three supernovae (SNe) SN 2013bz, PSN J0910+5003 and ASASSN-16ex. UV-optical photometric data of ASASSN-16ex obtained with Swift-UVOT are also analyzed. These objects were initially classified as 09dc-like type Ia SNe. The decline rate parameters ($\Delta m_{15}(B){true}$) are derived as 0.92 $\pm$ 0.04 (SN 2013bz), 0.70 $\pm$ 0.05 (PSN J0910+5003) and 0.73 $\pm$ 0.03 (ASASSN-16ex). The estimated $B$ band absolute magnitudes at maximum: $-$19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vorticity generation in cosmology and the role of shell crossing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vorticity_generation_in_cosmology_and_the_role_of_shell_crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vorticity_generation_in_cosmology_and_the_role_of_shell_crossing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Obinna Umeh
There is no source for cosmic vorticity within the cold dark matter cosmology. However, vorticity has been observed in the universe, especially on the scales of clusters, filaments, galaxies, etc. Recent results from high-resolution general relativistic N-body simulation show that the vorticity power spectrum dominates over the power spectrum of the divergence of the peculiar velocity field on scales where the effective field theory of large-scale structure breaks down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-HESS: a large sample of highly accreting serendipitous AGN under the XMM-Newton microscope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-hess_a_large_sample_of_highly_accreting_serendipitous_agn_under_the_xmm-newton_microscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-hess_a_large_sample_of_highly_accreting_serendipitous_agn_under_the_xmm-newton_microscope/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Laurenti
The bulk of X-ray spectroscopic studies of active galactic nuclei (AGN) are focused on local ($z &amp;lt; 0.1$) sources with low-to-moderate ($&amp;lt; 0.3$) Eddington ratio ($\lambda_\mathrm{Edd}$). It is then mandatory to overcome this limitation and improve our understanding of highly accreting AGN. In this work we present the preliminary results from the analysis of a sample of $\sim70$ high-$\lambda_\mathrm{Edd}$ radio-quiet AGN at $0.06 \leq z \leq 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dense Molecular Gas Properties of the Central Kpc of Nearby Ultraluminous Infrared Galaxies Constrained by ALMA Three Transition-line Observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dense_molecular_gas_properties_of_the_central_kpc_of_nearby_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_constrained_by_alma_three_transition-line_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dense_molecular_gas_properties_of_the_central_kpc_of_nearby_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_constrained_by_alma_three_transition-line_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Masatoshi Imanishi
We report the results of ALMA 1-2 kpc-resolution, three rotational transition line (J=2-1, J=3-2, and J=4-3) observations of multiple dense molecular gas tracers (HCN, HCO$^{+}$, and HNC) for ten nearby (ultra)luminous infrared galaxies ($[U]$LIRGs). Following the matching of beam sizes to 1-2 kpc for each (U)LIRG, the high-J to low-J transition-line flux ratios of each molecule and the emission line flux ratios of different molecules at each J transition are derived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct T_e-based Metallicities of z=2-9 Galaxies with JWST/NIRSpec: Empirical Metallicity Calibrations Applicable from Reionization to Cosmic Noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/direct_t_e-based_metallicities_of_z2-9_galaxies_with_jwst_nirspec_empirical_metallicity_calibrations_applicable_from_reionization_to_cosmic_noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/direct_t_e-based_metallicities_of_z2-9_galaxies_with_jwst_nirspec_empirical_metallicity_calibrations_applicable_from_reionization_to_cosmic_noon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan L. Sanders
We report detections of the $[OIII]$$\lambda$4364 auroral emission line for 16 galaxies at z=2.1-8.7, measured from JWST/NIRSpec observations obtained as part of the Cosmic Evolution Early Release Science (CEERS) survey program. We combine this CEERS sample with 9 objects from the literature at z=4-9 with auroral-line detections from JWST/NIRSpec and 21 galaxies at z=1.4-3.7 with auroral-line detections from ground-based spectroscopy. We derive electron temperature T_e and direct-method oxygen abundances for the combined sample of 46 star-forming galaxies at z=1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early results from GLASS-JWST XVI: Discovering a bluer z~4-7 Universe through UV slopes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.13860/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.13860/</guid>
      <description>Themiya Nanayakkara
We use the GLASS-JWST Early Release Science NIRCam parallel observations to provide a first view of the UV continuum properties of NIRCam/F444W selected galaxies at 4&amp;amp;lt;z&amp;amp;lt;7. By combining multiwavelength NIRCam observations, we constrain the UV continuum slope for a sample of 401 galaxies with stringent quality controls. We find that &amp;amp;gt;99% of the galaxies are blue star-forming galaxies with very low levels of dust (Avbeta~0.01+/-0.33). We find no statistically significant correlation for UV slope with redshift or UV magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Measurements of the CMB Blackbody Temperature Power Spectrum by Removing CIB and Thermal Sunyaev-Zel&#39;dovich Contamination Using External Galaxy Catalogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/enhancing_measurements_of_the_cmb_blackbody_temperature_power_spectrum_by_removing_cib_and_thermal_sunyaev-zeldovich_contamination_using_external_galaxy_catalogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/enhancing_measurements_of_the_cmb_blackbody_temperature_power_spectrum_by_removing_cib_and_thermal_sunyaev-zeldovich_contamination_using_external_galaxy_catalogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aleksandra Kusiak
Extracting the CMB blackbody temperature power spectrum &amp;ndash; which is dominated by the primary CMB signal and the kinematic Sunyaev-Zel&amp;rsquo;dovich (kSZ) effect &amp;ndash; from mm-wave sky maps requires cleaning other sky components. In this work, we develop new methods to use large-scale structure (LSS) tracers to remove cosmic infrared background (CIB) and thermal Sunyaev-Zel&amp;rsquo;dovich (tSZ) contamination in such measurements. Our methods rely on the fact that LSS tracers are correlated with the CIB and tSZ signals, but their two-point correlations with the CMB and kSZ signals vanish on small scales, thus leaving the CMB blackbody power spectrum unbiased after cleaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Cosmic Web Environment Affects Galaxy Quenching Across Cosmic Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_cosmic_web_environment_affects_galaxy_quenching_across_cosmic_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_cosmic_web_environment_affects_galaxy_quenching_across_cosmic_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Farhanul Hasan
We investigate how cosmic web structures affect galaxy quenching in the IllustrisTNG (TNG-100) cosmological simulations by reconstructing the cosmic web in each snapshot using the DisPerSE framework. We measure the distance from each galaxy with stellar mass log(M*/Msun)&amp;gt;=8 to the nearest node (dnode) and the nearest filament spine (dfil) and study the dependence of both median specific star formation rate () and median gas fraction () on these distances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-enhancement in GN-z11: First evidence for supermassive stars nucleosynthesis in proto-globular clusters-like conditions at high redshift ?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07955/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07955/</guid>
      <description>C. Charbonnel
Unusually high N/O abundances were recently reported for a very compact, intensively star-forming object GN-z11 at z=10.6 from JWST/NIRSpec observations. We present an empirical comparison with the C, N, and O abundance ratios in Galactic globular clusters (GCs) over a large metallicity range. We show that hot hydrogen-burning nucleosynthesis within supermassive stars (SMS) formed through runaway collisions can consistently explain the observed abundances ratio in GN-z11 and in GCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observational Evidence for Large-Scale Gas Heating in a Galaxy Protocluster at z=2.30</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_evidence_for_large-scale_gas_heating_in_a_galaxy_protocluster_at_z2.30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observational_evidence_for_large-scale_gas_heating_in_a_galaxy_protocluster_at_z2.30/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chenze Dong
We report a $z=2.30$ galaxy protocluster (COSTCO-I) in the COSMOS field, where the Lyman-$\alpha$ forest as seen in the CLAMATO IGM tomography survey does not show significant absorption. This departs from the transmission-density relationship (often dubbed the fluctuating Gunn-Peterson approximation; FGPA) usually expected to hold at this epoch, which would lead one to predict strong Ly$\alpha$ absorption at the overdensity. For comparison, we generate mock Lyman-$\alpha$ forest maps by applying FGPA to constrained simulations of the COSMOS density field, and create mocks that incorporate the effects of finite sightline sampling, pixel noise, and Wiener filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometry and spectroscopy of the Type Icn supernova 2021ckj: The diverse properties of the ejecta and circumstellar matter of Type Icn SNe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometry_and_spectroscopy_of_the_type_icn_supernova_2021ckj_the_diverse_properties_of_the_ejecta_and_circumstellar_matter_of_type_icn_sne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometry_and_spectroscopy_of_the_type_icn_supernova_2021ckj_the_diverse_properties_of_the_ejecta_and_circumstellar_matter_of_type_icn_sne/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Nagao
We present photometric and spectroscopic observations of the Type Icn supernova (SN) 2021ckj. Spectral modeling of SN 2021ckj reveals that its composition is dominated by oxygen, carbon and iron group elements, and the photospheric velocity at peak is ~10000 km/s. From the light curve (LC) modeling applied to SNe 2021ckj, 2019hgp, and 2021csp, we find that the ejecta and CSM properties of Type Icn SNe are diverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio halos and relics from extended cosmic-ray ion distributions with strong diffusion in galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_halos_and_relics_from_extended_cosmic-ray_ion_distributions_with_strong_diffusion_in_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_halos_and_relics_from_extended_cosmic-ray_ion_distributions_with_strong_diffusion_in_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Uri Keshet
A joint hadronic model is shown to quantitatively explain the observations of diffuse radio emission from galaxy clusters in the form of minihalos, giant halos, relics, and their hybrid, transitional stages. Cosmic-ray diffusion of order $D\sim 10^{31\text{&amp;ndash;}32}\text{ cm}^2\text{ s}^{-1}$, inferred independently from relic energies, the spatial variability of giant-halo spectra, and the spectral evolution of relics, reproduces the observed spatio-spectral distributions, explains the recently discovered mega-halos as enhanced peripheral magnetisation, and quenches electron (re)acceleration by weak shocks or turbulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search strategies for supermassive stars in young clusters and application to nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_strategies_for_supermassive_stars_in_young_clusters_and_application_to_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_strategies_for_supermassive_stars_in_young_clusters_and_application_to_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Kuruvanthodi
Supermassive stars (SMS) with masses $M \gtrsim 10^3-10^4 M_{\odot}$, formed by runaway collisions in young, massive, and dense star clusters have been invoked as a possible solution to the puzzles raised by the presence of multiple stellar populations and peculiar abundance patterns observed in globular clusters. However, such objects have not been observed so far. We developed observational strategies to search for SMS hosted within young massive clusters (thought to be the precursors of globular clusters, GCs), which could be applicable in a relatively general fashion, using both photometric and spectroscopic observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Outflow Feedback on Accretion of Compact Objects in Accretion Disk of Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07639/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07639/</guid>
      <description>Ken Chen
Compact objects (COs) can exist and evolve in an active galactic nuclei (AGN) disk, triggering a series of attractive CO-related multi-messenger events around a supermassive black hole. To better understand the nature of an embedded CO and its surroundings and to investigate CO-related events more accurately, in this paper, we study the specific accretion process of a CO in an AGN disk and explore the role of outflow feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRINITY II: The Luminosity-dependent Bias of the Supermassive Black Hole Mass--Galaxy Mass Relation for Bright Quasars at $z=6$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/trinity_ii_the_luminosity-dependent_bias_of_the_supermassive_black_hole_mass--galaxy_mass_relation_for_bright_quasars_at__z6_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/trinity_ii_the_luminosity-dependent_bias_of_the_supermassive_black_hole_mass--galaxy_mass_relation_for_bright_quasars_at__z6_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Haowen Zhang
Using recent empirical constraints on the dark matter halo&amp;ndash;galaxy&amp;ndash;supermassive black hole (SMBH) connection from $z=0-7$, we infer how undermassive, typical, and overmassive SMBHs contribute to the quasar luminosity function (QLF) at $z=6$. We find that beyond $L_\mathrm{bol} = 5 \times 10^{46}$ erg/s, the $z=6$ QLF is dominated by SMBHs that are at least 0.3 dex above the $z=6$ median $M_\bullet-M_$ relation. The QLF is dominated by typical SMBHs (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERTICO V: The environmentally driven evolution of the inner cold gas discs of Virgo cluster galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_v_the_environmentally_driven_evolution_of_the_inner_cold_gas_discs_of_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_v_the_environmentally_driven_evolution_of_the_inner_cold_gas_discs_of_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam B. Watts
The quenching of cluster satellite galaxies is inextricably linked to the suppression of their cold interstellar medium (ISM) by environmental mechanisms. While the removal of neutral atomic hydrogen (HI) at large radii is well studied, how the environment impacts the remaining gas in the centres of galaxies, which are dominated by molecular gas, is less clear. Using new observations from the Virgo Environment traced in CO survey (VERTICO) and archival HI data, we study the HI and molecular gas within the optical discs of Virgo cluster galaxies on 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$S_8$ increases with effective redshift in $Λ$CDM cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_s_8__increases_with_effective_redshift_in__%CE%BB_cdm_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_s_8__increases_with_effective_redshift_in__%CE%BB_cdm_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shahnawaz A. Adil
Hubble constant $H_0$ and weighted amplitude of matter fluctuations $S_8$ determinations are biased to higher and lower values, respectively, in the late Universe with respect to early Universe values inferred by the Planck collaboration within flat $\Lambda$CDM cosmology. If these anomalies are physical, i.e. not due to systematics, they naively suggest that $H_0$ decreases and $S_8$ increases with effective redshift. Here, on the assumption that matter density parameter today $\Omega_{m}$ is a constant, we show that $S_8$ determinations from $f \sigma_8(z)$ constraints increase with effective redshift, thereby providing corroborating support for an $S_8$ discrepancy that is physical in origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamics simulations of internal gravity waves in red giant branch stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_internal_gravity_waves_in_red_giant_branch_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_internal_gravity_waves_in_red_giant_branch_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Blouin
We present the first 3D hydrodynamics simulations of the excitation and propagation of internal gravity waves (IGWs) in the radiative interiors of low-mass stars on the red giant branch (RGB). We use the PPMstar explicit gas dynamics code to simulate a portion of the convective envelope and all the radiative zone down to the hydrogen-burning shell of a 1.2$M_{\odot}$ upper RGB star. We perform simulations for different grid resolutions (768$^3$, 1536$^3$ and 2880$^3$), a range of driving luminosities, and two different stratifications (corresponding to the bump luminosity and the tip of the RGB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Model of EUV Emission from Clusters of Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_model_of_euv_emission_from_clusters_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_model_of_euv_emission_from_clusters_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Richard Lieu
With tantalizing evidence of the recent e-Rosita mission, re-discovering very soft X-rays and EUV radiation from a cluster of galaxies or its environment, the question of the origin of cluster EUV excess is revisited in this work. It will be shown that the gas temperature, density, and frozen-in magnetic field of the intracluster medium, collectively support the emission and propagation of coherent \u{C}erenkov radiation, which is low frequency and large amplitude radiation capable of accelerating charged particles to relativistic speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark-ages reionization and galaxy formation simulation -- XXI. Constraining the evolution of the ionizing escape fraction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark-ages_reionization_and_galaxy_formation_simulation_--_xxi._constraining_the_evolution_of_the_ionizing_escape_fraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark-ages_reionization_and_galaxy_formation_simulation_--_xxi._constraining_the_evolution_of_the_ionizing_escape_fraction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon J. Mutch
The fraction of ionizing photons that escape their host galaxies to ionize hydrogen in the inter-galactic medium (IGM) is a critical parameter in analyses of the reionization era. In this paper we use the Meraxes semi-analytic galaxy formation model to infer the mean ionizing photon escape fraction and its dependence on galaxy properties through joint modelling of the observed high redshift galaxy population and existing constraints on the reionization history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eccentric black hole mergers via three-body interactions in young, globular and nuclear star clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07421/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07421/</guid>
      <description>Marco Dall&amp;rsquo;Amico
Eccentric mergers are a signature of the dynamical formation channel of binary black holes (BBHs) in dense stellar environments and hierarchical triple systems. Here, we investigate the production of eccentric mergers via binary-single interactions, by means of $2.5\times10^{5}$ direct $\textit{N}$-body simulations. Our simulations include post-Newtonian terms up to the 2.5th order and are designed to reflect the environmental conditions of young (YSCs), globular (GCs), and nuclear star clusters (NSCs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exotic energy injection in the early universe I: a novel treatment for low-energy electrons and photons</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07366/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07366/</guid>
      <description>Hongwan Liu,
Decaying or annihilating dark matter and other exotic energy injections can modify the spectrum of the universe&amp;amp;#39;s photon bath, resulting in e.g. new contributions to spectral distortions of the cosmic microwave background blackbody spectrum and modifications to the temperature and ionization history of the universe. Here, we present an improved version of the $\texttt{DarkHistory}$ code, which is now capable of consistently calculating the spectrum of low-energy photons by properly treating the interactions of these photons with the levels of hydrogen atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exotic energy injection in the early universe II: CMB spectral distortions and constraints on light dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07370/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07370/</guid>
      <description>Hongwan Liu
We calculate the post-recombination contribution to the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) spectral distortion due to general exotic energy injections, including dark matter (DM) decaying or annihilating to Standard Model particles. Upon subtracting the background distortion that would be present even without such energy injections, we find residual distortions that are still potentially large enough to be detectable by future experiments such as PIXIE. The distortions also have a high-energy spectral feature that is a unique signature of the injection of high-energy particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First emergence of cold accretion and supermassive star formation in the early universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.10263/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.10263/</guid>
      <description>Masaki Kiyuna
We investigate the first emergence of the so-called cold accretion, the accretion flows deeply penetrating a halo, in the early universe with cosmological N-body/SPH simulations. We study the structure of the accretion flow and its evolution within small halos with $\lesssim 10^8~{\rm M}_\odot$ with sufficiently high spatial resolutions down to $\sim 1 \ {\rm pc}$ scale. While previous studies only follow the evolution for a short period after the primordial cloud collapse, we follow the long-term evolution until the cold accretion first appears, employing the sink particle method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamma-Ray Bursts, Quasars, Baryonic Acoustic Oscillations, and Supernovae Ia: new statistical insights and cosmological constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_bursts_quasars_baryonic_acoustic_oscillations_and_supernovae_ia_new_statistical_insights_and_cosmological_constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_bursts_quasars_baryonic_acoustic_oscillations_and_supernovae_ia_new_statistical_insights_and_cosmological_constraints/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Bargiacchi
The recent $\sim 4 , \sigma$ Hubble constant, $H_{0}$, tension is observed between the value of $H_{0}$ from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Type Ia Supernovae (SNe Ia). It is a decade since this tension is excruciating the modern astrophysical community. To shed light on this problem is key to consider probes at intermediate redshifts between SNe Ia and CMB and reduce the uncertainty on $H_0$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Decline with Redshift of Dusty Star-forming Galaxies Using JWST and SCUBA-2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_the_decline_with_redshift_of_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_using_jwst_and_scuba-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_the_decline_with_redshift_of_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_using_jwst_and_scuba-2/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Barger
We use JWST NIRCam observations from 1.5 to 4.44 micron of the massive lensing cluster field A2744 to show that extreme red selected galaxies (f(F444W) &amp;gt; 1 uJy and f(F444W)/f(F150W) &amp;gt; 3.5) pick out all 9 &amp;gt;4.5-sigma ALMA 1.1 or 1.2 mm sources and 17 of the 19 &amp;gt;5-sigma SCUBA-2 850 micron sources in the covered areas. Next, we use the red selected galaxies as priors to probe deeper in the SCUBA-2 850 micron image, identifying a sample of 44 &amp;gt;3-sigma SCUBA-2 850 micron sources with accurate positions, photometric redshifts, and magnifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal Factories in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07376/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07376/</guid>
      <description>Stephen Eales
We have measured the mass of metals in 13 submillimetre galaxies at z~4 in which the gas, based on previous observations, lies in a cold rotating disk. We measured the metal masses using either the submillimetre line or continuum emission from three tracers of the overall metal content - carbon atoms, carbon monoxide molecules and dust grains - using the first calibration of this technique that treats all three tracers simultaneously (Dunne et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phantom dark energy as a natural selection of evolutionary processes $\hat{\rm a}$ $\textit{la}$ $\textit{genetic algorithm}$ and cosmological tensions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phantom_dark_energy_as_a_natural_selection_of_evolutionary_processes___hat_rm_a____textitla____textitgenetic_algorithm__and_cosmological_tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phantom_dark_energy_as_a_natural_selection_of_evolutionary_processes___hat_rm_a____textitla____textitgenetic_algorithm__and_cosmological_tensions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mayukh R. Gangopadhyay
We employ a machine learning (ML) algorithm to analyze cosmological background data and the linear red-shift space distortion (RSD) data in a model-independent way, with specific focus on the Hubble expansion rate and the growth of large-scale structure. We find strong evidence that the natural enhancement in the Hubble parameter at low redshifts is due to the underlying phantom nature of dark energy, rather than low matter density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio spectral properties at 150-5000MHz of star-forming galaxies in the ELAIS-N1 field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_spectral_properties_at_150-5000mhz_of_star-forming_galaxies_in_the_elais-n1_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_spectral_properties_at_150-5000mhz_of_star-forming_galaxies_in_the_elais-n1_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fangxia An
By combining high-sensitivity LOFAR 150MHz, uGMRT 400MHz, GMRT 610MHz, and JVLA 5GHz data in the ELAIS-N1 field, we study the radio spectral properties of radio-detected star-forming galaxies (SFGs) at observer-frame frequencies of 150-5000MHz. We select ~3,500 SFGs that have both LOFAR 150MHz and GMRT 610MHz detections by removing AGN from the two radio samples, and obtain a median spectral index of $\alpha_{150}^{610}=-0.51\pm0.01$ with a scatter of $\sigma=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatially resolved observations of outflows in the radio loud AGN of UGC 8782</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spatially_resolved_observations_of_outflows_in_the_radio_loud_agn_of_ugc_8782/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spatially_resolved_observations_of_outflows_in_the_radio_loud_agn_of_ugc_8782/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rogemar A. Riffel
We use optical Integral Field Spectroscopy (IFU) to study the gas emission structure and kinematics in the inner 3.4$\times$4.9 kpc$^2$ region of the galaxy UGC 8782 (3C 293), host of a radio loud Active Galactic Nucleus (AGN). The observations were performed with the GMOS-IFU on the Gemini North telescope, resulting in a spatial resolution of $\sim725$ pc at the distance of the galaxy. While the stars present ordered rotation following the orientation of the large scale disc, the gas shows a disturbed kinematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extended $[CII]$ under Construction? Observation of the brightest high-z lensed star-forming galaxy at z = 6.2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_extended_cii_under_construction_observation_of_the_brightest_high-z_lensed_star-forming_galaxy_at_z__6.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_extended_cii_under_construction_observation_of_the_brightest_high-z_lensed_star-forming_galaxy_at_z__6.2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yoshinobu Fudamoto
We present results of $[CII]$$,158,\rm{\mu m}$ emission line observations, and report the spectroscopic redshift confirmation of a strongly lensed ($\mu\sim20$) star-forming galaxy, MACS0308-zD1 at $z=6.2078\pm0.0002$. The $[CII]$ emission line is detected with a signal-to-noise ratio $&amp;gt;6$ within the rest-frame UV bright clump of the lensed galaxy (zD1.1) and exhibits multiple velocity components; the narrow $[CII]$ has a velocity full-width-half-maximum (FWHM) of $110\pm20,\rm{km/s}$, while broader $[CII]$ is seen with an FWHM of $230\pm20,\rm{km/s}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Masses of Supernova Remnant Progenitors in M33</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_masses_of_supernova_remnant_progenitors_in_m33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_masses_of_supernova_remnant_progenitors_in_m33/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brad Koplitz
Using resolved optical stellar photometry from the Panchromatic Hubble Andromeda Treasury Triangulum Extended Region (PHATTER) survey, we measured the star formation history (SFH) near the position of 85 supernova remnants (SNRs) in M33. We constrained the progenitor masses for 60 of these SNRs, finding the remaining 25 remnants had no local SF in the last 56 Myr consistent with core-collapse SNe (CCSNe), making them potential Type Ia candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Star Forming Main Sequence To Explore Quiescent Galaxies Across Cosmic Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_the_star_forming_main_sequence_to_explore_quiescent_galaxies_across_cosmic_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_the_star_forming_main_sequence_to_explore_quiescent_galaxies_across_cosmic_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tyler Houston
In this letter, we explore the quiescent lives of central galaxies using the SAGE galaxy model and Uchuu dark matter simulation. We ask three questions: (1) How much of a galaxy&amp;rsquo;s life is spent in quiescence? (2) How often do galaxies transition off the main sequence? (3) What is the typical duration of a quiescent phase? We find low and high-mass galaxies spend the highest fraction of their lives in quiescence: 45 \pm 19% for log10(Mstar) &amp;lt; 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zwicky Transient Facility and Globular Clusters: The Period-Luminosity and Period-Wesenheit Relations for SX Phoenicis Variables in the gri-Band</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07554/</guid>
      <description>Chow-Choong Ngeow
SX Phoenicis (SXP) variables are short period pulsating stars that exhibit a period-luminosity (PL) relation. We derived the gri-band PL and extinction-free period-Wesenheit (PW) relations, as well as the period-color (PC) and reddening-free period-Q-index (PQ) relations for 47 SXP stars in located in 21 globular clusters using the optical light curves taken from Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF). These empirically relations were derived for the first time in the gri filters except for the g-band PL relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matter Cosmology with Varying Viscosity: a Possible Resolution to the $ S_8 $ Tension</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_matter_cosmology_with_varying_viscosity_a_possible_resolution_to_the___s_8___tension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_matter_cosmology_with_varying_viscosity_a_possible_resolution_to_the___s_8___tension/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amjad Ashoorioon
We study varying forms of viscous dark matter and try to address the intriguing tensions of the standard model of cosmology with the recent cosmological data, including the Hubble and $S_8$ tensions. We note that assuming the dark matter viscosity depends on the Hubble parameter, dark matter density, or both, one can improve the statistics. Although the models tend to aggravate the Hubble tension a bit, they tend to reduce the $S_8$ tension, even in comparison with the constant viscosity case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequency-dependent Discrete Implicit Monte-Carlo Scheme for the Radiative Transfer Equation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.06634/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.06634/</guid>
      <description>Elad Steinberg
This work generalizes the discrete implicit Monte-Carlo (DIMC) method for modeling the radiative transfer equation from a gray treatment to an frequency-dependent one. The classic implicit Monte-Carlo (IMC) algorithm, that has been used for several decades, suffers from a well-known numerical problem, called teleportation, where the photons might propagate faster than the exact solution due to the finite size of the spatial and temporal resolution. The Semi-analog Monte-Carlo algorithm proposed the use of two kinds of particles, photons and material particles that are born when a photon is absorbed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational capture of magnetic monopoles by primordial black holes in the early universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07002/</guid>
      <description>Chen Zhang
It is intriguing to ask whether the existence of primordial black holes (PBHs) in the early universe could significantly reduce the abundance of certain stable massive particles (SMP) via gravitational capture, after which the PBHs evaporate before BBN to avoid conflict with stringent bounds. For example, this mechanism is relevant to an alternative solution of the monopole problem proposed by Stojkovic and Freese, in which magnetic monopoles produced in the early universe are captured by PBHs, thus freeing inflation from having to occur during or after the corresponding phase transitions that produced the monopoles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Nature of the First Galaxies with JWST and ALMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_nature_of_the_first_galaxies_with_jwst_and_alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_nature_of_the_first_galaxies_with_jwst_and_alma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maria Emilia De Rossi
By implementing a model of primordial dust emission, we predict dust-continuum fluxes for massive galaxy sources similar to those recently detected by JWST at $z \gtrsim 7$. Current upper flux limits, obtained with ALMA for some of these sources, can constrain gas metallicity and dust fraction of the first galaxies. Encouragingly, if assuming expected properties for typical first galaxies (i.e., dust-to-metal mass ratio: $D/M = 5 \times 10^{-3}$, gas metallicity: $Z_{\rm g} = 5 \times 10^{-3}~Z_{\odot}$, star formation efficiency: $\eta = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAD@home discovery of a one-sided radio jet hitting the companion galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radhome_discovery_of_a_one-sided_radio_jet_hitting_the_companion_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radhome_discovery_of_a_one-sided_radio_jet_hitting_the_companion_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ananda Hota
Minkowski&amp;rsquo;s Object and &amp;lsquo;Death Star galaxy&amp;rsquo; are two of the famous cases of rare instances when a radio jet has been observed to directly hit a neighbouring galaxy. RAD12, the RAD@home citizen science discovery with GMRT being presented here, is not only a new system being added to nearly half a dozen rare cases known so far but also the first case where the neighbouring galaxy is not a minor or dwarf companion but a galaxy bigger than the host of the radio jet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectropolarimetry of the type IIP supernova 2021yja: an unusually high continuum polarization during the photospheric phase</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectropolarimetry_of_the_type_iip_supernova_2021yja_an_unusually_high_continuum_polarization_during_the_photospheric_phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectropolarimetry_of_the_type_iip_supernova_2021yja_an_unusually_high_continuum_polarization_during_the_photospheric_phase/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergiy S. Vasylyev
We present six epochs of optical spectropolarimetry of the Type IIP supernova (SN) 2021yja ranging from $\sim$ 25 to 95 days after the explosion. An unusually high continuum linear polarization of $p \sim 0.9%$ is measured during the early photospheric phase, followed by a steady decrease well before the onset of the nebular phase. This behavior has not been observed before in Type IIP supernovae (SNe IIP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamic simulations of massive main-sequence stars II. Convective excitation and spectra of internal gravity waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars_ii._convective_excitation_and_spectra_of_internal_gravity_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars_ii._convective_excitation_and_spectra_of_internal_gravity_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Thompson
Recent photometric observations of massive stars have identified a low-frequency power excess which appears as stochastic low-frequency variability in light curve observations. We present the oscillation properties of high resolution hydrodynamic simulations of a 25 $\mathrm{M}\odot$ star performed with the PPMStar code. The model star has a convective core mass of $\approx, 12, \mathrm{M}\odot$ and approximately half of the envelope simulated. From this simulation, we extract light curves from several directions, average them over each hemisphere, and process them as if they were real photometric observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Versatile Code for Gamma-Ray Monte-Carlo Radiative Transfer</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.04450/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.04450/</guid>
      <description>Shing-Chi Leung
Ongoing MeV telescopes such as INTEGRAL/SPI and Fermi/GBM, and proposed telescopes including the recently accepted COSI and the e-ASTROGAM and AMEGO missions, provide another window in understanding transients. Their signals contain information about the stellar explosion mechanisms and their corresponding nucleosynthesis of short-lived radioactive isotopes. This raises the need of a radiative transfer code which may efficiently explore different types of astrophysical $γ$-ray sources and their dependence on model parameters and input physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological measurements from void-galaxy and galaxy-galaxy clustering in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_measurements_from_void-galaxy_and_galaxy-galaxy_clustering_in_the_sloan_digital_sky_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_measurements_from_void-galaxy_and_galaxy-galaxy_clustering_in_the_sloan_digital_sky_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex Woodfinden
We present the cosmological implications of measurements of void-galaxy and galaxy-galaxy clustering from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) Main Galaxy Sample (MGS), Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey (BOSS), and extended BOSS (eBOSS) luminous red galaxy catalogues from SDSS Data Release 7, 12, and 16, covering the redshift range $0.07 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 1.0$. We fit a standard $\Lambda$CDM cosmological model as well as various extensions including a constant dark energy equation of state not equal to $-1$, a time-varying dark energy equation of state, and these same models allowing for spatial curvature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distances to 10 nearby galaxies observed with the Hubble space telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/distances_to_10_nearby_galaxies_observed_with_the_hubble_space_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/distances_to_10_nearby_galaxies_observed_with_the_hubble_space_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. D. Karachentsev
Images of 10 galaxies in F814W and F606W filters obtained on the Hubble Space Telescope (HST) are used to construct color-magnitude diagrams for the star population of these galaxies. The distances to the galaxies are estimated from the luminosity of the tip of the red giant branch. The galaxies examined here have radial velocities from 250 to 760 km/s relative to the centroid of the Local Group and distances ranging from 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misidentification of Short GRBs as Magnetars in Nearby Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/misidentification_of_short_grbs_as_magnetars_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/misidentification_of_short_grbs_as_magnetars_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. C. Schösser
Context. Recent observations of GRB 200415A, a short and very bright pulse of $\gamma$-rays, have been claimed to be an extragalactic magnetar giant flare (MGF) whose proposed host galaxy is the nearby ${\mathrm{NGC} , 253}$. However, as the redshift of the transient object was not measured, it is possible that the measured location of the transient on the celestial sphere and the location of the local galaxy merely coincided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Gravity on Cosmological Scales: Theoretical Predictions with the COLA Method</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_gravity_on_cosmological_scales_theoretical_predictions_with_the_cola_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_gravity_on_cosmological_scales_theoretical_predictions_with_the_cola_method/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bartolomeo Fiorini
One of the main objectives of stage IV galaxy surveys is to constrain gravity on cosmological scales. To this end, it is crucial to make accurate theoretical predictions in the nonlinear regime of structure formation in order to maximise the scientific return. This is possible at a relatively low computational cost thanks to COLA simulations, an approximate and much faster alternative to full $N$-body simulations. In this thesis, we focus on two modified gravity theories, $f(R)$ and nDGP, and present an analysis of how COLA simulations can be combined with empirical models for the galaxy-halo connection to produce realistic mock galaxy catalogues in modified gravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The connection between stellar mass, age and quenching timescale in massive quiescent galaxies at $z \simeq 1$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_connection_between_stellar_mass_age_and_quenching_timescale_in_massive_quiescent_galaxies_at__z__simeq_1_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_connection_between_stellar_mass_age_and_quenching_timescale_in_massive_quiescent_galaxies_at__z__simeq_1_/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. L. Hamadouche
We present a spectro-photometric study of a mass-complete sample of quiescent galaxies at $1.0 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 1.3$ with $\mathrm{log_{10}}(M_{\star}/\mathrm{M_{\odot}}) \geq 10.3$ drawn from the VANDELS survey, exploring the relationship between stellar mass, age and star-formation history. Within our sample of 114 galaxies, we derive a stellar-mass vs stellar-age relation with a slope of $1.20^{+0.28}{-0.27}$ Gyr per decade in stellar mass. When combined with recent literature results, we find evidence that the slope of this relation remains consistent over the redshift interval $0&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effective volume of supernovae samples and sample variance</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effective_volume_of_supernovae_samples_and_sample_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effective_volume_of_supernovae_samples_and_sample_variance/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhongxu Zhai
The source of the tension between local SN Ia based Hubble constant measurements and those from the CMB or BAO+BBN measurements is one of the most interesting unknowns of modern cosmology. Sample variance forms a key component of the error on the local measurements, and will dominate the error budget in the future as more supernovae are observed. Many methods have been proposed to estimate sample variance in many contexts, and we compared results from a number of them in Zhai &amp;amp; Percival (2022), confirming that sample variance for the Pantheon supernovae sample does not solve the Hubble tension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The extended Planetary Nebula Spectrograph (ePN.S) early-type galaxy survey: The specific angular momentum of ETGs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_extended_planetary_nebula_spectrograph_epn.s_early-type_galaxy_survey_the_specific_angular_momentum_of_etgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_extended_planetary_nebula_spectrograph_epn.s_early-type_galaxy_survey_the_specific_angular_momentum_of_etgs/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Pulsoni
Mass and angular momentum are key parameters of galaxies. Their co-evolution establishes an empirical relation between the specific stellar angular momentum j* and the stellar mass M* that depends on morphology. In this work, we measure j* in a sample of 32 early type galaxies (ETGs) from the ePN.S survey, using full 2D kinematic information out to a mean 6Re. We present lambda and j* profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The void-galaxy cross-correlation function with massive neutrinos and modified gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_void-galaxy_cross-correlation_function_with_massive_neutrinos_and_modified_gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_void-galaxy_cross-correlation_function_with_massive_neutrinos_and_modified_gravity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Renate Mauland
Massive neutrinos and $f(R)$ modified gravity have degenerate observational signatures that can impact the interpretation of results in galaxy survey experiments, such as cosmological parameter estimations and gravity model tests. Because of this, it is important to investigate astrophysical observables that can break these degeneracies. Cosmic voids are sensitive to both massive neutrinos and modifications of gravity and provide a promising ground for disentangling the above mentioned degeneracies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamic simulations of massive main-sequence stars. I. Dynamics and mixing of convection and internal gravity waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars._i._dynamics_and_mixing_of_convection_and_internal_gravity_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars._i._dynamics_and_mixing_of_convection_and_internal_gravity_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Falk Herwig
We performed 3D hydrodynamic simulations of the inner $\approx 50%$ radial extent of a $25\ \mathrm{M_\odot}$ star in the early phase of the main sequence and investigate core convection and internal gravity waves in the core-envelope boundary region. Simulations for different grid resolutions and driving luminosities establish scaling relations to constrain models of mixing for 1D applications. As in previous works, the turbulent mass entrainment rate extrapolated to nominal heating is unrealistically high ($1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A UNIONS view of the brightest central galaxies of candidate fossil groups</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unions_view_of_the_brightest_central_galaxies_of_candidate_fossil_groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unions_view_of_the_brightest_central_galaxies_of_candidate_fossil_groups/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aline Chu
The formation process of fossil groups (FGs) is still under debate, and large samples of such objects are still missing. The aim of this paper is to increase the sample of known FGs, and to analyse the properties of their brightest group galaxies (BGG) and compare them with a control sample of non-FG BGGs. Based on the Tinker spectroscopic catalogue of haloes and galaxies, we extract 87 FG and 100 non-FG candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-Divided Mean Stellar Populations from Full Spectrum Fitting as the Simplified Star Formation and Chemical Evolution History of a Galaxy: Methodology and Reliability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/age-divided_mean_stellar_populations_from_full_spectrum_fitting_as_the_simplified_star_formation_and_chemical_evolution_history_of_a_galaxy_methodology_and_reliability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/age-divided_mean_stellar_populations_from_full_spectrum_fitting_as_the_simplified_star_formation_and_chemical_evolution_history_of_a_galaxy_methodology_and_reliability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joon Hyeop Lee
We introduce a practical methodology for investigating the star formation and chemical evolution history of a galaxy: age-divided mean stellar populations (ADPs) from full spectrum fitting. In this method, the mass-weighted mean stellar populations and mass fractions (f_mass) of young and old stellar components in a galaxy are separately estimated, which are divided with an age cut (selected to be 10^9.5 yr ~ 3.2 Gyr in this paper).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications of Machine Learning to Detecting Fast Neutrino Flavor Instabilities in Core-Collapse Supernova and Neutron Star Merger Models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/applications_of_machine_learning_to_detecting_fast_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_core-collapse_supernova_and_neutron_star_merger_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/applications_of_machine_learning_to_detecting_fast_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_core-collapse_supernova_and_neutron_star_merger_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sajad Abbar
Neutrinos propagating in a dense neutrino gas, such as those expected in core-collapse supernovae (CCSNe) and neutron star mergers (NSMs), can experience fast flavor conversions on relatively short scales. This can happen if the neutrino electron lepton number ($\nu$ELN) angular distribution crosses zero in a certain direction. Despite this, most of the state-of-the-art CCSN and NSM simulations do not provide such detailed angular information and instead, supply only a few moments of the neutrino angular distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are $JWST$/NIRCam color gradients in the lensed $z=2.3$ dusty star-forming galaxy $El~Anzuelo$ due to central dust attenuation or inside-out galaxy growth?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/are__jwst__nircam_color_gradients_in_the_lensed__z2.3__dusty_star-forming_galaxy__el~anzuelo__due_to_central_dust_attenuation_or_inside-out_galaxy_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/are__jwst__nircam_color_gradients_in_the_lensed__z2.3__dusty_star-forming_galaxy__el~anzuelo__due_to_central_dust_attenuation_or_inside-out_galaxy_growth/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick S. Kamieneski
Gradients in the mass-to-light ratio of distant galaxies impede our ability to characterize their size and compactness. The long-wavelength filters of $JWST$&amp;rsquo;s NIRCam offer a significant step forward. For galaxies at Cosmic Noon ($z\sim2$), this regime corresponds to the rest-frame near-infrared, which is less biased towards young stars and captures emission from the bulk of a galaxy&amp;rsquo;s stellar population. We present an initial analysis of an extraordinary lensed dusty star-forming galaxy (DSFG) at $z=2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common envelope jets supernova with thermonuclear outburst progenitor for the enigmatic supernova remnant W49B</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/common_envelope_jets_supernova_with_thermonuclear_outburst_progenitor_for_the_enigmatic_supernova_remnant_w49b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/common_envelope_jets_supernova_with_thermonuclear_outburst_progenitor_for_the_enigmatic_supernova_remnant_w49b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aldana Grichener
We suggest a common envelope jets supernova (CEJSN) origin to the supernova remnant (SNR) W49B where jets launched by a neutron star (NS) that collapsed to a black hole (BH) together with a thermonuclear outburst of the disrupted red super giant&amp;rsquo;s (RGS&amp;rsquo;s) core powered and shaped the ejecta. The jets account for the highly non-spherical morphology of W49B and the thermonuclear outburst to its high iron abundance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DES Y3 cosmic shear down to small scales: constraints on cosmology and baryons</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/des_y3_cosmic_shear_down_to_small_scales_constraints_on_cosmology_and_baryons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/des_y3_cosmic_shear_down_to_small_scales_constraints_on_cosmology_and_baryons/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giovanni Aricò
We present the first analysis of cosmic shear measured in DES Y3 that employs the entire range of angular scales in the data. To achieve this, we build upon recent advances in the theoretical modelling of weak lensing provided by a combination of $N$-body simulations, physical models of baryonic processes, and neural networks. Specifically, we use BACCOemu to model the linear and nonlinear matter power spectrum including baryonic physics, allowing us to robustly exploit scales smaller than those used by the DES Collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discordance of dipole asymmetries seen in recent large radio surveys with the Cosmological Principle</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discordance_of_dipole_asymmetries_seen_in_recent_large_radio_surveys_with_the_cosmological_principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discordance_of_dipole_asymmetries_seen_in_recent_large_radio_surveys_with_the_cosmological_principle/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ashok K. Singal
In recent years, large radio surveys of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGNs), comprising millions of sources, have become available where one could investigate dipole asymmetries, assumedly arising due to a peculiar motion of the Solar system. Investigations of such dipoles have yielded in past much larger amplitudes (a factor of 2 to 20) than that of the CMB dipole, though their inferred directions in sky seem to lie, within statistical uncertainties, close to the CMB dipole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Bispectrum Estimators for Galaxy Redshift Surveys with Velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/enhancing_bispectrum_estimators_for_galaxy_redshift_surveys_with_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/enhancing_bispectrum_estimators_for_galaxy_redshift_surveys_with_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Julius Wons
We forecast the ability of bispectrum estimators to constrain primordial non-Gaussianity using future photometric galaxy redshift surveys. A full-sky survey with photometric redshift resolution of $\sigma_z/(1+z)=0.05$ in the redshift range $0.2&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2$ can provide constraints $\sigma(f^\mathrm{local}\mathrm{NL})=3.4$, $\sigma(f^\mathrm{equil}\mathrm{NL})=15$, and $\sigma(f^\mathrm{orth}_\mathrm{NL})=17$ for the local, equilateral, and orthogonal shapes respectively, delivering constraints on primordial non-Gaussianities competitive to those from the cosmic microwave background. We generalize these results by deriving a scaling relation for the constraints on the amplitude of primordial non-Gaussianity as a function of redshift error, depth, sky coverage, and nonlinear scale cutoff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution in the orbital structure of quiescent galaxies from MAGPI, LEGA-C and SAMI surveys: direct evidence for merger-driven growth over the last 7 Gy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_in_the_orbital_structure_of_quiescent_galaxies_from_magpi_lega-c_and_sami_surveys_direct_evidence_for_merger-driven_growth_over_the_last_7_gy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_in_the_orbital_structure_of_quiescent_galaxies_from_magpi_lega-c_and_sami_surveys_direct_evidence_for_merger-driven_growth_over_the_last_7_gy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francesco D&amp;rsquo;Eugenio
We present the first study of spatially integrated higher-order stellar kinematics over cosmic time. We use deep rest-frame optical spectroscopy of quiescent galaxies at redshifts z=0.05, 0.3 and 0.8 from the SAMI, MAGPI and LEGA-C surveys to measure the excess kurtosis $h_4$ of the stellar velocity distribution, the latter parametrised as a Gauss-Hermite series. Conservatively using a redshift-independent cut in stellar mass ($M_\star = 10^{11},{\rm M}_\odot$), and matching the stellar-mass distributions of our samples, we find 7 $\sigma$ evidence of $h_4$ increasing with cosmic time, from a median value of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Instability of Gas-Dust Circumnuclear Disks in Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_instability_of_gas-dust_circumnuclear_disks_in_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_instability_of_gas-dust_circumnuclear_disks_in_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roman Tkachenko
We numerically study the origin of the multi-armed spiral structure observed in the circumnuclear gaseous mini-disks of nearby galaxies. We show that the presence of dust in such disks and its interaction with the gravitationally stable gaseous component leads to the development of a multi-armed spiral structure. As a particular example, we study the formation of the multi-armed spiral pattern in the mini-disk of the galaxy NGC 4736, for which the observational data for the rotation and the density distribution are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Ejecta and Cold Dust in the Young Supernova Remnant N132D</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_ejecta_and_cold_dust_in_the_young_supernova_remnant_n132d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_ejecta_and_cold_dust_in_the_young_supernova_remnant_n132d/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeonghee Rho
We present Spitzer, WISE, and Herschel observations of the young supernova remnant (SNR) N132D in the LMC, including 3-40 microns Spitzer IRS mapping, 12 microns WISE and 70, 100, 160, 250, 350, and 500 microns Herschel images. The high-velocity lines of $[Ne II]$ at 12.8 microns, $[Ne III]$ at 15.5 microns, and $[O IV]$ 26 microns reveal infrared ejecta concentrated in a central ring and coincide the optical and X-ray ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J1406&#43;0102: Dust Obscured Galaxy Hiding Super Eddington Accretion System with Bright Radio Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/j1406&#43;0102_dust_obscured_galaxy_hiding_super_eddington_accretion_system_with_bright_radio_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/j1406&#43;0102_dust_obscured_galaxy_hiding_super_eddington_accretion_system_with_bright_radio_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hikaru Fukuchi
Recent high-$z$ quasar observations strongly indicate that super-Eddington accretion is a crucial phase to describe the existence of supermassive black holes (SMBHs) with $M_\mathrm{BH} \gtrsim 10^9 M_\odot$ at $z \gtrsim 7$. Motivated by the theoretical suggestion that the super-Eddington phase efficiently produces outflows and jets bright in radio bands, we search and find a super-Eddington radio-loud dust-obscured galaxy (DOG) J1406+0102 at $z=0.236$, through cross-matching of the infrared-bright DOGs of Noboriguchi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PINION: Physics-informed neural network for accelerating radiative transfer simulations for cosmic reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.13803/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.13803/</guid>
      <description>Damien Korber
With the advent of the Square Kilometre Array Observatory (SKAO), scientists will be able to directly observe the Epoch of Reionization by mapping the distribution of neutral hydrogen at different redshifts. While physically motivated results can be simulated with radiative transfer codes, these simulations are computationally expensive and can not readily produce the required scale and resolution simultaneously. Here we introduce the Physics-Informed neural Network for reIONization (PINION), which can accurately and swiftly predict the complete 4-D hydrogen fraction evolution from the smoothed gas and mass density fields from pre-computed N-body simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating the enrichment of fossil radio electrons by multiple radio galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulating_the_enrichment_of_fossil_radio_electrons_by_multiple_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulating_the_enrichment_of_fossil_radio_electrons_by_multiple_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Vazza
{We simulate the evolution of relativistic electrons injected into the intracluster medium by five radio galaxies. We study the spatial transport and the emission properties of the injected radio plasma over a $\sim 5$ Gyr period, and the sequence of cooling and re-acceleration events experienced by electrons, using a Lagrangian approach joint with a numerical method to model the evolution of momentum spectra of relativistic electrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dark side of FIRE: predicting the population of dark matter subhaloes around Milky Way-mass galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_side_of_fire_predicting_the_population_of_dark_matter_subhaloes_around_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_side_of_fire_predicting_the_population_of_dark_matter_subhaloes_around_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Megan Barry
A variety of observational campaigns seek to test dark-matter models by measuring dark-matter subhaloes at low masses. Despite their predicted lack of stars, these subhaloes may be detectable through gravitational lensing or via their gravitational perturbations on stellar streams. To set measurable expectations for subhalo populations within LambdaCDM, we examine 11 Milky Way (MW)-mass haloes from the FIRE-2 baryonic simulations, quantifying the counts and orbital fluxes for subhaloes with properties relevant to stellar stream interactions: masses down to 10^6 Msun, distances &amp;lt; 50 kpc of the galactic center, across z = 0 - 1 (lookback time 0 - 8 Gyr).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Light Curve of a Type Ia Supernova 2021hpr in NGC 3147: Progenitor Constraints with the Companion Interaction Model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_early_light_curve_of_a_type_ia_supernova_2021hpr_in_ngc_3147_progenitor_constraints_with_the_companion_interaction_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_early_light_curve_of_a_type_ia_supernova_2021hpr_in_ngc_3147_progenitor_constraints_with_the_companion_interaction_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gu Lim
The progenitor system of Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) is expected to be a close binary system of a carbon/oxygen white dwarf (WD) and a non-degenerate star or another WD. Here, we present results from a high-cadence monitoring observation of SN 2021hpr in a spiral galaxy, NGC 3147, and constraints on the progenitor system based on its early multi-color light curve data. First, we classify SN 2021hpr as a normal SN Ia from its long-term photometric and spectroscopic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of the Galactic Bar on the Dynamics of Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.05603/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.05603/</guid>
      <description>Roman Tkachenko
We make use of recent estimates for the parameters of the Milky Way&amp;amp;#39;s halo globular clusters and study the influence of the galactic bar on the dynamics of these clusters by computing their orbits. We use both an axisymmetric and non-axisymmetric galactic potentials, which include the rotating elongated bar/bulge structure. We account for observational errors both in the positions and in the velocities of the globular clusters and explore the influence of the bar on cluster&amp;amp;#39;s evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rapid onset of stellar bars in the baryon-dominated centers of disk galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_rapid_onset_of_stellar_bars_in_the_baryon-dominated_centers_of_disk_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_rapid_onset_of_stellar_bars_in_the_baryon-dominated_centers_of_disk_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Bland-Hawthorn
Recent observations of high-redshift galactic disks ($z\approx 1-3$) show a strong negative trend in the dark matter fraction $f_{DM}$ with increasing baryonic surface density. For this to be true, the inner baryons must dominate over dark matter in early massive galaxies, as observed in the Milky Way today. If disks are dominant at early times, we show that stellar bars form promptly within these disks, leading to a high bar fraction at early times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A candidate magnetic helium core white dwarf in the globular cluster NGC 6397</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04184/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04184/</guid>
      <description>Manuel Pichardo Marcano
We report a peculiar variable blue star in the globular cluster NGC 6397, using Hubble Space Telescope optical imaging. Its position in the colour-magnitude diagrams, and its spectrum, are consistent with this star being a helium core white dwarf (He WD) in a binary system. The optical light curve shows a periodicity at 18.5 hours. We argue that this periodicity is due to the rotation of the WD and possibly due to magnetic spots on the surface of the WD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nearly constant CN/HCN line ratio in nearby galaxies: CN as a new tracer of dense gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_nearly_constant_cn_hcn_line_ratio_in_nearby_galaxies_cn_as_a_new_tracer_of_dense_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_nearly_constant_cn_hcn_line_ratio_in_nearby_galaxies_cn_as_a_new_tracer_of_dense_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christine D. Wilson
We investigate the relationship between CN N = 1 - 0 and HCN J = 1 - 0 emission on scales from 30 pc to 400 pc using ALMA archival data, for which CN is often observed simultaneously with the CO J = 1 - 0 line. In a sample of 9 nearby galaxies ranging from ultra-luminous infrared galaxies to normal spiral galaxies, we measure a remarkably constant CN/HCN line intensity ratio of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active galactic nuclei feedback in an elliptical galaxy (III): the impacts and fate of cosmological inflow</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/active_galactic_nuclei_feedback_in_an_elliptical_galaxy_iii_the_impacts_and_fate_of_cosmological_inflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/active_galactic_nuclei_feedback_in_an_elliptical_galaxy_iii_the_impacts_and_fate_of_cosmological_inflow/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bocheng Zhu
The cosmological inflow of a galaxy is speculated to be able to enter the galaxy and enhance the star formation rate (SFR) and black hole accretion rate (BHAR). In this paper, by performing high-resolution hydrodynamic simulations in the framework of {\it MACER}, we investigate the fate of the inflow and its impacts on the evolution of a massive elliptical galaxy. The inflow properties are adopted from the cosmological simulation IllustrisTNG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GN-z11 in context: possible signatures of globular cluster precursors at redshift 10</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04179/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04179/</guid>
      <description>Peter Senchyna
The first JWST spectroscopy of the luminous galaxy GN-z11 simultaneously both established its redshift at $z=10.6$ and revealed a rest-ultraviolet spectrum dominated by signatures of highly-ionized nitrogen, which has so far defied clear interpretation. Here we present a reappraisal of this spectrum in the context of both detailed nebular modeling and nearby metal-poor reference galaxies. The N IV] emission enables the first nebular density measurement in a star-forming galaxy at $z&amp;amp;gt;10$, and reveals evidence for extremely high densities $n_e\gtrsim 10^5$ $\mathrm{cm^{-3}}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New dwarf galaxy candidates in the sphere of influence of the Local Volume spiral galaxy NGC2683</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_in_the_sphere_of_influence_of_the_local_volume_spiral_galaxy_ngc2683/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_in_the_sphere_of_influence_of_the_local_volume_spiral_galaxy_ngc2683/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Crosby
We present initial results of a survey of host $L_{*}$ galaxies environments in the Local Volume ($D&amp;lt;10,$Mpc) searching for satellite dwarf galaxy candidates using the wide-field Hyper Suprime-Cam imager on the 8m Subaru Telescope. The current paper presents complete results on NGC2683 ($M_{B_T,0}=-19.62$, $D=9.36,Mpc$, $v_{\odot}=411,km,s^{-1}$), an isolated Sc spiral galaxy in the Leo Spur. At the distance of NGC2683, we image the complete volume out to projected radii of $380,kpc$ using a hexagonal arrangement of 7 pointings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primordial Gravitational Waves Assisted by Cosmological Scalar Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_gravitational_waves_assisted_by_cosmological_scalar_perturbations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_gravitational_waves_assisted_by_cosmological_scalar_perturbations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yan-Heng Yu
Primordial gravitational waves are one of the most important predictions of inflation theory, and measurements of their imprints on the cosmic microwave background are actively pursued, but not yet succeed until now. Here we point out that measurements of primordial gravitational waves could be conceivable through searching for a signal of second-order tensor perturbations, which were produced due to nonlinear couplings between the linear tensor and scalar perturbations in the early universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mass-loss rates of star clusters with stellar-mass black holes: implications for the globular cluster mass function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03791/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03791/</guid>
      <description>Mark Gieles
Stellar-mass black holes (BHs) can be retained in globular clusters (GCs) until the present. Simulations of GC evolution find that the relaxation driven mass-loss rate is elevated if BHs are present, especially near dissolution. We capture this behaviour in a parameterised mass-loss rate, benchmarked by results from $N$-body simulations, and use it to evolve an initial GC mass function (GCMF), similar to that of young massive clusters in the Local Universe, to an age of 12 Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the progenitor formation galaxies of merging binary black holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/understanding_the_progenitor_formation_galaxies_of_merging_binary_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/understanding_the_progenitor_formation_galaxies_of_merging_binary_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rahul Srinivasan
With nearly a hundred gravitational wave detections, the origin of black hole mergers has become a key question. Here, we focus on understanding the typical galactic environment in which binary black hole mergers arise. To this end, we synthesize progenitors of binary black hole mergers as a function of the redshift of progenitor formation, present-day formation galaxy mass, and progenitor stellar metallicity for $240$ star formation and binary evolution models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using entropy bounds to avoid the cosmological singularity and constrain particle production</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_entropy_bounds_to_avoid_the_cosmological_singularity_and_constrain_particle_production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_entropy_bounds_to_avoid_the_cosmological_singularity_and_constrain_particle_production/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hao Yu
In this work, we study the applications of entropy bounds in two toy cosmological models with particle production (annihilation), i.e., radiation-dominated universe and dust-dominated universe. Since entropy bounds are involved in the volume of the thermodynamc system, we need to specify the thermodynamc system in the universe in advance. We consider the co-moving volume and the volume covered by the particle horizon as the target thermodynamic system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can observations of 511 keV line from the M31 galaxy shed light on the AGN jet composition?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_observations_of_511_kev_line_from_the_m31_galaxy_shed_light_on_the_agn_jet_composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_observations_of_511_kev_line_from_the_m31_galaxy_shed_light_on_the_agn_jet_composition/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. A. Nizamov
Positron annihilation line at 511~keV is a known component of the gamma-ray diffuse emission. It is believed to be produced in the Galaxy, but there could be possible extragalactic contribution as well. E.g., positrons can be produced in jets of active galactic nuclei (AGN) and after that accumulate and gradually annihilate in hot gaseous halos around galaxies. In this work we test this hypothesis in application to an individual object &amp;ndash; the Andromeda galaxy (M31) which is close and has a supermassive black hole in its center, which powered an AGN before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining High-Energy Neutrino Emission from Supernovae with IceCube</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_supernovae_with_icecube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_supernovae_with_icecube/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Abbasi
Core-collapse supernovae are a promising potential high-energy neutrino source class. We test for correlation between seven years of IceCube neutrino data and a catalog containing more than 1000 core-collapse supernovae of types IIn and IIP and a sample of stripped-envelope supernovae. We search both for neutrino emission from individual supernovae, and for combined emission from the whole supernova sample through a stacking analysis. No significant spatial or temporal correlation of neutrinos with the cataloged supernovae was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Carbon to Cobalt: Chemical compositions and ages of $z\sim0.7$ quiescent galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_carbon_to_cobalt_chemical_compositions_and_ages_of__z_sim0.7__quiescent_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_carbon_to_cobalt_chemical_compositions_and_ages_of__z_sim0.7__quiescent_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aliza G. Beverage
We present elemental abundance patterns (C, N, Mg, Si, Ca, Ti, V, Cr, Fe, Co, and Ni) for a population of 135 massive quiescent galaxies at $z\sim0.7$ with ultra-deep rest-frame optical spectroscopy drawn from the LEGA-C survey. We derive average ages and elemental abundances in four bins of stellar velocity dispersion ($\sigma_v$) ranging from 150$~$km$,$s$^{-1}$ to 250$~$km$,$s$^{-1}$ using a full-spectrum hierarchical Bayesian model. The resulting elemental abundance measurements are precise to 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamma-ray emission from the Seyfert galaxy NGC 4151 and multimessenger implications for ultra-fast outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_emission_from_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc_4151_and_multimessenger_implications_for_ultra-fast_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_emission_from_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc_4151_and_multimessenger_implications_for_ultra-fast_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Enrico Peretti
The enhanced activity typical of the core of Seyfert galaxies can drive powerful winds where high-energy phenomena can occur. In spite of their high power content, the number of such non-jetted active galactic nuclei detected in gamma-ray is very limited. In this Letter, we report the detection of a gamma-ray flux from NGC 4151, a Seyfert galaxy located at about 15.8 Mpc. The source is known for hosting ultra-fast outflows (UFOs) in its innermost core through X-ray spectroscopic observations, thereby becoming the first UFO host ever detected in gamma rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General-relativistic radiation transport scheme in Gmunu I: Implementation of two-moment based multi-frequency radiative transfer and code tests</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03261/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03261/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Chi-Kit Cheong
We present the implementation of two-moment based general-relativistic multi-group radiation transport module in the $\texttt{G}$eneral-relativistic $\texttt{mu}$ltigrid $\texttt{nu}$merical ($\texttt{Gmunu}$) code. On top of solving the general-relativistic magnetohydrodynamics and the Einstein equations with conformally flat approximations, the code solves the evolution equations of the zeroth- and first-order moments of the radiations. Analytic closure relation is used to obtain the higher order moments and close the system. The finite-volume discretisation has been adopted for the radiation moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of tidal features in deep optical galaxy images with Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identification_of_tidal_features_in_deep_optical_galaxy_images_with_convolutional_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identification_of_tidal_features_in_deep_optical_galaxy_images_with_convolutional_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. Domínguez Sánchez
Interactions between galaxies leave distinguishable imprints in the form of tidal features which hold important clues about their mass assembly. Unfortunately, these structures are difficult to detect because they are low surface brightness features so deep observations are needed. Upcoming surveys promise several orders of magnitude increase in depth and sky coverage, for which automated methods for tidal feature detection will become mandatory. We test the ability of a convolutional neural network to reproduce human visual classifications for tidal detections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intergalactic magnetic field studies by means of $γ$-ray emission from GRB 190114C</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intergalactic_magnetic_field_studies_by_means_of__%CE%B3_-ray_emission_from_grb_190114c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intergalactic_magnetic_field_studies_by_means_of__%CE%B3_-ray_emission_from_grb_190114c/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paolo Da Vela
The presence of delayed GeV emission after a strong transient, such as a GRB (Gamma-Ray Burst), in the VHE (Very-High Energy, $E&amp;gt;100$ GeV) band can be the signature of a non-zero magnetic field in the intergalactic medium. We used a synchrotron self-Compton multiwavelength model to infer an analytical description of the intrinsic VHE spectrum (corrected for absorption by the Extragalactic Background Light, EBL) of GRB$,$190114C to predict the lightcurves and SEDs of the delayed emission with Monte Carlo simulations for different IGMF (Intergalactic Magnetic Field) configurations (strengths $B=8\times10^{-21}$ G, $10^{-20}$ G, $3\times 10^{-20}$G and correlation length $\lambda&amp;gt;1$ Mpc), and compared them with the Fermi-LAT (Fermi Large Area Telescope) limits computed for several exposure times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a dwarf galaxy satellite-of-satellite problem in $Λ$CDM?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_there_a_dwarf_galaxy_satellite-of-satellite_problem_in__%CE%BB_cdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_there_a_dwarf_galaxy_satellite-of-satellite_problem_in__%CE%BB_cdm/</guid>
      <description>First author: Oliver Müller
Dark matter clusters on all scales, therefore it is expected that even substructure should host its own substructure. Using the Extragalactic Distance Database, we searched for dwarf galaxy satellites of dwarf galaxies, i.e. satellite-of-satellite galaxies, corresponding to these substructures-of-substructure. Going through HST data of 117 dwarf galaxies, we report the discovery of a dwarf galaxy around the ultra-diffuse M96 companion M96-DF6 at 10 Mpc. Modelling its structural parameters, we find that it is an ultra-faint dwarf galaxy which is 135 times fainter than its host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the sizes of ionized bubbles around the highest redshift galaxies. Spectral shapes of the Lyman-alpha emission from galaxies III</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sizes_of_ionized_bubbles_around_the_highest_redshift_galaxies._spectral_shapes_of_the_lyman-alpha_emission_from_galaxies_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sizes_of_ionized_bubbles_around_the_highest_redshift_galaxies._spectral_shapes_of_the_lyman-alpha_emission_from_galaxies_iii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew J. Hayes
We develop a new method to determine the distance between a galaxy and a foreground screen of atomic hydrogen. In a partially neutral universe, and under the assumption of spherical symmetry, this equates to the radius of a ionized &amp;lsquo;bubble&amp;rsquo; (Rbub) surrounding the galaxy. The method requires an observed Lya equivalent width, velocity offset from systemic, and an input Lya profile for which we adopt scaled versions of the profiles observed in low-z galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper 1: The JWST PEARLS View of the El Gordo Galaxy Cluster and of the Structure It Magnifies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/paper_1_the_jwst_pearls_view_of_the_el_gordo_galaxy_cluster_and_of_the_structure_it_magnifies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/paper_1_the_jwst_pearls_view_of_the_el_gordo_galaxy_cluster_and_of_the_structure_it_magnifies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brenda L. Frye
The massive galaxy cluster El Gordo ($z=0.87$) imprints multitudes of gravitationally lensed arcs onto James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) images. Eight bands of NIRCam imaging were obtained in the Prime Extragalactic Areas for Reionization and Lensing Science (PEARLS) program (GTO #1176). PSF-matched photometry across a suite of Hubble Space Telescope (HST) and NIRCam filters gives new photometric redshifts. We confirm 54 known image multiplicities and find two new ones and construct a lens model based on the light-traces-mass method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population III X-ray Binaries and their Impact on the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03435/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03435/</guid>
      <description>Nina S. Sartorio
The first population of X-ray binaries (XRBs) is expected to affect the thermal and ionization states of the gas in the early Universe. Although these X-ray sources are predicted to have important implications for high-redshift observable signals, such as the hydrogen 21-cm signal from cosmic dawn and the cosmic X-ray background, their properties are poorly explored, leaving theoretical models largely uninformed. In this paper we model a population of X-ray binaries arising from zero metallicity stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Expansion of the Young Type Ia Supernova Remnant 0519-69.0: More Evidence for a Circumstellar Shell</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_expansion_of_the_young_type_ia_supernova_remnant_0519-69.0_more_evidence_for_a_circumstellar_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_expansion_of_the_young_type_ia_supernova_remnant_0519-69.0_more_evidence_for_a_circumstellar_shell/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benson T. Guest
The nature of Type Ia supernovae remains controversial. The youngest remnants of Ia supernovae hold clues to the explosion and to the immediate surroundings. We present a third epoch of Chandra observations of the $\sim600$-year-old Type Ia remnant 0519-69.0 in the Large Magellanic Cloud, extending the time baseline to 21 years from the initial 2000 observations. We find rapid expansion of X-ray emitting material, with an average velocity of 4760 km s$^{-1}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reoriented Memory of Galaxy Spins for the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reoriented_memory_of_galaxy_spins_for_the_early_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reoriented_memory_of_galaxy_spins_for_the_early_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jun-Sung Moon
Galaxy spins are believed to retain initially acquired tendency of being aligned with the intermediate principal axes of the linear tidal field, which disseminates a prospect of using them as a probe of the early universe physics. This roseate prospect, however, is contingent upon the key assumption that the observable stellar spins of the present galaxies measured at inner radii have the same alignment tendency toward the initial tidal field as their dark matter counterparts measured at virial limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN2017egm: A Helium-rich Superluminous Supernova with Multiple Bumps in the Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn2017egm_a_helium-rich_superluminous_supernova_with_multiple_bumps_in_the_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn2017egm_a_helium-rich_superluminous_supernova_with_multiple_bumps_in_the_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiazheng Zhu
When discovered, SN~2017egm was the closest (redshift $z=0.03$) hydrogen-poor superluminous supernova (SLSN-I) and a rare case that exploded in a massive and metal-rich galaxy. Thus, it has since been extensively observed and studied. We report spectroscopic data showing strong emission at around He~I $\lambda$10,830 and four He~I absorption lines in the optical. Consequently, we classify SN~2017egm as a member of an emerging population of helium-rich SLSNe-I (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The large scale limit of the observed galaxy power spectrum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_large_scale_limit_of_the_observed_galaxy_power_spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_large_scale_limit_of_the_observed_galaxy_power_spectrum/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matteo Foglieni
The large scale limit of the galaxy power spectrum provides a unique window into the early Universe through a possible detection of scale dependent bias produced by Primordial Non Gaussianities. On such large scales, relativistic effects could become important and, potentially, be confused for a primordial signal. In this work we provide the first consistent estimate of such effects in the observed galaxy power spectrum, and discuss their possible degeneracy with local Primordial Non Gaussianities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A luminous dust-obscured Tidal Disruption Event candidate in a star forming galaxy at 42 Mpc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_luminous_dust-obscured_tidal_disruption_event_candidate_in_a_star_forming_galaxy_at_42_mpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_luminous_dust-obscured_tidal_disruption_event_candidate_in_a_star_forming_galaxy_at_42_mpc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Panagiotou
While the vast majority of Tidal Disruption Events (TDEs) has been identified by wide-field sky surveys in the optical and X-ray bands, recent studies indicate that a considerable fraction of TDEs may be dust obscured, and thus preferentially detected in the infrared (IR) wavebands. In this Letter, we present the discovery of a luminous mid-IR nuclear flare (termed WTP 14adbjsh) identified in a systematic transient search of archival images from the NEOWISE mid-IR survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo-observation of spiral galaxies in the radio band to verify depolarization models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pseudo-observation_of_spiral_galaxies_in_the_radio_band_to_verify_depolarization_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pseudo-observation_of_spiral_galaxies_in_the_radio_band_to_verify_depolarization_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuta Tashima
Studies of the three-dimensional (3D) structures of galactic magnetic fields are now entering a new era, with broadband, highly sensitive radio observations and new analysis methods. To reveal the magnetic field configuration from the observed value integrated along the line of sight, it is necessary to derive an appropriate model that can reproduce the observational characteristics. We aim to clarify the relationship between the radiation field and the spatial distribution of physical quantities through pseudo-observations using global 3D magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) simulation results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing of Pulsars in the Globular Cluster Omega Centauri</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02834/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02834/</guid>
      <description>S. Dai
We present the timing of the first five millisecond pulsars discovered in the globular cluster Omega Centauri and the discovery of a pulsar with a spin period of 3.68 ms. With a timing baseline of $\sim$3.5 yr we are able to measure the derivative of the spin frequency ($\dotν$) for the first five pulsars. Upper limits on the pulsar line-of-sight acceleration are estimated and compared with predictions based on analytical models of the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An optical/X-ray/radio view of Abell 1213: a galaxy cluster with an anomalous diffuse radio emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_optical_x-ray_radio_view_of_abell_1213_a_galaxy_cluster_with_an_anomalous_diffuse_radio_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_optical_x-ray_radio_view_of_abell_1213_a_galaxy_cluster_with_an_anomalous_diffuse_radio_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Boschin
Context. Abell 1213, a poor galaxy system, is known to host an anomalous radio halo detected in VLA data which is an outsider in the relation between the radio halos power and the X-ray luminosity of the parent clusters. Aims. Our aim is to analyze the cluster from the optical, X-ray and radio point of view to characterize the environment of its diffuse radio emission and shed new light on its nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic Simulations of a Relativistic Jet Interacting with the Intracluster Medium: Application to Cygnus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_of_a_relativistic_jet_interacting_with_the_intracluster_medium_application_to_cygnus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_of_a_relativistic_jet_interacting_with_the_intracluster_medium_application_to_cygnus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: John A. ZuHone
The Fanaroff-Riley class II radio galaxy Cygnus A hosts jets which produce radio emission, X-ray cavities, cocoon shocks, and X-ray hotspots where the jet interacts with the ICM. Surrounding one hotspot is a peculiar &amp;ldquo;hole&amp;rdquo; feature which appears as a deficit in X-ray emission. We use relativistic hydrodynamic simulations of a collimated jet interacting with an inclined interface between lobe and cluster plasma to model the basic processes which may lead to such a feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An archival search for type Ia supernova siblings</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_archival_search_for_type_ia_supernova_siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_archival_search_for_type_ia_supernova_siblings/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Kelsey
By searching the Open Supernova Catalog, an extra-galactic transient host galaxy database, and literature analyses, I present the largest sample of type Ia supernova (SN Ia) siblings to date. The sample comprises 158 galaxies, consisting of 327 confirmed SNe Ia - over 10 times larger than existing sibling SN Ia samples. SN siblings share host galaxies, and thus share global environmental properties and associated systematic uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical models of adenine precursors cyanamide and carbodiimide in the interstellar medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_models_of_adenine_precursors_cyanamide_and_carbodiimide_in_the_interstellar_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_models_of_adenine_precursors_cyanamide_and_carbodiimide_in_the_interstellar_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xia Zhang
Cyanamide (NH2CN) and its isomer, carbodiimide (HNCNH), may form adenine in the interstellar medium (ISM) via a series of reactions. Therefore, they are considered key prebiotic molecules in the study of the origin of life. We used the three-phase NAUTILUS chemical code, which includes the gas, the dust surface, and the icy mantle, to investigate the formation and destruction of cyanamide and carbodiimide. We added over 200 new chemical reactions of the two isomers and related species, and established a relatively complete network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Chameleon screening using galaxy cluster dynamics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_chameleon_screening_using_galaxy_cluster_dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_chameleon_screening_using_galaxy_cluster_dynamics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yacer Boumechta
We constrain the Chameleon \textit{screening} mechanism in galaxy clusters, essentially obtaining limits on the coupling strength $\beta$ and the asymptotic value of the field $\phi_{\infty}$. For this purpose, we utilized a collection of the 9 relaxed galaxy clusters within the X-COP compilation in the redshift range of $z \le 0.1$. We implement the formalism assuming an NFW mass profile for the dark matter density and study the degeneracy present between the mass $\M$ and the chameleon coupling with a high degree of improvement in the constraints for excluded parameter space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Radioactivity and Galactic Chemical Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_radioactivity_and_galactic_chemical_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_radioactivity_and_galactic_chemical_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roland Diehl
The description of the tempo-spatial evolution of the composition of cosmic gas on galactic scales is called &amp;lsquo;modelling galactic chemical evolution&amp;rsquo;. It aims to use knowledge about sources of nucleosynthesis and how they change the composition of interstellar gas, following the formation of stars and the ejection of products from nuclear fusion during their evolution and terminating explosions. Sources of nucleosynthesis are diverse: Stars with hydrostatic nuclear burning eject some of the products, and core-collapse supernovae add ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the diversity and similarity of radially anisotropic Milky Way-like stellar haloes: implications for dwarf galaxy searches</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_diversity_and_similarity_of_radially_anisotropic_milky_way-like_stellar_haloes_implications_for_dwarf_galaxy_searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_diversity_and_similarity_of_radially_anisotropic_milky_way-like_stellar_haloes_implications_for_dwarf_galaxy_searches/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew D. A. Orkney
We investigate the properties of mergers that are comparable to the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) using cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of Milky Way-like galaxies. It was previously shown that these mergers occur over a wide range of times ($6-10,$Gyr ago). We find that the merger progenitors span an order of magnitude in their peak stellar mass ($3\times10^8&amp;lt;M_{\star}/\rm{M}{\odot}&amp;lt;4\times10^9$) and include both rotation and pressure-supported galaxies ($0.10&amp;lt;D/T&amp;lt;0.77$). In a minority of cases, the GSE-like debris is comprised of stars from more than one merger progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster formation histories, masses and radii inferred from gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02263/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02263/</guid>
      <description>Maya Fishbach
Globular clusters (GCs) are found in all types of galaxies and harbor some of the most extreme stellar systems, including black holes that may dynamically assemble into merging binaries (BBHs). Despite their ubiquity, the origin and evolution of GCs remains an open question. Uncertain GC properties, including when they formed, their initial masses and sizes, affect their production rate of BBH mergers. Using the gravitational-wave catalog GWTC-3, we measure that dynamically-assembled BBHs -- those that are consistent with isotropic spin directions -- make up $61^{+29}_{-44}\%$ of the total merger rate, with a local merger rate of $10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Matter Creation, Multi-fluid Cosmology and Kinetic Theory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_matter_creation_multi-fluid_cosmology_and_kinetic_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_matter_creation_multi-fluid_cosmology_and_kinetic_theory/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. R. G. Trevisani
A macroscopic and kinetic relativistic description for a decoupled multi-fluid cosmology endowed with gravitationally induced particle production of all components is proposed. The temperature law for each decoupled particle species is also kinetically derived. The present approach points to the possibility of an exact (semi-classical) quantum-gravitational kinetic treatment by incorporating back reaction effects for an arbitrary set of dominant decoupled components. As an illustration we show that a cosmology driven by creation of cold dark matter and baryons (without dark energy) evolves like $\Lambda$CDM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric galaxy morphology from stellar and nebular emission with the CALIFA sample</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonparametric_galaxy_morphology_from_stellar_and_nebular_emission_with_the_califa_sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonparametric_galaxy_morphology_from_stellar_and_nebular_emission_with_the_califa_sample/</guid>
      <description>First author: Angelos Nersesian
We present a nonparametric morphology analysis of the stellar continuum and nebular emission lines for a sample of local galaxies. We explore the dependence of the various morphological parameters on wavelength and morphological type. Our goal is to quantify the difference in morphology between the stellar and nebular components. We derive the nonparametric morphological indicators of 364 galaxies from the CALIFA Survey. To calculate those indicators, we apply the StatMorph package on the high-quality integral field spectroscopic data cubes, as well as to the most prominent nebular emission-line maps, namely $[OIII]$$\lambda$5007, H$\alpha$, and $[NII]$$\lambda$6583.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fast X-ray Transient XRT 210423 and its Host Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fast_x-ray_transient_xrt_210423_and_its_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fast_x-ray_transient_xrt_210423_and_its_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Eappachen
Fast X-ray Transients (FXTs) are X-ray flares with a duration ranging from a few hundred seconds to a few hours. Possible origins include the tidal disruption of a white dwarf by an intermediate-mass black hole, a supernova shock breakout, and a binary neutron star merger. We present the X-ray light curve and spectrum, and deep optical imaging of the FXT XRT 210423, which has been suggested to be powered by a magnetar produced in a binary neutron star merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion of sub-stellar companions as the origin of chemical abundance inhomogeneities in globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.11412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.11412/</guid>
      <description>Andrew J. Winter
Globular clusters exhibit abundance variations, defining `multiple populations&amp;amp;#39;, which have prompted a protracted search for their origin. Properties requiring explanation include: the high fraction of polluted stars ($\sim 40{-}90$~percent, correlated with cluster mass), the absence of pollution in young clusters and the lower pollution rate with binarity and distance from the cluster centre. We present a novel mechanism for late delivery of pollutants into stars via accretion of sub-stellar companions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrasting X-ray/UV time-lags in Seyfert 1 galaxies NGC 4593 and NGC 7469 using AstroSat observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/contrasting_x-ray_uv_time-lags_in_seyfert_1_galaxies_ngc_4593_and_ngc_7469_using_astrosat_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/contrasting_x-ray_uv_time-lags_in_seyfert_1_galaxies_ngc_4593_and_ngc_7469_using_astrosat_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kavita Kumari
We study accretion disk-corona connection in Seyfert 1 galaxies using simultaneous UV/X-ray observations of NGC 4593 (July 14-18, 2016) and NGC 7469 (October 15-19, 2017) performed with AstroSat. We use the X-ray (0.5-7.0 keV) data acquired with the Soft X-ray Telescope (SXT) and the UV (FUV: 130-180 nm, NUV: 200-300 nm) data obtained with the Ultra-Violet Imaging Telescope (UVIT). We also use the contemporaneous Swift observations of NGC 4593 and demonstrate AstroSat&amp;rsquo;s capability for X-ray/UV correlation studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detailed shapes of the line-of-sight velocity distributions in massive early-type galaxies from non-parametric spectral models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detailed_shapes_of_the_line-of-sight_velocity_distributions_in_massive_early-type_galaxies_from_non-parametric_spectral_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detailed_shapes_of_the_line-of-sight_velocity_distributions_in_massive_early-type_galaxies_from_non-parametric_spectral_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kianusch Mehrgan
We present the first systematic study of the detailed shapes of the line-of-sight velocity distributions (LOSVDs) in nine massive early-type galaxies (ETGs) using the novel non-parametric modelling code WINGFIT. High-signal spectral observations with MUSE at the VLT allow us to measure between 40 and 400 individual LOSVDs in each galaxy at a signal-to-noise level better than 100 per spectral bin and to trace the LOSVDs all the way out to the highest stellar velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early results from GLASS-JWST. XX: Unveiling a population of &#34;red-excess&#39;&#39; galaxies in Abell2744 and in the coeval field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early_results_from_glass-jwst._xx_unveiling_a_population_of_red-excess_galaxies_in_abell2744_and_in_the_coeval_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early_results_from_glass-jwst._xx_unveiling_a_population_of_red-excess_galaxies_in_abell2744_and_in_the_coeval_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benedetta Vulcani
We combine the superior JWST/NIRCam imaging and MUSE data to characterize the properties of galaxies in different environmental conditions in the cluster Abell2744 (z=0.3064) and in its immediate surroundings. Our most striking result is the discovery of a ``red-excess&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; population in F200W-F444W colors both in the cluster regions and the field. These galaxies have normal F115W-F150W colors, but are up to 0.8 mag redder than red sequence galaxies in F200W-F444W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitation of Langmuir waves in the magnetospheres of AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/excitation_of_langmuir_waves_in_the_magnetospheres_of_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/excitation_of_langmuir_waves_in_the_magnetospheres_of_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Z. N. Osmanov
In the paper we study the process of excitation of Langmuir waves in the magnetospheres of active galactic nuclei (AGN), by taking a general-relativistic expression of the Goldreich-Julian density into account. We considered the linearised set of equations which describe dynamics of the studied mechanism: the Euler equation, the continuity equation and the Poisson equation. After solving the dispersion relation and obtaining the instability growth rate, we explored it versus several physical parameters: electron&amp;rsquo;s and proton&amp;rsquo;s relativistic factors and the mass and luminosity of AGN, which are supposed to be Kerr black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMultimass modelling of Milky Way globular clusters -- I. Implications on their stellar initial mass function above 1 M⊙</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.01637/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.01637/</guid>
      <description>Nolan Dickson
The distribution of stars and stellar remnants (white dwarfs, neutron stars, black holes) within globular clusters holds clues about their formation and long-term evolution, with important implications for their initial mass function (IMF) and the formation of black hole mergers. In this work, we present best-fitting multimass models for 37 Milky Way globular clusters, which were inferred from various datasets, including proper motions from Gaia EDR3 and HST, line-of-sight velocities from ground-based spectroscopy and deep stellar mass functions from HST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth-rate measurement with type-Ia supernovae using ZTF survey simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growth-rate_measurement_with_type-ia_supernovae_using_ztf_survey_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growth-rate_measurement_with_type-ia_supernovae_using_ztf_survey_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bastien Carreres
Measurements of the growth rate of structures at $z &amp;lt; 0.1$ with peculiar velocity surveys have the potential of testing the validity of general relativity on cosmic scales. In this work, we present growth-rate measurements from realistic simulated sets of type-Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF). We describe our simulation methodology, the light-curve fitting and peculiar velocity estimation. Using the maximum likelihood method, we derive constraints on $f\sigma_8$ using only ZTF SN Ia peculiar velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-accuracy emulators for observables in $Λ$CDM, $N_\mathrm{eff}$, $Σm_ν$, and $w$ cosmologies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-accuracy_emulators_for_observables_in__%CE%BB_cdm__n__mathrmeff___%CF%83m_%CE%BD__and__w__cosmologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-accuracy_emulators_for_observables_in__%CE%BB_cdm__n__mathrmeff___%CF%83m_%CE%BD__and__w__cosmologies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Boris Bolliet
We use the emulation framework CosmoPower to construct and publicly release neural network emulators of cosmological observables, including the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) temperature and polarization power spectra, matter power spectrum, distance-redshift relation, baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) and redshift-space distortion (RSD) observables, and derived parameters. We train our emulators on Einstein-Boltzmann calculations obtained with high-precision numerical convergence settings, for a wide range of cosmological models including $\Lambda$CDM, $w$CDM, $\Lambda$CDM+$N_\mathrm{eff}$, and $\Lambda$CDM+$\Sigma m_\nu$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the properties of active galactic nuclei disks with gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.03992/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.03992/</guid>
      <description>Avi Vajpeyi
Active galactic nuclei (AGN) are promising environments for the assembly of merging binary black hole (BBH) systems. Interest in AGNs as nurseries for merging BBH is rising following the detection of gravitational waves from a BBH system from the purported pair-instability mass gap, most notably, GW190521. Active galactic nuclei have also been invoked to explain the formation of the high-mass-ratio system, GW190814. We draw on simulations of BBH systems in AGN to propose a phenomenological model for the distribution of black hole spins of merging binaries in AGN disks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observed UV continuum slopes ($β$) of galaxies at $z = 0.40-0.75$ in the GOODS-north field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observed_uv_continuum_slopes__%CE%B2__of_galaxies_at__z__0.40-0.75__in_the_goods-north_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observed_uv_continuum_slopes__%CE%B2__of_galaxies_at__z__0.40-0.75__in_the_goods-north_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chayan Mondal
We estimate the UV continuum slope ($\beta$) of 465 galaxies (with luminosities of 0.028 $-$ 3.3 $L^{}{z=0.5}$) in the Great Observatories Origins Survey (GOODS) Northern field in the redshift range $z=0.40 - 0.75$. We use two AstroSat/UVIT (N242W, N245M), two HST (F275W, F336W), and a KPNO (U) bands to sample the UV continuum slope of selected galaxies between 1215 and 2600 angstrom. The mean (median) and 1$\sigma$ scatter in the observed $\beta$ are found to be $-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for the warm-hot intergalactic medium using XMM-Newton high-resolution X-ray spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_using_xmm-newton_high-resolution_x-ray_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_using_xmm-newton_high-resolution_x-ray_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Gatuzz
The problem of missing baryons in the local universe remains an open question. One propose alternative is that at low redshift missing baryons are in the form of the Warm Hot Intergalactic Medium (WHIM). In order to test this idea, we present a detailed analysis of X-ray high-resolution spectra of six extragalactic sources, Mrk 421, 1ES 1028+511, 1ES 1553+113, H2356-309, PKS 0558-504 and PG 1116+215, obtained with the XMM-Newton Reflection Grating Spectrometer to search for signals of WHIM and/or circumgalactic medium (CGM) X-ray absorbing gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic red supergiant explosion model grid for systematic characterization of Type II supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synthetic_red_supergiant_explosion_model_grid_for_systematic_characterization_of_type_ii_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synthetic_red_supergiant_explosion_model_grid_for_systematic_characterization_of_type_ii_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takashi J. Moriya
A new model grid containing 228,016 synthetic red supergiant explosions (Type II supernovae) is introduced. Time evolution of spectral energy distributions from 1 A to 50,000 A (100 frequency bins in a log scale) is computed at each time step up to 500 days after explosion in each model. We provide light curves for the filters of the Vera C. Rubin Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST), Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF), Sloan Digital Sky Servey (SDSS), and the Neil Gehrels Swift Observatory, but light curves for any photometric filters can be constructed by convolving any filter response functions to the synthetic spectral energy distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A massive interacting galaxy 525 million years after the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_massive_interacting_galaxy_525_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_massive_interacting_galaxy_525_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kristan Boyett
JWST observations confirm the existence of galaxies as early as 300Myr and at a higher number density than expected based on galaxy formation models and HST observations. Yet, sources confirmed spectroscopically in the first 500Myr have estimated stellar masses $&amp;lt;5\times10^8M_\odot$, limiting the signal to noise ratio (SNR) for investigating substructure. We present a high-resolution spectroscopic and spatially resolved study of a rare bright galaxy at $z=9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Chemical Anomalies of Seven A-types Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_chemical_anomalies_of_seven_a-types_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_chemical_anomalies_of_seven_a-types_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yahya Nasolo
We present a chemical abundance analysis of seven A-type stars with no detailed chemical abundance measurements in the literature. High-resolution spectra of the targets HD 2924, HD 4321, HD 26553, HD 125658, HD 137928, HD 154713, and HD 159834 were obtained using the Coude Echelle Spectrograph at the TUBITAK National Observatory. We determined the atmospheric abundances of the samples and measured the elemental abundances of C, N, O, Na, Mg, Al, Si, S, K, Ca, Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Sr, Y, Zr, Ba, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, Eu, and Gd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Chemical Anomalies of Seven A-types Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black hole mergers as tracers of spinning massive black hole and galaxy populations in the Obelisk simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_mergers_as_tracers_of_spinning_massive_black_hole_and_galaxy_populations_in_the_obelisk_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_mergers_as_tracers_of_spinning_massive_black_hole_and_galaxy_populations_in_the_obelisk_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. A. Dong-Páez
Massive black hole (BH) mergers will be key targets of future gravitational wave and electromagnetic observational facilities. In order to constrain BH evolution with the information extracted from BH mergers, one must take into account the complex relationship between the population of merging BHs and the global BH population. We analyse the high-resolution cosmological radiation-hydrodynamics simulation Obelisk, run to redshift $z=3.5$, to study the properties of the merging BH population, and its differences with the underlying global BH population in terms of BH and galaxy properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonical Hubble-Tension-Resolving Early Dark Energy Cosmologies are Inconsistent with the Lyman-$α$ Forest</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/canonical_hubble-tension-resolving_early_dark_energy_cosmologies_are_inconsistent_with_the_lyman-_%CE%B1__forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/canonical_hubble-tension-resolving_early_dark_energy_cosmologies_are_inconsistent_with_the_lyman-_%CE%B1__forest/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samuel Goldstein
Current cosmological data exhibit discordance between indirect and some direct inferences of the present-day expansion rate, $H_0$. Early dark energy (EDE), which briefly increases the cosmic expansion rate prior to recombination, is a leading scenario for resolving this &amp;ldquo;Hubble tension&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; while preserving a good fit to cosmic microwave background (CMB) data. However, this comes at the cost of changes in parameters that affect structure formation in the late-time universe, including the spectral index of scalar perturbations, $n_s$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Census of Gaseous Satellites around Local Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/census_of_gaseous_satellites_around_local_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/census_of_gaseous_satellites_around_local_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jingyao Zhu
We present a search for gas-containing dwarf galaxies as satellite systems around nearby spiral galaxies using 21 cm neutral hydrogen (HI) data from the Arecibo Legacy Fast ALFA (ALFALFA) Survey. We have identified 15 spiral `primary&amp;rsquo; galaxies in a local volume of 10 Mpc with a range of total masses, and have found 19 gas-containing dwarf satellite candidates within the primaries&amp;rsquo; virial volumes ($R_{200}$) and 46 candidates within $2R_{200}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Hubble Space Telescope Archives: A Catalogue of 21,926 Interacting Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/harnessing_the_hubble_space_telescope_archives_a_catalogue_of_21926_interacting_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/harnessing_the_hubble_space_telescope_archives_a_catalogue_of_21926_interacting_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David O&amp;rsquo;Ryan
Mergers play a complex role in galaxy formation and evolution. Continuing to improve our understanding of these systems require ever larger samples, which can be difficult (even impossible) to select from individual surveys. We use the new platform ESA Datalabs to assemble a catalogue of interacting galaxies from the Hubble Space Telescope science archives; this catalogue is larger than previously published catalogues by nearly an order of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Galaxy Mergers on Stellar Population Profiles of Early-type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.00559/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.00559/</guid>
      <description>Yongmin Yoon
We study the impact of galaxy mergers on stellar population profiles/gradients of early-type galaxies (ETGs) using ETGs at $z&amp;amp;lt;0.055$ in the Stripe 82 region of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and MaNGA integral field unit spectroscopic data. Tidal features around ETGs, which are detected from deep coadded images, are regarded as direct observational evidence for recent mergers. We find that ETGs with tidal features have less negative metallicity gradients and more positive age gradients than ETGs without tidal features at $M_\mathrm{star}\gtrsim10^{10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Galaxy Mergers on Stellar Population Profiles of Early-type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_galaxy_mergers_on_stellar_population_profiles_of_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_galaxy_mergers_on_stellar_population_profiles_of_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yongmin Yoon
We study the impact of galaxy mergers on stellar population profiles/gradients of early-type galaxies (ETGs) using ETGs at $z&amp;lt;0.055$ in the Stripe 82 region of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and MaNGA integral field unit spectroscopic data. Tidal features around ETGs, which are detected from deep coadded images, are regarded as direct observational evidence for recent mergers. We find that ETGs with tidal features have less negative metallicity gradients and more positive age gradients than ETGs without tidal features at $M_\mathrm{star}\gtrsim10^{10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misaligned gas accretion as a formation pathway of S0 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/misaligned_gas_accretion_as_a_formation_pathway_of_s0_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/misaligned_gas_accretion_as_a_formation_pathway_of_s0_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuren Zhou
We select 753 S0 galaxies from the internal Product Lauch-10 of MaNGA survey (MPL-10) and find that $\sim$11% of S0 galaxies show gas-star kinematic misalignments, which is higher than the misaligned fraction in spiral ($\sim$1%) and elliptical galaxies ($\sim$6%) in MPL-10. If we only consider the emission-line galaxies (401 emission-line S0s), the misaligned fraction in S0s increases to $\sim$20%. In S0s, the kinematic misalignments are more common than the merger remnant features ($\sim$8%).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Discreteness Errors in Multi-Species Cosmological N-body Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_discreteness_errors_in_multi-species_cosmological_n-body_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_discreteness_errors_in_multi-species_cosmological_n-body_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xin Liu
We present a detailed analysis of numerical discreteness errors in two-species, gravity-only, cosmological simulations using the density power spectrum as a diagnostic probe. In a simple setup where both species are initialized with the same total matter transfer function, biased growth of power forms on small scales when the solver force resolution is finer than the mean interparticle separation. The artificial bias is more severe when individual density and velocity transfer functions are applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quenching star formation with low-luminosity AGN winds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quenching_star_formation_with_low-luminosity_agn_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quenching_star_formation_with_low-luminosity_agn_winds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivan Almeida
We present a simple model for low-luminosity active galactic nucleus (LLAGN) feedback through thermal winds produced by a hot accretion flow. The wind carries considerable energy and deposits it on the host galaxy at kiloparsec scales and beyond, heating the galactic gas thereby quenching star formation. Our model predicts that the typical LLAGN can quench more than $10%$ of star formation in its host galaxy. We find that long-lived LLAGN winds from supermassive black holes (SMBH) with masses $\geq 10^8 M_{\odot}$ and mass accretion rates $\dot{M} &amp;gt; 10^{-3}\dot{M}{\rm Edd}$ can prevent gas collapse and significantly quench galactic star formation compared to a scenario without AGN, if the wind persists over 1 Myr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the alignment of radio galaxies in the ELAIS-N1 field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revisiting_the_alignment_of_radio_galaxies_in_the_elais-n1_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revisiting_the_alignment_of_radio_galaxies_in_the_elais-n1_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marco Simonte
Aims. Previous studies reported an alignment of the major axes of radio galaxies on various angular scales. Here, we study the alignment of radio galaxies in the ELAIS-N1 Low Frequency ARray (LOFAR) deep field, which covers an area of 25 $\rm deg^2$. \newline Methods. The low noise level of about 20$ \rm ~ \mu Jy/beam$ of the LOFAR deep field observations at 150 MHz enabled the identification of 447 extended ($&amp;gt; 30 \rm &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;$) radio galaxies for which we have measured the major axis position angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for galaxy-scale strong-lenses in galaxy clusters with deep networks -- I: methodology and network performance</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_galaxy-scale_strong-lenses_in_galaxy_clusters_with_deep_networks_--_i_methodology_and_network_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_galaxy-scale_strong-lenses_in_galaxy_clusters_with_deep_networks_--_i_methodology_and_network_performance/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Angora
Galaxy-scale strong lenses in galaxy clusters provide a unique tool to investigate their inner mass distribution and the sub-halo density profiles in the low-mass regime, which can be compared with the predictions from cosmological simulations. We search for galaxy-galaxy strong-lensing systems in HST multi-band imaging of galaxy cluster cores from the CLASH and HFF programs by exploring the classification capabilities of deep learning techniques. Convolutional neural networks are trained utilising highly-realistic simulations of galaxy-scale strong lenses injected into the HST cluster fields around cluster members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematically Measuring Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies (SMUDGes). IV. Ultra-Diffuse Satellites of Milky Way Analogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/systematically_measuring_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_smudges._iv._ultra-diffuse_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/systematically_measuring_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_smudges._iv._ultra-diffuse_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hina Goto
To better understand the formation of large, low surface brightness galaxies, we measure the correlation function between ultra-diffuse galaxy (UDG) candidates and Milky Way analogs (MWAs). We find that (1) the projected radial distribution of UDG satellites (projected surface density $\propto r^{-0.84\pm0.06}$) is consistent with that of normal satellite galaxies, (2) the number of UDG satellites per MWA ($S_{\rm UDG}$) is $\sim 0.5\pm0.1$ over projected radii from 20 to 250 kpc and $-17&amp;lt; M_r &amp;lt; -13.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
