<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/3month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/3month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A candidate magnetic helium core white dwarf in the globular cluster NGC 6397</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04184/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04184/</guid>
      <description>Manuel Pichardo Marcano
We report a peculiar variable blue star in the globular cluster NGC 6397, using Hubble Space Telescope optical imaging. Its position in the colour-magnitude diagrams, and its spectrum, are consistent with this star being a helium core white dwarf (He WD) in a binary system. The optical light curve shows a periodicity at 18.5 hours. We argue that this periodicity is due to the rotation of the WD and possibly due to magnetic spots on the surface of the WD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nearly constant CN/HCN line ratio in nearby galaxies: CN as a new tracer of dense gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_nearly_constant_cn_hcn_line_ratio_in_nearby_galaxies_cn_as_a_new_tracer_of_dense_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_nearly_constant_cn_hcn_line_ratio_in_nearby_galaxies_cn_as_a_new_tracer_of_dense_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christine D. Wilson
We investigate the relationship between CN N = 1 - 0 and HCN J = 1 - 0 emission on scales from 30 pc to 400 pc using ALMA archival data, for which CN is often observed simultaneously with the CO J = 1 - 0 line. In a sample of 9 nearby galaxies ranging from ultra-luminous infrared galaxies to normal spiral galaxies, we measure a remarkably constant CN/HCN line intensity ratio of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active galactic nuclei feedback in an elliptical galaxy (III): the impacts and fate of cosmological inflow</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/active_galactic_nuclei_feedback_in_an_elliptical_galaxy_iii_the_impacts_and_fate_of_cosmological_inflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/active_galactic_nuclei_feedback_in_an_elliptical_galaxy_iii_the_impacts_and_fate_of_cosmological_inflow/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bocheng Zhu
The cosmological inflow of a galaxy is speculated to be able to enter the galaxy and enhance the star formation rate (SFR) and black hole accretion rate (BHAR). In this paper, by performing high-resolution hydrodynamic simulations in the framework of {\it MACER}, we investigate the fate of the inflow and its impacts on the evolution of a massive elliptical galaxy. The inflow properties are adopted from the cosmological simulation IllustrisTNG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GN-z11 in context: possible signatures of globular cluster precursors at redshift 10</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04179/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.04179/</guid>
      <description>Peter Senchyna
The first JWST spectroscopy of the luminous galaxy GN-z11 simultaneously both established its redshift at $z=10.6$ and revealed a rest-ultraviolet spectrum dominated by signatures of highly-ionized nitrogen, which has so far defied clear interpretation. Here we present a reappraisal of this spectrum in the context of both detailed nebular modeling and nearby metal-poor reference galaxies. The N IV] emission enables the first nebular density measurement in a star-forming galaxy at $z&amp;amp;gt;10$, and reveals evidence for extremely high densities $n_e\gtrsim 10^5$ $\mathrm{cm^{-3}}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New dwarf galaxy candidates in the sphere of influence of the Local Volume spiral galaxy NGC2683</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_in_the_sphere_of_influence_of_the_local_volume_spiral_galaxy_ngc2683/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_in_the_sphere_of_influence_of_the_local_volume_spiral_galaxy_ngc2683/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Crosby
We present initial results of a survey of host $L_{*}$ galaxies environments in the Local Volume ($D&amp;lt;10,$Mpc) searching for satellite dwarf galaxy candidates using the wide-field Hyper Suprime-Cam imager on the 8m Subaru Telescope. The current paper presents complete results on NGC2683 ($M_{B_T,0}=-19.62$, $D=9.36,Mpc$, $v_{\odot}=411,km,s^{-1}$), an isolated Sc spiral galaxy in the Leo Spur. At the distance of NGC2683, we image the complete volume out to projected radii of $380,kpc$ using a hexagonal arrangement of 7 pointings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primordial Gravitational Waves Assisted by Cosmological Scalar Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_gravitational_waves_assisted_by_cosmological_scalar_perturbations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_gravitational_waves_assisted_by_cosmological_scalar_perturbations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yan-Heng Yu
Primordial gravitational waves are one of the most important predictions of inflation theory, and measurements of their imprints on the cosmic microwave background are actively pursued, but not yet succeed until now. Here we point out that measurements of primordial gravitational waves could be conceivable through searching for a signal of second-order tensor perturbations, which were produced due to nonlinear couplings between the linear tensor and scalar perturbations in the early universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mass-loss rates of star clusters with stellar-mass black holes: implications for the globular cluster mass function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03791/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03791/</guid>
      <description>Mark Gieles
Stellar-mass black holes (BHs) can be retained in globular clusters (GCs) until the present. Simulations of GC evolution find that the relaxation driven mass-loss rate is elevated if BHs are present, especially near dissolution. We capture this behaviour in a parameterised mass-loss rate, benchmarked by results from $N$-body simulations, and use it to evolve an initial GC mass function (GCMF), similar to that of young massive clusters in the Local Universe, to an age of 12 Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the progenitor formation galaxies of merging binary black holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/understanding_the_progenitor_formation_galaxies_of_merging_binary_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/understanding_the_progenitor_formation_galaxies_of_merging_binary_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rahul Srinivasan
With nearly a hundred gravitational wave detections, the origin of black hole mergers has become a key question. Here, we focus on understanding the typical galactic environment in which binary black hole mergers arise. To this end, we synthesize progenitors of binary black hole mergers as a function of the redshift of progenitor formation, present-day formation galaxy mass, and progenitor stellar metallicity for $240$ star formation and binary evolution models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using entropy bounds to avoid the cosmological singularity and constrain particle production</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_entropy_bounds_to_avoid_the_cosmological_singularity_and_constrain_particle_production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_entropy_bounds_to_avoid_the_cosmological_singularity_and_constrain_particle_production/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hao Yu
In this work, we study the applications of entropy bounds in two toy cosmological models with particle production (annihilation), i.e., radiation-dominated universe and dust-dominated universe. Since entropy bounds are involved in the volume of the thermodynamc system, we need to specify the thermodynamc system in the universe in advance. We consider the co-moving volume and the volume covered by the particle horizon as the target thermodynamic system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can observations of 511 keV line from the M31 galaxy shed light on the AGN jet composition?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_observations_of_511_kev_line_from_the_m31_galaxy_shed_light_on_the_agn_jet_composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_observations_of_511_kev_line_from_the_m31_galaxy_shed_light_on_the_agn_jet_composition/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. A. Nizamov
Positron annihilation line at 511~keV is a known component of the gamma-ray diffuse emission. It is believed to be produced in the Galaxy, but there could be possible extragalactic contribution as well. E.g., positrons can be produced in jets of active galactic nuclei (AGN) and after that accumulate and gradually annihilate in hot gaseous halos around galaxies. In this work we test this hypothesis in application to an individual object &amp;ndash; the Andromeda galaxy (M31) which is close and has a supermassive black hole in its center, which powered an AGN before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining High-Energy Neutrino Emission from Supernovae with IceCube</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_supernovae_with_icecube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_supernovae_with_icecube/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Abbasi
Core-collapse supernovae are a promising potential high-energy neutrino source class. We test for correlation between seven years of IceCube neutrino data and a catalog containing more than 1000 core-collapse supernovae of types IIn and IIP and a sample of stripped-envelope supernovae. We search both for neutrino emission from individual supernovae, and for combined emission from the whole supernova sample through a stacking analysis. No significant spatial or temporal correlation of neutrinos with the cataloged supernovae was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Carbon to Cobalt: Chemical compositions and ages of $z\sim0.7$ quiescent galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_carbon_to_cobalt_chemical_compositions_and_ages_of__z_sim0.7__quiescent_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_carbon_to_cobalt_chemical_compositions_and_ages_of__z_sim0.7__quiescent_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aliza G. Beverage
We present elemental abundance patterns (C, N, Mg, Si, Ca, Ti, V, Cr, Fe, Co, and Ni) for a population of 135 massive quiescent galaxies at $z\sim0.7$ with ultra-deep rest-frame optical spectroscopy drawn from the LEGA-C survey. We derive average ages and elemental abundances in four bins of stellar velocity dispersion ($\sigma_v$) ranging from 150$~$km$,$s$^{-1}$ to 250$~$km$,$s$^{-1}$ using a full-spectrum hierarchical Bayesian model. The resulting elemental abundance measurements are precise to 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamma-ray emission from the Seyfert galaxy NGC 4151 and multimessenger implications for ultra-fast outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_emission_from_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc_4151_and_multimessenger_implications_for_ultra-fast_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_emission_from_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc_4151_and_multimessenger_implications_for_ultra-fast_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Enrico Peretti
The enhanced activity typical of the core of Seyfert galaxies can drive powerful winds where high-energy phenomena can occur. In spite of their high power content, the number of such non-jetted active galactic nuclei detected in gamma-ray is very limited. In this Letter, we report the detection of a gamma-ray flux from NGC 4151, a Seyfert galaxy located at about 15.8 Mpc. The source is known for hosting ultra-fast outflows (UFOs) in its innermost core through X-ray spectroscopic observations, thereby becoming the first UFO host ever detected in gamma rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General-relativistic radiation transport scheme in Gmunu I: Implementation of two-moment based multi-frequency radiative transfer and code tests</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03261/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03261/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Chi-Kit Cheong
We present the implementation of two-moment based general-relativistic multi-group radiation transport module in the $\texttt{G}$eneral-relativistic $\texttt{mu}$ltigrid $\texttt{nu}$merical ($\texttt{Gmunu}$) code. On top of solving the general-relativistic magnetohydrodynamics and the Einstein equations with conformally flat approximations, the code solves the evolution equations of the zeroth- and first-order moments of the radiations. Analytic closure relation is used to obtain the higher order moments and close the system. The finite-volume discretisation has been adopted for the radiation moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of tidal features in deep optical galaxy images with Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identification_of_tidal_features_in_deep_optical_galaxy_images_with_convolutional_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identification_of_tidal_features_in_deep_optical_galaxy_images_with_convolutional_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. Domínguez Sánchez
Interactions between galaxies leave distinguishable imprints in the form of tidal features which hold important clues about their mass assembly. Unfortunately, these structures are difficult to detect because they are low surface brightness features so deep observations are needed. Upcoming surveys promise several orders of magnitude increase in depth and sky coverage, for which automated methods for tidal feature detection will become mandatory. We test the ability of a convolutional neural network to reproduce human visual classifications for tidal detections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intergalactic magnetic field studies by means of $γ$-ray emission from GRB 190114C</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intergalactic_magnetic_field_studies_by_means_of__%CE%B3_-ray_emission_from_grb_190114c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intergalactic_magnetic_field_studies_by_means_of__%CE%B3_-ray_emission_from_grb_190114c/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paolo Da Vela
The presence of delayed GeV emission after a strong transient, such as a GRB (Gamma-Ray Burst), in the VHE (Very-High Energy, $E&amp;gt;100$ GeV) band can be the signature of a non-zero magnetic field in the intergalactic medium. We used a synchrotron self-Compton multiwavelength model to infer an analytical description of the intrinsic VHE spectrum (corrected for absorption by the Extragalactic Background Light, EBL) of GRB$,$190114C to predict the lightcurves and SEDs of the delayed emission with Monte Carlo simulations for different IGMF (Intergalactic Magnetic Field) configurations (strengths $B=8\times10^{-21}$ G, $10^{-20}$ G, $3\times 10^{-20}$G and correlation length $\lambda&amp;gt;1$ Mpc), and compared them with the Fermi-LAT (Fermi Large Area Telescope) limits computed for several exposure times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a dwarf galaxy satellite-of-satellite problem in $Λ$CDM?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_there_a_dwarf_galaxy_satellite-of-satellite_problem_in__%CE%BB_cdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_there_a_dwarf_galaxy_satellite-of-satellite_problem_in__%CE%BB_cdm/</guid>
      <description>First author: Oliver Müller
Dark matter clusters on all scales, therefore it is expected that even substructure should host its own substructure. Using the Extragalactic Distance Database, we searched for dwarf galaxy satellites of dwarf galaxies, i.e. satellite-of-satellite galaxies, corresponding to these substructures-of-substructure. Going through HST data of 117 dwarf galaxies, we report the discovery of a dwarf galaxy around the ultra-diffuse M96 companion M96-DF6 at 10 Mpc. Modelling its structural parameters, we find that it is an ultra-faint dwarf galaxy which is 135 times fainter than its host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the sizes of ionized bubbles around the highest redshift galaxies. Spectral shapes of the Lyman-alpha emission from galaxies III</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sizes_of_ionized_bubbles_around_the_highest_redshift_galaxies._spectral_shapes_of_the_lyman-alpha_emission_from_galaxies_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sizes_of_ionized_bubbles_around_the_highest_redshift_galaxies._spectral_shapes_of_the_lyman-alpha_emission_from_galaxies_iii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew J. Hayes
We develop a new method to determine the distance between a galaxy and a foreground screen of atomic hydrogen. In a partially neutral universe, and under the assumption of spherical symmetry, this equates to the radius of a ionized &amp;lsquo;bubble&amp;rsquo; (Rbub) surrounding the galaxy. The method requires an observed Lya equivalent width, velocity offset from systemic, and an input Lya profile for which we adopt scaled versions of the profiles observed in low-z galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper 1: The JWST PEARLS View of the El Gordo Galaxy Cluster and of the Structure It Magnifies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/paper_1_the_jwst_pearls_view_of_the_el_gordo_galaxy_cluster_and_of_the_structure_it_magnifies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/paper_1_the_jwst_pearls_view_of_the_el_gordo_galaxy_cluster_and_of_the_structure_it_magnifies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brenda L. Frye
The massive galaxy cluster El Gordo ($z=0.87$) imprints multitudes of gravitationally lensed arcs onto James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) images. Eight bands of NIRCam imaging were obtained in the Prime Extragalactic Areas for Reionization and Lensing Science (PEARLS) program (GTO #1176). PSF-matched photometry across a suite of Hubble Space Telescope (HST) and NIRCam filters gives new photometric redshifts. We confirm 54 known image multiplicities and find two new ones and construct a lens model based on the light-traces-mass method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population III X-ray Binaries and their Impact on the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03435/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03435/</guid>
      <description>Nina S. Sartorio
The first population of X-ray binaries (XRBs) is expected to affect the thermal and ionization states of the gas in the early Universe. Although these X-ray sources are predicted to have important implications for high-redshift observable signals, such as the hydrogen 21-cm signal from cosmic dawn and the cosmic X-ray background, their properties are poorly explored, leaving theoretical models largely uninformed. In this paper we model a population of X-ray binaries arising from zero metallicity stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population III X-ray Binaries and their Impact on the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Expansion of the Young Type Ia Supernova Remnant 0519-69.0: More Evidence for a Circumstellar Shell</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_expansion_of_the_young_type_ia_supernova_remnant_0519-69.0_more_evidence_for_a_circumstellar_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_expansion_of_the_young_type_ia_supernova_remnant_0519-69.0_more_evidence_for_a_circumstellar_shell/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benson T. Guest
The nature of Type Ia supernovae remains controversial. The youngest remnants of Ia supernovae hold clues to the explosion and to the immediate surroundings. We present a third epoch of Chandra observations of the $\sim600$-year-old Type Ia remnant 0519-69.0 in the Large Magellanic Cloud, extending the time baseline to 21 years from the initial 2000 observations. We find rapid expansion of X-ray emitting material, with an average velocity of 4760 km s$^{-1}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reoriented Memory of Galaxy Spins for the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reoriented_memory_of_galaxy_spins_for_the_early_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reoriented_memory_of_galaxy_spins_for_the_early_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jun-Sung Moon
Galaxy spins are believed to retain initially acquired tendency of being aligned with the intermediate principal axes of the linear tidal field, which disseminates a prospect of using them as a probe of the early universe physics. This roseate prospect, however, is contingent upon the key assumption that the observable stellar spins of the present galaxies measured at inner radii have the same alignment tendency toward the initial tidal field as their dark matter counterparts measured at virial limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN2017egm: A Helium-rich Superluminous Supernova with Multiple Bumps in the Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn2017egm_a_helium-rich_superluminous_supernova_with_multiple_bumps_in_the_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn2017egm_a_helium-rich_superluminous_supernova_with_multiple_bumps_in_the_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiazheng Zhu
When discovered, SN~2017egm was the closest (redshift $z=0.03$) hydrogen-poor superluminous supernova (SLSN-I) and a rare case that exploded in a massive and metal-rich galaxy. Thus, it has since been extensively observed and studied. We report spectroscopic data showing strong emission at around He~I $\lambda$10,830 and four He~I absorption lines in the optical. Consequently, we classify SN~2017egm as a member of an emerging population of helium-rich SLSNe-I (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The large scale limit of the observed galaxy power spectrum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_large_scale_limit_of_the_observed_galaxy_power_spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_large_scale_limit_of_the_observed_galaxy_power_spectrum/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matteo Foglieni
The large scale limit of the galaxy power spectrum provides a unique window into the early Universe through a possible detection of scale dependent bias produced by Primordial Non Gaussianities. On such large scales, relativistic effects could become important and, potentially, be confused for a primordial signal. In this work we provide the first consistent estimate of such effects in the observed galaxy power spectrum, and discuss their possible degeneracy with local Primordial Non Gaussianities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A luminous dust-obscured Tidal Disruption Event candidate in a star forming galaxy at 42 Mpc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_luminous_dust-obscured_tidal_disruption_event_candidate_in_a_star_forming_galaxy_at_42_mpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_luminous_dust-obscured_tidal_disruption_event_candidate_in_a_star_forming_galaxy_at_42_mpc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Panagiotou
While the vast majority of Tidal Disruption Events (TDEs) has been identified by wide-field sky surveys in the optical and X-ray bands, recent studies indicate that a considerable fraction of TDEs may be dust obscured, and thus preferentially detected in the infrared (IR) wavebands. In this Letter, we present the discovery of a luminous mid-IR nuclear flare (termed WTP 14adbjsh) identified in a systematic transient search of archival images from the NEOWISE mid-IR survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo-observation of spiral galaxies in the radio band to verify depolarization models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pseudo-observation_of_spiral_galaxies_in_the_radio_band_to_verify_depolarization_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pseudo-observation_of_spiral_galaxies_in_the_radio_band_to_verify_depolarization_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuta Tashima
Studies of the three-dimensional (3D) structures of galactic magnetic fields are now entering a new era, with broadband, highly sensitive radio observations and new analysis methods. To reveal the magnetic field configuration from the observed value integrated along the line of sight, it is necessary to derive an appropriate model that can reproduce the observational characteristics. We aim to clarify the relationship between the radiation field and the spatial distribution of physical quantities through pseudo-observations using global 3D magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) simulation results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing of Pulsars in the Globular Cluster Omega Centauri</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02834/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02834/</guid>
      <description>S. Dai
We present the timing of the first five millisecond pulsars discovered in the globular cluster Omega Centauri and the discovery of a pulsar with a spin period of 3.68 ms. With a timing baseline of $\sim$3.5 yr we are able to measure the derivative of the spin frequency ($\dotν$) for the first five pulsars. Upper limits on the pulsar line-of-sight acceleration are estimated and compared with predictions based on analytical models of the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An optical/X-ray/radio view of Abell 1213: a galaxy cluster with an anomalous diffuse radio emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_optical_x-ray_radio_view_of_abell_1213_a_galaxy_cluster_with_an_anomalous_diffuse_radio_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_optical_x-ray_radio_view_of_abell_1213_a_galaxy_cluster_with_an_anomalous_diffuse_radio_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Boschin
Context. Abell 1213, a poor galaxy system, is known to host an anomalous radio halo detected in VLA data which is an outsider in the relation between the radio halos power and the X-ray luminosity of the parent clusters. Aims. Our aim is to analyze the cluster from the optical, X-ray and radio point of view to characterize the environment of its diffuse radio emission and shed new light on its nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic Simulations of a Relativistic Jet Interacting with the Intracluster Medium: Application to Cygnus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_of_a_relativistic_jet_interacting_with_the_intracluster_medium_application_to_cygnus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_of_a_relativistic_jet_interacting_with_the_intracluster_medium_application_to_cygnus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: John A. ZuHone
The Fanaroff-Riley class II radio galaxy Cygnus A hosts jets which produce radio emission, X-ray cavities, cocoon shocks, and X-ray hotspots where the jet interacts with the ICM. Surrounding one hotspot is a peculiar &amp;ldquo;hole&amp;rdquo; feature which appears as a deficit in X-ray emission. We use relativistic hydrodynamic simulations of a collimated jet interacting with an inclined interface between lobe and cluster plasma to model the basic processes which may lead to such a feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An archival search for type Ia supernova siblings</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_archival_search_for_type_ia_supernova_siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_archival_search_for_type_ia_supernova_siblings/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Kelsey
By searching the Open Supernova Catalog, an extra-galactic transient host galaxy database, and literature analyses, I present the largest sample of type Ia supernova (SN Ia) siblings to date. The sample comprises 158 galaxies, consisting of 327 confirmed SNe Ia - over 10 times larger than existing sibling SN Ia samples. SN siblings share host galaxies, and thus share global environmental properties and associated systematic uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical models of adenine precursors cyanamide and carbodiimide in the interstellar medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_models_of_adenine_precursors_cyanamide_and_carbodiimide_in_the_interstellar_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_models_of_adenine_precursors_cyanamide_and_carbodiimide_in_the_interstellar_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xia Zhang
Cyanamide (NH2CN) and its isomer, carbodiimide (HNCNH), may form adenine in the interstellar medium (ISM) via a series of reactions. Therefore, they are considered key prebiotic molecules in the study of the origin of life. We used the three-phase NAUTILUS chemical code, which includes the gas, the dust surface, and the icy mantle, to investigate the formation and destruction of cyanamide and carbodiimide. We added over 200 new chemical reactions of the two isomers and related species, and established a relatively complete network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Chameleon screening using galaxy cluster dynamics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_chameleon_screening_using_galaxy_cluster_dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_chameleon_screening_using_galaxy_cluster_dynamics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yacer Boumechta
We constrain the Chameleon \textit{screening} mechanism in galaxy clusters, essentially obtaining limits on the coupling strength $\beta$ and the asymptotic value of the field $\phi_{\infty}$. For this purpose, we utilized a collection of the 9 relaxed galaxy clusters within the X-COP compilation in the redshift range of $z \le 0.1$. We implement the formalism assuming an NFW mass profile for the dark matter density and study the degeneracy present between the mass $\M$ and the chameleon coupling with a high degree of improvement in the constraints for excluded parameter space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Radioactivity and Galactic Chemical Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_radioactivity_and_galactic_chemical_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_radioactivity_and_galactic_chemical_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roland Diehl
The description of the tempo-spatial evolution of the composition of cosmic gas on galactic scales is called &amp;lsquo;modelling galactic chemical evolution&amp;rsquo;. It aims to use knowledge about sources of nucleosynthesis and how they change the composition of interstellar gas, following the formation of stars and the ejection of products from nuclear fusion during their evolution and terminating explosions. Sources of nucleosynthesis are diverse: Stars with hydrostatic nuclear burning eject some of the products, and core-collapse supernovae add ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the diversity and similarity of radially anisotropic Milky Way-like stellar haloes: implications for dwarf galaxy searches</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_diversity_and_similarity_of_radially_anisotropic_milky_way-like_stellar_haloes_implications_for_dwarf_galaxy_searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_diversity_and_similarity_of_radially_anisotropic_milky_way-like_stellar_haloes_implications_for_dwarf_galaxy_searches/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew D. A. Orkney
We investigate the properties of mergers that are comparable to the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) using cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of Milky Way-like galaxies. It was previously shown that these mergers occur over a wide range of times ($6-10,$Gyr ago). We find that the merger progenitors span an order of magnitude in their peak stellar mass ($3\times10^8&amp;lt;M_{\star}/\rm{M}{\odot}&amp;lt;4\times10^9$) and include both rotation and pressure-supported galaxies ($0.10&amp;lt;D/T&amp;lt;0.77$). In a minority of cases, the GSE-like debris is comprised of stars from more than one merger progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster formation histories, masses and radii inferred from gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02263/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.02263/</guid>
      <description>Maya Fishbach
Globular clusters (GCs) are found in all types of galaxies and harbor some of the most extreme stellar systems, including black holes that may dynamically assemble into merging binaries (BBHs). Despite their ubiquity, the origin and evolution of GCs remains an open question. Uncertain GC properties, including when they formed, their initial masses and sizes, affect their production rate of BBH mergers. Using the gravitational-wave catalog GWTC-3, we measure that dynamically-assembled BBHs -- those that are consistent with isotropic spin directions -- make up $61^{+29}_{-44}\%$ of the total merger rate, with a local merger rate of $10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Matter Creation, Multi-fluid Cosmology and Kinetic Theory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_matter_creation_multi-fluid_cosmology_and_kinetic_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_matter_creation_multi-fluid_cosmology_and_kinetic_theory/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. R. G. Trevisani
A macroscopic and kinetic relativistic description for a decoupled multi-fluid cosmology endowed with gravitationally induced particle production of all components is proposed. The temperature law for each decoupled particle species is also kinetically derived. The present approach points to the possibility of an exact (semi-classical) quantum-gravitational kinetic treatment by incorporating back reaction effects for an arbitrary set of dominant decoupled components. As an illustration we show that a cosmology driven by creation of cold dark matter and baryons (without dark energy) evolves like $\Lambda$CDM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric galaxy morphology from stellar and nebular emission with the CALIFA sample</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonparametric_galaxy_morphology_from_stellar_and_nebular_emission_with_the_califa_sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonparametric_galaxy_morphology_from_stellar_and_nebular_emission_with_the_califa_sample/</guid>
      <description>First author: Angelos Nersesian
We present a nonparametric morphology analysis of the stellar continuum and nebular emission lines for a sample of local galaxies. We explore the dependence of the various morphological parameters on wavelength and morphological type. Our goal is to quantify the difference in morphology between the stellar and nebular components. We derive the nonparametric morphological indicators of 364 galaxies from the CALIFA Survey. To calculate those indicators, we apply the StatMorph package on the high-quality integral field spectroscopic data cubes, as well as to the most prominent nebular emission-line maps, namely $[OIII]$$\lambda$5007, H$\alpha$, and $[NII]$$\lambda$6583.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fast X-ray Transient XRT 210423 and its Host Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fast_x-ray_transient_xrt_210423_and_its_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fast_x-ray_transient_xrt_210423_and_its_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Eappachen
Fast X-ray Transients (FXTs) are X-ray flares with a duration ranging from a few hundred seconds to a few hours. Possible origins include the tidal disruption of a white dwarf by an intermediate-mass black hole, a supernova shock breakout, and a binary neutron star merger. We present the X-ray light curve and spectrum, and deep optical imaging of the FXT XRT 210423, which has been suggested to be powered by a magnetar produced in a binary neutron star merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion of sub-stellar companions as the origin of chemical abundance inhomogeneities in globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.11412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.11412/</guid>
      <description>Andrew J. Winter
Globular clusters exhibit abundance variations, defining `multiple populations&amp;amp;#39;, which have prompted a protracted search for their origin. Properties requiring explanation include: the high fraction of polluted stars ($\sim 40{-}90$~percent, correlated with cluster mass), the absence of pollution in young clusters and the lower pollution rate with binarity and distance from the cluster centre. We present a novel mechanism for late delivery of pollutants into stars via accretion of sub-stellar companions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrasting X-ray/UV time-lags in Seyfert 1 galaxies NGC 4593 and NGC 7469 using AstroSat observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/contrasting_x-ray_uv_time-lags_in_seyfert_1_galaxies_ngc_4593_and_ngc_7469_using_astrosat_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/contrasting_x-ray_uv_time-lags_in_seyfert_1_galaxies_ngc_4593_and_ngc_7469_using_astrosat_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kavita Kumari
We study accretion disk-corona connection in Seyfert 1 galaxies using simultaneous UV/X-ray observations of NGC 4593 (July 14-18, 2016) and NGC 7469 (October 15-19, 2017) performed with AstroSat. We use the X-ray (0.5-7.0 keV) data acquired with the Soft X-ray Telescope (SXT) and the UV (FUV: 130-180 nm, NUV: 200-300 nm) data obtained with the Ultra-Violet Imaging Telescope (UVIT). We also use the contemporaneous Swift observations of NGC 4593 and demonstrate AstroSat&amp;rsquo;s capability for X-ray/UV correlation studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detailed shapes of the line-of-sight velocity distributions in massive early-type galaxies from non-parametric spectral models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detailed_shapes_of_the_line-of-sight_velocity_distributions_in_massive_early-type_galaxies_from_non-parametric_spectral_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detailed_shapes_of_the_line-of-sight_velocity_distributions_in_massive_early-type_galaxies_from_non-parametric_spectral_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kianusch Mehrgan
We present the first systematic study of the detailed shapes of the line-of-sight velocity distributions (LOSVDs) in nine massive early-type galaxies (ETGs) using the novel non-parametric modelling code WINGFIT. High-signal spectral observations with MUSE at the VLT allow us to measure between 40 and 400 individual LOSVDs in each galaxy at a signal-to-noise level better than 100 per spectral bin and to trace the LOSVDs all the way out to the highest stellar velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early results from GLASS-JWST. XX: Unveiling a population of &#34;red-excess&#39;&#39; galaxies in Abell2744 and in the coeval field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early_results_from_glass-jwst._xx_unveiling_a_population_of_red-excess_galaxies_in_abell2744_and_in_the_coeval_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early_results_from_glass-jwst._xx_unveiling_a_population_of_red-excess_galaxies_in_abell2744_and_in_the_coeval_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benedetta Vulcani
We combine the superior JWST/NIRCam imaging and MUSE data to characterize the properties of galaxies in different environmental conditions in the cluster Abell2744 (z=0.3064) and in its immediate surroundings. Our most striking result is the discovery of a ``red-excess&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; population in F200W-F444W colors both in the cluster regions and the field. These galaxies have normal F115W-F150W colors, but are up to 0.8 mag redder than red sequence galaxies in F200W-F444W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitation of Langmuir waves in the magnetospheres of AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/excitation_of_langmuir_waves_in_the_magnetospheres_of_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/excitation_of_langmuir_waves_in_the_magnetospheres_of_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Z. N. Osmanov
In the paper we study the process of excitation of Langmuir waves in the magnetospheres of active galactic nuclei (AGN), by taking a general-relativistic expression of the Goldreich-Julian density into account. We considered the linearised set of equations which describe dynamics of the studied mechanism: the Euler equation, the continuity equation and the Poisson equation. After solving the dispersion relation and obtaining the instability growth rate, we explored it versus several physical parameters: electron&amp;rsquo;s and proton&amp;rsquo;s relativistic factors and the mass and luminosity of AGN, which are supposed to be Kerr black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMultimass modelling of Milky Way globular clusters -- I. Implications on their stellar initial mass function above 1 M⊙</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.01637/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.01637/</guid>
      <description>Nolan Dickson
The distribution of stars and stellar remnants (white dwarfs, neutron stars, black holes) within globular clusters holds clues about their formation and long-term evolution, with important implications for their initial mass function (IMF) and the formation of black hole mergers. In this work, we present best-fitting multimass models for 37 Milky Way globular clusters, which were inferred from various datasets, including proper motions from Gaia EDR3 and HST, line-of-sight velocities from ground-based spectroscopy and deep stellar mass functions from HST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth-rate measurement with type-Ia supernovae using ZTF survey simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growth-rate_measurement_with_type-ia_supernovae_using_ztf_survey_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growth-rate_measurement_with_type-ia_supernovae_using_ztf_survey_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bastien Carreres
Measurements of the growth rate of structures at $z &amp;lt; 0.1$ with peculiar velocity surveys have the potential of testing the validity of general relativity on cosmic scales. In this work, we present growth-rate measurements from realistic simulated sets of type-Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF). We describe our simulation methodology, the light-curve fitting and peculiar velocity estimation. Using the maximum likelihood method, we derive constraints on $f\sigma_8$ using only ZTF SN Ia peculiar velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-accuracy emulators for observables in $Λ$CDM, $N_\mathrm{eff}$, $Σm_ν$, and $w$ cosmologies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-accuracy_emulators_for_observables_in__%CE%BB_cdm__n__mathrmeff___%CF%83m_%CE%BD__and__w__cosmologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-accuracy_emulators_for_observables_in__%CE%BB_cdm__n__mathrmeff___%CF%83m_%CE%BD__and__w__cosmologies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Boris Bolliet
We use the emulation framework CosmoPower to construct and publicly release neural network emulators of cosmological observables, including the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) temperature and polarization power spectra, matter power spectrum, distance-redshift relation, baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) and redshift-space distortion (RSD) observables, and derived parameters. We train our emulators on Einstein-Boltzmann calculations obtained with high-precision numerical convergence settings, for a wide range of cosmological models including $\Lambda$CDM, $w$CDM, $\Lambda$CDM+$N_\mathrm{eff}$, and $\Lambda$CDM+$\Sigma m_\nu$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the properties of active galactic nuclei disks with gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.03992/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.03992/</guid>
      <description>Avi Vajpeyi
Active galactic nuclei (AGN) are promising environments for the assembly of merging binary black hole (BBH) systems. Interest in AGNs as nurseries for merging BBH is rising following the detection of gravitational waves from a BBH system from the purported pair-instability mass gap, most notably, GW190521. Active galactic nuclei have also been invoked to explain the formation of the high-mass-ratio system, GW190814. We draw on simulations of BBH systems in AGN to propose a phenomenological model for the distribution of black hole spins of merging binaries in AGN disks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observed UV continuum slopes ($β$) of galaxies at $z = 0.40-0.75$ in the GOODS-north field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observed_uv_continuum_slopes__%CE%B2__of_galaxies_at__z__0.40-0.75__in_the_goods-north_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observed_uv_continuum_slopes__%CE%B2__of_galaxies_at__z__0.40-0.75__in_the_goods-north_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chayan Mondal
We estimate the UV continuum slope ($\beta$) of 465 galaxies (with luminosities of 0.028 $-$ 3.3 $L^{}{z=0.5}$) in the Great Observatories Origins Survey (GOODS) Northern field in the redshift range $z=0.40 - 0.75$. We use two AstroSat/UVIT (N242W, N245M), two HST (F275W, F336W), and a KPNO (U) bands to sample the UV continuum slope of selected galaxies between 1215 and 2600 angstrom. The mean (median) and 1$\sigma$ scatter in the observed $\beta$ are found to be $-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for the warm-hot intergalactic medium using XMM-Newton high-resolution X-ray spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_using_xmm-newton_high-resolution_x-ray_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_using_xmm-newton_high-resolution_x-ray_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Gatuzz
The problem of missing baryons in the local universe remains an open question. One propose alternative is that at low redshift missing baryons are in the form of the Warm Hot Intergalactic Medium (WHIM). In order to test this idea, we present a detailed analysis of X-ray high-resolution spectra of six extragalactic sources, Mrk 421, 1ES 1028+511, 1ES 1553+113, H2356-309, PKS 0558-504 and PG 1116+215, obtained with the XMM-Newton Reflection Grating Spectrometer to search for signals of WHIM and/or circumgalactic medium (CGM) X-ray absorbing gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic red supergiant explosion model grid for systematic characterization of Type II supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synthetic_red_supergiant_explosion_model_grid_for_systematic_characterization_of_type_ii_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synthetic_red_supergiant_explosion_model_grid_for_systematic_characterization_of_type_ii_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takashi J. Moriya
A new model grid containing 228,016 synthetic red supergiant explosions (Type II supernovae) is introduced. Time evolution of spectral energy distributions from 1 A to 50,000 A (100 frequency bins in a log scale) is computed at each time step up to 500 days after explosion in each model. We provide light curves for the filters of the Vera C. Rubin Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST), Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF), Sloan Digital Sky Servey (SDSS), and the Neil Gehrels Swift Observatory, but light curves for any photometric filters can be constructed by convolving any filter response functions to the synthetic spectral energy distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A massive interacting galaxy 525 million years after the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_massive_interacting_galaxy_525_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_massive_interacting_galaxy_525_million_years_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kristan Boyett
JWST observations confirm the existence of galaxies as early as 300Myr and at a higher number density than expected based on galaxy formation models and HST observations. Yet, sources confirmed spectroscopically in the first 500Myr have estimated stellar masses $&amp;lt;5\times10^8M_\odot$, limiting the signal to noise ratio (SNR) for investigating substructure. We present a high-resolution spectroscopic and spatially resolved study of a rare bright galaxy at $z=9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Chemical Anomalies of Seven A-types Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_chemical_anomalies_of_seven_a-types_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_chemical_anomalies_of_seven_a-types_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yahya Nasolo
We present a chemical abundance analysis of seven A-type stars with no detailed chemical abundance measurements in the literature. High-resolution spectra of the targets HD 2924, HD 4321, HD 26553, HD 125658, HD 137928, HD 154713, and HD 159834 were obtained using the Coude Echelle Spectrograph at the TUBITAK National Observatory. We determined the atmospheric abundances of the samples and measured the elemental abundances of C, N, O, Na, Mg, Al, Si, S, K, Ca, Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Sr, Y, Zr, Ba, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, Eu, and Gd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Chemical Anomalies of Seven A-types Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black hole mergers as tracers of spinning massive black hole and galaxy populations in the Obelisk simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_mergers_as_tracers_of_spinning_massive_black_hole_and_galaxy_populations_in_the_obelisk_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_mergers_as_tracers_of_spinning_massive_black_hole_and_galaxy_populations_in_the_obelisk_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. A. Dong-Páez
Massive black hole (BH) mergers will be key targets of future gravitational wave and electromagnetic observational facilities. In order to constrain BH evolution with the information extracted from BH mergers, one must take into account the complex relationship between the population of merging BHs and the global BH population. We analyse the high-resolution cosmological radiation-hydrodynamics simulation Obelisk, run to redshift $z=3.5$, to study the properties of the merging BH population, and its differences with the underlying global BH population in terms of BH and galaxy properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonical Hubble-Tension-Resolving Early Dark Energy Cosmologies are Inconsistent with the Lyman-$α$ Forest</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/canonical_hubble-tension-resolving_early_dark_energy_cosmologies_are_inconsistent_with_the_lyman-_%CE%B1__forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/canonical_hubble-tension-resolving_early_dark_energy_cosmologies_are_inconsistent_with_the_lyman-_%CE%B1__forest/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samuel Goldstein
Current cosmological data exhibit discordance between indirect and some direct inferences of the present-day expansion rate, $H_0$. Early dark energy (EDE), which briefly increases the cosmic expansion rate prior to recombination, is a leading scenario for resolving this &amp;ldquo;Hubble tension&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; while preserving a good fit to cosmic microwave background (CMB) data. However, this comes at the cost of changes in parameters that affect structure formation in the late-time universe, including the spectral index of scalar perturbations, $n_s$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Census of Gaseous Satellites around Local Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/census_of_gaseous_satellites_around_local_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/census_of_gaseous_satellites_around_local_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jingyao Zhu
We present a search for gas-containing dwarf galaxies as satellite systems around nearby spiral galaxies using 21 cm neutral hydrogen (HI) data from the Arecibo Legacy Fast ALFA (ALFALFA) Survey. We have identified 15 spiral `primary&amp;rsquo; galaxies in a local volume of 10 Mpc with a range of total masses, and have found 19 gas-containing dwarf satellite candidates within the primaries&amp;rsquo; virial volumes ($R_{200}$) and 46 candidates within $2R_{200}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Hubble Space Telescope Archives: A Catalogue of 21,926 Interacting Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/harnessing_the_hubble_space_telescope_archives_a_catalogue_of_21926_interacting_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/harnessing_the_hubble_space_telescope_archives_a_catalogue_of_21926_interacting_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David O&amp;rsquo;Ryan
Mergers play a complex role in galaxy formation and evolution. Continuing to improve our understanding of these systems require ever larger samples, which can be difficult (even impossible) to select from individual surveys. We use the new platform ESA Datalabs to assemble a catalogue of interacting galaxies from the Hubble Space Telescope science archives; this catalogue is larger than previously published catalogues by nearly an order of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Galaxy Mergers on Stellar Population Profiles of Early-type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.00559/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.00559/</guid>
      <description>Yongmin Yoon
We study the impact of galaxy mergers on stellar population profiles/gradients of early-type galaxies (ETGs) using ETGs at $z&amp;amp;lt;0.055$ in the Stripe 82 region of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and MaNGA integral field unit spectroscopic data. Tidal features around ETGs, which are detected from deep coadded images, are regarded as direct observational evidence for recent mergers. We find that ETGs with tidal features have less negative metallicity gradients and more positive age gradients than ETGs without tidal features at $M_\mathrm{star}\gtrsim10^{10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Galaxy Mergers on Stellar Population Profiles of Early-type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_galaxy_mergers_on_stellar_population_profiles_of_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_galaxy_mergers_on_stellar_population_profiles_of_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yongmin Yoon
We study the impact of galaxy mergers on stellar population profiles/gradients of early-type galaxies (ETGs) using ETGs at $z&amp;lt;0.055$ in the Stripe 82 region of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and MaNGA integral field unit spectroscopic data. Tidal features around ETGs, which are detected from deep coadded images, are regarded as direct observational evidence for recent mergers. We find that ETGs with tidal features have less negative metallicity gradients and more positive age gradients than ETGs without tidal features at $M_\mathrm{star}\gtrsim10^{10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misaligned gas accretion as a formation pathway of S0 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/misaligned_gas_accretion_as_a_formation_pathway_of_s0_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/misaligned_gas_accretion_as_a_formation_pathway_of_s0_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuren Zhou
We select 753 S0 galaxies from the internal Product Lauch-10 of MaNGA survey (MPL-10) and find that $\sim$11% of S0 galaxies show gas-star kinematic misalignments, which is higher than the misaligned fraction in spiral ($\sim$1%) and elliptical galaxies ($\sim$6%) in MPL-10. If we only consider the emission-line galaxies (401 emission-line S0s), the misaligned fraction in S0s increases to $\sim$20%. In S0s, the kinematic misalignments are more common than the merger remnant features ($\sim$8%).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Discreteness Errors in Multi-Species Cosmological N-body Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_discreteness_errors_in_multi-species_cosmological_n-body_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_discreteness_errors_in_multi-species_cosmological_n-body_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xin Liu
We present a detailed analysis of numerical discreteness errors in two-species, gravity-only, cosmological simulations using the density power spectrum as a diagnostic probe. In a simple setup where both species are initialized with the same total matter transfer function, biased growth of power forms on small scales when the solver force resolution is finer than the mean interparticle separation. The artificial bias is more severe when individual density and velocity transfer functions are applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quenching star formation with low-luminosity AGN winds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quenching_star_formation_with_low-luminosity_agn_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quenching_star_formation_with_low-luminosity_agn_winds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivan Almeida
We present a simple model for low-luminosity active galactic nucleus (LLAGN) feedback through thermal winds produced by a hot accretion flow. The wind carries considerable energy and deposits it on the host galaxy at kiloparsec scales and beyond, heating the galactic gas thereby quenching star formation. Our model predicts that the typical LLAGN can quench more than $10%$ of star formation in its host galaxy. We find that long-lived LLAGN winds from supermassive black holes (SMBH) with masses $\geq 10^8 M_{\odot}$ and mass accretion rates $\dot{M} &amp;gt; 10^{-3}\dot{M}{\rm Edd}$ can prevent gas collapse and significantly quench galactic star formation compared to a scenario without AGN, if the wind persists over 1 Myr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the alignment of radio galaxies in the ELAIS-N1 field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revisiting_the_alignment_of_radio_galaxies_in_the_elais-n1_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revisiting_the_alignment_of_radio_galaxies_in_the_elais-n1_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marco Simonte
Aims. Previous studies reported an alignment of the major axes of radio galaxies on various angular scales. Here, we study the alignment of radio galaxies in the ELAIS-N1 Low Frequency ARray (LOFAR) deep field, which covers an area of 25 $\rm deg^2$. \newline Methods. The low noise level of about 20$ \rm ~ \mu Jy/beam$ of the LOFAR deep field observations at 150 MHz enabled the identification of 447 extended ($&amp;gt; 30 \rm &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;$) radio galaxies for which we have measured the major axis position angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for galaxy-scale strong-lenses in galaxy clusters with deep networks -- I: methodology and network performance</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_galaxy-scale_strong-lenses_in_galaxy_clusters_with_deep_networks_--_i_methodology_and_network_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_galaxy-scale_strong-lenses_in_galaxy_clusters_with_deep_networks_--_i_methodology_and_network_performance/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Angora
Galaxy-scale strong lenses in galaxy clusters provide a unique tool to investigate their inner mass distribution and the sub-halo density profiles in the low-mass regime, which can be compared with the predictions from cosmological simulations. We search for galaxy-galaxy strong-lensing systems in HST multi-band imaging of galaxy cluster cores from the CLASH and HFF programs by exploring the classification capabilities of deep learning techniques. Convolutional neural networks are trained utilising highly-realistic simulations of galaxy-scale strong lenses injected into the HST cluster fields around cluster members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematically Measuring Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies (SMUDGes). IV. Ultra-Diffuse Satellites of Milky Way Analogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/systematically_measuring_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_smudges._iv._ultra-diffuse_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/systematically_measuring_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_smudges._iv._ultra-diffuse_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hina Goto
To better understand the formation of large, low surface brightness galaxies, we measure the correlation function between ultra-diffuse galaxy (UDG) candidates and Milky Way analogs (MWAs). We find that (1) the projected radial distribution of UDG satellites (projected surface density $\propto r^{-0.84\pm0.06}$) is consistent with that of normal satellite galaxies, (2) the number of UDG satellites per MWA ($S_{\rm UDG}$) is $\sim 0.5\pm0.1$ over projected radii from 20 to 250 kpc and $-17&amp;lt; M_r &amp;lt; -13.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
