<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>11(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/11month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 11(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/11month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Morphological signatures of mergers in the TNG50 simulation and the Kilo-Degree Survey: the merger fraction from dwarfs to Milky Way-like galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2210.14123/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2210.14123/</guid>
      <description>Tiger Yu-Yang Hsiao
MACS0647$-$JD is a triply-lensed $z\sim11$ galaxy originally discovered with the Hubble Space Telescope. Here we report new JWST imaging, which clearly resolves MACS0647$-$JD as having two components that are either merging galaxies or stellar complexes within a single galaxy. Both are very small, with stellar masses $\sim10^8,M_\odot$ and radii $r&amp;lt;100,\rm pc$. The brighter larger component &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; is intrinsically very blue ($β\sim-2.6$), likely due to very recent star formation and no dust, and is spatially extended with an effective radius $\sim70,\rm pc$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological signatures of mergers in the TNG50 simulation and the Kilo-Degree Survey: the merger fraction from dwarfs to Milky Way-like galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05785/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05785/</guid>
      <description>Alejandro Guzmán-Ortega
Using the TNG50 cosmological simulation and observations from the Kilo-Degree Survey (KiDS), we investigate the connection between galaxy mergers and optical morphology in the local Universe over a wide range of galaxy stellar masses ($8.5\leqslant\log(M_\ast/\text{M}\odot)\leqslant11$). To this end, we have generated over 16,000 synthetic images of TNG50 galaxies designed to match KiDS observations, including the effects of dust attenuation and scattering, and used the $\mathrm{\mathtt{statmorph}}$ code to measure various image-based morphological diagnostics in the $r$-band for both data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing early universe through redshifted 21-cm signal: Modelling and observational challenges</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</guid>
      <description>Abinash Kumar Shaw
The redshifted 21-cm radiation from the atomic hydrogen (HI) provides an excellent direct probe to study the evolution of HI in IGM and thus reveal the nature of the first luminous objects, their evolution and role during Cosmic Dawn (CD) and Epoch of Reionization (EoR), and formation and evolution of the structures thereafter. Direct mapping of the HI density during the CD-EoR is rather difficult with the current and future instruments due to large foreground and other observational contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2022ann: A type Icn supernova from a dwarf galaxy that reveals helium in its circumstellar environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05134/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05134/</guid>
      <description>K. W. Davis
We present optical and near-infrared (NIR) observations of the Type Icn supernova (SN Icn) 2022ann, the fifth member of its newly identified class of SNe. Its early optical spectra are dominated by narrow carbon and oxygen P-Cygni features with absorption velocities of 800 km/s; slower than other SNe Icn and indicative of interaction with a dense, H/He-poor circumstellar medium (CSM) that is outflowing slower than a typical Wolf-Rayet wind velocity of $&amp;gt;$1000 km/s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of neutrino decoupling from the early universe to the current universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2210.10307/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2210.10307/</guid>
      <description>Kensuke Akita
We review the distortions of spectra of relic neutrinos due to the interactions with electrons, positrons, and neutrinos in the early universe. We solve integro-differential kinetic equations for the neutrino density matrix, including vacuum three-flavor neutrino oscillations, oscillations in electron and positron background, a collision term and finite temperature corrections to electron mass and electromagnetic plasma up to the next-to-leading order $\mathcal{O}(e^3)$. After that, we estimate the effects of the spectral distortions in neutrino decoupling on the number density and energy density of the Cosmic Neutrino Background (C$ν$B) in the current universe, and discuss the implications of these effects on the capture rates in direct detection of the C$ν$B on tritium, with emphasis on the PTOLEMY-type experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.04503/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.04503/</guid>
      <description>Roark Habegger
In galactic disks, the Parker instability results when non-thermal pressure support exceeds a certain threshold. The non-thermal pressures considered in the Parker instability are cosmic ray pressure and magnetic pressure. This instability takes a long time to saturate $(&amp;gt;500 , \mathrm{Myr})$ and assumes a background with fixed cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio. In reality, galactic cosmic rays are injected into localized regions $(&amp;lt; 100 ,\mathrm{pc})$ by events like supernovae, increasing the cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05275/</guid>
      <description>Ray S. Sharma
We examine the quenching characteristics of $328$ isolated dwarf galaxies $\left(10^{8} &amp;lt; M_{\rm star}/M_\odot &amp;lt; 10^{10} \right)$ within the \Rom{} cosmological hydrodynamic simulation. Using mock observation methods, we identify isolated dwarf galaxies with quenched star formation and make direct comparisons to the quenched fraction in the NASA Sloan Atlas (NSA). Similar to other cosmological simulations, we find a population of quenched, isolated dwarf galaxies below $M_{\rm star} &amp;lt; 10^{9} M_\odot$ not detected within the NSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and dynamics of the peculiar stream Jhelum, A tentative role for the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2202.02132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2202.02132/</guid>
      <description>Hanneke C. Woudenberg
Stellar streams are a promising tool to study the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s dark matter subhalo population, as interactions with subhalos could produce substructure in streams. However, other possible causes for substructure first need to be well understood. Here we study the kinematics and the unusual morphology of the stellar stream Jhelum. Using a combination of ground-based photometry and Gaia EDR3 astrometry we characterize the morphology of Jhelum. We combine this new data with radial velocities from the literature to perform orbit integrations of the stream in static Galactic potentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic inhomogeneities in the early Universe: A numerical relativity approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03534/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03534/</guid>
      <description>Cristian Joana
Cosmic inflation is arguably the most favoured paradigm of the very early Universe. It postulates an early phase of fast, nearly exponential, and accelerated expansion. Inflationary models are capable of explaining the overall flatness and homogeneity of today&amp;rsquo;s Universe at large scales. Despite being widely accepted by the physics community, these models are not absent from criticism. In scalar field inflation, a necessary condition to begin inflation is the requirement of a Universe dominated by the field&amp;rsquo;s potential, which implies a subdominant contribution from the scalar field dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between the globular cluster systems of the Virgo and Fornax Galaxy Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02711/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02711/</guid>
      <description>J. Dabringhausen
It is well known that Globular cluster systems are different among galaxies. Here we test to which degree these differences remain on the scale of galaxy clusters by comparing the globular clusters (GCs) in optical surveys of the Virgo galaxy cluster (ACSVCS) and the Fornax galaxy cluster (ACSFCS) in Kolmogorov-Smirnoff Tests. Both surveys were obtained with the Advanced Camera for Surveys (ACS) on board the Hubble Space Telescope, and contain thousands of GCs in dozens of galaxies each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a double sequence of blue straggler stars in the core-collapsed globular cluster NGC 6256</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02671/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02671/</guid>
      <description>Mario Cadelano
We used a combination of high-resolution optical images acquired with the Hubble Space Telescope and near-IR wide-field data to investigate the stellar density profile and the population of blue straggler star (BSS) in the Galactic globular cluster NGC6256, with the aim of probing its current stage of internal dynamical evolution. We found that the inner stellar density profile significantly deviates from a King model while is well reproduced by a steep cusp with a power-law slope alpha=-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a new Local Group Dwarf Galaxy Candidate in UNIONS: Boötes V</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2209.08242/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2209.08242/</guid>
      <description>Simon E. T. Smith
We present the discovery of Boötes V, a new ultra-faint dwarf galaxy candidate. This satellite is detected as a resolved overdensity of stars during an ongoing search for new Local Group dwarf galaxy candidates in the UNIONS photometric dataset. It has a physical half-light radius of 26.9$^{+7.5}_{-5.4}$ pc, a $V$-band magnitude of $-$4.5 $\pm$ 0.4 mag, and resides at a heliocentric distance of approximately 100 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinguishing Dark Matter Cusps from Cores using Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.01384/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.01384/</guid>
      <description>Shaunak Modak
Globular Clusters (GCs) provide valuable insight into the properties of their host galaxies&amp;rsquo; dark matter halos. Using N-body simulations incorporating semianalytic dynamical friction and GC-GC merger prescriptions, we study the evolution of GC radial distributions and mass functions in cuspy and cored dark matter halos. Modeling the dynamics of the GC-rich system in the dwarf galaxy UGC7369, we find that friction-induced inspiral and subsequent mergers of massive GCs can naturally and robustly explain the mass segregation of the GCs and the existence of a nuclear star cluster (NSC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DUVET: Spatially Resolved Observations of Star Formation Regulation via Galactic Outflows in a Starbursting Disk Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02063/</guid>
      <description>Bronwyn Reichardt Chu
We compare 500~pc scale, resolved observations of ionised and molecular gas for the $z\sim0.02$ starbursting disk galaxy IRAS08339+6517, using measurements from KCWI and NOEMA. We explore the relationship of the star formation driven ionised gas outflows with colocated galaxy properties. We find a roughly linear relationship between the outflow mass flux ($\dotΣ_{\rm out}$) and star formation rate surface density ($Σ_{\rm SFR}$), $\dotΣ_{\rm out}\proptoΣ_{\rm SFR}^{1.06\pm0.10}$, and a strong correlation between $\dotΣ_{\rm out}$ and the gas depletion time, such that $\dotΣ_{\rm out} \propto t_{dep}^{-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Stellar Parameters Estimation through CMD of Star Clusters: Open (NGC2360) and Globular (NGC 5272)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2209.03019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2209.03019/</guid>
      <description>Kanwar Preet Kaur
The fundamentals of estimating essential stellar parameters of an open cluster-NGC 2360 and globular clusters-NGC 5272 are presented extensively in this work. Here, the evaluation of stellar parameters, by manually fitting the appropriate isochrones on the color magnitude diagrams (CMDs), of the selected star clusters is discussed comprehensively. Aperture photometry and PSF fitting photometry are conducted on g, r, and i standard band filter images of Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) using the aperture photometry tool (APT) to obtain the respective CMDs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-rich, field ultra-diffuse galaxies host few globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.00650/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.00650/</guid>
      <description>S. Jang
Hubble Space Telescope (HST) photometry is providing an extensive analysis of globular clusters (GCs). In particular, the pseudo two-colour diagram dubbed &#39;chromosome map (ChM)&#39; allowed to detect and characterize their multiple populations with unprecedented detail. The main limitation of these studies is the small field of view of HST, which makes it challenging to investigate some important aspects of the multiple populations, such as their spatial distributions and the internal kinematics in the outermost cluster regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-rich, field ultra-diffuse galaxies host few globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.00651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.00651/</guid>
      <description>Michael G. Jones
We present Hubble Space Telescope imaging of 14 gas-rich, low surface brightness and ultra-diffuse galaxies (UDGs) in the field at distances of 25-36 Mpc. An inspection of point-like sources brighter than the turnover magnitude of the globular cluster luminosity function and within twice the half-light radii of each galaxy reveals that, unlike those in denser environments, gas-rich, field UDGs host very few old globular clusters (GCs). Most of the targets (nine) have zero candidate GCs, with the remainder having one or two candidates each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster formation with multiple stellar populations: A single-binary composite scenario</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.00344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.00344/</guid>
      <description>Kenji Bekki
We discuss a GC formation scenario in which the first generation (1G) of single asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars and intermediate-mass close binaries (IMCBs) eject gas, from which the second generation (2G) of stars can be formed. The two key parameters in the scenario are the fractions of binary stars (f_b) and the slopes (alpha) of the stellar initial mass functions (IMFs) for 1G stars. Principle results derived by analytic and one-zone models of GC formation are as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Population III homogeneous stellar evolution on early cosmic reionisation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2205.15125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2205.15125/</guid>
      <description>Yves Sibony
Context: Population III (Pop III) stars may be fast rotating. An expected consequence of fast rotation is strong internal mixing that deeply affects their evolutionary tracks in the Hertzsprung-Russell diagram and hence their ionising power. aims: We investigate the impact on the ionising power of Pop III stars in an extreme case of internal mixing, the one leading to chemically homogeneous evolution (CHE). In that situation, during the main sequence phase, the star keeps the same chemical composition from its center to its surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting Kilonovae: Long-lasting Electromagnetic Counterparts to Binary Mergers in the Accretion Disks of Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03097/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03097/</guid>
      <description>Jia Ren
We investigate the dynamics and electromagnetic (EM) signatures of neutron star-neutron star (NS-NS) or neutron star-black hole (NS-BH) merger ejecta that occurs in the accretion disk of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We find that the interaction between ejecta and disk gas leads to important effects on the dynamics and radiation. We show five stages of the ejecta dynamics: gravitational slowing down, coasting, Sedov-Taylor deceleration in the disk, re-acceleration after the breakout from the disk surface, and momentum-conserved snowplow phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic signatures of impulsive supernova feedback in dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03795/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03795/</guid>
      <description>Jan D. Burger
Impulsive supernova feedback and non-standard dark matter models, such as self-interacting dark matter (SIDM), are the two main contenders for the role of the dominant core formation mechanism at the dwarf galaxy scale. Here we show that the impulsive supernova cycles that follow episodes of bursty star formation leave distinct features in the distribution function of stars: groups of stars with similar ages and metallicities develop overdense shells in phase space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the observability and identification of Population III galaxies with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.02038/</guid>
      <description>James A. A. Trussler
We utilise theoretical models of Population III stellar+nebular spectra to investigate the prospects of observing and accurately identifying Population III galaxies with JWST using both deep imaging and spectroscopy. We investigate a series of different colour cuts, finding that a combination of NIRCam and MIRI photometry through the F444W-F560W, F560W-F770W colours offers the most robust identifier of potential $z=8$ Pop III candidates. We calculate that NIRCam will have to reach $\sim$ 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANDORA project: photo-nuclear reactions below A=60</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03986/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.03986/</guid>
      <description>A. Tamii, L. Pellegri
Photo-nuclear reactions of light nuclei below a mass of $A=60$ are studied experimentally and theoretically by the PANDORA (Photo-Absorption of Nuclei and Decay Observation for Reactions in Astrophysics) project. Two experimental methods, virtual-photon excitation by proton scattering and real-photo absorption by a high-brilliance gamma-ray beam produced by laser Compton scattering, will be applied to measure the photo-absorption cross sections and the decay branching ratio of each decay channel as a function of the photon energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of globular clusters formed in dark matter mini-halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2112.01265/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2112.01265/</guid>
      <description>Eduardo Vitral
We seek to differentiate dynamical and morphological attributes between globular clusters (GCs) that were formed inside their own dark matter (DM) mini-halo, and those who were not. We employ high resolution full N-body simulations on GPU of GCs with and without a DM mini-halo, orbiting a Fornax-like dwarf galaxy. For GCs with DM, we observe that this dark extra mass triggers a tidal radius growth that allows the mini-halo to act as a protective shield against tidal stripping, being itself stripped beforehand the stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of globular clusters formed in dark matter mini-halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.04485/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.04485/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mass-Metallicity Relation of Dwarf Galaxies at the Cosmic Noon in the JWST Era</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.01382/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.01382/</guid>
      <description>Mingyu Li, Zheng Cai
We present the mass-metallicity relation (MZR) at $z=2-3$ in the stellar mass range of $M_\star\approx 10^{6.5}-10^{9.5}M_\odot$ using 55 dwarf galaxies in the Abell 2744 and SMACS J0723-3732 galaxy cluster fields. These dwarf galaxies are identified and confirmed by deep JWST/NIRISS imaging and slitless grism spectroscopic observations. Taking advantage of the gravitational lensing effect, we extend the previous MZR relation at $z=2-3$ to a much lower mass regime by more than 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present-day gas content of simulated field dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2209.11782/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2209.11782/</guid>
      <description>Georg Herzog
We examine the gas content of field dwarf galaxies in a high-resolution cosmological simulation. In agreement with previous work, we find that galaxies inhabiting dark matter haloes with mass below a critical value, $M_{200} \lesssim M_{\rm crit} \approx 5\times 10^{9} \ M_{\odot}$, are quiescent at the present day. The gas content of these galaxies is thus insensitive to feedback from evolving stars. Almost half of these quiescent systems today have gas masses much smaller than that expected for their mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Candidates for Dual AGN in Dwarf-Dwarf Galaxy Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.04609/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.04609/</guid>
      <description>Marko Mićić
Dual AGN are important for understanding galaxy-merger-triggered fueling of black holes and hierarchical growth of structures. The least explored type of dual AGN are those associated with mergers of two dwarf galaxies. According to observations and cosmological simulations, dwarf galaxies are the most abundant type of galaxies in the early Universe and the galaxy merger rate is dominated by dwarfs. However, these mergers are generally too distant to be directly observed, and low-redshift dwarf-dwarf merger-related dual AGN are notoriously hard to find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Physics Informed Neural Networks for Supernova Radiative Transfer Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05219/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arxiv.2211.05219/</guid>
      <description>Xingzhuo Chen
We use physics informed neural networks (PINNs) to solve the radiative transfer equation and calculate a synthetic spectrum for a Type Ia supernova (SN~Ia) SN 2011fe. The calculation is based on local thermodynamic equilibrium (LTE) and 9 elements are included. Physical processes included are approximate radiative equilibrium, bound-bound transitions, and the Doppler effect. A PINN based gamma-ray scattering approximation is used for radioactive decay energy deposition. The PINN synthetic spectrum is compared to an observed spectrum, a synthetic spectrum calculated by the Monte-Carlo radiative transfer program TARDIS, and the formal solution of the radiative transfer equation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
