<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>11(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/11month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 11(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/11month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A non-repeating fast radio burst in a dwarf host galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_non-repeating_fast_radio_burst_in_a_dwarf_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_non-repeating_fast_radio_burst_in_a_dwarf_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shivani Bhandari
We present the discovery of as-of-yet non-repeating Fast Radio Burst (FRB) with the Australian Square Kilometer Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) as a part of the Commensal Real-time ASKAP Fast Transients (CRAFT) Survey. FRB 20210117A was detected at the center frequency of 1271.5 MHz with a dispersion measure (DM) of $728.95\pm 0.01$ pc cm$^{-3}$. The sub-arcsecond localization of the burst led to the identification of its host galaxy at a $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Mode Gas Accretion on Two Galaxy Groups at z$\sim$2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cold_mode_gas_accretion_on_two_galaxy_groups_at_z__sim_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cold_mode_gas_accretion_on_two_galaxy_groups_at_z__sim_2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrey Vayner
We present Keck Cosmic Web Imager (KCWI) integral field spectroscopy (IFS) observations of rest-frame UV emission lines $\rm Ly\alpha$, C IV $\lambda \lambda$ 1548 \AA, 1550\AA and He II 1640 \AA observed in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) of two $z=2$ radio-loud quasar host galaxies. We detect extended emission on 80-90 kpc scale in $\rm Ly\alpha$ in both systems with C IV, and He II emission also detected out to 30-50 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of the Central Mass Concentration on Bar Formation in Disk Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_the_central_mass_concentration_on_bar_formation_in_disk_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_the_central_mass_concentration_on_bar_formation_in_disk_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dajeong Jang
While bars are common in disk galaxies, their formation conditions are not well understood. We use $N$-body simulations to study bar formation and evolution in isolated galaxies consisting of a stellar disk, a classical bulge, and a dark halo. We consider 24 galaxy models that are similar to the Milky Way but differ in the mass and compactness of the classical bulge and halo concentration. We find that the bar formation requires $(Q_{T,\text{min}}/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme nature of four blue-excess dust-obscured galaxies revealed by optical spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extreme_nature_of_four_blue-excess_dust-obscured_galaxies_revealed_by_optical_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extreme_nature_of_four_blue-excess_dust-obscured_galaxies_revealed_by_optical_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Akatoki Noboriguchi
We report optical spectroscopic observations of four blue-excess dust-obscured galaxies (BluDOGs) identified by Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam. BluDOGs are a sub-class of dust-obscured galaxies (DOGs, defined with the extremely red color $(i-[22]){\rm AB} \geq 7.0$; Toba et al. 2015), showing a significant flux excess in the optical $g$- and $r$-bands over the power-law fits to the fluxes at the longer wavelengths. Noboriguchi et al. (2019) has suggested that BluDOGs may correspond to the blowing-out phase involved in a gas-rich major merger scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Spectra of Supernova Remnants in M83</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Frank Winkler
In order to better characterize the rich supernova remnant (SNR) population of M83 (NGC 5236), we have obtained high-resolution (about 85 km/s) spectra of 119 of the SNRs and SNR candidates in M83 with Gemini/GMOS, as well as new spectra of the young SNRs B12-174a and SN1957D. Most of the SNRs and SNR candidates have [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios that exceed 0.4. Combining these results with earlier studies we have carried out with MUSE and at lower spectroscopic resolution with GMOS, we have confirmed a total of 238 emission nebulae to be SNRs on the basis of their [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios, about half of which have emission lines that show velocity broadening greater than 100 km/s, providing a kinematic confirmation that they are SNRs and not H II regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological Parameters and Associated Uncertainties for 8 Million Galaxies in the Hyper Suprime-Cam Wide Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphological_parameters_and_associated_uncertainties_for_8_million_galaxies_in_the_hyper_suprime-cam_wide_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphological_parameters_and_associated_uncertainties_for_8_million_galaxies_in_the_hyper_suprime-cam_wide_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aritra Ghosh
We use the Galaxy Morphology Posterior Estimation Network (GaMPEN) to estimate morphological parameters and associated uncertainties for $\sim 8$ million galaxies in the Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) Wide survey with $z \leq 0.75$ and $m \leq 23$. GaMPEN is a machine learning framework that estimates Bayesian posteriors for a galaxy&amp;rsquo;s bulge-to-total light ratio ($L_B/L_T$), effective radius ($R_e$), and flux ($F$). By first training on simulations of galaxies and then applying transfer learning using real data, we trained GaMPEN with $&amp;lt;1%$ of our dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuSTAR Observes Two Bulgeless Galaxies: No Hard X-ray AGN Detected in NGC 4178 or J0851&#43;3926</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan W. Pfeifle
The discovery over the last several decades of moderate luminosity AGNs in disk-dominated galaxies - which show no &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; bulges - suggests that secular mechanisms represent an important growth pathway for supermassive black holes in these systems. We present new follow-up NuSTAR observations of the optically-elusive AGNs in two bulgeless galaxies, NGC 4178 and J0851+3926. NGC 4178 was originally reported as hosting an AGN based on the detection of [Ne V] mid-infrared emission detected by Spitzer, and based on Chandra X-ray imaging it has since been argued to host either a heavily obscured AGN or a supernova remnant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHANGS-JWST First Results: The Influence of Stellar Clusters on PAHs in Nearby Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs-jwst_first_results_the_influence_of_stellar_clusters_on_pahs_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs-jwst_first_results_the_influence_of_stellar_clusters_on_pahs_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel A. Dale
We present a comparison of theoretical predictions of dust continuum and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) emission with new JWST observations in three nearby galaxies: NGC 628, NGC 1365, and NGC 7496. Our analysis focuses on a total of 1063 compact stellar clusters and 2654 stellar associations previously characterized by HST in the three galaxies. We find that the distributions and trends in the observed PAH-focused infrared colors generally agree with theoretical expectations, and that the bulk of the observations is more aligned with models of larger, ionized PAHs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repeating periodic eruptions of the supernova impostor SN 2000ch</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mojgan Aghakhanloo
We analyse photometric observations of the supernova (SN) impostor SN 2000ch in NGC 3432 covering the time since its discovery. This source was previously observed to have four outbursts in 2000&amp;ndash;2010. Observations now reveal at least two additional outbursts in 2004-2006, and ten outbursts in 2013-2022. Outburst light curves are irregular and multipeaked, exhibiting a wide variety of peak magnitude, duration, and shape. The more recent outbursts (after 2010) repeat with a period of $198.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSD measurements from BOSS galaxy power spectrum using the halo perturbation theory model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rsd_measurements_from_boss_galaxy_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_perturbation_theory_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rsd_measurements_from_boss_galaxy_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_perturbation_theory_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Byeonghee Yu
We present growth of structure constraints from the cosmological analysis of the power spectrum multipoles of SDSS-III BOSS DR12 galaxies. We use the galaxy power spectrum model of Hand et al. (2017), which decomposes the galaxies into halo mass bins, each of which is modeled separately using the relations between halo biases and halo mass. The model combines Eulerian perturbation theory and halo model calibrated on $N$-body simulations to model the halo clustering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernova 2020wnt: An Atypical Superluminous Supernova with a Hidden Central Engine</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samaporn Tinyanont
We present observations of a peculiar hydrogen- and helium-poor stripped-envelope (SE) supernova (SN) 2020wnt, primarily in the optical and near-infrared (near-IR). Its peak absolute bolometric magnitude of -20.9 mag and a rise time of 69~days are reminiscent of hydrogen-poor superluminous SNe (SLSNe~I), luminous transients potentially powered by spinning-down magnetars. Before the main peak, there is a brief peak lasting &amp;lt;10 days post-explosion, likely caused by interaction with circumstellar medium (CSM) ejected ~years before the SN explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Cosmology with Double Source Lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_cosmology_with_double_source_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_cosmology_with_double_source_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Divij Sharma
Double source lensing provides a dimensionless ratio of distance ratios, a &amp;ldquo;remote viewing&amp;rdquo; of cosmology through distances relative to the gravitational lens, beyond the observer. We use this to test the cosmological framework, particularly with respect to spatial curvature and the distance duality relation. We derive a consistency equation for constant spatial curvature, allowing not only the investigation of flat vs curved but of the Friedmann-Lema^itre-Robertson-Walker framework itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ALPINE-ALMA [CII] survey: double stellar population and AGN activity in a galaxy at $z\sim5.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Barchiesi
GDS J033218.92-275302.7 (here GS-14) is a $z\sim5.5$ galaxy detected in [CII] as part of the ALPINE survey with unusual UV spectral features that have been interpreted as signatures of either a double stellar population or of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We exploited the multi-wavelength coverage of GS-14 to investigate the properties and the origin of its emission. We performed UV-to-NIR SED-fitting, with single/double stellar population and/or AGN component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The disappearances of six supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Schuyler D. Van Dyk
As part of a larger completed Hubble Space Telescope (HST) Snapshot program, we observed the sites of six nearby core-collapse supernovae (SNe) at high spatial resolution: SN 2012A, SN 2013ej, SN 2016gkg, SN 2017eaw, SN 2018zd, and SN 2018aoq. These observations were all conducted at sufficiently late times in each SN&amp;rsquo;s evolution to demonstrate that the massive-star progenitor candidate identified in each case in pre-explosion imaging data had indeed vanished and was therefore most likely the actual progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The galaxy mass-size relation in CARLA clusters and proto-clusters at 1.4 &lt; z &lt; 2.8: larger cluster galaxy sizes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_galaxy_mass-size_relation_in_carla_clusters_and_proto-clusters_at_1.4__z__2.8_larger_cluster_galaxy_sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_galaxy_mass-size_relation_in_carla_clusters_and_proto-clusters_at_1.4__z__2.8_larger_cluster_galaxy_sizes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anton V. Afanasiev
(Abridged) We study the galaxy mass-size relation in CARLA spectroscopically confirmed clusters at $1.4&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2.8$, which span a total stellar mass $11.3&amp;lt;\mathrm{log}(M^c_*/M_{\odot})&amp;lt;12.6$ (halo mass $13.5 \lesssim \mathrm{log}(M^c_h/M_{\odot}) \lesssim 14.5$). Our main finding is that cluster passive ETG at $z \gtrsim 1.5$ with ${\rm log}(M/M_{\odot})&amp;gt;10.5$ are systematically $\gtrsim 0.2-0.3~{\rm dex}$ larger than field ETGs. The passive ETG average size evolution is slower at $1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2$ when compared to the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The H$α$ and [O III] $λ5007$ Luminosity Functions of $1.2&lt;z&lt;1.9$ Emission-Line Galaxies from HST Grism Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__and_o_iii__%CE%BB5007__luminosity_functions_of__1.2z1.9__emission-line_galaxies_from_hst_grism_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__and_o_iii__%CE%BB5007__luminosity_functions_of__1.2z1.9__emission-line_galaxies_from_hst_grism_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gautam Nagaraj
Euclid and the Roman Space Telescope (Roman) will soon use grism spectroscopy to detect millions of galaxies via H$\alpha$ and [O III] $\lambda 5007$ emission. To better constrain the expected galaxy counts from these instruments, we use a vetted sample of 4,239 emission-line galaxies from the 3D-HST survey to measure the H$\alpha$ and [O III] $\lambda 5007$ luminosity functions between $1.16&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;1.90$; this sample is $\sim 4$ times larger than previous studies at this redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one-loop bispectrum of galaxies in redshift space from the Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_one-loop_bispectrum_of_galaxies_in_redshift_space_from_the_effective_field_theory_of_large-scale_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_one-loop_bispectrum_of_galaxies_in_redshift_space_from_the_effective_field_theory_of_large-scale_structure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guido D&amp;rsquo;Amico
We derive the kernels and the Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure counterterms for the one-loop bispectrum of dark matter and of biased tracers in real and redshift space. This requires the expansion of biased tracers up to fourth order in fluctuations. In the process, we encounter several subtleties related to renormalization. One is the fact that, in renormalizing the momentum, a local counterterm contributes non-locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The radio structure of the $γ$-ray narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy SDSS J211852.96$-$073227.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_radio_structure_of_the__%CE%B3_-ray_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_sdss_j211852.96_-_073227.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_radio_structure_of_the__%CE%B3_-ray_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_sdss_j211852.96_-_073227.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xi Shao
The $\gamma$-ray narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxies (NLS1s) can be considered to be the third class of $\gamma$-ray active galactic nuclei possessing relativistic jets. In this paper, we present multi-band high resolution Very Long Baseline Array (VLBA) images of the $\gamma$-ray NLS1, SDSS J211852.96$-$073227.5 (J2118$-$0732, $z=0.26$). We find a core-jet radio morphology and significant flux density variations in the radio core. The high brightness temperature estimated from VLBA images and core variability demonstrate that it exhibits substantial relativistic beaming effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibrating cosmological simulations with implicit likelihood inference using galaxy growth observables</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/calibrating_cosmological_simulations_with_implicit_likelihood_inference_using_galaxy_growth_observables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/calibrating_cosmological_simulations_with_implicit_likelihood_inference_using_galaxy_growth_observables/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yongseok Jo
In a novel approach employing implicit likelihood inference (ILI), also known as likelihood-free inference, we calibrate the parameters of cosmological hydrodynamic simulations against observations, which has previously been unfeasible due to the high computational cost of these simulations. For computational efficiency, we train neural networks as emulators on ~1000 cosmological simulations from the CAMELS project to estimate simulated observables, taking as input the cosmological and astrophysical parameters, and use these emulators as surrogates to the cosmological simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting the interstellar medium of a z=6.3 galaxy: X-shooter spectroscopy and HST imaging of the afterglow and environment of the Swift GRB 210905A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dissecting_the_interstellar_medium_of_a_z6.3_galaxy_x-shooter_spectroscopy_and_hst_imaging_of_the_afterglow_and_environment_of_the_swift_grb_210905a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dissecting_the_interstellar_medium_of_a_z6.3_galaxy_x-shooter_spectroscopy_and_hst_imaging_of_the_afterglow_and_environment_of_the_swift_grb_210905a/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Saccardi
The study of the properties of galaxies in the first billion years after the Big Bang is one of the major topic of current astrophysics. Optical/near-infrared spectroscopy of the afterglows of long Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) provide a powerful diagnostic tool to probe the interstellar medium (ISM) of their host galaxies and foreground absorbers, even up to the highest redshifts. We analyze the VLT/X-shooter afterglow spectrum of GRB 210905A, triggered by the Swift Neil Gehrels Observatory, and detect neutral-hydrogen, low-ionization, high-ionization, and fine-structure absorption lines from a complex system at z=6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for a Massive Andromeda Galaxy Using Satellite Galaxy Proper Motions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_a_massive_andromeda_galaxy_using_satellite_galaxy_proper_motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_a_massive_andromeda_galaxy_using_satellite_galaxy_proper_motions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ekta Patel
We present new mass estimates for Andromeda (M31) using the orbital angular momenta of four satellite galaxies (M33, NGC 185, NGC 147, IC 10) derived from existing proper motions, distances, and line-of-sight velocities. We infer two masses for M31: $M_{\rm vir}= 2.81^{+1.48}{-0.75}\times10^{12}, M{\odot}$ using satellite galaxy phase space information derived with HST-based M31 proper motions and $M_{\rm vir}=2.99^{+1.32}{-0.68}\times10^{12}, M{\odot}$ using phase space information derived with the weighted average of HST+Gaia-based M31 proper motions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for supernova feedback sustaining gas turbulence in nearby star-forming galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
HI and CO observations indicate that the cold gas in galaxies is very turbulent. However, the turbulent energy is expected to be quickly dissipated, implying that some energy source is needed to explain the observations. The nature of such turbulence was long unclear, as even the main candidate, supernova (SN) feedback, seemed insufficient. Other mechanisms have been proposed, but without reaching a general consensus. The key novelty of our work is considering that the gas disc thickness and flaring increase the dissipation timescale of turbulence, thus reducing the energy injection rate required to sustain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA): The Dependence of Star Formation on Surface Brightness in Low Redshift Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_the_dependence_of_star_formation_on_surface_brightness_in_low_redshift_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_the_dependence_of_star_formation_on_surface_brightness_in_low_redshift_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Phillipps
The star formation rate in galaxies is well known to correlate with stellar mass (the `star-forming main sequence&amp;rsquo;). Here we extend this further to explore any additional dependence on galaxy surface brightness, a proxy for stellar mass surface density. We use a large sample of low redshift ($z \leq 0.08$) galaxies from the GAMA survey which have both SED derived star formation rates and photometric bulge-disc decompositions, the latter providing measures of disc surface brightness and disc masses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lopsided Galaxies in a cosmological context: a new galaxy-halo connection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lopsided_galaxies_in_a_cosmological_context_a_new_galaxy-halo_connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lopsided_galaxies_in_a_cosmological_context_a_new_galaxy-halo_connection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Silvio Varela-Lavin
Disc galaxies commonly show asymmetric features in their morphology, such as warps and lopsidedness. These features can provide key information regarding the recent evolution of a given disc galaxy. In the nearby Universe, up to ~30 percent of late-type galaxies display a global non-axisymmetric lopsided mass distribution, but little attention has been paid to the origin of this perturbation. In this work, we study the origin of lopsided perturbations in simulated disc galaxies extracted from the TNG50 simulation of the IllustrisTNG project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merger Signatures are Common, but not Universal, In Massive, Recently-Quenched Galaxies at z~0.7</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/merger_signatures_are_common_but_not_universal_in_massive_recently-quenched_galaxies_at_z~0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/merger_signatures_are_common_but_not_universal_in_massive_recently-quenched_galaxies_at_z~0.7/</guid>
      <description>First author: Margaret Verrico
We present visual classifications of merger-induced tidal disturbances in 143 $\rm{M}* \sim 10^{11}\rm{M}\odot$ post-starburst galaxies at z$\sim$0.7 identified in the SQuIGG$\vec{L}$E Sample. This sample spectroscopically selects galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey that have stopped their primary epoch of star formation within the past $\sim$500 Myrs. Visual classifications are performed on Hyper Suprime Cam (HSC) i-band imaging. We compare to a control sample of mass- and redshift-matched star-forming and quiescent galaxies from the Large Early Galaxy Census and find that post-starburst galaxies are more likely to be classified as disturbed than either category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Reconstructed Images of Jets Launched by SANE Super-Eddington Accretion Flows Around SMBHs with the ngEHT</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_reconstructed_images_of_jets_launched_by_sane_super-eddington_accretion_flows_around_smbhs_with_the_ngeht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_reconstructed_images_of_jets_launched_by_sane_super-eddington_accretion_flows_around_smbhs_with_the_ngeht/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brandon Curd
Tidal disruption events (TDEs) around super massive black holes (SMBHs) are a potential laboratory to study super-Eddington accretion disks and sometimes result in powerful jets or outflows which may shine in the radio and sub millimeter bands. In this work, we model the thermal synchrotron emission of jets from general relativistic radiation magneto-hydrodynamics (GRRMHD) simulations of a BH accretion disk/jet system which assumes the TDE resulted in a magnetized accretion disk around a BH accreting at $\sim 12-25$ times the Eddington accretion rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the sociology and hierarchy of voids: a study of seven CAVITY nearby galaxy voids and their dynamical CosmicFlows-3 environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sociology_and_hierarchy_of_voids_a_study_of_seven_cavity_nearby_galaxy_voids_and_their_dynamical_cosmicflows-3_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sociology_and_hierarchy_of_voids_a_study_of_seven_cavity_nearby_galaxy_voids_and_their_dynamical_cosmicflows-3_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. M. Courtois
Context. The present study addresses a key question for our understanding of the relation between void galaxies and their environment: the relationship between luminous and dark matter in and around voids. Aims. To explore how empty of matter local Universe voids are, we study the full (dark+luminous) matter content of seven nearby cosmic voids that are fully contained within the CosmicFlows-3 volume. Methods. The cosmic voids matter density profiles are independently obtained using two different methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientations of DM Halos in FIRE-2 Milky Way-mass Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/orientations_of_dm_halos_in_fire-2_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/orientations_of_dm_halos_in_fire-2_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jay Baptista
The shape and orientation of dark matter (DM) halos are sensitive to the micro-physics of the DM particle, yet in many mass models, the symmetry axes of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s DM halo are often assumed to be aligned with the symmetry axes of the stellar disk. This is well-motivated for the inner DM halo but not for the outer halo. We use zoomed cosmological-baryonic simulations from the Latte suite of FIRE-2 Milky Way-mass galaxies to explore the evolution of the DM halo&amp;rsquo;s orientation with radius and time, with or without a major merger with a Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) analog, and when varying the DM model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the extended structure of multiple sources strongly lensed by the ultra-massive elliptical galaxy SDSS J0100&#43;1818</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_the_extended_structure_of_multiple_sources_strongly_lensed_by_the_ultra-massive_elliptical_galaxy_sdss_j0100&#43;1818/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_the_extended_structure_of_multiple_sources_strongly_lensed_by_the_ultra-massive_elliptical_galaxy_sdss_j0100&#43;1818/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Bolamperti
We study the total and baryonic mass distributions of the deflector SDSS J0100+1818 through a full strong lensing analysis. The system is composed by an ultra-massive early-type galaxy at $z=0.581$, with total stellar mass of $(1.5 \pm 0.3) 10^{12}$ M$\odot$ and stellar velocity dispersion of ($450 \pm 40$) km s$^{-1}$, surrounded by ten multiple images of three background sources, two of which spectroscopically confirmed at $z=1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying cosmic ray sources using intergalactic electromagnetic cascades</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/studying_cosmic_ray_sources_using_intergalactic_electromagnetic_cascades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/studying_cosmic_ray_sources_using_intergalactic_electromagnetic_cascades/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Uryson
In this paper intergalatic electromagnetic cascades are used as a probe of cosmic ray sources. This is achieved as follows. In extragalactic space cosmic rays initiate electromagnetic cascades in which gamma-ray and neutrino emission arises. We used the joint analysis of cosmic ray data, along with extragalactic gamma-ray and neutrino emission, to study particle acceleration in the vicinity of supermassive black holes. Particle injection spectra depend on processes of particle acceleration, and here we discuss models with various injection spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of a Relativistic Jet Following the Disruption of a Star by a Cosmological Black Hole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_birth_of_a_relativistic_jet_following_the_disruption_of_a_star_by_a_cosmological_black_hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_birth_of_a_relativistic_jet_following_the_disruption_of_a_star_by_a_cosmological_black_hole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dheeraj R. Pasham
A black hole can launch a powerful relativistic jet after it tidally disrupts a star. If this jet fortuitously aligns with our line of sight, the overall brightness is Doppler boosted by several orders of magnitude. Consequently, such on-axis relativistic tidal disruption events (TDEs) have the potential to unveil cosmological (redshift $z&amp;gt;$1) quiescent black holes and are ideal test beds to understand the radiative mechanisms operating in super-Eddington jets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Energy Survey Year 3 high redshift sample: Selection, characterization and analysis of galaxy clustering</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_energy_survey_year_3_high_redshift_sample_selection_characterization_and_analysis_of_galaxy_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_energy_survey_year_3_high_redshift_sample_selection_characterization_and_analysis_of_galaxy_clustering/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Sánchez
The fiducial cosmological analyses of imaging galaxy surveys like the Dark Energy Survey (DES) typically probe the Universe at redshifts $z &amp;lt; 1$. This is mainly because of the limited depth of these surveys, and also because such analyses rely heavily on galaxy lensing, which is more efficient at low redshifts. In this work we present the selection and characterization of high-redshift galaxy samples using DES Year 3 data, and the analysis of their galaxy clustering measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The volumetric star formation law in nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
Star formation laws are empirical relations between the cold gas (HI+H$_2$) content of a galaxy and its star formation rate (SFR), being crucial for any model of galaxy formation and evolution. A well known example of such laws is the Schmidt-Kennicutt law, which is based on the projected surface densities. However, it has been long unclear whether a more fundamental relation exists between the intrinsic volume densities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward Accurate Modeling of Galaxy Clustering on Small Scales: Halo Model Extensions &amp; Lingering Tension</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toward_accurate_modeling_of_galaxy_clustering_on_small_scales_halo_model_extensions__lingering_tension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toward_accurate_modeling_of_galaxy_clustering_on_small_scales_halo_model_extensions__lingering_tension/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gillian D. Beltz-Mohrmann
This paper represents an effort to provide robust constraints on cosmology and the galaxy-halo connection using a fully numerical model of small-scale galaxy clustering. We explore two extensions to the standard Halo Occupation Distribution model: assembly bias, whereby halo occupation depends on both halo mass and the larger environment, and velocity bias, whereby galaxy velocities do not perfectly trace the velocity of the dark matter within the halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERTICO III: The Kennicutt-Schmidt relation in Virgo cluster galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_iii_the_kennicutt-schmidt_relation_in_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_iii_the_kennicutt-schmidt_relation_in_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. J. Jiménez-Donaire
In this VERTICO science paper we aim to study how the star formation process depends on galactic environment and gravitational interactions in the context of galaxy evolution. We explore the scaling relation between the star formation rate (SFR) surface density and the molecular gas surface density, also known as the Kennicutt-Schmidt (KS) relation, in a subsample of Virgo cluster spiral galaxies. We use new ACA and TP observations from the VERTICO-ALMA Large Program at 720pc resolution to resolve the molecular gas content, as traced by the 12CO(2-1) transition, across the disks of 37 spiral galaxies in the Virgo cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Optical, Ultraviolet and Soft X-ray excess Emissions in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Nour
Soft X-ray emission (0.5&amp;ndash;2.0 keV) plays a pivotal role in regulating the optical and UV emission in the AGNs. We collected a sample of 1811 AGNs from the SDSS database and obtained various parameters of Balmer lines, optical continuum, MgII line &amp;amp; UV continuum and studied their dependencies on soft X-ray luminosity. Based on the linear regression analysis, we found that FWHM${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ FWHM${\text{H}\beta}^{0.554}$ suggesting that UV emission is arising from a region relatively outside the broad line region (BLR) associated to the H$\beta$ emission and found a strong correlation between optical and UV luminosities (L${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ L${\text{H}\beta}^{0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical abundances in the dwarf galaxy NGC 4163 based on the nebular and auroral emission lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_abundances_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4163_based_on_the_nebular_and_auroral_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_abundances_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4163_based_on_the_nebular_and_auroral_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. A. Zinchenko
We constructed an oxygen abundance map and N/O ratio map of the unusually low excitation dwarf irregular galaxy NGC 4163 based on publicly available spectroscopy obtained by the MaNGA survey. We detected auroral emission line [OII]$\lambda\lambda$7320,7330 which allows us to measure chemical abundance by direct T$_e$ method. We found that the scatter of the oxygen abundance derived by the strong line method is large. The oxygen abundances 12 + log(O/H) derived by strong line method vary from ~7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-noising non-Gaussian fields in cosmology with normalizing flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/de-noising_non-gaussian_fields_in_cosmology_with_normalizing_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/de-noising_non-gaussian_fields_in_cosmology_with_normalizing_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Rouhiainen
Fields in cosmology, such as the matter distribution, are observed by experiments up to experimental noise. The first step in cosmological data analysis is usually to de-noise the observed field using an analytic or simulation driven prior. On large enough scales, such fields are Gaussian, and the de-noising step is known as Wiener filtering. However, on smaller scales probed by upcoming experiments, a Gaussian prior is substantially sub-optimal because the true field distribution is very non-Gaussian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of star clusters and enrichment by massive stars in simulations of low-metallicity galaxies with a fully sampled initial stellar mass function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_star_clusters_and_enrichment_by_massive_stars_in_simulations_of_low-metallicity_galaxies_with_a_fully_sampled_initial_stellar_mass_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_star_clusters_and_enrichment_by_massive_stars_in_simulations_of_low-metallicity_galaxies_with_a_fully_sampled_initial_stellar_mass_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalia Lahén
We present new GRIFFIN project hydrodynamical simulations that model the formation of galactic star cluster populations in low-metallicity ($Z=0.00021$) dwarf galaxies, including radiation, supernova and stellar wind feedback of individual massive stars. In the simulations, stars are sampled from the stellar initial mass function (IMF) down to the hydrogen burning limit of 0.08 M$_\odot$. Mass conservation is enforced within a radius of 1 pc for the formation massive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard X-ray Observations of the Hydrogen-poor Superluminous Supernova SN 2018hti with NuSTAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Igor Andreoni
Some Hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae are likely powered by a magnetar central engine, making their luminosity larger than common supernovae. Although a significant amount of X-ray flux is expected from the spin down of the magnetar, direct observational evidence is still to be found, giving rise to the &amp;ldquo;missing energy&amp;rdquo; problem. Here we present NuSTAR observations of nearby SN 2018hti 2.4y (rest frame) after its optical peak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferencing Progenitor and Explosion Properties of Evolving Core-collapse Supernovae from Zwicky Transient Facility Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bhagya M. Subrayan
We analyze a sample of 45 Type II supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) public survey using a grid of hydrodynamical models in order to assess whether theoretically-driven forecasts can intelligently guide follow up observations supporting all-sky survey alert streams. We estimate several progenitor properties and explosion physics parameters including zero-age-main-sequence (ZAMS) mass, mass-loss rate, kinetic energy, 56Ni mass synthesized, host extinction, and the time of explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOJAVE XX. Decade-long linear polarization variability in AGN jets at parsec scales</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. I. Zobnina
We studied the variability properties of the linear polarization of active galactic nucleus (AGN) jets on parsec-scales using stacking. Our sample is drawn from the MOJAVE program and consists of 436 AGNs manifesting core-jet morphology and having at least five VLBA observing epochs at 15 GHz from January 1996 through August 2019, with some additional archival VLBA data reduced by us. We employed a stacking procedure and constructed maps of (i) standard deviation of fractional polarization and electric vector position angle (EVPA) over epochs as the measure of variability, (ii) median polarization degree to quantify typical values in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential contributions of Pop III and intermediate-mass Pop II stars to cosmic chemical enrichment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_contributions_of_pop_iii_and_intermediate-mass_pop_ii_stars_to_cosmic_chemical_enrichment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_contributions_of_pop_iii_and_intermediate-mass_pop_ii_stars_to_cosmic_chemical_enrichment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lia C. Corazza
We propose a semi-analytic model that is developed to understand the cosmological evolution of the mean metallicity in the Universe. In particular, we study the contributions of Population III (Pop III) and Population II (Pop II) stars to the production of $\mathrm{Fe,~Si,~Zn, ~Ni,~P, ~Mg, ~Al, ~S, ~C, ~N}$, and $\mathrm{~O}$. We aim to quantify the roles of two different models in the chemical enrichment of the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pristine Inner Galaxy Survey (PIGS) VI: Different vertical distributions between two DIBs at 442.8 nm and 862.1 nm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pristine_inner_galaxy_survey_pigs_vi_different_vertical_distributions_between_two_dibs_at_442.8_nm_and_862.1_nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pristine_inner_galaxy_survey_pigs_vi_different_vertical_distributions_between_two_dibs_at_442.8_nm_and_862.1_nm/</guid>
      <description>First author: He Zhao
Although diffuse interstellar bands (DIBs) were discovered over 100 years ago, for most of them, their origins are still unknown. Investigation on the correlations between different DIBs is an important way to study the behavior and distributions of their carriers. Based on stacking thousands of spectra from the Pristine Inner Galaxy Survey, we study the correlations between two DIBs at 442.8 nm ($\lambda$442.8) and 862.1 nm ($\lambda$862.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VINTERGATAN-GM: The cosmological imprints of early mergers on Milky-Way-mass galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vintergatan-gm_the_cosmological_imprints_of_early_mergers_on_milky-way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vintergatan-gm_the_cosmological_imprints_of_early_mergers_on_milky-way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martin P. Rey
We present a new suite of cosmological zoom-in hydrodynamical ($\approx 20, \mathrm{pc}$) simulations of Milky-Way mass galaxies to study how a varying mass ratio for a Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) progenitor impacts the $z=0$ chemodynamics of halo stars. Using the genetic modification approach, we create five cosmological histories for a Milky-Way-mass dark matter halo ($M_{200} \approx 10^{12} , M_\mathrm{\odot}$), incrementally increasing the stellar mass ratio of a $z\approx2$ merger from 1:25 to 1:2, while fixing the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s final dynamical, stellar mass and large-scale environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: HI gas kinematics of galaxy pairs in cluster environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_hi_gas_kinematics_of_galaxy_pairs_in_cluster_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_hi_gas_kinematics_of_galaxy_pairs_in_cluster_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shin-Jeong Kim
We examine the HI gas kinematics of galaxy pairs in two clusters and a group using Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) WALLABY pilot survey observations. We compare the HI properties of galaxy pair candidates in the Hydra I and Norma clusters, and the NGC 4636 group, with those of non-paired control galaxies selected in the same fields. We perform HI profile decomposition of the sample galaxies using a tool, {\sc baygaud} which allows us to de-blend a line-of-sight velocity profile with an optimal number of Gaussian components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray Absorption Lines in the Warm-Hot Intergalactic Medium: Probing Chandra observations with the CAMEL simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_absorption_lines_in_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_probing_chandra_observations_with_the_camel_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_absorption_lines_in_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_probing_chandra_observations_with_the_camel_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amanda Butler Contreras
Known as the &amp;ldquo;Missing Baryon Problem&amp;rdquo;, about one-third of baryons in the local universe remain unaccounted for. The missing baryons are thought to reside in the warm-hot intergalactic medium (WHIM) of the cosmic web filaments, which are challenging to detect. Recent Chandra X-ray observations from Kov&#39;acs et al. (2019) used a novel stacking analysis and detected an OVII absorption line toward the sightline of a luminous quasar, hinting that the missing baryons may reside in the WHIM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Properties of OGLE4 Mira variables in our Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_properties_of_ogle4_mira_variables_in_our_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_properties_of_ogle4_mira_variables_in_our_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyung-Won Suh
We investigate infrared properties of OGLE4 Mira variables in our Galaxy. For each object, we cross-identify the WISE, 2MASS, and IRAS counterparts. We present various IR two-color diagrams (2CDs) and period-magnitude and period-color relations for the Mira variables. Generally, the Miras variables with longer periods are brighter in the IR fluxes and redder in the IR colors. In this work, we also revise and update the previous catalog of AGB stars in our Galaxy using the new sample of OGLE4 Mira variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Fourier-Transformation Model for the Production of Hard and Soft X-Ray Time Lags in AGNs: Application to 1H 0707-495</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</guid>
      <description>First author: David C. Baughman
The variability of the X-ray emission from active galactic nuclei is often characterized using time lags observed between soft and hard energy bands in the detector. The time lags are usually computed using the complex cross spectrum, which is based on the Fourier transforms of the hard and soft time series data. It has been noted that some active galactic nuclei display soft X-ray time lags, in addition to the more ubiquitous hard lags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Herschel observations of the 2Jy sample: assessing the non-thermal and AGN contributions to the far-IR continuum</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_herschel_observations_of_the_2jy_sample_assessing_the_non-thermal_and_agn_contributions_to_the_far-ir_continuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_herschel_observations_of_the_2jy_sample_assessing_the_non-thermal_and_agn_contributions_to_the_far-ir_continuum/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Dicken
The far-IR/sub-mm wavelength range contains a wealth of diagnostic information that is important for understanding the role of radio AGN in galaxy evolution. Here we present the results of Herschel PACS and SPIRE observations of a complete sample of 46 powerful 2Jy radio AGN at intermediate redshifts (0.05 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.7), which represent the deepest pointed observations of a major sample of radio AGN undertaken by Herschel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid preparation. XXVII. Covariance model validation for the 2-point correlation function of galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxvii._covariance_model_validation_for_the_2-point_correlation_function_of_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxvii._covariance_model_validation_for_the_2-point_correlation_function_of_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Euclid Collaboration
Aims. We validate a semi-analytical model for the covariance of real-space 2-point correlation function of galaxy clusters. Methods. Using 1000 PINOCCHIO light cones mimicking the expected Euclid sample of galaxy clusters, we calibrate a simple model to accurately describe the clustering covariance. Then, we use such a model to quantify the likelihood analysis response to variations of the covariance, and investigate the impact of a cosmology-dependent matrix at the level of statistics expected for the Euclid survey of galaxy clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOREVER22: the first bright galaxies with population III stars at redshifts $z \simeq 10-20$ and comparisons with JWST data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forever22_the_first_bright_galaxies_with_population_iii_stars_at_redshifts__z__simeq_10-20__and_comparisons_with_jwst_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forever22_the_first_bright_galaxies_with_population_iii_stars_at_redshifts__z__simeq_10-20__and_comparisons_with_jwst_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hidenobu Yajima
We study the formation of the first galaxies in overdense regions modelled by the FOREVER22 simulation project. Our simulations successfully reproduce the star formation rates and the $M_{\rm UV}-M_{\rm star}$ relations of candidate galaxies at $z \sim 10-14$ observed by James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). We suggest that the observed galaxies are hosted by dark-matter haloes with $M_{\rm h} \sim 10^{11}~\rm M_{\odot}$ and are in short-period starburst phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA): Extended Intra-Group Light in a group at $z=0.2$ from deep Hyper-Suprime Cam images</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_extended_intra-group_light_in_a_group_at__z0.2__from_deep_hyper-suprime_cam_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_extended_intra-group_light_in_a_group_at__z0.2__from_deep_hyper-suprime_cam_images/</guid>
      <description>First author: Cristina Martinez-Lombilla
We present a pilot study to assess the potential of Hyper Suprime-Cam Public Data Release 2 (HSC-PDR2) images for the analysis of extended faint structures within groups of galaxies. We examine the intra-group light (IGL) of the group 400138 ($M_{\rm{dyn}}= 1.3 \pm 0.5 \times 10^{13} $M${\odot}$, $z\sim 0.2$) from the Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) survey using Hyper-Suprime Cam Subaru Strategic Program Public Data Release 2 (HSC-PDR2) images in $g$, $r$, and $i$ bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Characterizing the Most Heavily Dust-Obscured Galaxies at $1 \le z \le 4$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_and_characterizing_the_most_heavily_dust-obscured_galaxies_at__1__le_z__le_4_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_and_characterizing_the_most_heavily_dust-obscured_galaxies_at__1__le_z__le_4_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicholas S. Martis
We present 65 extremely dust-obscured galaxies from the UltraVISTA DR3 survey of the COSMOS field at $1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4$. In contrast to other studies of dusty galaxies, we select our sample based on dust attenuation measured by UV-MIR spectral energy distribution (SED) modeling that allows for extreme attenuation levels. We construct our sample by making cuts at $1 \le z \le 4$, A$V \ge 3$, and log(M$*$/M$_\odot$)$ \ge 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMaNGA: mock MaNGA galaxies based on IllustrisTNG-50 and MaStar SSPs. II. the catalogue</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imanga_mock_manga_galaxies_based_on_illustristng-50_and_mastar_ssps._ii._the_catalogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imanga_mock_manga_galaxies_based_on_illustristng-50_and_mastar_ssps._ii._the_catalogue/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lorenza Nanni
To probe the current theory on galaxy formation and evolution, an increased synergy between observations and simulations is necessary. For this reason, in our previous paper of this series, we presented a method to mock SDSS-IV/MaNGA integral-field spectroscopic galaxy observations from cosmological simulations of galaxy formation. Here we present the resulting mock galaxy catalogue. This catalogue consists of 1,000 unique galaxies in IllustrisTNG-50 falling into the SDSS-IV/MaNGA-primary target footprint, defined in the redshift and i-band absolute magnitude space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Activity in the Low Metallicity Dwarf Galaxy SDSS J0944-0038: A Glimpse into the Primordial Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_activity_in_the_low_metallicity_dwarf_galaxy_sdss_j0944-0038_a_glimpse_into_the_primordial_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_activity_in_the_low_metallicity_dwarf_galaxy_sdss_j0944-0038_a_glimpse_into_the_primordial_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael Reefe
Local low metallicity dwarf galaxies are relics of the early universe and hold clues into the origins of supermassive black holes (SMBHs). In recent work, coronal lines have been used to unveil a population of candidate accreting black holes in dwarf galaxies with gas phase metallicities and stellar masses well below the host galaxies of any previously known AGNs. Using MUSE/VLT observations, we report the detection of [Fe X] $\lambda$6374 coronal line emission and a broad H$\alpha$ line in the nucleus of SDSS J094401.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Nearly) Model-Independent Constraints on the Neutral Hydrogen Fraction in the Intergalactic Medium at $z\sim 5-7$ Using Dark Pixel Fractions in Ly$α$ and Ly$β$ Forests</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nearly_model-independent_constraints_on_the_neutral_hydrogen_fraction_in_the_intergalactic_medium_at__z_sim_5-7__using_dark_pixel_fractions_in_ly_%CE%B1__and_ly_%CE%B2__forests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nearly_model-independent_constraints_on_the_neutral_hydrogen_fraction_in_the_intergalactic_medium_at__z_sim_5-7__using_dark_pixel_fractions_in_ly_%CE%B1__and_ly_%CE%B2__forests/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiangyu Jin
Cosmic reionization was the last major phase transition of hydrogen from neutral to highly ionized in the intergalactic medium (IGM). Current observations show that the IGM is significantly neutral at $z&amp;gt;7$, and largely ionized by $z\sim5.5$. However, most methods to measure the IGM neutral fraction are highly model-dependent, and are limited to when the volume-averaged neutral fraction of the IGM is either relatively low ($\bar{x}{\rm HI} \lesssim 10^{-3}$) or close to unity ($\bar{x}{\rm HI}\sim 1$).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at supernovae as seeds for galactic magnetization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_closer_look_at_supernovae_as_seeds_for_galactic_magnetization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_closer_look_at_supernovae_as_seeds_for_galactic_magnetization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Evangelia Ntormousi
Explaining the currently observed magnetic fields in galaxies requires relatively strong seeding in the early Universe. One theory proposes that magnetic fields of the order of $\mu$G were expelled by supernova (SN) explosions after primordial, nG or weaker fields were amplified in stellar interiors. In this work, we calculate the maximum magnetic energy that can be injected in the interstellar medium by a stellar cluster of mass $M_{cl}$ based on what is currently known about stellar magnetism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on modified gravity from the BOSS galaxy survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_modified_gravity_from_the_boss_galaxy_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_modified_gravity_from_the_boss_galaxy_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lorenzo Piga
We develop a pipeline to set new constraints on scale-independent modified gravity, from the galaxy power spectrum in redshift space of BOSS DR12. The latter is modelled using the effective field theory of large-scale structure up to 1-loop order in perturbation theory. We test our pipeline on synthetic and simulated data, to assess systematic biases on the inferred cosmological parameters due to marginalization and theoretical errors, and we apply it to the normal branch of the DGP model with a $\Lambda$CDM background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology from Galaxy Redshift Surveys with PointNet</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_from_galaxy_redshift_surveys_with_pointnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_from_galaxy_redshift_surveys_with_pointnet/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sotiris Anagnostidis
In recent years, deep learning approaches have achieved state-of-the-art results in the analysis of point cloud data. In cosmology, galaxy redshift surveys resemble such a permutation invariant collection of positions in space. These surveys have so far mostly been analysed with two-point statistics, such as power spectra and correlation functions. The usage of these summary statistics is best justified on large scales, where the density field is linear and Gaussian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in chemical evolution between isolated and embedded prestellar cores</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/differences_in_chemical_evolution_between_isolated_and_embedded_prestellar_cores/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/differences_in_chemical_evolution_between_isolated_and_embedded_prestellar_cores/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. D. Priestley
Models of prestellar cores often assume that the cores are isolated from their environment - material outside the core boundary plays no role in the subsequent evolution. This is unlikely to be the case in reality, where cores are located within hierarchically substructured molecular clouds. We investigate the dynamical and chemical evolution of prestellar cores, modelled as Bonnor-Ebert spheres, and show that the density of the ambient medium has a large impact on the resulting chemical properties of the cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust-free starburst galaxies at redshifts $z&gt;10$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust-free_starburst_galaxies_at_redshifts__z10_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust-free_starburst_galaxies_at_redshifts__z10_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Biman B. Nath
One of the most distant galaxies GN-z11 was formed when the Universe was $\le$ 400 Myr old, and it displays a burst-like star formation rate $\sim 25~\msun$ yr$^{-1}$ with a metallicity $Z\sim 0.2\pm 0.1Z_\odot$. It resembles $z=2-3$ galaxies (at ``cosmic noon&amp;quot;) except for the fact that the measured reddening $E(B-V)=0.01\pm 0.01$ indicates the presence of little or no dust. This marked absence of dust hints towards violent dynamical events that destroy or evacuate dust along with gas out of the galaxy on a relatively short time scale and make it transparent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAVN Astrometry toward the Extreme Outer Galaxy: Kinematic distance with the proper motion of G034.84-00.95</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eavn_astrometry_toward_the_extreme_outer_galaxy_kinematic_distance_with_the_proper_motion_of_g034.84-00.95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eavn_astrometry_toward_the_extreme_outer_galaxy_kinematic_distance_with_the_proper_motion_of_g034.84-00.95/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nobuyuki Sakai
We aim to reveal the structure and kinematics of the Outer-Scutum-Centaurus (OSC) arm located on the far side of the Milky Way through very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) astrometry using KaVA, which is composed of KVN (Korean VLBI Network) and VERA (VLBI Exploration of Radio Astrometry). We report the proper motion of a 22 GHz H${2}$O maser source, which is associated with the star-forming region G034.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid: Modelling massive neutrinos in cosmology -- a code comparison</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_modelling_massive_neutrinos_in_cosmology_--_a_code_comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_modelling_massive_neutrinos_in_cosmology_--_a_code_comparison/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Adamek
The measurement of the absolute neutrino mass scale from cosmological large-scale clustering data is one of the key science goals of the Euclid mission. Such a measurement relies on precise modelling of the impact of neutrinos on structure formation, which can be studied with $N$-body simulations. Here we present the results from a major code comparison effort to establish the maturity and reliability of numerical methods for treating massive neutrinos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrostatic Mass Profiles of Galaxy Clusters in the eROSITA Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrostatic_mass_profiles_of_galaxy_clusters_in_the_erosita_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrostatic_mass_profiles_of_galaxy_clusters_in_the_erosita_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominik Scheck
To assume hydrostatic equilibrium between the intracluster medium and the gravitational potential of galaxy clusters is an extensively used method to investigate their total masses. We want to test hydrostatic masses obtained with an observational code in the context of the SRG/eROSITA survey. We use the hydrostatic modeling code MBProj2 to fit surface-brightness profiles to simulated clusters with idealized properties as well as to a sample of 93 clusters taken from the Magneticum Pathfinder simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASCOT: Molecular gas depletion times and metallicity gradients -- evidence for feedback in quenching active galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mascot_molecular_gas_depletion_times_and_metallicity_gradients_--_evidence_for_feedback_in_quenching_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mascot_molecular_gas_depletion_times_and_metallicity_gradients_--_evidence_for_feedback_in_quenching_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bertemes
We present results from the first public data release of the MaNGA-ARO Survey of CO Targets (MASCOT), focussing our study on galaxies whose star-formation rates and stellar masses place them below the ridge of the star-forming Main Sequence. In optically-selected type 2 AGN/LINERs/Composites, we find an empirical relation between gas-phase metallicity gradients $\nabla Z$ and global molecular gas depletion times $t_\mathrm{dep} = M_{H_2}$/SFR with &amp;ldquo;more quenched&amp;rdquo; systems showing flatter/positive gradients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesh-free hydrodynamics in PKDGRAV3 for galaxy formation simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mesh-free_hydrodynamics_in_pkdgrav3_for_galaxy_formation_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mesh-free_hydrodynamics_in_pkdgrav3_for_galaxy_formation_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Isaac Alonso Asensio
We extend the state-of-the-art N-body code PKDGRAV3 with the inclusion of mesh-free gas hydrodynamics for cosmological simulations. Two new hydrodynamic solvers have been implemented, the mesh-less finite volume and mesh-less finite mass methods. The solvers manifestly conserve mass, momentum and energy, and have been validated with a wide range of standard test simulations, including cosmological simulations. We also describe improvements to PKDGRAV3 that have been implemented for performing hydrodynamic simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The production of ionizing photons in UV-faint z~3-7 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_production_of_ionizing_photons_in_uv-faint_z~3-7_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_production_of_ionizing_photons_in_uv-faint_z~3-7_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gonzalo Prieto-Lyon
The demographics of the production and escape of ionizing photons from UV-faint early galaxies is a key unknown in discovering the primary drivers of reionization. With the advent of JWST it is finally possible to observe the rest-frame optical nebular emission from individual sub-L$^*$ z&amp;gt;3 galaxies to measure the production of ionizing photons, $\xi_\mathrm{ion}$. Here we study a sample of 380 z~3-7 galaxies spanning -23 &amp;lt;M$\mathrm{UV}$ &amp;lt; -15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spatially resolved view of star formation in galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spatially_resolved_view_of_star_formation_in_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spatially_resolved_view_of_star_formation_in_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bianca M. Poggianti
Integral field spectroscopic studies of galaxies in dense environments, such as clusters and groups of galaxies, have provided new insights for understanding how star formation proceeds, and quenches. I present the spatially resolved view of the star formation activity and its link with the multiphase gas in cluster galaxies based on MUSE and multi-wavelength data of the GASP survey. I discuss the link among the different scales (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Witnessing a Galaxy Cluster Merger with JWST and a Chandra X-ray Temperature Map</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/witnessing_a_galaxy_cluster_merger_with_jwst_and_a_chandra_x-ray_temperature_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/witnessing_a_galaxy_cluster_merger_with_jwst_and_a_chandra_x-ray_temperature_map/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brian C. Alden
The first James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) image released was of galaxy cluster SMACSJ0723.3- 7327, a lensing cluster at z=0.39 showing detail only JWST can provide. While the majority of the focus has been on the brilliantly lensed galaxies at redshifts far beyond it, there is more to the story than it being just a lensing cluster. The Chandra X-ray temperature map tells a tale of a merging cluster with a significant subcluster leaving a wake in the intracluster medium (ICM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistent and simultaneous modelling of galaxy clustering and galaxy-galaxy lensing with Subhalo Abundance Matching</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/consistent_and_simultaneous_modelling_of_galaxy_clustering_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_with_subhalo_abundance_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/consistent_and_simultaneous_modelling_of_galaxy_clustering_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_with_subhalo_abundance_matching/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergio Contreras
The spatial distribution of galaxies and their gravitational lensing signal offer complementary tests of galaxy formation physics and cosmology. However, their synergy can only be fully exploited if both probes are modelled accurately and consistently. In this paper, we demonstrate that this can be achieved using an extension of Subhalo Abundance Matching, dubbed SHAMe. Specifically, we use mock catalogues built from the TNG300 hydrodynamical simulation to show that SHAMe can simultaneously model the multipoles of the redshift-space galaxy correlation function and galaxy-galaxy lensing, without noticeable bias within the statistical sampling uncertainties of a SDSS volume and on scales r = [0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity of dust properties in external galaxies confirmed by polarization signals from Type II supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/diversity_of_dust_properties_in_external_galaxies_confirmed_by_polarization_signals_from_type_ii_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/diversity_of_dust_properties_in_external_galaxies_confirmed_by_polarization_signals_from_type_ii_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takashi Nagao
Investigating interstellar (IS) dust properties in external galaxies is important not only to infer the intrinsic properties of astronomical objects but also to understand the star/planet formation in the galaxies. From the non-Milky-Way-like extinction and interstellar polarization (ISP) observed in reddened Type~Ia supernovae (SNe), it has been suggested that their host galaxies contain dust grains whose properties are substantially different from the Milky-Way (MW) dust. It is important to investigate the universality of such non-MW-like dust in the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GalaxyFlow: Upsampling Hydrodynamical Simulations for Realistic Gaia Mock Catalogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxyflow_upsampling_hydrodynamical_simulations_for_realistic_gaia_mock_catalogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxyflow_upsampling_hydrodynamical_simulations_for_realistic_gaia_mock_catalogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sung Hak Lim
Cosmological N-body simulations of galaxies operate at the level of &amp;ldquo;star particles&amp;rdquo; with a mass resolution on the scale of thousands of solar masses. Turning these simulations into stellar mock catalogs requires &amp;ldquo;upsampling&amp;rdquo; the star particles into individual stars following the same phase-space density. In this paper, we demonstrate that normalizing flows provide a viable upsampling method that greatly improves on conventionally-used kernel smoothing algorithms such as EnBiD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MaNGIA: 10,000 mock galaxies for stellar population analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mangia_10000_mock_galaxies_for_stellar_population_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mangia_10000_mock_galaxies_for_stellar_population_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Regina Sarmiento
Modern astronomical observations give unprecedented access to the physical properties of nearby galaxies, including spatially resolved stellar populations. However, observations can only give a present-day view of the Universe, whereas cosmological simulations give access to the past record of the processes that galaxies have experienced in their evolution. To connect the events that happened in the past with galactic properties as seen today, simulations must be taken to a common ground before being compared to observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the accretion and feedback of supermassive black hole binaries in gas-rich galaxy mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_the_accretion_and_feedback_of_supermassive_black_hole_binaries_in_gas-rich_galaxy_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_the_accretion_and_feedback_of_supermassive_black_hole_binaries_in_gas-rich_galaxy_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shihong Liao
We introduce a new model for the accretion and feedback of supermassive black hole (SMBH) binaries to the KETJU code, which enables us to resolve the evolution of SMBH binaries down to separations of tens of Schwarzschild radii in gas-rich galaxy mergers. Our subgrid binary accretion model extends the widely used Bondi&amp;ndash;Hoyle&amp;ndash;Lyttleton accretion into the binary phase and incorporates preferential mass accretion onto the secondary SMBH, which is motivated by results from small-scale hydrodynamical circumbinary disc simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peering into the Milky Way by FAST: IV. Identification of two new Galactic supernova remnants G203.1&#43;6.6 and G206.7&#43;5.9</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peering_into_the_milky_way_by_fast_iv._identification_of_two_new_galactic_supernova_remnants_g203.1&#43;6.6_and_g206.7&#43;5.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peering_into_the_milky_way_by_fast_iv._identification_of_two_new_galactic_supernova_remnants_g203.1&#43;6.6_and_g206.7&#43;5.9/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xuyang Gao
A $5^{\circ} \times 7^{\circ}$ sky area containing two large radio structures of G203.1+6.6 and G206.7+5.9 with a size of about 2.5$^{\circ}$ and 3.5$^{\circ}$ respectively is scanned by using the L-band 19-beam receiver of the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope (FAST). The FAST L-band receiver covers a frequency range of 1.0 GHz $-$ 1.5 GHz. Commissioning of the receiving system, including the measurements of the half-power beam width, gain, and main-beam efficiency is made by observing the calibrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting sub-millimeter flux densities from global galaxy properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/predicting_sub-millimeter_flux_densities_from_global_galaxy_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/predicting_sub-millimeter_flux_densities_from_global_galaxy_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. K. Cochrane
Recent years have seen growing interest in post-processing cosmological simulations with radiative transfer codes to predict observable fluxes for simulated galaxies. However, this can be slow, and requires a number of assumptions in cases where simulations do not resolve the ISM. Zoom-in simulations better resolve the detailed structure of the ISM and the geometry of stars and gas, however statistics are limited due to the computational cost of simulating even a single halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing and Classifying SDSS DR16 Galaxy Spectra with Machine-Learning and Dimensionality Reduction Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_and_classifying_sdss_dr16_galaxy_spectra_with_machine-learning_and_dimensionality_reduction_algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_and_classifying_sdss_dr16_galaxy_spectra_with_machine-learning_and_dimensionality_reduction_algorithms/</guid>
      <description>First author: Felix Pat
Optical spectra of galaxies and quasars from large cosmological surveys are used to measure redshifts and infer distances. They are also rich with information on the intrinsic properties of these astronomical objects. However, their physical interpretation can be challenging due to the substantial number of degrees of freedom, various sources of noise, and degeneracies between physical parameters that cause similar spectral characteristics. To gain deeper insights into these degeneracies, we apply two unsupervised machine learning frameworks to a sample from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey data release 16 (SDSS DR16).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dark side of galaxy stellar populations II: The dependence of star formation histories on halo mass and on the scatter of the main sequence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_side_of_galaxy_stellar_populations_ii_the_dependence_of_star_formation_histories_on_halo_mass_and_on_the_scatter_of_the_main_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_side_of_galaxy_stellar_populations_ii_the_dependence_of_star_formation_histories_on_halo_mass_and_on_the_scatter_of_the_main_sequence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Scholz-Diaz
Nearby galaxies are the end result of their cosmological evolution, which is predicted to be influenced by the growth of their host dark matter halos. This co-evolution potentially leaves signatures in present-day observed galaxy properties, which might be essential to further understand how the growth and properties of galaxies are connected to those of their host halos. In this work, we study the evolutionary histories of nearby galaxies both in terms of their host halos and the scatter of the star-forming main sequence by investigating their time-resolved stellar populations using absorption optical spectra drawn from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magneto hydrodynamic simulations of the supernova remnant G1.9&#43;0.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magneto_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_the_supernova_remnant_g1.9&#43;0.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magneto_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_the_supernova_remnant_g1.9&#43;0.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shaobo Zhang
The youngest Galactic supernova remnant G1.9+0.3 shows a discrete feature between its radio and X-ray morphologies. The observed radio morphology features a single maximum in the north, while the X-ray observation shows two opposite &amp;rsquo;ears&amp;rsquo; on the east and west sides. Using 3D magneto hydrodynamical simulations, we investigate the formation of the discrete feature of the remnant. We have tested different parameters for better simulation and reproduced similar discrete features under an environment with density gradient and an environment with clump, which provides a possible explanation of the observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A unified model for the co-evolution of galaxies and their circumgalactic medium: the relative roles of turbulence and atomic cooling physics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unified_model_for_the_co-evolution_of_galaxies_and_their_circumgalactic_medium_the_relative_roles_of_turbulence_and_atomic_cooling_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unified_model_for_the_co-evolution_of_galaxies_and_their_circumgalactic_medium_the_relative_roles_of_turbulence_and_atomic_cooling_physics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Viraj Pandya
The circumgalactic medium (CGM) plays a pivotal role in regulating gas flows around galaxies and thus shapes their evolution. However, the details of how galaxies and their CGM co-evolve remain poorly understood. We present a new time-dependent two-zone model that self-consistently tracks not just mass and metal flows between galaxies and their CGM but also the evolution of the global thermal and turbulent kinetic energy of the CGM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-based galaxy image deconvolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_learning-based_galaxy_image_deconvolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_learning-based_galaxy_image_deconvolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Utsav Akhaury
With the onset of large-scale astronomical surveys capturing millions of images, there is an increasing need to develop fast and accurate deconvolution algorithms that generalize well to different images. A powerful and accessible deconvolution method would allow for the reconstruction of a cleaner estimation of the sky. The deconvolved images would be helpful to perform photometric measurements to help make progress in the fields of galaxy formation and evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Space Telescope Observations of Tadpole Galaxies Kiso 3867, SBS0, SBS1, and UM461</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_space_telescope_observations_of_tadpole_galaxies_kiso_3867_sbs0_sbs1_and_um461/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_space_telescope_observations_of_tadpole_galaxies_kiso_3867_sbs0_sbs1_and_um461/</guid>
      <description>First author: Debra Meloy Elmegreen
Tadpole galaxies are metal-poor dwarfs with typically one dominant star-forming region, giving them a head-tail structure when inclined. A metallicity drop in the head suggests that gas accretion with even lower metallicity stimulated the star formation. Here we present multiband HST WFC3 and ACS images of four nearby (&amp;lt;25 Mpc) tadpoles, SBS0, SBS1, Kiso 3867, and UM461, selected for their clear metallicity drops shown in previous spectroscopic studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Alignments Between Galaxies and the Cosmic Web at $z\sim 1-2$ in the IllustrisTNG Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intrinsic_alignments_between_galaxies_and_the_cosmic_web_at__z_sim_1-2__in_the_illustristng_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intrinsic_alignments_between_galaxies_and_the_cosmic_web_at__z_sim_1-2__in_the_illustristng_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin Zhang
Galaxy formation theories predict that galaxy shapes and angular momenta have intrinsic alignments (IA) with the cosmic web, which provides an observational test of various theories, and is important to quantify as a nuisance parameter for weak lensing. We study galaxy IA in the IllustrisTNG suite of hydrodynamical simulations at redshifts 1 and 2, finding that alignment trends are consistent with previous studies. However, we find that the magnitude of the spin alignment signal is $\sim 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mock Galaxy Surveys for HST and JWST from the IllustrisTNG Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mock_galaxy_surveys_for_hst_and_jwst_from_the_illustristng_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mock_galaxy_surveys_for_hst_and_jwst_from_the_illustristng_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gregory F. Snyder
We present and analyze a series of synthetic galaxy survey fields based on the IllustrisTNG Simulation suite. With the Illustris public data release and JupyterLab service, we generated a set of twelve lightcone catalogs covering areas from 5 to 365 square arcminutes, similar to several JWST Cycle 1 programs, including JADES, CEERS, PRIMER, and NGDEEP. From these catalogs, we queried the public API to generate simple mock images in a series of broadband filters used by JWST-NIRCam and the Hubble Space Telescope cameras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric redshift estimation of galaxies in the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_redshift_estimation_of_galaxies_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_redshift_estimation_of_galaxies_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Changhua Li
The accurate estimation of photometric redshifts plays a crucial role in accomplishing science objectives of the large survey projects. The template-fitting and machine learning are the two main types of methods applied currently. Based on the training set obtained by cross-correlating the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys DR9 galaxy catalogue and SDSS DR16 galaxy catalogue, the two kinds of methods are used and optimized, such as EAZY for template-fitting approach and CATBOOST for machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of star-forming rings in S0 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_star-forming_rings_in_s0_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_star-forming_rings_in_s0_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. L. Tous
Spatially resolved IFS maps in a sample of $532$ S0 galaxies from the MaNGA survey have unveiled the existence of inner rings ($\langle R\rangle\sim 1,R_\mathrm{e}$) betraying ongoing star formation in a number of these objects. Activity gradients averaged over bins of galactocentric radius up to $\sim 1.5,R_\mathrm{e}$ have been measured in the subspace defined by the first two principal components of the optical spectra of these galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing ICM cooling and AGN feedback from the macro to the meso scales in the galaxy cluster ZwCl 235</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chasing_icm_cooling_and_agn_feedback_from_the_macro_to_the_meso_scales_in_the_galaxy_cluster_zwcl_235/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chasing_icm_cooling_and_agn_feedback_from_the_macro_to_the_meso_scales_in_the_galaxy_cluster_zwcl_235/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Ubertosi
We aim to investigate the AGN/ICM interplay in ZwCl 235, a galaxy cluster with high X-ray flux, an extended central radio galaxy, and evidence of multi-phase gas at its center. Using archival data from the Chandra telescope, the VLASS survey, the LOTSS survey and the VLBA telescope, we perform a complete study of ZwCl 235, dissecting the dynamics of the ICM, the thermodynamic state of the central gas, and the properties of the BCG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining quenching timescales in galaxy clusters by forward-modelling stellar ages and quiescent fractions in projected phase space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_quenching_timescales_in_galaxy_clusters_by_forward-modelling_stellar_ages_and_quiescent_fractions_in_projected_phase_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_quenching_timescales_in_galaxy_clusters_by_forward-modelling_stellar_ages_and_quiescent_fractions_in_projected_phase_space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew M. M. Reeves
We forward-model mass-weighted ages (MWAs) and quiescent fractions in projected phase space (PPS), using data from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, to jointly constrain an infall quenching model for galaxies in $\log(M_{\mathrm{vir}}/\mathrm{M}{\odot})&amp;gt;14$ galaxy clusters at $z\sim 0$. We find the average deviation in MWA from the MWA-$M\star$ relation depends on position in PPS, with a maximum difference between the inner cluster and infalling interloper galaxies of $\sim 1$ Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Synoptic Array science I: discovery of the host galaxy of FRB 20220912A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_i_discovery_of_the_host_galaxy_of_frb_20220912a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_i_discovery_of_the_host_galaxy_of_frb_20220912a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vikram Ravi
We report the detection and interferometric localization of the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20220912A during commissioning observations with the Deep Synoptic Array (DSA-110). Two bursts were detected from FRB 20220912A, one each on 2022 October 18 and 2022 October 25. The best-fit position is (R.A. J2000, decl. J2000) = (23:09:04.9, +48:42:25.4), with a 90% confidence error ellipse of $\pm2$ arcsec and $\pm1$ arcsec in right ascension and declination respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIGS: Deep Inference of Galaxy Spectra with Neural Posterior Estimation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/digs_deep_inference_of_galaxy_spectra_with_neural_posterior_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/digs_deep_inference_of_galaxy_spectra_with_neural_posterior_estimation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gourav Khullar
With the advent of billion-galaxy surveys with complex data, the need of the hour is to efficiently model galaxy spectral energy distributions (SEDs) with robust uncertainty quantification. The combination of Simulation-Based inference (SBI) and amortized Neural Posterior Estimation (NPE) has been successfully used to analyse simulated and real galaxy photometry both precisely and efficiently. In this work, we utilise this combination and build on existing literature to analyse simulated noisy galaxy spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dusty winds clear JWST super-early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dusty_winds_clear_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dusty_winds_clear_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrizio Fiore
The JWST discovery of a number of super-early (redshift $z&amp;gt;10$), blue galaxies requires these systems to be essentially dust-free in spite of their large stellar masses. A possible explanation is that dust is evacuated by radiatively-driven outflows. We test this hypothesis by deriving the Eddington ratio, $\lambda_E$, for 134 galaxies at $6.5&amp;lt; z &amp;lt;16$. We find a strong anti-correlation between $\lambda_E$ and dust UV optical depth, $\tau_{1500} \propto \lambda_E^{-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid: performance on main cosmological parameter science</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_performance_on_main_cosmological_parameter_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_performance_on_main_cosmological_parameter_science/</guid>
      <description>First author: Isaac Tutusaus
Euclid will observe 15 000 deg$^2$ of the darkest sky, in regions free of contamination by light from our Galaxy and our Solar System. Three &amp;ldquo;Euclid Deep Fields&amp;rdquo; surveys covering around 40 deg$^2$ in total will extend the scientific scope of the mission to the high-redshift Universe. The complete survey will be constituted by hundreds of thousands of images and several tens of petabytes of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Galactic Chemical Evolution to Cosmic Supernova Rates Synchronized with Core-Collapse Supernovae Limited to the Narrow Progenitor Mass Range</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_galactic_chemical_evolution_to_cosmic_supernova_rates_synchronized_with_core-collapse_supernovae_limited_to_the_narrow_progenitor_mass_range/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_galactic_chemical_evolution_to_cosmic_supernova_rates_synchronized_with_core-collapse_supernovae_limited_to_the_narrow_progenitor_mass_range/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takuji Tsujimoto
Massive ($\geq$8 $M_\odot$) stars perish via one of two fates: core-collapse supernovae (CCSNe), which release synthesized heavy elements, or failed supernovae, thereby forming black holes. In the conventional Galactic chemical evolution (GCE) scheme, a substantial portion of massive stars, e.g., all stars in the mass range of 8-100 $M_{\odot},$ are assumed to enrich the Galaxy with their nucleosynthetic products. However, this hypothesis conflicts with the observations, namely, few CCSNe whose progenitor stars are more massive than $\sim$18 $M_{\odot}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution spectroscopic analysis of four new chemically peculiar stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectroscopic_analysis_of_four_new_chemically_peculiar_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectroscopic_analysis_of_four_new_chemically_peculiar_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. P. Roriz
We present detailed chemical compositions of four stars on the first-ascent red giant branch that are classified as chemically peculiar, but lack comprehensive analyses at high spectral resolution. For BD+03{\deg}2688, HE 0457-1805, HE 1255-2324, and HE 2207-1746, we derived metallicities [Fe/H] $=-1.21$, $-0.19$, $-0.31$, and $-0.55$, respectively, indicating a range in Galactic population membership. In addition to atmospheric parameters, we extracted elemental abundances for 28 elements, including the evolutionary-sensitive CNO group and $^{12}$C/$^{13}$C ratios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Low-mass End of the Black Hole Mass Function via a Study of Faint Local Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_the_black_hole_mass_function_via_a_study_of_faint_local_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_the_black_hole_mass_function_via_a_study_of_faint_local_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael S. Fusco
We present an analysis of the pitch angle distribution function (PADF) for nearby galaxies and its resulting black hole mass function (BHMF) via the well-known relationship between pitch angle and black hole mass. Our sample consists of a subset of 74 spiral galaxies from the Carnegie-Irvine Galaxy Survey with absolute $B$-band magnitude $\mathfrak{M}{B}&amp;gt;-19.12$ mag and luminosity distance $D{\mathrm{L}} \leq 25.4$ Mpc, which is an extension of a complementary set of 140 more luminous ($\mathfrak{M}{B}\leq-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Galaxy Cluster Convergence from Lensed CMB with Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recovering_galaxy_cluster_convergence_from_lensed_cmb_with_generative_adversarial_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recovering_galaxy_cluster_convergence_from_lensed_cmb_with_generative_adversarial_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liam Parker
We present a new method which leverages conditional Generative Adversarial Networks (cGAN) to reconstruct galaxy cluster convergence from lensed CMB temperature maps. Our model is constructed to emphasize structure and high-frequency correctness relative to the Residual U-Net approach presented by Caldeira, et. al. (2019). Ultimately, we demonstrate that while both models perform similarly in the no-noise regime (as well as after random off-centering of the cluster center), cGAN outperforms ResUNet when processing CMB maps noised with 5uK/arcmin white noise or astrophysical foregrounds (tSZ and kSZ); this out-performance is especially pronounced at high l, which is exactly the regime in which the ResUNet under-performs traditional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shattering and growth of cold clouds in galaxy clusters: the role of radiative cooling, magnetic fields and thermal conduction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/shattering_and_growth_of_cold_clouds_in_galaxy_clusters_the_role_of_radiative_cooling_magnetic_fields_and_thermal_conduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/shattering_and_growth_of_cold_clouds_in_galaxy_clusters_the_role_of_radiative_cooling_magnetic_fields_and_thermal_conduction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fred Jennings
In galaxy clusters, the hot intracluster medium (ICM) can develop a striking multi-phase structure around the brightest cluster galaxy. Much work has been done on understanding the origin of this central nebula, but less work has studied its eventual fate after the originally filamentary structure is broken into individual cold clumps. In this paper we perform a suite of 30 (magneto-)hydrodynamical simulations of kpc-scale cold clouds with typical parameters as found by galaxy cluster simulations, to understand whether clouds are mixed back into the hot ICM or can persist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pandora project. I: the impact of radiation and cosmic rays on baryonic and dark matter properties of dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pandora_project._i_the_impact_of_radiation_and_cosmic_rays_on_baryonic_and_dark_matter_properties_of_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pandora_project._i_the_impact_of_radiation_and_cosmic_rays_on_baryonic_and_dark_matter_properties_of_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergio Martin-Alvarez
Enshrouded in several well-known controversies, dwarf galaxies have been extensively studied to learn about the underlying cosmology, notwithstanding that physical processes regulating their properties are poorly understood. To shed light on these processes, we introduce the Pandora suite of 17 high-resolution (3.5 parsec half-cell side) dwarf galaxy formation cosmological simulations. Commencing with thermo-turbulent star formation and mechanical supernova feedback, we gradually increase the complexity of physics incorporated leading to full-physics models combining magnetism, on-the-fly radiative transfer and the corresponding stellar photoheating, and SN-accelerated cosmic rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A ~600 pc view of the strongly-lensed, massive main sequence galaxy J0901: a baryon-dominated, thick turbulent rotating disk with a clumpy cold gas ring at z = 2.259</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_~600_pc_view_of_the_strongly-lensed_massive_main_sequence_galaxy_j0901_a_baryon-dominated_thick_turbulent_rotating_disk_with_a_clumpy_cold_gas_ring_at_z__2.259/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_~600_pc_view_of_the_strongly-lensed_massive_main_sequence_galaxy_j0901_a_baryon-dominated_thick_turbulent_rotating_disk_with_a_clumpy_cold_gas_ring_at_z__2.259/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daizhong Liu
We present a high-resolution kinematic study of the massive main-sequence star-forming galaxy (SFG) SDSS J090122.37+181432.3 (J0901) at z=2.259, using 0.36 arcsec ALMA CO(3-2) and 0.1-0.5 arcsec SINFONI/VLT H-alpha observations. J0901 is a rare, strongly-lensed but otherwise normal massive (log(M_star/M_sun)~11) main sequence SFG, offering a unique opportunity to study a typical massive SFG under the microscope of lensing. Through forward dynamical modeling incorporating lensing deflection, we fit the CO and H-alpha kinematics in the image plane out to about one disk effective radius (R_e ~ 4 kpc) at a ~600pc delensed physical resolution along the kinematic major axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tilt Instability in the Cosmological Principle</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_tilt_instability_in_the_cosmological_principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_tilt_instability_in_the_cosmological_principle/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chethan Krishnan
We show that the Friedmann-Lema^{i}tre-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) framework has an instability towards the growth of fluid flow anisotropies, even if the Universe is accelerating. This flow (tilt) instability in the matter sector is invisible to Cosmic No-Hair Theorem-like arguments, which typically only flag shear anisotropies in the metric. We illustrate our claims in the setting of ``dipole cosmology&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;, the maximally Copernican generalization of FLRW that can accommodate a flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoencoding Galaxy Spectra I: Architecture</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/autoencoding_galaxy_spectra_i_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/autoencoding_galaxy_spectra_i_architecture/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Melchior
We introduce the neural network architecture SPENDER as a core differentiable building block for analyzing, representing, and creating galaxy spectra. It combines a convolutional encoder, which pays attention to up to 256 spectral features and compresses them into a low-dimensional latent space, with a decoder that generates a restframe representation, whose spectral range and resolution exceeds that of the observing instrument. The decoder is followed by explicit redshift, resampling, and convolution transformations to match the observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing a supernova&#39;s Standing Accretion Shock Instability with neutrinos and gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zidu Lin
We perform a novel multi-messenger analysis for the identification and parameter estimation of the Standing Accretion Shock Instability (SASI) in a core collapse supernova with neutrino and gravitational wave (GW) signals. In the neutrino channel, this method performs a likelihood ratio test for the presence of SASI in the frequency domain. For gravitational wave signals we process an event with a modified constrained likelihood method. Using simulated supernova signals, the properties of the Hyper-Kamiokande neutrino detector, and O3 LIGO Interferometric data, we produce the two-dimensional probability density distribution (PDF) of the SASI activity indicator and calculate the probability of detection $P_\mathrm{D}$ as well as the false identification probability $P_\mathrm{FI}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of the 4.4-MeV gamma rays from $^{16}$O($ν, ν^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O(12.97 ${\rm MeV}, 2^-)$ with a water-Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Makoto Sakuda
We first discuss and determine the isospin mixing of the two $2^-$ states (12.53 MeV and 12.97 MeV) of $^{16}$O nucleus using the inelastic electron scattering data. We then evaluate the cross section of 4.4-MeV $\gamma$ rays produced in the neutrino neutral-current (NC) reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(12.97~{\rm MeV}, 2^-$) in a water Cherenkov detector at the low energy below 100 MeV. The detection of $\gamma$ rays for $E_{\gamma}&amp;gt;5$~MeV from the NC reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(E_x&amp;gt;16\ {\rm MeV}, T=1$) with a water Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts has been proposed and discussed by several authors previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGER I. a large sample of [OIII]-emitting galaxies at $5.3 &lt; z &lt; 6.9$ and direct evidence for local reionization by galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_i._a_large_sample_of_oiii-emitting_galaxies_at__5.3__z__6.9__and_direct_evidence_for_local_reionization_by_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_i._a_large_sample_of_oiii-emitting_galaxies_at__5.3__z__6.9__and_direct_evidence_for_local_reionization_by_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daichi Kashino
We present a first sample of 117 [OIII]$\lambda\lambda$4960,5008-selected star-forming galaxies at $5.33 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 6.93$ detected in JWST/NIRCam 3.5$\mu$m slitless spectroscopy of a $6.5 \times 3.4$ arcmin$^2$ field centered on the hyperluminous quasar SDSS J0100+2802, obtained as part of the EIGER (Emission-line galaxies and Intergalactic Gas in the Epoch of Reionization) survey. Three prominent galaxy overdensities are observed, one of them at the redshift of the quasar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGER II. first spectroscopic characterisation of the young stars and ionised gas associated with strong H$β$ and [OIII] line-emission in galaxies at z=5-7 with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_ii._first_spectroscopic_characterisation_of_the_young_stars_and_ionised_gas_associated_with_strong_h_%CE%B2__and_oiii_line-emission_in_galaxies_at_z5-7_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_ii._first_spectroscopic_characterisation_of_the_young_stars_and_ionised_gas_associated_with_strong_h_%CE%B2__and_oiii_line-emission_in_galaxies_at_z5-7_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jorryt Matthee
We present emission-line measurements and physical interpretations for a sample of 117 [OIII] emitting galaxies at $z=5.33-6.93$, using the first deep JWST/NIRCam wide field slitless spectroscopic observations. Our 9.7-hour integration is centered upon the $z=6.3$ quasar J0100+2802 &amp;ndash; the first of six fields targeted by the EIGER survey &amp;ndash; and covers $\lambda=3-4$ microns. We detect 133 [OIII] doublets, but merge pairs within $\approx$10 kpc and 600 km s$^{-1}$, motivated by their small scale clustering excess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly: Galaxy Morphology in the Green Valley, Prominent rings and looser Spiral Arms</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_galaxy_morphology_in_the_green_valley_prominent_rings_and_looser_spiral_arms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_galaxy_morphology_in_the_green_valley_prominent_rings_and_looser_spiral_arms/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominic Smith
Galaxies broadly fall into two categories: star-forming (blue) galaxies and quiescent (red) galaxies. In between, one finds the less populated ``green valley&amp;quot;. Some of these galaxies are suspected to be in the process of ceasing their star-formation through a gradual exhaustion of gas supply or already dead and are experiencing a rejuvenation of star-formation through fuel injection. We use the Galaxy And Mass Assembly database and the Galaxy Zoo citizen science morphological estimates to compare the morphology of galaxies in the green valley against those in the red sequence and blue cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lagrangian displacement field estimators in cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lagrangian_displacement_field_estimators_in_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lagrangian_displacement_field_estimators_in_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Atsuhisa Ota
The nonlinear Lagrangian displacement field and initial linear density field are highly correlated. Therefore, reconstructing the nonlinear displacement field could better extract the primordial cosmological information from the late time density field. Continuing from Ref. [1], we investigate to what extent the iterative displacement reconstruction in Ref. [2] can recover the true displacement field with a particular emphasis on improving the numerical discreteness effect and improving the perturbation theory model for the postreconstructed field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric identification of compact galaxies, stars and quasars using multiple neural networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_identification_of_compact_galaxies_stars_and_quasars_using_multiple_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_identification_of_compact_galaxies_stars_and_quasars_using_multiple_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Siddharth Chaini
We present MargNet, a deep learning-based classifier for identifying stars, quasars and compact galaxies using photometric parameters and images from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) Data Release 16 (DR16) catalogue. MargNet consists of a combination of Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Artificial Neural Network (ANN) architectures. Using a carefully curated dataset consisting of 240,000 compact objects and an additional 150,000 faint objects, the machine learns classification directly from the data, minimising the need for human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of stochastic modeling on the predictive power of galaxy formation simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_stochastic_modeling_on_the_predictive_power_of_galaxy_formation_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_stochastic_modeling_on_the_predictive_power_of_galaxy_formation_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Josh Borrow
All modern galaxy formation models employ stochastic elements in their sub-grid prescriptions to discretise continuous equations across the time domain. In this paper, we investigate how the stochastic nature of these models, notably star formation, black hole accretion, and their associated feedback, that act on small ($&amp;lt;$ kpc) scales, can back-react on macroscopic galaxy properties (e.g. stellar mass and size) across long ($&amp;gt;$ Gyr) timescales. We find that the scatter in scaling relations predicted by the EAGLE model implemented in the SWIFT code can be significantly impacted by random variability between re-simulations of the same object, even when galaxies are resolved by tens of thousands of particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inefficiency of stellar feedback in driving galactic outflows in massive galaxies at high redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_inefficiency_of_stellar_feedback_in_driving_galactic_outflows_in_massive_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_inefficiency_of_stellar_feedback_in_driving_galactic_outflows_in_massive_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Bassini
Recent observations indicate that galactic outflows are ubiquitous in high redshift galaxies, including normal star forming galaxies, quasar hosts, and dusty star forming galaxies (DSFGs). However, the impact of outflows on the evolution of their hosts is still an open question. Here, we analyse the star formation histories (SFH) and galactic outflow properties of galaxies in massive haloes ($10^{12}M_{\odot}&amp;lt;M_{\rm vir} &amp;lt;5\times 10^{12}M_{\odot}$) at $z\gtrsim5.5$ in three zoom-in cosmological simulations from the MassiveFIRE suite, as part of the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A BayeSN Distance Ladder: $H_0$ from a consistent modelling of Type Ia supernovae from the optical to the near infrared</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suhail Dhawan
The local distance ladder estimate of the Hubble constant ($H_0$) is important in cosmology, given the recent tension with the early universe inference. We estimate $H_0$ from the Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) distance ladder, inferring SN Ia distances with the hierarchical Bayesian SED model, BayeSN. This method has a notable advantage of being able to continuously model the optical and near-infrared (NIR) SN Ia light curves simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new method for age-dating the formation of bars in disc galaxies: The TIMER view on NGC1433&#39;s old bar and the inside-out growth of its nuclear disc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_for_age-dating_the_formation_of_bars_in_disc_galaxies_the_timer_view_on_ngc1433s_old_bar_and_the_inside-out_growth_of_its_nuclear_disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_for_age-dating_the_formation_of_bars_in_disc_galaxies_the_timer_view_on_ngc1433s_old_bar_and_the_inside-out_growth_of_its_nuclear_disc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camila de Sá-Freitas
The epoch in which galactic discs settle is a major benchmark to test models of galaxy formation and evolution but is as yet largely unknown. Once discs settle and become self-gravitating enough, stellar bars are able to form; therefore, determining the ages of bars can shed light on the epoch of disc settling, and on the onset of secular evolution. Nevertheless, until now, timing when the bar formed has proven challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Physical Picture for AGNs Lacking Optical Emission Lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher J. Agostino
In this work, we use ~500 low-redshift (z ~ 0.1) X-ray AGNs observed by XMM-Newton and SDSS to investigate the prevalence and nature of AGNs that apparently lack optical emission lines (optically dull AGNs&#39;&#39;). Although 1/4 of spectra appear absorption-line dominated in visual assessment, line extraction with robust continuum subtraction from the MPA/JHU catalog reveals usable [OIII] measurements in 98% of the sample, allowing us to study [OIII]-underluminous AGNs together with more typical AGNs in the context of the L$_{\mathrm{[OIII]}}$--L$_{X}$ relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of local ultraluminous infrared galaxies and quasars with kernel principal component analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classification_of_local_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_and_quasars_with_kernel_principal_component_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classification_of_local_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_and_quasars_with_kernel_principal_component_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Evangelos S. Papaefthymiou
We present a new diagnostic diagram for local ultraluminous infrared galaxies (ULIRGs) and quasars, analysing particularly the Spitzer Space Telescope&amp;rsquo;s Infrared Spectrograph (IRS) spectra of 102 local ULIRGs and 37 Palomar Green quasars. Our diagram is based on a special non-linear mapping of these data, employing the Kernel Principal Component Analysis method. The novelty of this map lies in the fact that it distributes the galaxies under study on the surface of a well-defined ellipsoid, which, in turn, links basic concepts from geometry to physical properties of the galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Census: Relative Distributions of Dark Matter, Galaxies and Diffuse Gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_census_relative_distributions_of_dark_matter_galaxies_and_diffuse_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_census_relative_distributions_of_dark_matter_galaxies_and_diffuse_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Raphaël Kou
Galaxies, diffuse gas and dark matter make up the cosmic web defining the large-scale structure of the universe. We constrain the joint distribution of these constituents by cross-correlating galaxy samples binned by stellar mass from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey CMASS catalogue with maps of lensing convergence and the thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich (tSZ) effect from the Planck mission. Fitting a halo-based model to our measured angular power spectra (galaxy-galaxy, galaxy-lensing convergence, galaxy-tSZ) at a median redshift of $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints on unimodular gravity models with diffusion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_on_unimodular_gravity_models_with_diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_on_unimodular_gravity_models_with_diffusion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Susana J. Landau
A discrete space-time structure lying at about the Planck scale may become manifest in the form of very small violations of the conservation of the matter energy-momentum tensor. In order to include such kind of violations, forbidden within the General Relativity framework, the theory of unimodular gravity seems as the simplest option to describe the gravitational interaction. In the cosmological context, a direct consequence of such violation of energy conservation might be heuristically viewed a &amp;ldquo;diffusion process of matter (both dark and ordinary)&amp;rdquo; into an effective dark energy term in Einstein&amp;rsquo;s equations, which leads under natural assumptions to an adequate estimate for the value of the cosmological constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLARES VIII. The Emergence of Passive Galaxies in the Early Universe ($z &gt; 5$)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flares_viii._the_emergence_of_passive_galaxies_in_the_early_universe__z__5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flares_viii._the_emergence_of_passive_galaxies_in_the_early_universe__z__5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher C. Lovell
Passive galaxies are ubiquitous in the local universe, and various physical channels have been proposed that lead to this passivity. To date, robust passive galaxy candidates have been detected up to $z \leqslant 5$, but it is still unknown if they exist at higher redshifts, what their relative abundances are, and what causes them to stop forming stars. We present predictions from the First Light And Reionisation Epoch Simulations (FLARES), a series of zoom simulations of a range of overdensities using the EAGLE code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular Cluster Ultraluminous X-ray Sources in the Furthest Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_sources_in_the_furthest_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_sources_in_the_furthest_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Thygesen
Ultraluminous X-ray Sources (ULXs) in globular clusters are low mass X-ray binaries that achieve high X-ray luminosities through a currently uncertain accretion mechanism. Using archival Chandra and Hubble Space Telescope observations, we perform a volume-limited search ($\lesssim$ 70 Mpc) of 21 of the most massive ($&amp;gt;10^{11.5} M_\odot$) early-type galaxies to identify ULXs hosted by globular cluster (GC) candidates. We find a total of 34 ULX candidates above the expected background within 5 times the effective radius of each galaxy, with 10 of these ($\sim29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonthermal processes and particle acceleration in supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacco Vink
Shocks of supernova remnants (SNRs) accelerate charged particles up to 100 TeV range via diffusive shock acceleration (DSA) mechanism. It is believed that shocks of SNRs are the main contributors to the pool of Galactic cosmic rays, although it is still under debate whether they can accelerate particles up to the &amp;ldquo;knee&amp;rdquo; energy (10^15.5 eV) or not. In this chapter, we start with introducing SNRs as likely sources of cosmic rays and the radiation mechanisms associated with cosmic rays (section 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing quasar lifetimes with proximate $21$-centimetre absorption in the diffuse intergalactic medium at redshifts $z\geq 6$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_quasar_lifetimes_with_proximate__21_-centimetre_absorption_in_the_diffuse_intergalactic_medium_at_redshifts__z_geq_6_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_quasar_lifetimes_with_proximate__21_-centimetre_absorption_in_the_diffuse_intergalactic_medium_at_redshifts__z_geq_6_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tomáš Šoltinský
Enhanced ionizing radiation in close proximity to redshift $z\gtrsim 6$ quasars creates short windows of intergalactic Ly$\alpha$ transmission blueward of the quasar Ly$\alpha$ emission lines. The majority of these Ly$\alpha$ near-zones are consistent with quasars that have optically/UV bright lifetimes of $t_{\rm Q}\sim 10^{5}-10^{7}\rm,yr$. However, lifetimes as short as $t_{\rm Q}\lesssim 10^{4}\rm,yr$ appear to be required by the smallest Ly$\alpha$ near-zones. These short lifetimes present an apparent challenge for the growth of $\sim 10^{9}\rm,M_{\odot}$ black holes at $z\gtrsim 6$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1): Light Curves and Photometric Classification of 1975 Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. D. Aleo
We present the Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1), comprised of processed multi-color Pan-STARRS1 (PS1) griz and Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) gr photometry of 1975 transients with host-galaxy associations, redshifts, spectroscopic/photometric classifications, and additional data products from 2019 November 24 to 2021 December 20. YSE DR1 spans discoveries and observations from young and fast-rising supernovae (SNe) to transients that persist for over a year, with a redshift distribution reaching z~0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Galaxy Morphological Visual Representation with Deep Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unsupervised_galaxy_morphological_visual_representation_with_deep_contrastive_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unsupervised_galaxy_morphological_visual_representation_with_deep_contrastive_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shoulin Wei
Galaxy morphology reflects structural properties which contribute to understand the formation and evolution of galaxies. Deep convolutional networks have proven to be very successful in learning hidden features that allow for unprecedented performance on galaxy morphological classification. Such networks mostly follow the supervised learning paradigm which requires sufficient labelled data for training. However, it is an expensive and complicated process of labeling for million galaxies, particularly for the forthcoming survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: Public release of HI data for almost 600 galaxies from phase 1 of ASKAP pilot observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_data_for_almost_600_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_data_for_almost_600_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Westmeier
We present WALLABY pilot data release 1, the first public release of HI pilot survey data from the Wide-field ASKAP L-band Legacy All-sky Blind Survey (WALLABY) on the Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder. Phase 1 of the WALLABY pilot survey targeted three $60~{\rm deg}^2$ regions on the sky in the direction of the Hydra and Norma galaxy clusters and the NGC 4636 galaxy group, covering the redshift range of z &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: Public release of HI kinematic models for more than 100 galaxies from phase 1 of ASKAP pilot observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_kinematic_models_for_more_than_100_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_kinematic_models_for_more_than_100_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Deg
We present the Widefield ASKAP L-band Legacy All-sky Blind surveY (WALLABY) Pilot Phase I HI kinematic models. This first data release consists of HI observations of three fields in the direction of the Hydra and Norma clusters, and the NGC 4636 galaxy group. In this paper, we describe how we generate and publicly release flat-disk tilted-ring kinematic models for 109/592 unique HI detections in these fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the moderate UV/X-ray correlation in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Panagiotou
The UV/optical and X-ray variability of active galactic nuclei (AGN) have long been expected to be well correlated as a result of the X-ray illumination of the accretion disk. Recent monitoring campaigns of nearby AGN, however, found that their X-ray and UV/optical emission are only moderately correlated, challenging the aforementioned paradigm. In this work, we aim to demonstrate that due to the definition of the cross correlation function, a low UV/X-ray correlation is well expected in the case of an X-ray illuminated accretion disk, when the dynamic variability of the X-ray source is taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-detection of Broad Hydrogen Radio Recombination Lines in Circinus Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-detection_of_broad_hydrogen_radio_recombination_lines_in_circinus_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-detection_of_broad_hydrogen_radio_recombination_lines_in_circinus_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junzhi Wang
The line widths of broad line regions (BLRs) of AGNs are key parameters for understanding the central super massive black holes (SMBHs). However, due to obscuration from dusty torus, optical recombination lines from BLRs in type II AGNs can not be directly detected. Radio recombination lines (RRLs), with low extinction, can be ideal tracers to probe emission from BLRs in type II AGNs. We performed RRL observations for H35$\alpha$ and H36$\alpha$ toward the center of Circinus galaxy with ALMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the evolution of Type Ia supernovae with their ejecta velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. -C. Pan
There is growing evidence that Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are likely produced via multiple explosion channels. Understanding how different channels evolve with redshift is critical in determining their precision in measuring cosmological parameters. Previous studies indicated that SN Ia ejecta velocity is one powerful tool to differentiate between different channels. It was also suspected that the tight correlation with the host-galaxy environment could result in the evolution of SN ejecta velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fisher Forecasting for Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_fisher_forecasting_for_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_fisher_forecasting_for_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph Ryan
The planning and design of future experiments rely heavily on forecasting to assess the potential scientific value provided by a hypothetical set of measurements. The Fisher information matrix, due to its convenient properties and low computational cost, provides an especially useful forecasting tool. However, the Fisher matrix only provides a reasonable approximation to the true likelihood when data are nearly Gaussian distributed and observables have nearly linear dependence on the parameters of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating cosmological growth functions with B-Splines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_cosmological_growth_functions_with_b-splines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emulating_cosmological_growth_functions_with_b-splines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ngai Pok Kwan
In the light of GPU accelerations, sequential operations such as solving ordinary differential equations can be bottlenecks for gradient evaluations and hinder potential speed gains. In this work, we focus on growth functions and their time derivatives in cosmological particle mesh simulations and show that these are the majority time cost when using gradient based inference algorithms. We propose to construct novel conditional B-spline emulators which directly learn an interpolating function for the growth factor as a function of time, conditioned on the cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological signatures of mergers in the TNG50 simulation and the Kilo-Degree Survey: the merger fraction from dwarfs to Milky Way-like galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.14123/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.14123/</guid>
      <description>Tiger Yu-Yang Hsiao
MACS0647$-$JD is a triply-lensed $z\sim11$ galaxy originally discovered with the Hubble Space Telescope. Here we report new JWST imaging, which clearly resolves MACS0647$-$JD as having two components that are either merging galaxies or stellar complexes within a single galaxy. Both are very small, with stellar masses $\sim10^8,M_\odot$ and radii $r&amp;lt;100,\rm pc$. The brighter larger component &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; is intrinsically very blue ($β\sim-2.6$), likely due to very recent star formation and no dust, and is spatially extended with an effective radius $\sim70,\rm pc$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological signatures of mergers in the TNG50 simulation and the Kilo-Degree Survey: the merger fraction from dwarfs to Milky Way-like galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05785/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05785/</guid>
      <description>Alejandro Guzmán-Ortega
Using the TNG50 cosmological simulation and observations from the Kilo-Degree Survey (KiDS), we investigate the connection between galaxy mergers and optical morphology in the local Universe over a wide range of galaxy stellar masses ($8.5\leqslant\log(M_\ast/\text{M}\odot)\leqslant11$). To this end, we have generated over 16,000 synthetic images of TNG50 galaxies designed to match KiDS observations, including the effects of dust attenuation and scattering, and used the $\mathrm{\mathtt{statmorph}}$ code to measure various image-based morphological diagnostics in the $r$-band for both data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing early universe through redshifted 21-cm signal: Modelling and observational challenges</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</guid>
      <description>Abinash Kumar Shaw
The redshifted 21-cm radiation from the atomic hydrogen (HI) provides an excellent direct probe to study the evolution of HI in IGM and thus reveal the nature of the first luminous objects, their evolution and role during Cosmic Dawn (CD) and Epoch of Reionization (EoR), and formation and evolution of the structures thereafter. Direct mapping of the HI density during the CD-EoR is rather difficult with the current and future instruments due to large foreground and other observational contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2022ann: A type Icn supernova from a dwarf galaxy that reveals helium in its circumstellar environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05134/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05134/</guid>
      <description>K. W. Davis
We present optical and near-infrared (NIR) observations of the Type Icn supernova (SN Icn) 2022ann, the fifth member of its newly identified class of SNe. Its early optical spectra are dominated by narrow carbon and oxygen P-Cygni features with absorption velocities of 800 km/s; slower than other SNe Icn and indicative of interaction with a dense, H/He-poor circumstellar medium (CSM) that is outflowing slower than a typical Wolf-Rayet wind velocity of $&amp;gt;$1000 km/s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of neutrino decoupling from the early universe to the current universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.10307/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.10307/</guid>
      <description>Kensuke Akita
We review the distortions of spectra of relic neutrinos due to the interactions with electrons, positrons, and neutrinos in the early universe. We solve integro-differential kinetic equations for the neutrino density matrix, including vacuum three-flavor neutrino oscillations, oscillations in electron and positron background, a collision term and finite temperature corrections to electron mass and electromagnetic plasma up to the next-to-leading order $\mathcal{O}(e^3)$. After that, we estimate the effects of the spectral distortions in neutrino decoupling on the number density and energy density of the Cosmic Neutrino Background (C$ν$B) in the current universe, and discuss the implications of these effects on the capture rates in direct detection of the C$ν$B on tritium, with emphasis on the PTOLEMY-type experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04503/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04503/</guid>
      <description>Roark Habegger
In galactic disks, the Parker instability results when non-thermal pressure support exceeds a certain threshold. The non-thermal pressures considered in the Parker instability are cosmic ray pressure and magnetic pressure. This instability takes a long time to saturate $(&amp;gt;500 , \mathrm{Myr})$ and assumes a background with fixed cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio. In reality, galactic cosmic rays are injected into localized regions $(&amp;lt; 100 ,\mathrm{pc})$ by events like supernovae, increasing the cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05275/</guid>
      <description>Ray S. Sharma
We examine the quenching characteristics of $328$ isolated dwarf galaxies $\left(10^{8} &amp;lt; M_{\rm star}/M_\odot &amp;lt; 10^{10} \right)$ within the \Rom{} cosmological hydrodynamic simulation. Using mock observation methods, we identify isolated dwarf galaxies with quenched star formation and make direct comparisons to the quenched fraction in the NASA Sloan Atlas (NSA). Similar to other cosmological simulations, we find a population of quenched, isolated dwarf galaxies below $M_{\rm star} &amp;lt; 10^{9} M_\odot$ not detected within the NSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and dynamics of the peculiar stream Jhelum, A tentative role for the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2202.02132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2202.02132/</guid>
      <description>Hanneke C. Woudenberg
Stellar streams are a promising tool to study the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s dark matter subhalo population, as interactions with subhalos could produce substructure in streams. However, other possible causes for substructure first need to be well understood. Here we study the kinematics and the unusual morphology of the stellar stream Jhelum. Using a combination of ground-based photometry and Gaia EDR3 astrometry we characterize the morphology of Jhelum. We combine this new data with radial velocities from the literature to perform orbit integrations of the stream in static Galactic potentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic inhomogeneities in the early Universe: A numerical relativity approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03534/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03534/</guid>
      <description>Cristian Joana
Cosmic inflation is arguably the most favoured paradigm of the very early Universe. It postulates an early phase of fast, nearly exponential, and accelerated expansion. Inflationary models are capable of explaining the overall flatness and homogeneity of today&amp;rsquo;s Universe at large scales. Despite being widely accepted by the physics community, these models are not absent from criticism. In scalar field inflation, a necessary condition to begin inflation is the requirement of a Universe dominated by the field&amp;rsquo;s potential, which implies a subdominant contribution from the scalar field dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between the globular cluster systems of the Virgo and Fornax Galaxy Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02711/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02711/</guid>
      <description>J. Dabringhausen
It is well known that Globular cluster systems are different among galaxies. Here we test to which degree these differences remain on the scale of galaxy clusters by comparing the globular clusters (GCs) in optical surveys of the Virgo galaxy cluster (ACSVCS) and the Fornax galaxy cluster (ACSFCS) in Kolmogorov-Smirnoff Tests. Both surveys were obtained with the Advanced Camera for Surveys (ACS) on board the Hubble Space Telescope, and contain thousands of GCs in dozens of galaxies each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a double sequence of blue straggler stars in the core-collapsed globular cluster NGC 6256</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02671/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02671/</guid>
      <description>Mario Cadelano
We used a combination of high-resolution optical images acquired with the Hubble Space Telescope and near-IR wide-field data to investigate the stellar density profile and the population of blue straggler star (BSS) in the Galactic globular cluster NGC6256, with the aim of probing its current stage of internal dynamical evolution. We found that the inner stellar density profile significantly deviates from a King model while is well reproduced by a steep cusp with a power-law slope alpha=-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a new Local Group Dwarf Galaxy Candidate in UNIONS: Boötes V</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.08242/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.08242/</guid>
      <description>Simon E. T. Smith
We present the discovery of Boötes V, a new ultra-faint dwarf galaxy candidate. This satellite is detected as a resolved overdensity of stars during an ongoing search for new Local Group dwarf galaxy candidates in the UNIONS photometric dataset. It has a physical half-light radius of 26.9$^{+7.5}_{-5.4}$ pc, a $V$-band magnitude of $-$4.5 $\pm$ 0.4 mag, and resides at a heliocentric distance of approximately 100 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinguishing Dark Matter Cusps from Cores using Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01384/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01384/</guid>
      <description>Shaunak Modak
Globular Clusters (GCs) provide valuable insight into the properties of their host galaxies&amp;rsquo; dark matter halos. Using N-body simulations incorporating semianalytic dynamical friction and GC-GC merger prescriptions, we study the evolution of GC radial distributions and mass functions in cuspy and cored dark matter halos. Modeling the dynamics of the GC-rich system in the dwarf galaxy UGC7369, we find that friction-induced inspiral and subsequent mergers of massive GCs can naturally and robustly explain the mass segregation of the GCs and the existence of a nuclear star cluster (NSC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DUVET: Spatially Resolved Observations of Star Formation Regulation via Galactic Outflows in a Starbursting Disk Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02063/</guid>
      <description>Bronwyn Reichardt Chu
We compare 500~pc scale, resolved observations of ionised and molecular gas for the $z\sim0.02$ starbursting disk galaxy IRAS08339+6517, using measurements from KCWI and NOEMA. We explore the relationship of the star formation driven ionised gas outflows with colocated galaxy properties. We find a roughly linear relationship between the outflow mass flux ($\dotΣ_{\rm out}$) and star formation rate surface density ($Σ_{\rm SFR}$), $\dotΣ_{\rm out}\proptoΣ_{\rm SFR}^{1.06\pm0.10}$, and a strong correlation between $\dotΣ_{\rm out}$ and the gas depletion time, such that $\dotΣ_{\rm out} \propto t_{dep}^{-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Stellar Parameters Estimation through CMD of Star Clusters: Open (NGC2360) and Globular (NGC 5272)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.03019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.03019/</guid>
      <description>Kanwar Preet Kaur
The fundamentals of estimating essential stellar parameters of an open cluster-NGC 2360 and globular clusters-NGC 5272 are presented extensively in this work. Here, the evaluation of stellar parameters, by manually fitting the appropriate isochrones on the color magnitude diagrams (CMDs), of the selected star clusters is discussed comprehensively. Aperture photometry and PSF fitting photometry are conducted on g, r, and i standard band filter images of Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) using the aperture photometry tool (APT) to obtain the respective CMDs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-rich, field ultra-diffuse galaxies host few globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00650/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00650/</guid>
      <description>S. Jang
Hubble Space Telescope (HST) photometry is providing an extensive analysis of globular clusters (GCs). In particular, the pseudo two-colour diagram dubbed &#39;chromosome map (ChM)&#39; allowed to detect and characterize their multiple populations with unprecedented detail. The main limitation of these studies is the small field of view of HST, which makes it challenging to investigate some important aspects of the multiple populations, such as their spatial distributions and the internal kinematics in the outermost cluster regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-rich, field ultra-diffuse galaxies host few globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00651/</guid>
      <description>Michael G. Jones
We present Hubble Space Telescope imaging of 14 gas-rich, low surface brightness and ultra-diffuse galaxies (UDGs) in the field at distances of 25-36 Mpc. An inspection of point-like sources brighter than the turnover magnitude of the globular cluster luminosity function and within twice the half-light radii of each galaxy reveals that, unlike those in denser environments, gas-rich, field UDGs host very few old globular clusters (GCs). Most of the targets (nine) have zero candidate GCs, with the remainder having one or two candidates each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster formation with multiple stellar populations: A single-binary composite scenario</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00344/</guid>
      <description>Kenji Bekki
We discuss a GC formation scenario in which the first generation (1G) of single asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars and intermediate-mass close binaries (IMCBs) eject gas, from which the second generation (2G) of stars can be formed. The two key parameters in the scenario are the fractions of binary stars (f_b) and the slopes (alpha) of the stellar initial mass functions (IMFs) for 1G stars. Principle results derived by analytic and one-zone models of GC formation are as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Population III homogeneous stellar evolution on early cosmic reionisation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.15125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.15125/</guid>
      <description>Yves Sibony
Context: Population III (Pop III) stars may be fast rotating. An expected consequence of fast rotation is strong internal mixing that deeply affects their evolutionary tracks in the Hertzsprung-Russell diagram and hence their ionising power. aims: We investigate the impact on the ionising power of Pop III stars in an extreme case of internal mixing, the one leading to chemically homogeneous evolution (CHE). In that situation, during the main sequence phase, the star keeps the same chemical composition from its center to its surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting Kilonovae: Long-lasting Electromagnetic Counterparts to Binary Mergers in the Accretion Disks of Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03097/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03097/</guid>
      <description>Jia Ren
We investigate the dynamics and electromagnetic (EM) signatures of neutron star-neutron star (NS-NS) or neutron star-black hole (NS-BH) merger ejecta that occurs in the accretion disk of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We find that the interaction between ejecta and disk gas leads to important effects on the dynamics and radiation. We show five stages of the ejecta dynamics: gravitational slowing down, coasting, Sedov-Taylor deceleration in the disk, re-acceleration after the breakout from the disk surface, and momentum-conserved snowplow phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic signatures of impulsive supernova feedback in dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03795/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03795/</guid>
      <description>Jan D. Burger
Impulsive supernova feedback and non-standard dark matter models, such as self-interacting dark matter (SIDM), are the two main contenders for the role of the dominant core formation mechanism at the dwarf galaxy scale. Here we show that the impulsive supernova cycles that follow episodes of bursty star formation leave distinct features in the distribution function of stars: groups of stars with similar ages and metallicities develop overdense shells in phase space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the observability and identification of Population III galaxies with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02038/</guid>
      <description>James A. A. Trussler
We utilise theoretical models of Population III stellar+nebular spectra to investigate the prospects of observing and accurately identifying Population III galaxies with JWST using both deep imaging and spectroscopy. We investigate a series of different colour cuts, finding that a combination of NIRCam and MIRI photometry through the F444W-F560W, F560W-F770W colours offers the most robust identifier of potential $z=8$ Pop III candidates. We calculate that NIRCam will have to reach $\sim$ 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANDORA project: photo-nuclear reactions below A=60</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03986/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03986/</guid>
      <description>A. Tamii, L. Pellegri
Photo-nuclear reactions of light nuclei below a mass of $A=60$ are studied experimentally and theoretically by the PANDORA (Photo-Absorption of Nuclei and Decay Observation for Reactions in Astrophysics) project. Two experimental methods, virtual-photon excitation by proton scattering and real-photo absorption by a high-brilliance gamma-ray beam produced by laser Compton scattering, will be applied to measure the photo-absorption cross sections and the decay branching ratio of each decay channel as a function of the photon energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of globular clusters formed in dark matter mini-halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2112.01265/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2112.01265/</guid>
      <description>Eduardo Vitral
We seek to differentiate dynamical and morphological attributes between globular clusters (GCs) that were formed inside their own dark matter (DM) mini-halo, and those who were not. We employ high resolution full N-body simulations on GPU of GCs with and without a DM mini-halo, orbiting a Fornax-like dwarf galaxy. For GCs with DM, we observe that this dark extra mass triggers a tidal radius growth that allows the mini-halo to act as a protective shield against tidal stripping, being itself stripped beforehand the stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of globular clusters formed in dark matter mini-halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04485/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04485/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mass-Metallicity Relation of Dwarf Galaxies at the Cosmic Noon in the JWST Era</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01382/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01382/</guid>
      <description>Mingyu Li, Zheng Cai
We present the mass-metallicity relation (MZR) at $z=2-3$ in the stellar mass range of $M_\star\approx 10^{6.5}-10^{9.5}M_\odot$ using 55 dwarf galaxies in the Abell 2744 and SMACS J0723-3732 galaxy cluster fields. These dwarf galaxies are identified and confirmed by deep JWST/NIRISS imaging and slitless grism spectroscopic observations. Taking advantage of the gravitational lensing effect, we extend the previous MZR relation at $z=2-3$ to a much lower mass regime by more than 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present-day gas content of simulated field dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.11782/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.11782/</guid>
      <description>Georg Herzog
We examine the gas content of field dwarf galaxies in a high-resolution cosmological simulation. In agreement with previous work, we find that galaxies inhabiting dark matter haloes with mass below a critical value, $M_{200} \lesssim M_{\rm crit} \approx 5\times 10^{9} \ M_{\odot}$, are quiescent at the present day. The gas content of these galaxies is thus insensitive to feedback from evolving stars. Almost half of these quiescent systems today have gas masses much smaller than that expected for their mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Candidates for Dual AGN in Dwarf-Dwarf Galaxy Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04609/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04609/</guid>
      <description>Marko Mićić
Dual AGN are important for understanding galaxy-merger-triggered fueling of black holes and hierarchical growth of structures. The least explored type of dual AGN are those associated with mergers of two dwarf galaxies. According to observations and cosmological simulations, dwarf galaxies are the most abundant type of galaxies in the early Universe and the galaxy merger rate is dominated by dwarfs. However, these mergers are generally too distant to be directly observed, and low-redshift dwarf-dwarf merger-related dual AGN are notoriously hard to find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Physics Informed Neural Networks for Supernova Radiative Transfer Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05219/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05219/</guid>
      <description>Xingzhuo Chen
We use physics informed neural networks (PINNs) to solve the radiative transfer equation and calculate a synthetic spectrum for a Type Ia supernova (SN~Ia) SN 2011fe. The calculation is based on local thermodynamic equilibrium (LTE) and 9 elements are included. Physical processes included are approximate radiative equilibrium, bound-bound transitions, and the Doppler effect. A PINN based gamma-ray scattering approximation is used for radioactive decay energy deposition. The PINN synthetic spectrum is compared to an observed spectrum, a synthetic spectrum calculated by the Monte-Carlo radiative transfer program TARDIS, and the formal solution of the radiative transfer equation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
