<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>11(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/11month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 11(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/11month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A unified model for the co-evolution of galaxies and their circumgalactic medium: the relative roles of turbulence and atomic cooling physics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_unified_model_for_the_co-evolution_of_galaxies_and_their_circumgalactic_medium_the_relative_roles_of_turbulence_and_atomic_cooling_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_unified_model_for_the_co-evolution_of_galaxies_and_their_circumgalactic_medium_the_relative_roles_of_turbulence_and_atomic_cooling_physics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Viraj Pandya
The circumgalactic medium (CGM) plays a pivotal role in regulating gas flows around galaxies and thus shapes their evolution. However, the details of how galaxies and their CGM co-evolve remain poorly understood. We present a new time-dependent two-zone model that self-consistently tracks not just mass and metal flows between galaxies and their CGM but also the evolution of the global thermal and turbulent kinetic energy of the CGM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-based galaxy image deconvolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/deep_learning-based_galaxy_image_deconvolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/deep_learning-based_galaxy_image_deconvolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Utsav Akhaury
With the onset of large-scale astronomical surveys capturing millions of images, there is an increasing need to develop fast and accurate deconvolution algorithms that generalize well to different images. A powerful and accessible deconvolution method would allow for the reconstruction of a cleaner estimation of the sky. The deconvolved images would be helpful to perform photometric measurements to help make progress in the fields of galaxy formation and evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Space Telescope Observations of Tadpole Galaxies Kiso 3867, SBS0, SBS1, and UM461</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hubble_space_telescope_observations_of_tadpole_galaxies_kiso_3867_sbs0_sbs1_and_um461/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hubble_space_telescope_observations_of_tadpole_galaxies_kiso_3867_sbs0_sbs1_and_um461/</guid>
      <description>First author: Debra Meloy Elmegreen
Tadpole galaxies are metal-poor dwarfs with typically one dominant star-forming region, giving them a head-tail structure when inclined. A metallicity drop in the head suggests that gas accretion with even lower metallicity stimulated the star formation. Here we present multiband HST WFC3 and ACS images of four nearby (&amp;lt;25 Mpc) tadpoles, SBS0, SBS1, Kiso 3867, and UM461, selected for their clear metallicity drops shown in previous spectroscopic studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Alignments Between Galaxies and the Cosmic Web at $z\sim 1-2$ in the IllustrisTNG Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/intrinsic_alignments_between_galaxies_and_the_cosmic_web_at__z_sim_1-2__in_the_illustristng_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/intrinsic_alignments_between_galaxies_and_the_cosmic_web_at__z_sim_1-2__in_the_illustristng_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin Zhang
Galaxy formation theories predict that galaxy shapes and angular momenta have intrinsic alignments (IA) with the cosmic web, which provides an observational test of various theories, and is important to quantify as a nuisance parameter for weak lensing. We study galaxy IA in the IllustrisTNG suite of hydrodynamical simulations at redshifts 1 and 2, finding that alignment trends are consistent with previous studies. However, we find that the magnitude of the spin alignment signal is $\sim 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mock Galaxy Surveys for HST and JWST from the IllustrisTNG Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mock_galaxy_surveys_for_hst_and_jwst_from_the_illustristng_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mock_galaxy_surveys_for_hst_and_jwst_from_the_illustristng_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gregory F. Snyder
We present and analyze a series of synthetic galaxy survey fields based on the IllustrisTNG Simulation suite. With the Illustris public data release and JupyterLab service, we generated a set of twelve lightcone catalogs covering areas from 5 to 365 square arcminutes, similar to several JWST Cycle 1 programs, including JADES, CEERS, PRIMER, and NGDEEP. From these catalogs, we queried the public API to generate simple mock images in a series of broadband filters used by JWST-NIRCam and the Hubble Space Telescope cameras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric redshift estimation of galaxies in the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/photometric_redshift_estimation_of_galaxies_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/photometric_redshift_estimation_of_galaxies_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Changhua Li
The accurate estimation of photometric redshifts plays a crucial role in accomplishing science objectives of the large survey projects. The template-fitting and machine learning are the two main types of methods applied currently. Based on the training set obtained by cross-correlating the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys DR9 galaxy catalogue and SDSS DR16 galaxy catalogue, the two kinds of methods are used and optimized, such as EAZY for template-fitting approach and CATBOOST for machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of star-forming rings in S0 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_origin_of_star-forming_rings_in_s0_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_origin_of_star-forming_rings_in_s0_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. L. Tous
Spatially resolved IFS maps in a sample of $532$ S0 galaxies from the MaNGA survey have unveiled the existence of inner rings ($\langle R\rangle\sim 1,R_\mathrm{e}$) betraying ongoing star formation in a number of these objects. Activity gradients averaged over bins of galactocentric radius up to $\sim 1.5,R_\mathrm{e}$ have been measured in the subspace defined by the first two principal components of the optical spectra of these galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing ICM cooling and AGN feedback from the macro to the meso scales in the galaxy cluster ZwCl 235</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/chasing_icm_cooling_and_agn_feedback_from_the_macro_to_the_meso_scales_in_the_galaxy_cluster_zwcl_235/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/chasing_icm_cooling_and_agn_feedback_from_the_macro_to_the_meso_scales_in_the_galaxy_cluster_zwcl_235/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Ubertosi
We aim to investigate the AGN/ICM interplay in ZwCl 235, a galaxy cluster with high X-ray flux, an extended central radio galaxy, and evidence of multi-phase gas at its center. Using archival data from the Chandra telescope, the VLASS survey, the LOTSS survey and the VLBA telescope, we perform a complete study of ZwCl 235, dissecting the dynamics of the ICM, the thermodynamic state of the central gas, and the properties of the BCG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining quenching timescales in galaxy clusters by forward-modelling stellar ages and quiescent fractions in projected phase space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_quenching_timescales_in_galaxy_clusters_by_forward-modelling_stellar_ages_and_quiescent_fractions_in_projected_phase_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_quenching_timescales_in_galaxy_clusters_by_forward-modelling_stellar_ages_and_quiescent_fractions_in_projected_phase_space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew M. M. Reeves
We forward-model mass-weighted ages (MWAs) and quiescent fractions in projected phase space (PPS), using data from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, to jointly constrain an infall quenching model for galaxies in $\log(M_{\mathrm{vir}}/\mathrm{M}{\odot})&amp;gt;14$ galaxy clusters at $z\sim 0$. We find the average deviation in MWA from the MWA-$M\star$ relation depends on position in PPS, with a maximum difference between the inner cluster and infalling interloper galaxies of $\sim 1$ Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Synoptic Array science I: discovery of the host galaxy of FRB 20220912A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/deep_synoptic_array_science_i_discovery_of_the_host_galaxy_of_frb_20220912a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/deep_synoptic_array_science_i_discovery_of_the_host_galaxy_of_frb_20220912a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vikram Ravi
We report the detection and interferometric localization of the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20220912A during commissioning observations with the Deep Synoptic Array (DSA-110). Two bursts were detected from FRB 20220912A, one each on 2022 October 18 and 2022 October 25. The best-fit position is (R.A. J2000, decl. J2000) = (23:09:04.9, +48:42:25.4), with a 90% confidence error ellipse of $\pm2$ arcsec and $\pm1$ arcsec in right ascension and declination respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIGS: Deep Inference of Galaxy Spectra with Neural Posterior Estimation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/digs_deep_inference_of_galaxy_spectra_with_neural_posterior_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/digs_deep_inference_of_galaxy_spectra_with_neural_posterior_estimation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gourav Khullar
With the advent of billion-galaxy surveys with complex data, the need of the hour is to efficiently model galaxy spectral energy distributions (SEDs) with robust uncertainty quantification. The combination of Simulation-Based inference (SBI) and amortized Neural Posterior Estimation (NPE) has been successfully used to analyse simulated and real galaxy photometry both precisely and efficiently. In this work, we utilise this combination and build on existing literature to analyse simulated noisy galaxy spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dusty winds clear JWST super-early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dusty_winds_clear_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dusty_winds_clear_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrizio Fiore
The JWST discovery of a number of super-early (redshift $z&amp;gt;10$), blue galaxies requires these systems to be essentially dust-free in spite of their large stellar masses. A possible explanation is that dust is evacuated by radiatively-driven outflows. We test this hypothesis by deriving the Eddington ratio, $\lambda_E$, for 134 galaxies at $6.5&amp;lt; z &amp;lt;16$. We find a strong anti-correlation between $\lambda_E$ and dust UV optical depth, $\tau_{1500} \propto \lambda_E^{-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid: performance on main cosmological parameter science</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/euclid_performance_on_main_cosmological_parameter_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/euclid_performance_on_main_cosmological_parameter_science/</guid>
      <description>First author: Isaac Tutusaus
Euclid will observe 15 000 deg$^2$ of the darkest sky, in regions free of contamination by light from our Galaxy and our Solar System. Three &amp;ldquo;Euclid Deep Fields&amp;rdquo; surveys covering around 40 deg$^2$ in total will extend the scientific scope of the mission to the high-redshift Universe. The complete survey will be constituted by hundreds of thousands of images and several tens of petabytes of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Galactic Chemical Evolution to Cosmic Supernova Rates Synchronized with Core-Collapse Supernovae Limited to the Narrow Progenitor Mass Range</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/from_galactic_chemical_evolution_to_cosmic_supernova_rates_synchronized_with_core-collapse_supernovae_limited_to_the_narrow_progenitor_mass_range/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/from_galactic_chemical_evolution_to_cosmic_supernova_rates_synchronized_with_core-collapse_supernovae_limited_to_the_narrow_progenitor_mass_range/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takuji Tsujimoto
Massive ($\geq$8 $M_\odot$) stars perish via one of two fates: core-collapse supernovae (CCSNe), which release synthesized heavy elements, or failed supernovae, thereby forming black holes. In the conventional Galactic chemical evolution (GCE) scheme, a substantial portion of massive stars, e.g., all stars in the mass range of 8-100 $M_{\odot},$ are assumed to enrich the Galaxy with their nucleosynthetic products. However, this hypothesis conflicts with the observations, namely, few CCSNe whose progenitor stars are more massive than $\sim$18 $M_{\odot}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution spectroscopic analysis of four new chemically peculiar stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-resolution_spectroscopic_analysis_of_four_new_chemically_peculiar_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-resolution_spectroscopic_analysis_of_four_new_chemically_peculiar_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. P. Roriz
We present detailed chemical compositions of four stars on the first-ascent red giant branch that are classified as chemically peculiar, but lack comprehensive analyses at high spectral resolution. For BD+03{\deg}2688, HE 0457-1805, HE 1255-2324, and HE 2207-1746, we derived metallicities [Fe/H] $=-1.21$, $-0.19$, $-0.31$, and $-0.55$, respectively, indicating a range in Galactic population membership. In addition to atmospheric parameters, we extracted elemental abundances for 28 elements, including the evolutionary-sensitive CNO group and $^{12}$C/$^{13}$C ratios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Low-mass End of the Black Hole Mass Function via a Study of Faint Local Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_the_black_hole_mass_function_via_a_study_of_faint_local_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_the_black_hole_mass_function_via_a_study_of_faint_local_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael S. Fusco
We present an analysis of the pitch angle distribution function (PADF) for nearby galaxies and its resulting black hole mass function (BHMF) via the well-known relationship between pitch angle and black hole mass. Our sample consists of a subset of 74 spiral galaxies from the Carnegie-Irvine Galaxy Survey with absolute $B$-band magnitude $\mathfrak{M}{B}&amp;gt;-19.12$ mag and luminosity distance $D{\mathrm{L}} \leq 25.4$ Mpc, which is an extension of a complementary set of 140 more luminous ($\mathfrak{M}{B}\leq-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Galaxy Cluster Convergence from Lensed CMB with Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/recovering_galaxy_cluster_convergence_from_lensed_cmb_with_generative_adversarial_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/recovering_galaxy_cluster_convergence_from_lensed_cmb_with_generative_adversarial_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liam Parker
We present a new method which leverages conditional Generative Adversarial Networks (cGAN) to reconstruct galaxy cluster convergence from lensed CMB temperature maps. Our model is constructed to emphasize structure and high-frequency correctness relative to the Residual U-Net approach presented by Caldeira, et. al. (2019). Ultimately, we demonstrate that while both models perform similarly in the no-noise regime (as well as after random off-centering of the cluster center), cGAN outperforms ResUNet when processing CMB maps noised with 5uK/arcmin white noise or astrophysical foregrounds (tSZ and kSZ); this out-performance is especially pronounced at high l, which is exactly the regime in which the ResUNet under-performs traditional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shattering and growth of cold clouds in galaxy clusters: the role of radiative cooling, magnetic fields and thermal conduction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/shattering_and_growth_of_cold_clouds_in_galaxy_clusters_the_role_of_radiative_cooling_magnetic_fields_and_thermal_conduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/shattering_and_growth_of_cold_clouds_in_galaxy_clusters_the_role_of_radiative_cooling_magnetic_fields_and_thermal_conduction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fred Jennings
In galaxy clusters, the hot intracluster medium (ICM) can develop a striking multi-phase structure around the brightest cluster galaxy. Much work has been done on understanding the origin of this central nebula, but less work has studied its eventual fate after the originally filamentary structure is broken into individual cold clumps. In this paper we perform a suite of 30 (magneto-)hydrodynamical simulations of kpc-scale cold clouds with typical parameters as found by galaxy cluster simulations, to understand whether clouds are mixed back into the hot ICM or can persist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pandora project. I: the impact of radiation and cosmic rays on baryonic and dark matter properties of dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_pandora_project._i_the_impact_of_radiation_and_cosmic_rays_on_baryonic_and_dark_matter_properties_of_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_pandora_project._i_the_impact_of_radiation_and_cosmic_rays_on_baryonic_and_dark_matter_properties_of_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergio Martin-Alvarez
Enshrouded in several well-known controversies, dwarf galaxies have been extensively studied to learn about the underlying cosmology, notwithstanding that physical processes regulating their properties are poorly understood. To shed light on these processes, we introduce the Pandora suite of 17 high-resolution (3.5 parsec half-cell side) dwarf galaxy formation cosmological simulations. Commencing with thermo-turbulent star formation and mechanical supernova feedback, we gradually increase the complexity of physics incorporated leading to full-physics models combining magnetism, on-the-fly radiative transfer and the corresponding stellar photoheating, and SN-accelerated cosmic rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A ~600 pc view of the strongly-lensed, massive main sequence galaxy J0901: a baryon-dominated, thick turbulent rotating disk with a clumpy cold gas ring at z = 2.259</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_~600_pc_view_of_the_strongly-lensed_massive_main_sequence_galaxy_j0901_a_baryon-dominated_thick_turbulent_rotating_disk_with_a_clumpy_cold_gas_ring_at_z__2.259/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_~600_pc_view_of_the_strongly-lensed_massive_main_sequence_galaxy_j0901_a_baryon-dominated_thick_turbulent_rotating_disk_with_a_clumpy_cold_gas_ring_at_z__2.259/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daizhong Liu
We present a high-resolution kinematic study of the massive main-sequence star-forming galaxy (SFG) SDSS J090122.37+181432.3 (J0901) at z=2.259, using 0.36 arcsec ALMA CO(3-2) and 0.1-0.5 arcsec SINFONI/VLT H-alpha observations. J0901 is a rare, strongly-lensed but otherwise normal massive (log(M_star/M_sun)~11) main sequence SFG, offering a unique opportunity to study a typical massive SFG under the microscope of lensing. Through forward dynamical modeling incorporating lensing deflection, we fit the CO and H-alpha kinematics in the image plane out to about one disk effective radius (R_e ~ 4 kpc) at a ~600pc delensed physical resolution along the kinematic major axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tilt Instability in the Cosmological Principle</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_tilt_instability_in_the_cosmological_principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_tilt_instability_in_the_cosmological_principle/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chethan Krishnan
We show that the Friedmann-Lema^{i}tre-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) framework has an instability towards the growth of fluid flow anisotropies, even if the Universe is accelerating. This flow (tilt) instability in the matter sector is invisible to Cosmic No-Hair Theorem-like arguments, which typically only flag shear anisotropies in the metric. We illustrate our claims in the setting of ``dipole cosmology&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;, the maximally Copernican generalization of FLRW that can accommodate a flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoencoding Galaxy Spectra I: Architecture</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/autoencoding_galaxy_spectra_i_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/autoencoding_galaxy_spectra_i_architecture/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Melchior
We introduce the neural network architecture SPENDER as a core differentiable building block for analyzing, representing, and creating galaxy spectra. It combines a convolutional encoder, which pays attention to up to 256 spectral features and compresses them into a low-dimensional latent space, with a decoder that generates a restframe representation, whose spectral range and resolution exceeds that of the observing instrument. The decoder is followed by explicit redshift, resampling, and convolution transformations to match the observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing a supernova&#39;s Standing Accretion Shock Instability with neutrinos and gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zidu Lin
We perform a novel multi-messenger analysis for the identification and parameter estimation of the Standing Accretion Shock Instability (SASI) in a core collapse supernova with neutrino and gravitational wave (GW) signals. In the neutrino channel, this method performs a likelihood ratio test for the presence of SASI in the frequency domain. For gravitational wave signals we process an event with a modified constrained likelihood method. Using simulated supernova signals, the properties of the Hyper-Kamiokande neutrino detector, and O3 LIGO Interferometric data, we produce the two-dimensional probability density distribution (PDF) of the SASI activity indicator and calculate the probability of detection $P_\mathrm{D}$ as well as the false identification probability $P_\mathrm{FI}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of the 4.4-MeV gamma rays from $^{16}$O($ν, ν^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O(12.97 ${\rm MeV}, 2^-)$ with a water-Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Makoto Sakuda
We first discuss and determine the isospin mixing of the two $2^-$ states (12.53 MeV and 12.97 MeV) of $^{16}$O nucleus using the inelastic electron scattering data. We then evaluate the cross section of 4.4-MeV $\gamma$ rays produced in the neutrino neutral-current (NC) reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(12.97~{\rm MeV}, 2^-$) in a water Cherenkov detector at the low energy below 100 MeV. The detection of $\gamma$ rays for $E_{\gamma}&amp;gt;5$~MeV from the NC reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(E_x&amp;gt;16\ {\rm MeV}, T=1$) with a water Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts has been proposed and discussed by several authors previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGER I. a large sample of [OIII]-emitting galaxies at $5.3 &lt; z &lt; 6.9$ and direct evidence for local reionization by galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/eiger_i._a_large_sample_of_oiii-emitting_galaxies_at__5.3__z__6.9__and_direct_evidence_for_local_reionization_by_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/eiger_i._a_large_sample_of_oiii-emitting_galaxies_at__5.3__z__6.9__and_direct_evidence_for_local_reionization_by_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daichi Kashino
We present a first sample of 117 [OIII]$\lambda\lambda$4960,5008-selected star-forming galaxies at $5.33 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 6.93$ detected in JWST/NIRCam 3.5$\mu$m slitless spectroscopy of a $6.5 \times 3.4$ arcmin$^2$ field centered on the hyperluminous quasar SDSS J0100+2802, obtained as part of the EIGER (Emission-line galaxies and Intergalactic Gas in the Epoch of Reionization) survey. Three prominent galaxy overdensities are observed, one of them at the redshift of the quasar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGER II. first spectroscopic characterisation of the young stars and ionised gas associated with strong H$β$ and [OIII] line-emission in galaxies at z=5-7 with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/eiger_ii._first_spectroscopic_characterisation_of_the_young_stars_and_ionised_gas_associated_with_strong_h_%CE%B2__and_oiii_line-emission_in_galaxies_at_z5-7_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/eiger_ii._first_spectroscopic_characterisation_of_the_young_stars_and_ionised_gas_associated_with_strong_h_%CE%B2__and_oiii_line-emission_in_galaxies_at_z5-7_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jorryt Matthee
We present emission-line measurements and physical interpretations for a sample of 117 [OIII] emitting galaxies at $z=5.33-6.93$, using the first deep JWST/NIRCam wide field slitless spectroscopic observations. Our 9.7-hour integration is centered upon the $z=6.3$ quasar J0100+2802 &amp;ndash; the first of six fields targeted by the EIGER survey &amp;ndash; and covers $\lambda=3-4$ microns. We detect 133 [OIII] doublets, but merge pairs within $\approx$10 kpc and 600 km s$^{-1}$, motivated by their small scale clustering excess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly: Galaxy Morphology in the Green Valley, Prominent rings and looser Spiral Arms</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_galaxy_morphology_in_the_green_valley_prominent_rings_and_looser_spiral_arms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_galaxy_morphology_in_the_green_valley_prominent_rings_and_looser_spiral_arms/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominic Smith
Galaxies broadly fall into two categories: star-forming (blue) galaxies and quiescent (red) galaxies. In between, one finds the less populated ``green valley&amp;quot;. Some of these galaxies are suspected to be in the process of ceasing their star-formation through a gradual exhaustion of gas supply or already dead and are experiencing a rejuvenation of star-formation through fuel injection. We use the Galaxy And Mass Assembly database and the Galaxy Zoo citizen science morphological estimates to compare the morphology of galaxies in the green valley against those in the red sequence and blue cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lagrangian displacement field estimators in cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lagrangian_displacement_field_estimators_in_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lagrangian_displacement_field_estimators_in_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Atsuhisa Ota
The nonlinear Lagrangian displacement field and initial linear density field are highly correlated. Therefore, reconstructing the nonlinear displacement field could better extract the primordial cosmological information from the late time density field. Continuing from Ref. [1], we investigate to what extent the iterative displacement reconstruction in Ref. [2] can recover the true displacement field with a particular emphasis on improving the numerical discreteness effect and improving the perturbation theory model for the postreconstructed field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric identification of compact galaxies, stars and quasars using multiple neural networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/photometric_identification_of_compact_galaxies_stars_and_quasars_using_multiple_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/photometric_identification_of_compact_galaxies_stars_and_quasars_using_multiple_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Siddharth Chaini
We present MargNet, a deep learning-based classifier for identifying stars, quasars and compact galaxies using photometric parameters and images from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) Data Release 16 (DR16) catalogue. MargNet consists of a combination of Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Artificial Neural Network (ANN) architectures. Using a carefully curated dataset consisting of 240,000 compact objects and an additional 150,000 faint objects, the machine learns classification directly from the data, minimising the need for human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of stochastic modeling on the predictive power of galaxy formation simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_impact_of_stochastic_modeling_on_the_predictive_power_of_galaxy_formation_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_impact_of_stochastic_modeling_on_the_predictive_power_of_galaxy_formation_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Josh Borrow
All modern galaxy formation models employ stochastic elements in their sub-grid prescriptions to discretise continuous equations across the time domain. In this paper, we investigate how the stochastic nature of these models, notably star formation, black hole accretion, and their associated feedback, that act on small ($&amp;lt;$ kpc) scales, can back-react on macroscopic galaxy properties (e.g. stellar mass and size) across long ($&amp;gt;$ Gyr) timescales. We find that the scatter in scaling relations predicted by the EAGLE model implemented in the SWIFT code can be significantly impacted by random variability between re-simulations of the same object, even when galaxies are resolved by tens of thousands of particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inefficiency of stellar feedback in driving galactic outflows in massive galaxies at high redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_inefficiency_of_stellar_feedback_in_driving_galactic_outflows_in_massive_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_inefficiency_of_stellar_feedback_in_driving_galactic_outflows_in_massive_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Bassini
Recent observations indicate that galactic outflows are ubiquitous in high redshift galaxies, including normal star forming galaxies, quasar hosts, and dusty star forming galaxies (DSFGs). However, the impact of outflows on the evolution of their hosts is still an open question. Here, we analyse the star formation histories (SFH) and galactic outflow properties of galaxies in massive haloes ($10^{12}M_{\odot}&amp;lt;M_{\rm vir} &amp;lt;5\times 10^{12}M_{\odot}$) at $z\gtrsim5.5$ in three zoom-in cosmological simulations from the MassiveFIRE suite, as part of the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A BayeSN Distance Ladder: $H_0$ from a consistent modelling of Type Ia supernovae from the optical to the near infrared</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suhail Dhawan
The local distance ladder estimate of the Hubble constant ($H_0$) is important in cosmology, given the recent tension with the early universe inference. We estimate $H_0$ from the Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) distance ladder, inferring SN Ia distances with the hierarchical Bayesian SED model, BayeSN. This method has a notable advantage of being able to continuously model the optical and near-infrared (NIR) SN Ia light curves simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new method for age-dating the formation of bars in disc galaxies: The TIMER view on NGC1433&#39;s old bar and the inside-out growth of its nuclear disc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_method_for_age-dating_the_formation_of_bars_in_disc_galaxies_the_timer_view_on_ngc1433s_old_bar_and_the_inside-out_growth_of_its_nuclear_disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_method_for_age-dating_the_formation_of_bars_in_disc_galaxies_the_timer_view_on_ngc1433s_old_bar_and_the_inside-out_growth_of_its_nuclear_disc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camila de Sá-Freitas
The epoch in which galactic discs settle is a major benchmark to test models of galaxy formation and evolution but is as yet largely unknown. Once discs settle and become self-gravitating enough, stellar bars are able to form; therefore, determining the ages of bars can shed light on the epoch of disc settling, and on the onset of secular evolution. Nevertheless, until now, timing when the bar formed has proven challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Physical Picture for AGNs Lacking Optical Emission Lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_new_physical_picture_for_agns_lacking_optical_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher J. Agostino
In this work, we use ~500 low-redshift (z ~ 0.1) X-ray AGNs observed by XMM-Newton and SDSS to investigate the prevalence and nature of AGNs that apparently lack optical emission lines (optically dull AGNs&#39;&#39;). Although 1/4 of spectra appear absorption-line dominated in visual assessment, line extraction with robust continuum subtraction from the MPA/JHU catalog reveals usable [OIII] measurements in 98% of the sample, allowing us to study [OIII]-underluminous AGNs together with more typical AGNs in the context of the L$_{\mathrm{[OIII]}}$--L$_{X}$ relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of local ultraluminous infrared galaxies and quasars with kernel principal component analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/classification_of_local_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_and_quasars_with_kernel_principal_component_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/classification_of_local_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_and_quasars_with_kernel_principal_component_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Evangelos S. Papaefthymiou
We present a new diagnostic diagram for local ultraluminous infrared galaxies (ULIRGs) and quasars, analysing particularly the Spitzer Space Telescope&amp;rsquo;s Infrared Spectrograph (IRS) spectra of 102 local ULIRGs and 37 Palomar Green quasars. Our diagram is based on a special non-linear mapping of these data, employing the Kernel Principal Component Analysis method. The novelty of this map lies in the fact that it distributes the galaxies under study on the surface of a well-defined ellipsoid, which, in turn, links basic concepts from geometry to physical properties of the galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Census: Relative Distributions of Dark Matter, Galaxies and Diffuse Gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmic_census_relative_distributions_of_dark_matter_galaxies_and_diffuse_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmic_census_relative_distributions_of_dark_matter_galaxies_and_diffuse_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Raphaël Kou
Galaxies, diffuse gas and dark matter make up the cosmic web defining the large-scale structure of the universe. We constrain the joint distribution of these constituents by cross-correlating galaxy samples binned by stellar mass from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey CMASS catalogue with maps of lensing convergence and the thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich (tSZ) effect from the Planck mission. Fitting a halo-based model to our measured angular power spectra (galaxy-galaxy, galaxy-lensing convergence, galaxy-tSZ) at a median redshift of $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints on unimodular gravity models with diffusion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmological_constraints_on_unimodular_gravity_models_with_diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cosmological_constraints_on_unimodular_gravity_models_with_diffusion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Susana J. Landau
A discrete space-time structure lying at about the Planck scale may become manifest in the form of very small violations of the conservation of the matter energy-momentum tensor. In order to include such kind of violations, forbidden within the General Relativity framework, the theory of unimodular gravity seems as the simplest option to describe the gravitational interaction. In the cosmological context, a direct consequence of such violation of energy conservation might be heuristically viewed a &amp;ldquo;diffusion process of matter (both dark and ordinary)&amp;rdquo; into an effective dark energy term in Einstein&amp;rsquo;s equations, which leads under natural assumptions to an adequate estimate for the value of the cosmological constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLARES VIII. The Emergence of Passive Galaxies in the Early Universe ($z &gt; 5$)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/flares_viii._the_emergence_of_passive_galaxies_in_the_early_universe__z__5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/flares_viii._the_emergence_of_passive_galaxies_in_the_early_universe__z__5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher C. Lovell
Passive galaxies are ubiquitous in the local universe, and various physical channels have been proposed that lead to this passivity. To date, robust passive galaxy candidates have been detected up to $z \leqslant 5$, but it is still unknown if they exist at higher redshifts, what their relative abundances are, and what causes them to stop forming stars. We present predictions from the First Light And Reionisation Epoch Simulations (FLARES), a series of zoom simulations of a range of overdensities using the EAGLE code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular Cluster Ultraluminous X-ray Sources in the Furthest Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_sources_in_the_furthest_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_sources_in_the_furthest_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Thygesen
Ultraluminous X-ray Sources (ULXs) in globular clusters are low mass X-ray binaries that achieve high X-ray luminosities through a currently uncertain accretion mechanism. Using archival Chandra and Hubble Space Telescope observations, we perform a volume-limited search ($\lesssim$ 70 Mpc) of 21 of the most massive ($&amp;gt;10^{11.5} M_\odot$) early-type galaxies to identify ULXs hosted by globular cluster (GC) candidates. We find a total of 34 ULX candidates above the expected background within 5 times the effective radius of each galaxy, with 10 of these ($\sim29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonthermal processes and particle acceleration in supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacco Vink
Shocks of supernova remnants (SNRs) accelerate charged particles up to 100 TeV range via diffusive shock acceleration (DSA) mechanism. It is believed that shocks of SNRs are the main contributors to the pool of Galactic cosmic rays, although it is still under debate whether they can accelerate particles up to the &amp;ldquo;knee&amp;rdquo; energy (10^15.5 eV) or not. In this chapter, we start with introducing SNRs as likely sources of cosmic rays and the radiation mechanisms associated with cosmic rays (section 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing quasar lifetimes with proximate $21$-centimetre absorption in the diffuse intergalactic medium at redshifts $z\geq 6$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_quasar_lifetimes_with_proximate__21_-centimetre_absorption_in_the_diffuse_intergalactic_medium_at_redshifts__z_geq_6_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_quasar_lifetimes_with_proximate__21_-centimetre_absorption_in_the_diffuse_intergalactic_medium_at_redshifts__z_geq_6_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tomáš Šoltinský
Enhanced ionizing radiation in close proximity to redshift $z\gtrsim 6$ quasars creates short windows of intergalactic Ly$\alpha$ transmission blueward of the quasar Ly$\alpha$ emission lines. The majority of these Ly$\alpha$ near-zones are consistent with quasars that have optically/UV bright lifetimes of $t_{\rm Q}\sim 10^{5}-10^{7}\rm,yr$. However, lifetimes as short as $t_{\rm Q}\lesssim 10^{4}\rm,yr$ appear to be required by the smallest Ly$\alpha$ near-zones. These short lifetimes present an apparent challenge for the growth of $\sim 10^{9}\rm,M_{\odot}$ black holes at $z\gtrsim 6$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1): Light Curves and Photometric Classification of 1975 Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. D. Aleo
We present the Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1), comprised of processed multi-color Pan-STARRS1 (PS1) griz and Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) gr photometry of 1975 transients with host-galaxy associations, redshifts, spectroscopic/photometric classifications, and additional data products from 2019 November 24 to 2021 December 20. YSE DR1 spans discoveries and observations from young and fast-rising supernovae (SNe) to transients that persist for over a year, with a redshift distribution reaching z~0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Galaxy Morphological Visual Representation with Deep Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/unsupervised_galaxy_morphological_visual_representation_with_deep_contrastive_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/unsupervised_galaxy_morphological_visual_representation_with_deep_contrastive_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shoulin Wei
Galaxy morphology reflects structural properties which contribute to understand the formation and evolution of galaxies. Deep convolutional networks have proven to be very successful in learning hidden features that allow for unprecedented performance on galaxy morphological classification. Such networks mostly follow the supervised learning paradigm which requires sufficient labelled data for training. However, it is an expensive and complicated process of labeling for million galaxies, particularly for the forthcoming survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: Public release of HI data for almost 600 galaxies from phase 1 of ASKAP pilot observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_data_for_almost_600_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_data_for_almost_600_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Westmeier
We present WALLABY pilot data release 1, the first public release of HI pilot survey data from the Wide-field ASKAP L-band Legacy All-sky Blind Survey (WALLABY) on the Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder. Phase 1 of the WALLABY pilot survey targeted three $60~{\rm deg}^2$ regions on the sky in the direction of the Hydra and Norma galaxy clusters and the NGC 4636 galaxy group, covering the redshift range of z &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: Public release of HI kinematic models for more than 100 galaxies from phase 1 of ASKAP pilot observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_kinematic_models_for_more_than_100_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_kinematic_models_for_more_than_100_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Deg
We present the Widefield ASKAP L-band Legacy All-sky Blind surveY (WALLABY) Pilot Phase I HI kinematic models. This first data release consists of HI observations of three fields in the direction of the Hydra and Norma clusters, and the NGC 4636 galaxy group. In this paper, we describe how we generate and publicly release flat-disk tilted-ring kinematic models for 109/592 unique HI detections in these fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the moderate UV/X-ray correlation in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/explaining_the_moderate_uv_x-ray_correlation_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Panagiotou
The UV/optical and X-ray variability of active galactic nuclei (AGN) have long been expected to be well correlated as a result of the X-ray illumination of the accretion disk. Recent monitoring campaigns of nearby AGN, however, found that their X-ray and UV/optical emission are only moderately correlated, challenging the aforementioned paradigm. In this work, we aim to demonstrate that due to the definition of the cross correlation function, a low UV/X-ray correlation is well expected in the case of an X-ray illuminated accretion disk, when the dynamic variability of the X-ray source is taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-detection of Broad Hydrogen Radio Recombination Lines in Circinus Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/non-detection_of_broad_hydrogen_radio_recombination_lines_in_circinus_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/non-detection_of_broad_hydrogen_radio_recombination_lines_in_circinus_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junzhi Wang
The line widths of broad line regions (BLRs) of AGNs are key parameters for understanding the central super massive black holes (SMBHs). However, due to obscuration from dusty torus, optical recombination lines from BLRs in type II AGNs can not be directly detected. Radio recombination lines (RRLs), with low extinction, can be ideal tracers to probe emission from BLRs in type II AGNs. We performed RRL observations for H35$\alpha$ and H36$\alpha$ toward the center of Circinus galaxy with ALMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the evolution of Type Ia supernovae with their ejecta velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. -C. Pan
There is growing evidence that Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are likely produced via multiple explosion channels. Understanding how different channels evolve with redshift is critical in determining their precision in measuring cosmological parameters. Previous studies indicated that SN Ia ejecta velocity is one powerful tool to differentiate between different channels. It was also suspected that the tight correlation with the host-galaxy environment could result in the evolution of SN ejecta velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fisher Forecasting for Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/beyond_fisher_forecasting_for_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/beyond_fisher_forecasting_for_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph Ryan
The planning and design of future experiments rely heavily on forecasting to assess the potential scientific value provided by a hypothetical set of measurements. The Fisher information matrix, due to its convenient properties and low computational cost, provides an especially useful forecasting tool. However, the Fisher matrix only provides a reasonable approximation to the true likelihood when data are nearly Gaussian distributed and observables have nearly linear dependence on the parameters of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating cosmological growth functions with B-Splines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/emulating_cosmological_growth_functions_with_b-splines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/emulating_cosmological_growth_functions_with_b-splines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ngai Pok Kwan
In the light of GPU accelerations, sequential operations such as solving ordinary differential equations can be bottlenecks for gradient evaluations and hinder potential speed gains. In this work, we focus on growth functions and their time derivatives in cosmological particle mesh simulations and show that these are the majority time cost when using gradient based inference algorithms. We propose to construct novel conditional B-spline emulators which directly learn an interpolating function for the growth factor as a function of time, conditioned on the cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological signatures of mergers in the TNG50 simulation and the Kilo-Degree Survey: the merger fraction from dwarfs to Milky Way-like galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.14123/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.14123/</guid>
      <description>Tiger Yu-Yang Hsiao
MACS0647$-$JD is a triply-lensed $z\sim11$ galaxy originally discovered with the Hubble Space Telescope. Here we report new JWST imaging, which clearly resolves MACS0647$-$JD as having two components that are either merging galaxies or stellar complexes within a single galaxy. Both are very small, with stellar masses $\sim10^8,M_\odot$ and radii $r&amp;lt;100,\rm pc$. The brighter larger component &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; is intrinsically very blue ($β\sim-2.6$), likely due to very recent star formation and no dust, and is spatially extended with an effective radius $\sim70,\rm pc$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological signatures of mergers in the TNG50 simulation and the Kilo-Degree Survey: the merger fraction from dwarfs to Milky Way-like galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05785/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05785/</guid>
      <description>Alejandro Guzmán-Ortega
Using the TNG50 cosmological simulation and observations from the Kilo-Degree Survey (KiDS), we investigate the connection between galaxy mergers and optical morphology in the local Universe over a wide range of galaxy stellar masses ($8.5\leqslant\log(M_\ast/\text{M}\odot)\leqslant11$). To this end, we have generated over 16,000 synthetic images of TNG50 galaxies designed to match KiDS observations, including the effects of dust attenuation and scattering, and used the $\mathrm{\mathtt{statmorph}}$ code to measure various image-based morphological diagnostics in the $r$-band for both data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing early universe through redshifted 21-cm signal: Modelling and observational challenges</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</guid>
      <description>Abinash Kumar Shaw
The redshifted 21-cm radiation from the atomic hydrogen (HI) provides an excellent direct probe to study the evolution of HI in IGM and thus reveal the nature of the first luminous objects, their evolution and role during Cosmic Dawn (CD) and Epoch of Reionization (EoR), and formation and evolution of the structures thereafter. Direct mapping of the HI density during the CD-EoR is rather difficult with the current and future instruments due to large foreground and other observational contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2022ann: A type Icn supernova from a dwarf galaxy that reveals helium in its circumstellar environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05134/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05134/</guid>
      <description>K. W. Davis
We present optical and near-infrared (NIR) observations of the Type Icn supernova (SN Icn) 2022ann, the fifth member of its newly identified class of SNe. Its early optical spectra are dominated by narrow carbon and oxygen P-Cygni features with absorption velocities of 800 km/s; slower than other SNe Icn and indicative of interaction with a dense, H/He-poor circumstellar medium (CSM) that is outflowing slower than a typical Wolf-Rayet wind velocity of $&amp;gt;$1000 km/s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of neutrino decoupling from the early universe to the current universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.10307/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.10307/</guid>
      <description>Kensuke Akita
We review the distortions of spectra of relic neutrinos due to the interactions with electrons, positrons, and neutrinos in the early universe. We solve integro-differential kinetic equations for the neutrino density matrix, including vacuum three-flavor neutrino oscillations, oscillations in electron and positron background, a collision term and finite temperature corrections to electron mass and electromagnetic plasma up to the next-to-leading order $\mathcal{O}(e^3)$. After that, we estimate the effects of the spectral distortions in neutrino decoupling on the number density and energy density of the Cosmic Neutrino Background (C$ν$B) in the current universe, and discuss the implications of these effects on the capture rates in direct detection of the C$ν$B on tritium, with emphasis on the PTOLEMY-type experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04503/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04503/</guid>
      <description>Roark Habegger
In galactic disks, the Parker instability results when non-thermal pressure support exceeds a certain threshold. The non-thermal pressures considered in the Parker instability are cosmic ray pressure and magnetic pressure. This instability takes a long time to saturate $(&amp;gt;500 , \mathrm{Myr})$ and assumes a background with fixed cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio. In reality, galactic cosmic rays are injected into localized regions $(&amp;lt; 100 ,\mathrm{pc})$ by events like supernovae, increasing the cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05275/</guid>
      <description>Ray S. Sharma
We examine the quenching characteristics of $328$ isolated dwarf galaxies $\left(10^{8} &amp;lt; M_{\rm star}/M_\odot &amp;lt; 10^{10} \right)$ within the \Rom{} cosmological hydrodynamic simulation. Using mock observation methods, we identify isolated dwarf galaxies with quenched star formation and make direct comparisons to the quenched fraction in the NASA Sloan Atlas (NSA). Similar to other cosmological simulations, we find a population of quenched, isolated dwarf galaxies below $M_{\rm star} &amp;lt; 10^{9} M_\odot$ not detected within the NSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and dynamics of the peculiar stream Jhelum, A tentative role for the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2202.02132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2202.02132/</guid>
      <description>Hanneke C. Woudenberg
Stellar streams are a promising tool to study the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s dark matter subhalo population, as interactions with subhalos could produce substructure in streams. However, other possible causes for substructure first need to be well understood. Here we study the kinematics and the unusual morphology of the stellar stream Jhelum. Using a combination of ground-based photometry and Gaia EDR3 astrometry we characterize the morphology of Jhelum. We combine this new data with radial velocities from the literature to perform orbit integrations of the stream in static Galactic potentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic inhomogeneities in the early Universe: A numerical relativity approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03534/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03534/</guid>
      <description>Cristian Joana
Cosmic inflation is arguably the most favoured paradigm of the very early Universe. It postulates an early phase of fast, nearly exponential, and accelerated expansion. Inflationary models are capable of explaining the overall flatness and homogeneity of today&amp;rsquo;s Universe at large scales. Despite being widely accepted by the physics community, these models are not absent from criticism. In scalar field inflation, a necessary condition to begin inflation is the requirement of a Universe dominated by the field&amp;rsquo;s potential, which implies a subdominant contribution from the scalar field dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between the globular cluster systems of the Virgo and Fornax Galaxy Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02711/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02711/</guid>
      <description>J. Dabringhausen
It is well known that Globular cluster systems are different among galaxies. Here we test to which degree these differences remain on the scale of galaxy clusters by comparing the globular clusters (GCs) in optical surveys of the Virgo galaxy cluster (ACSVCS) and the Fornax galaxy cluster (ACSFCS) in Kolmogorov-Smirnoff Tests. Both surveys were obtained with the Advanced Camera for Surveys (ACS) on board the Hubble Space Telescope, and contain thousands of GCs in dozens of galaxies each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a double sequence of blue straggler stars in the core-collapsed globular cluster NGC 6256</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02671/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02671/</guid>
      <description>Mario Cadelano
We used a combination of high-resolution optical images acquired with the Hubble Space Telescope and near-IR wide-field data to investigate the stellar density profile and the population of blue straggler star (BSS) in the Galactic globular cluster NGC6256, with the aim of probing its current stage of internal dynamical evolution. We found that the inner stellar density profile significantly deviates from a King model while is well reproduced by a steep cusp with a power-law slope alpha=-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a new Local Group Dwarf Galaxy Candidate in UNIONS: Boötes V</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.08242/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.08242/</guid>
      <description>Simon E. T. Smith
We present the discovery of Boötes V, a new ultra-faint dwarf galaxy candidate. This satellite is detected as a resolved overdensity of stars during an ongoing search for new Local Group dwarf galaxy candidates in the UNIONS photometric dataset. It has a physical half-light radius of 26.9$^{+7.5}_{-5.4}$ pc, a $V$-band magnitude of $-$4.5 $\pm$ 0.4 mag, and resides at a heliocentric distance of approximately 100 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinguishing Dark Matter Cusps from Cores using Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01384/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01384/</guid>
      <description>Shaunak Modak
Globular Clusters (GCs) provide valuable insight into the properties of their host galaxies&amp;rsquo; dark matter halos. Using N-body simulations incorporating semianalytic dynamical friction and GC-GC merger prescriptions, we study the evolution of GC radial distributions and mass functions in cuspy and cored dark matter halos. Modeling the dynamics of the GC-rich system in the dwarf galaxy UGC7369, we find that friction-induced inspiral and subsequent mergers of massive GCs can naturally and robustly explain the mass segregation of the GCs and the existence of a nuclear star cluster (NSC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DUVET: Spatially Resolved Observations of Star Formation Regulation via Galactic Outflows in a Starbursting Disk Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02063/</guid>
      <description>Bronwyn Reichardt Chu
We compare 500~pc scale, resolved observations of ionised and molecular gas for the $z\sim0.02$ starbursting disk galaxy IRAS08339+6517, using measurements from KCWI and NOEMA. We explore the relationship of the star formation driven ionised gas outflows with colocated galaxy properties. We find a roughly linear relationship between the outflow mass flux ($\dotΣ_{\rm out}$) and star formation rate surface density ($Σ_{\rm SFR}$), $\dotΣ_{\rm out}\proptoΣ_{\rm SFR}^{1.06\pm0.10}$, and a strong correlation between $\dotΣ_{\rm out}$ and the gas depletion time, such that $\dotΣ_{\rm out} \propto t_{dep}^{-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Stellar Parameters Estimation through CMD of Star Clusters: Open (NGC2360) and Globular (NGC 5272)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.03019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.03019/</guid>
      <description>Kanwar Preet Kaur
The fundamentals of estimating essential stellar parameters of an open cluster-NGC 2360 and globular clusters-NGC 5272 are presented extensively in this work. Here, the evaluation of stellar parameters, by manually fitting the appropriate isochrones on the color magnitude diagrams (CMDs), of the selected star clusters is discussed comprehensively. Aperture photometry and PSF fitting photometry are conducted on g, r, and i standard band filter images of Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) using the aperture photometry tool (APT) to obtain the respective CMDs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-rich, field ultra-diffuse galaxies host few globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00650/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00650/</guid>
      <description>S. Jang
Hubble Space Telescope (HST) photometry is providing an extensive analysis of globular clusters (GCs). In particular, the pseudo two-colour diagram dubbed &#39;chromosome map (ChM)&#39; allowed to detect and characterize their multiple populations with unprecedented detail. The main limitation of these studies is the small field of view of HST, which makes it challenging to investigate some important aspects of the multiple populations, such as their spatial distributions and the internal kinematics in the outermost cluster regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-rich, field ultra-diffuse galaxies host few globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00651/</guid>
      <description>Michael G. Jones
We present Hubble Space Telescope imaging of 14 gas-rich, low surface brightness and ultra-diffuse galaxies (UDGs) in the field at distances of 25-36 Mpc. An inspection of point-like sources brighter than the turnover magnitude of the globular cluster luminosity function and within twice the half-light radii of each galaxy reveals that, unlike those in denser environments, gas-rich, field UDGs host very few old globular clusters (GCs). Most of the targets (nine) have zero candidate GCs, with the remainder having one or two candidates each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster formation with multiple stellar populations: A single-binary composite scenario</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.00344/</guid>
      <description>Kenji Bekki
We discuss a GC formation scenario in which the first generation (1G) of single asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars and intermediate-mass close binaries (IMCBs) eject gas, from which the second generation (2G) of stars can be formed. The two key parameters in the scenario are the fractions of binary stars (f_b) and the slopes (alpha) of the stellar initial mass functions (IMFs) for 1G stars. Principle results derived by analytic and one-zone models of GC formation are as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Population III homogeneous stellar evolution on early cosmic reionisation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.15125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.15125/</guid>
      <description>Yves Sibony
Context: Population III (Pop III) stars may be fast rotating. An expected consequence of fast rotation is strong internal mixing that deeply affects their evolutionary tracks in the Hertzsprung-Russell diagram and hence their ionising power. aims: We investigate the impact on the ionising power of Pop III stars in an extreme case of internal mixing, the one leading to chemically homogeneous evolution (CHE). In that situation, during the main sequence phase, the star keeps the same chemical composition from its center to its surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting Kilonovae: Long-lasting Electromagnetic Counterparts to Binary Mergers in the Accretion Disks of Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03097/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03097/</guid>
      <description>Jia Ren
We investigate the dynamics and electromagnetic (EM) signatures of neutron star-neutron star (NS-NS) or neutron star-black hole (NS-BH) merger ejecta that occurs in the accretion disk of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We find that the interaction between ejecta and disk gas leads to important effects on the dynamics and radiation. We show five stages of the ejecta dynamics: gravitational slowing down, coasting, Sedov-Taylor deceleration in the disk, re-acceleration after the breakout from the disk surface, and momentum-conserved snowplow phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic signatures of impulsive supernova feedback in dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03795/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03795/</guid>
      <description>Jan D. Burger
Impulsive supernova feedback and non-standard dark matter models, such as self-interacting dark matter (SIDM), are the two main contenders for the role of the dominant core formation mechanism at the dwarf galaxy scale. Here we show that the impulsive supernova cycles that follow episodes of bursty star formation leave distinct features in the distribution function of stars: groups of stars with similar ages and metallicities develop overdense shells in phase space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the observability and identification of Population III galaxies with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02038/</guid>
      <description>James A. A. Trussler
We utilise theoretical models of Population III stellar+nebular spectra to investigate the prospects of observing and accurately identifying Population III galaxies with JWST using both deep imaging and spectroscopy. We investigate a series of different colour cuts, finding that a combination of NIRCam and MIRI photometry through the F444W-F560W, F560W-F770W colours offers the most robust identifier of potential $z=8$ Pop III candidates. We calculate that NIRCam will have to reach $\sim$ 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANDORA project: photo-nuclear reactions below A=60</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03986/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03986/</guid>
      <description>A. Tamii, L. Pellegri
Photo-nuclear reactions of light nuclei below a mass of $A=60$ are studied experimentally and theoretically by the PANDORA (Photo-Absorption of Nuclei and Decay Observation for Reactions in Astrophysics) project. Two experimental methods, virtual-photon excitation by proton scattering and real-photo absorption by a high-brilliance gamma-ray beam produced by laser Compton scattering, will be applied to measure the photo-absorption cross sections and the decay branching ratio of each decay channel as a function of the photon energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of globular clusters formed in dark matter mini-halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2112.01265/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2112.01265/</guid>
      <description>Eduardo Vitral
We seek to differentiate dynamical and morphological attributes between globular clusters (GCs) that were formed inside their own dark matter (DM) mini-halo, and those who were not. We employ high resolution full N-body simulations on GPU of GCs with and without a DM mini-halo, orbiting a Fornax-like dwarf galaxy. For GCs with DM, we observe that this dark extra mass triggers a tidal radius growth that allows the mini-halo to act as a protective shield against tidal stripping, being itself stripped beforehand the stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of globular clusters formed in dark matter mini-halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04485/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04485/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mass-Metallicity Relation of Dwarf Galaxies at the Cosmic Noon in the JWST Era</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01382/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01382/</guid>
      <description>Mingyu Li, Zheng Cai
We present the mass-metallicity relation (MZR) at $z=2-3$ in the stellar mass range of $M_\star\approx 10^{6.5}-10^{9.5}M_\odot$ using 55 dwarf galaxies in the Abell 2744 and SMACS J0723-3732 galaxy cluster fields. These dwarf galaxies are identified and confirmed by deep JWST/NIRISS imaging and slitless grism spectroscopic observations. Taking advantage of the gravitational lensing effect, we extend the previous MZR relation at $z=2-3$ to a much lower mass regime by more than 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present-day gas content of simulated field dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.11782/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.11782/</guid>
      <description>Georg Herzog
We examine the gas content of field dwarf galaxies in a high-resolution cosmological simulation. In agreement with previous work, we find that galaxies inhabiting dark matter haloes with mass below a critical value, $M_{200} \lesssim M_{\rm crit} \approx 5\times 10^{9} \ M_{\odot}$, are quiescent at the present day. The gas content of these galaxies is thus insensitive to feedback from evolving stars. Almost half of these quiescent systems today have gas masses much smaller than that expected for their mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Candidates for Dual AGN in Dwarf-Dwarf Galaxy Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04609/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04609/</guid>
      <description>Marko Mićić
Dual AGN are important for understanding galaxy-merger-triggered fueling of black holes and hierarchical growth of structures. The least explored type of dual AGN are those associated with mergers of two dwarf galaxies. According to observations and cosmological simulations, dwarf galaxies are the most abundant type of galaxies in the early Universe and the galaxy merger rate is dominated by dwarfs. However, these mergers are generally too distant to be directly observed, and low-redshift dwarf-dwarf merger-related dual AGN are notoriously hard to find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Physics Informed Neural Networks for Supernova Radiative Transfer Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05219/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05219/</guid>
      <description>Xingzhuo Chen
We use physics informed neural networks (PINNs) to solve the radiative transfer equation and calculate a synthetic spectrum for a Type Ia supernova (SN~Ia) SN 2011fe. The calculation is based on local thermodynamic equilibrium (LTE) and 9 elements are included. Physical processes included are approximate radiative equilibrium, bound-bound transitions, and the Doppler effect. A PINN based gamma-ray scattering approximation is used for radioactive decay energy deposition. The PINN synthetic spectrum is compared to an observed spectrum, a synthetic spectrum calculated by the Monte-Carlo radiative transfer program TARDIS, and the formal solution of the radiative transfer equation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
