<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AIROPA II: Modeling Instrumental Aberrations for Off-Axis Point Spread Functions in Adaptive Optics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/airopa_ii_modeling_instrumental_aberrations_for_off-axis_point_spread_functions_in_adaptive_optics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/airopa_ii_modeling_instrumental_aberrations_for_off-axis_point_spread_functions_in_adaptive_optics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Ciurlo
Images obtained with single-conjugate adaptive optics (AO) show spatial variation of the point spread function (PSF) due to both atmospheric anisoplanatism and instrumental aberrations. The poor knowledge of the PSF across the field of view strongly impacts the ability to take full advantage of AO capabilities. The AIROPA project aims to model these PSF variations for the NIRC2 imager at the Keck Observatory. Here, we present the characterization of the instrumental phase aberrations over the entire NIRC2 field of view and we present a new metric for quantifying the quality of the calibration, the fraction of variance unexplained (FVU).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of two new interstellar molecules with QUIJOTE: HCCCHCCC and HCCCCS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/discovery_of_two_new_interstellar_molecules_with_quijote_hccchccc_and_hccccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/discovery_of_two_new_interstellar_molecules_with_quijote_hccchccc_and_hccccs/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Fuentetaja
We report on the discovery of two new molecules, HCCCHCCC and HCCCCS, towards the starless core TMC-1 in the Taurus region from the QUIJOTE line survey in the 31.1-50.2 GHz frequency range. We identify a total of twenty-nine lines of HCCCHCCC and six rotational transitions of HCCCCS. The rotational quantum numbers range from Ju=10 up to 15 and Ka &amp;lt;=2 for HCCCHCCC and Ju=21/2 up to 31/2 for HCCCCS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface instabilities in hydrodynamic relativistic jets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/interface_instabilities_in_hydrodynamic_relativistic_jets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/interface_instabilities_in_hydrodynamic_relativistic_jets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pavel Abolmasov
Both the dynamics and the observational properties of relativistic jets are determined by their interaction with the ambient medium. A crucial role is played by the contact discontinuity at the jet boundary, which in the presence of jet collimation may become subject to Rayleigh-Taylor instability (RTI) and Richtmyer-Meshkov instability (RMI). Here, we study the evolution of these instabilities in non-magnetized relativistic jets using special relativistic three-dimensional hydrodynamic simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower-than-expected flare temperatures for TRAPPIST-1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lower-than-expected_flare_temperatures_for_trappist-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lower-than-expected_flare_temperatures_for_trappist-1/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Maas
Although high energetic radiation from flares is a potential threat to exoplanet atmospheres and may lead to surface sterilization, it might also provide the extra energy for low-mass stars needed to trigger and sustain prebiotic chemistry. We investigate two flares on TRAPPIST-1, an ultra-cool dwarf star that hosts seven exoplanets of which three lie within its habitable zone. The flares are detected in all four passbands of the MuSCAT2 allowing a determination of their temperatures and bolometric energies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the origin of the dichotomy of stellar activity cycles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_origin_of_the_dichotomy_of_stellar_activity_cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_origin_of_the_dichotomy_of_stellar_activity_cycles/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alfio Bonanno
The presence of possible correlations between stellar rotation rate $\Omega$ and the frequency of the activity cycle $\omega_\mathrm{cyc}$ is still much debated. We implement a new Bayesian classification algorithm based on a simultaneous regression analysis of multiple scaling laws and we demonstrate the existence of two different scalings in the $\log_{10} \omega_\mathrm{cyc}$ &amp;ndash; $\log_{10} \Omega$ plane for an extended Mt.~Wilson sample of 67 stars. Thanks to metallicity measurements obtained from both ESA Gaia and high-resolution spectroscopy, we argue that the origin of this dichotomy is likely related to the chemical composition: stars whose magnetic cycle frequency increases with rotation rate are less metallic than stars whose magnetic cycle frequency decreases with stellar rotation rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Initial Magnetic Field Distribution in AB Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_initial_magnetic_field_distribution_in_ab_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_initial_magnetic_field_distribution_in_ab_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eoin Farrell
Stars are born with magnetic fields, but the distribution of their initial field strengths remains uncertain. We combine observations with theoretical models of magnetic field evolution to infer the initial distribution of magnetic fields for AB stars in the mass range of 1.6 - 3.4 M$_{\odot}$. We tested a variety of distributions with different shapes and found that a distribution with a mean of $\sim$800 G and a full width of $\sim$600 G is most consistent with the observed fraction of strongly magnetized stars as a function of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Treatise on Converting Stellar Mass Fractions to Abundances to Molar Ratios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_concise_treatise_on_converting_stellar_mass_fractions_to_abundances_to_molar_ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_concise_treatise_on_converting_stellar_mass_fractions_to_abundances_to_molar_ratios/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalie R. Hinkel
Understanding stellar composition is fundamental not only to our comprehension of the galaxy, especially chemical evolution, but it can also shed light on the interior structure and mineralogy of exoplanets, which are formed from the same material as their host stars. Unfortunately, the underlying mathematics describing stellar mass fractions and stellar elemental abundances is difficult to parse, fragmented across the literature, and contains vexing omissions that makes any calculation far from trivial, especially for non-experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Low-Mass, Pre-Main Sequence Eclipsing Binary in the 40 Myr Columba Association -- Fundamental Stellar Parameters and Modeling the Effect of Star Spots</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_low-mass_pre-main_sequence_eclipsing_binary_in_the_40_myr_columba_association_--_fundamental_stellar_parameters_and_modeling_the_effect_of_star_spots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_low-mass_pre-main_sequence_eclipsing_binary_in_the_40_myr_columba_association_--_fundamental_stellar_parameters_and_modeling_the_effect_of_star_spots/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin M. Tofflemire
Young eclipsing binaries (EBs) are powerful probes of early stellar evolution. Current models are unable to simultaneously reproduce the measured and derived properties that are accessible for EB systems (e.g., mass, radius, temperature, luminosity). In this study we add a benchmark EB to the pre-main sequence population with our characterization of TOI 450 (TIC 77951245). Using \gaia\ astrometry to identify its comoving, coeval companions, we confirm TOI 450 is a member of the $\sim$40 Myr Columba association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Ring Galaxies Detected Using Deep Learning with Real and Simulated Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/analysis_of_ring_galaxies_detected_using_deep_learning_with_real_and_simulated_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/analysis_of_ring_galaxies_detected_using_deep_learning_with_real_and_simulated_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Harish Krishnakumar
Understanding the formation and evolution of ring galaxies, galaxies with an atypical ring-like structure, will improve understanding of black holes and galaxy dynamics as a whole. Current catalogs of rings are extremely limited: manual analysis takes months to accumulate an appreciable sample of rings and existing computational methods are vastly limited in terms of accuracy and detection rate. Without a sizable sample of rings, further research into their properties is severely restricted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death at watersheds: galaxy quenching in low-density environments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/death_at_watersheds_galaxy_quenching_in_low-density_environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/death_at_watersheds_galaxy_quenching_in_low-density_environments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maret Einasto
Our aim is to understand the effect of environment to galaxy quenching in various local and global environments. We focus on galaxies with very old stellar populations (VO galaxies), typically found in the centers of clusters and groups, and search for such galaxies in the lowest global density environments, watersheds between superclusters. We use the Sloan Digital Sky Survey MAIN galaxy sample to calculate the luminosity-density field and get global density field, to determine groups and filaments, and to obtain data on galaxy properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble WFC3 Spectroscopy of the Rocky Planet L 98-59 b: No Evidence for a Cloud-Free Primordial Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hubble_wfc3_spectroscopy_of_the_rocky_planet_l_98-59_b_no_evidence_for_a_cloud-free_primordial_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hubble_wfc3_spectroscopy_of_the_rocky_planet_l_98-59_b_no_evidence_for_a_cloud-free_primordial_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Li Zhou
We are using archived data from HST of transiting exoplanet L~98-59~b to place constraints on its potentially hot atmosphere. We analyze the data from five transit visits and extract the final combined transmission spectrum using Iraclis. Then we use the inverse atmospheric retrieval code TauREx to analyze the combined transmission spectrum. There is a weak absorption feature near 1.40~$\mu m$ and 1.55~$\mu m$ in the transmission spectrum, which can be modeled by a cloudy atmosphere with abundant HCN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Lemaitre-Tolman model and the mass and turn-around radius in group of galaxies II: the role of dark energy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/improved_lemaitre-tolman_model_and_the_mass_and_turn-around_radius_in_group_of_galaxies_ii_the_role_of_dark_energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/improved_lemaitre-tolman_model_and_the_mass_and_turn-around_radius_in_group_of_galaxies_ii_the_role_of_dark_energy/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Del Popolo
In this paper, we extend our previous study \cite{DelPopolo2021} on the Lemaitre-Tolman (LT) model showing how the prediction of the model changes when the equation of state parameter ($w$) of dark energy is modified. In the previous study, it was considered that dark energy was merely constituted by the cosmological constant. In this paper, as in the previous study, we also took into account the effect of angular momentum and dynamical friction ($J\eta$ LT model) that modifies the evolution of a perturbation, initially moving with the Hubble flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LavAtmos: An open source chemical equilibrium vaporisation code for lava worlds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lavatmos_an_open_source_chemical_equilibrium_vaporisation_code_for_lava_worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lavatmos_an_open_source_chemical_equilibrium_vaporisation_code_for_lava_worlds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christiaan van Buchem
To date, over 500 short-period rocky planets with equilibrium temperatures above 1500 K have been discovered. Such planets are expected to support magma oceans, providing a direct interface between the interior and atmosphere. This provides a unique opportunity to gain insight into their interior compositions through atmospheric observations. A key process in doing such work is the vapor outgassing from the lava surface. LavAtmos is an open-source code that calculates the equilibrium chemical composition of vapor above a melt for a given composition and temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Lensing by Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/strong_lensing_by_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/strong_lensing_by_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Shajib
Strong lensing at the galaxy-scale is useful for numerous applications in Astrophysics and Cosmology. Some of the principal applications are studying the mass structure of elliptical galaxies, their formation and evolution, constraining the stellar initial mass function, and measuring cosmological parameters. Since the first discovery of a galaxy-scale strong lens in the eighties, this field has come a long way in terms of data quality and availability, and techniques to model the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The stability of galaxies in an expanding universe obtained by Newtonian dynamics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_stability_of_galaxies_in_an_expanding_universe_obtained_by_newtonian_dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_stability_of_galaxies_in_an_expanding_universe_obtained_by_newtonian_dynamics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Søren Toxvaerd
The dynamics of galaxies in an expanding universe is often determined for gravitational and dark matter in an Einstein-de Sitter universe, or alternatively by modifying the gravitational long-range attractions in the Newtonian dynamics (MOND). Here the time evolution of galaxies is determined by simulations of systems with pure gravitational forces by classical Molecular Dynamic simulations. A time reversible algorithm for formation and aging of gravitational systems by self-assembly of baryonic objects, recently derived (Eur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lagrangian construction of rotating stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_lagrangian_construction_of_rotating_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_lagrangian_construction_of_rotating_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Misa Ogata
We present a new formulation for numerically obtaining axisymmetric equilibrium structures of rotating stars in two spatial dimensions. With a view to apply it to the secular evolution of rotating stars, we base it on the Lagrangian description, i.e., we solve the force-balance equations to find the spatial positions of fluid elements endowed individually with a mass, specific entropy and angular momentum. The system of nonlinear equations obtained by finite-differencing the basic equations are solved with the W4 method, which is a new multi-dimensional root-finding scheme of our own devising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Metallicity of Cool Supergiant Formation. I. Effects on Stellar Mass Loss and Feedback</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/critical_metallicity_of_cool_supergiant_formation._i._effects_on_stellar_mass_loss_and_feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/critical_metallicity_of_cool_supergiant_formation._i._effects_on_stellar_mass_loss_and_feedback/</guid>
      <description>First author: Po-Sheng Ou
This paper systematically studies the relation between metallicity and mass loss of massive stars. We perform one-dimensional stellar evolution simulations and build a grid of $\sim$2000 models with initial masses ranging between 11 and 60 $M_{\odot}$ and absolute metallicities $Z$ between 0.00001 and 0.02. Steady-state winds, comprising hot main-sequence winds and cool supergiant winds, are the main drivers of the mass loss of massive stars in our models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HD 222925: a New Opportunity to Explore the Astrophysical and Nuclear Conditions of r-process Sites</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hd_222925_a_new_opportunity_to_explore_the_astrophysical_and_nuclear_conditions_of_r-process_sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hd_222925_a_new_opportunity_to_explore_the_astrophysical_and_nuclear_conditions_of_r-process_sites/</guid>
      <description>First author: Erika M. Holmbeck
With the most trans-iron elements detected of any star outside the Solar System, HD 222925 represents the most complete chemical inventory among r-process-enhanced, metal-poor stars. While the abundance pattern of the heaviest elements identified in HD 222925 agrees with the scaled Solar r-process residuals, as is characteristic of its r-process-enhanced classification, the newly measured lighter r-process elements display marked differences from their Solar counterparts. In this work, we explore which single astrophysical site (if any) produced the entire range of elements ($34\leq Z\leq 90$) present in HD 222925.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean opacities of a strongly magnetized high temperature plasma</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mean_opacities_of_a_strongly_magnetized_high_temperature_plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mean_opacities_of_a_strongly_magnetized_high_temperature_plasma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Valery F. Suleimanov
Geometry and dynamical structure of emission regions in accreting pulsars are shaped by the interplay between gravity, radiation, and strong magnetic field, which significantly affects the opacities of a plasma and radiative pressure under such extreme conditions. Quantitative consideration of magnetic plasma opacities is, therefore, an essential ingredient of any self-consistent modeling of emission region structure of X-ray pulsars. We present results of computations of the Rosseland and Planck mean opacities of a strongly magnetized plasma with a simple chemical composition,namely the solar hydrogen/helium mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapster: a fast code for dynamical formation of black-hole binaries in dense star clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/rapster_a_fast_code_for_dynamical_formation_of_black-hole_binaries_in_dense_star_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/rapster_a_fast_code_for_dynamical_formation_of_black-hole_binaries_in_dense_star_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Konstantinos Kritos
Gravitational-wave observations have just started probing the properties of black-hole binary merger populations. The observation of binaries with very massive black holes and small mass ratios motivates the study of dense star clusters as astrophysical environments which can produce such events dynamically. In this paper we present Rapster (for &amp;ldquo;Rapid cluster evolution&amp;rdquo;), a new code designed to rapidly model binary black hole population synthesis and the evolution of star clusters based on simple, yet realistic prescriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The orbital evolution of Atira asteroids</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_orbital_evolution_of_atira_asteroids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_orbital_evolution_of_atira_asteroids/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hsuan-Ting Lai
Asteroids having perihelion distance $q$ $&amp;lt;$ 1.3 AU are classified as near-Earth objects (NEOs), which are divided into different sub-groups: Vatira-class, Atira-class, Aten-class, Apollo-class, and Amor-class. 2020 $AV_2$, the first Vatira (Orbiting totally inside Venus&amp;rsquo; orbit) was discovered by the Twilight project of the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) on January 4, 2020. Upon the discovery of 2020 $AV_2$, a couple of orbital studies of the short-term orbital evolution of 2020 $AV_2$ have been performed and published (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A population of Type Ibc supernovae with massive progenitors; broad lightcurves not uncommon in (i)PTF</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_population_of_type_ibc_supernovae_with_massive_progenitors_broad_lightcurves_not_uncommon_in_iptf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_population_of_type_ibc_supernovae_with_massive_progenitors_broad_lightcurves_not_uncommon_in_iptf/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Karamehmetoglu
If high-mass stars (&amp;gt;20-25 Msun) are the progenitors of stripped-envelope (SE) supernovae (SNe), their massive ejecta should lead to broad, long-duration lightcurves (LCs). Instead, literature samples of SE~SNe have reported relatively narrow LCs with ejecta masses between 1-4 Msun that favor progenitors &amp;lt;20-25 Msun. Working with the untargeted sample of (i)PTF SNe to better constrain their rates, we search for SE~SNe with broad LCs. Using a simple LC stretch compared to a template to measure broadness, we identified eight significantly broader Type~Ibc SNe after applying quantitative sample selection criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALMACAL IX: multi-band ALMA survey for dusty star-forming galaxies and the resolved fractions of the cosmic infrared background</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/almacal_ix_multi-band_alma_survey_for_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_and_the_resolved_fractions_of_the_cosmic_infrared_background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/almacal_ix_multi-band_alma_survey_for_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_and_the_resolved_fractions_of_the_cosmic_infrared_background/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jianhang Chen
Wide, deep, blind continuum surveys at submillimetre/millimetre (submm/mm) wavelengths are required to provide a full inventory of the dusty, distant Universe. However, conducting such surveys to the necessary depth, with sub-arcsec angular resolution, is prohibitively time-consuming, even for the most advanced submm/mm telescopes. Here, we report the most recent results from the ALMACAL project, which exploits the &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; calibration data from the Atacama Large Millimetre/submillimetre Array (ALMA) to map the lines of sight towards and beyond the ALMA calibrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemically Peculiar Stars in the Open Cluster Stock 2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/chemically_peculiar_stars_in_the_open_cluster_stock_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/chemically_peculiar_stars_in_the_open_cluster_stock_2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laia Casamiquela
The recently re-discovered open cluster Stock 2, located roughly 375 pc away and about 400 Myr old, has the potential to be an exciting new testbed for our understanding of stellar evolution. We present results from a spectroscopic campaign to characterize stars near the cluster&amp;rsquo;s main-sequence turnoff; our goal is to identify candidate chemically peculiar stars among the cluster&amp;rsquo;s A stars. We obtained echelle spectra for 64 cluster members with ESPaDOnS on the 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectro-spatial evolution of the CMB I: discretisation of the thermalisation Green&#39;s function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_i_discretisation_of_the_thermalisation_greens_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_i_discretisation_of_the_thermalisation_greens_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jens Chluba
Spectral distortions of the cosmic microwave background (CMB) have been recognized as an important future probe of the early Universe. Existing theoretical studies primarily focused on describing the evolution and creation of average distortions, ignoring spatial perturbations in the plasma. One of the main reasons for this choice is that a treatment of the spectro-spatial evolution of the photon field deep into the primordial Universe requires solving a radiative transfer problem for the distortion signals, which in full detail is computationally challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stability analysis of planetary systems via second-order Rényi entropy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/stability_analysis_of_planetary_systems_via_second-order_r%C3%A9nyi_entropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/stability_analysis_of_planetary_systems_via_second-order_r%C3%A9nyi_entropy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tamás Kovács
The long-term dynamical evolution is a crucial point in recent planetary research. Although the amount of observational data is continuously growing and the precision allows us to obtain accurate planetary orbits, the canonical stability analysis still requires N-body simulations and phase space trajectory investigations. We propose a method for stability analysis of planetary motion based on the generalized R&#39;enyi entropy obtained from a scalar measurement. The radial velocity data of the central body in the gravitational three-body problem is used as the basis of a phase space reconstruction procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Turbulent Vertical Mixing in the Venus Clouds on Chemical Tracers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_impact_of_turbulent_vertical_mixing_in_the_venus_clouds_on_chemical_tracers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_impact_of_turbulent_vertical_mixing_in_the_venus_clouds_on_chemical_tracers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maxence Lefèvre
Venus clouds host a convective layer between roughly 50 and 60 km that mixes heat, momentum, and chemical species. Observations and numerical modelling have helped to understand the complexity of this region. However, the impact on chemistry is still not known. Here, we use for the first time a three-dimensional convection-resolving model with passive tracers to mimic SO$_2$ and H$_2$O for two latitudinal cases. The tracers are relaxed towards a vertical profile in agreement with measured values, with a timescale varying over several orders of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal and Reionisation History within a Large-volume Semi-Analytic Galaxy Formation Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/thermal_and_reionisation_history_within_a_large-volume_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/thermal_and_reionisation_history_within_a_large-volume_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sreedhar Balu
We predict the 21-cm global signal and power spectra during the Epoch of Reionisation using the MERAXES semi-analytic galaxy formation and reionisation model, updated to include X-ray heating and thermal evolution of the intergalactic medium. Studying the formation and evolution of galaxies together with the reionisation of cosmic hydrogen using semi-analytic models (such as MERAXES) requires N-body simulations within large volumes and high mass resolutions. For this, we use a simulation of side-length $210$ $h^{-1}$ Mpc with $4320^3$ particles resolving dark matter haloes to masses of $5\times10^8$ $h^{-1}$ $M_\odot$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-969: a late-K dwarf with a hot mini-Neptune in the desert and an eccentric cold Jupiter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/toi-969_a_late-k_dwarf_with_a_hot_mini-neptune_in_the_desert_and_an_eccentric_cold_jupiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/toi-969_a_late-k_dwarf_with_a_hot_mini-neptune_in_the_desert_and_an_eccentric_cold_jupiter/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Lillo-Box
The current architecture of a given multi-planetary system is a key fingerprint of its past formation and dynamical evolution history. Long-term follow-up observations are key to complete their picture. In this paper we focus on the confirmation and characterization of the components of the TOI-969 planetary system, where TESS detected a Neptune-size planet candidate in a very close-in orbit around a late K-dwarf star. We use a set of precise radial velocity observations from HARPS, PFS and CORALIE instruments covering more than two years in combination with the TESS photometric light curve and other ground-based follow-up observations to confirm and characterize the components of this planetary system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M31N 1926-07c: A Recurrent Nova in M31 with a 2.8 Year Recurrence Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/m31n_1926-07c_a_recurrent_nova_in_m31_with_a_2.8_year_recurrence_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/m31n_1926-07c_a_recurrent_nova_in_m31_with_a_2.8_year_recurrence_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Allen W. Shafter
The M31 recurrent nova M31N 1926-07c has had five recorded eruptions. Well-sampled light curves of the two most recent outbursts, in January of 2020 (M31N 2020-01b) and September 2022 (M31N 2022-09a), are presented showing that the photometric evolution of the two events were quite similar, with peak magnitudes of $R=17.2\pm0.1$ and $R=17.1\pm0.1$, and $t_2$ times of $9.7\pm0.9$ and $8.1\pm0.5$ days for the 2020 and 2022 eruptions, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission spectroscopy of WASP-7 b with UVES -- Detection of Na I D$_2$ and tentative D$_1$ line absorption</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/transmission_spectroscopy_of_wasp-7_b_with_uves_--_detection_of_na_i_d_2_and_tentative_d_1_line_absorption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/transmission_spectroscopy_of_wasp-7_b_with_uves_--_detection_of_na_i_d_2_and_tentative_d_1_line_absorption/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hossein Rahmati
Transmission spectroscopy is a prime technique to study the chemical composition and structure of exoplanetary atmospheres. Strong excess absorption signals have been detected in the optical Na I D1, 2 Fraunhofer lines during transits of hot Jupiters, which are attributed to the planetary atmospheres and allow us to constrain its structure. We study the atmosphere of WASP-7 b by means of high-resolution transit spectroscopy in the sodium lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A sub-Neptune transiting the young field star HD 18599 at 40 pc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_sub-neptune_transiting_the_young_field_star_hd_18599_at_40_pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_sub-neptune_transiting_the_young_field_star_hd_18599_at_40_pc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jerome P. de Leon
Transiting exoplanets orbiting young nearby stars are ideal laboratories for testing theories of planet formation and evolution. However, to date only a handful of stars with age &amp;lt;1 Gyr have been found to host transiting exoplanets. Here we present the discovery and validation of a sub-Neptune around HD 18599, a young (300 Myr), nearby (d=40 pc) K star. We validate the transiting planet candidate as a bona fide planet using data from the TESS, Spitzer, and Gaia missions, ground-based photometry from IRSF, LCO, PEST, and NGTS, speckle imaging from Gemini, and spectroscopy from CHIRON, NRES, FEROS, and Minerva-Australis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Structure and Evolution of BASS AGN through Eddington Ratios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_the_structure_and_evolution_of_bass_agn_through_eddington_ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/probing_the_structure_and_evolution_of_bass_agn_through_eddington_ratios/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tonima Tasnim Ananna
We constrain the intrinsic Eddington ratio (\lamEdd ) distribution function for local AGN in bins of low and high obscuration (log NH &amp;lt;= 22 and 22 &amp;lt; log NH &amp;lt; 25), using the Swift-BAT 70-month/BASS DR2 survey. We interpret the fraction of obscured AGN in terms of circum-nuclear geometry and temporal evolution. Specifically, at low Eddington ratios (log lamEdd &amp;lt; -2), obscured AGN outnumber unobscured ones by a factor of ~4, reflecting the covering factor of the circum-nuclear material (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Evolution and Eruption of the Coronal Magnetic Field through a Data-Driven MHD Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_evolution_and_eruption_of_the_coronal_magnetic_field_through_a_data-driven_mhd_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_evolution_and_eruption_of_the_coronal_magnetic_field_through_a_data-driven_mhd_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Satoshi Inoue
We present a newly developed data-driven magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) simulation code under a zero-beta approximation based on a method proposed by Hayashi et al. 2018 and 2019. Although many data-driven MHD simulations have been developed and conducted, there are not many studies on how accurately those simulations can reproduce the phenomena observed in the solar corona. In this study, we investigated the performance of our data-driven simulation quantitatively using ground-truth data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO2-driven surface changes in the Hapi region on Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/co2-driven_surface_changes_in_the_hapi_region_on_comet_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/co2-driven_surface_changes_in_the_hapi_region_on_comet_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</guid>
      <description>First author: Björn J. R. Davidsson
Between 2014 December 31 and 2015 March 17, the OSIRIS cameras on Rosetta documented the growth of a 140m wide and 0.5m deep depression in the Hapi region on Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko. This shallow pit is one of several that later formed elsewhere on the comet, all in smooth terrain that primarily is the result of airfall of coma particles. We have compiled observations of this region in Hapi by the microwave instrument MIRO on Rosetta, acquired during October and November 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on Evolutionary Timescales for M Dwarf Planets from Dynamical Stability Arguments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraints_on_evolutionary_timescales_for_m_dwarf_planets_from_dynamical_stability_arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraints_on_evolutionary_timescales_for_m_dwarf_planets_from_dynamical_stability_arguments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Katie Teixeira
The diversity of dynamical conditions among exoplanets is now well established. Yet, the relevance of orbital dynamical timescales to biological evolutionary timescales is poorly understood. Given that even minor orbital changes may place significant pressure on any organisms living on a planet, dynamical sculpting has important implications for the putative evolution of life. In this manuscript, we employ a Monte Carlo framework to investigate how a range of exoplanetary dynamical sculpting timescales affects timescales for biological evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy Aquarius: evolution of a Milky-way like system in the Fuzzy Dark Matter scenario</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/fuzzy_aquarius_evolution_of_a_milky-way_like_system_in_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/fuzzy_aquarius_evolution_of_a_milky-way_like_system_in_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_scenario/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matteo Nori
We present the first high-resolution zoom-in simulation of a Milky-way-like halo extracted from the Aquarius Project in the Fuzzy Dark Matter (FDM) framework. We use the N-body code AX-GADGET, based on a particle oriented solution of the Schr&amp;quot;{o}dinger-Poisson equations, able to detail the complexity of structure formation while keeping track of the quantum effects in FDM. The halo shows a cored density profile, with a core size of several kpc for a FDM mass of $m_{\chi}=2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-energy neutrino emission from magnetised jets of rapidly rotating protomagnetars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_magnetised_jets_of_rapidly_rotating_protomagnetars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_magnetised_jets_of_rapidly_rotating_protomagnetars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mukul Bhattacharya
Relativistic jets originating from protomagnetar central engines can lead to long duration gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) and are considered potential sources of ultrahigh-energy cosmic rays and secondary neutrinos. We explore the propagation of such jets through a broad range of progenitors, from stars which have shed their envelopes to supergiants which have not. We use a semi-analytical spindown model for the strongly magnetised and rapidly rotating PNS to investigate the role of central engine properties such as the surface dipole field strength, initial rotation period, and jet opening angle on the interactions and dynamical evolution of the jet-cocoon system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical simulations for the common-envelope wind model for Type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hydrodynamical_simulations_for_the_common-envelope_wind_model_for_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hydrodynamical_simulations_for_the_common-envelope_wind_model_for_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yingzhen Cui
The single-degenerate (SD) model is one of the leading models for the progenitors of Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia). Recently, a new version of the SD model, the common-envelope wind (CEW) model, has been proposed, which, in principle, has the potential to resolve most of the difficulties encountered by previous SD models. This model is still being developed and a number of open issues remain, such as the details of the mass-loss mechanism from the surface of the common envelope (CE), the main observational properties, and the spiral-in timescale of the binary inside the envelope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar feedback impact on the ionized gas kinematics in the dwarf galaxy Sextans A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/stellar_feedback_impact_on_the_ionized_gas_kinematics_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_sextans_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/stellar_feedback_impact_on_the_ionized_gas_kinematics_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_sextans_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivan S. Gerasimov
Feedback from massive stars shapes the ISM and affects the evolution of galaxies, but its mechanisms acting at the small scales ($\sim 10$ pc) are still not well constrained observationally, especially in the low-metallicity environments. We present the analysis of the ionized gas (focusing on its kinematics, which were never studied before), and its connection to the massive stars in the nearby ($D \sim 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Contribution of In-situ and Ex-situ Star Formation in Early-Type Galaxies: MaNGA versus IllustrisTNG</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_contribution_of_in-situ_and_ex-situ_star_formation_in_early-type_galaxies_manga_versus_illustristng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_contribution_of_in-situ_and_ex-situ_star_formation_in_early-type_galaxies_manga_versus_illustristng/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carlo Cannarozzo
We compare stellar mass surface density, metallicity, age, and line-of-sight velocity dispersion profiles in massive ($M_\geq10^{10.5},\mathrm{M_\odot}$) present-day early-type galaxies (ETGs) from the MaNGA survey with simulated galaxies from the TNG100 simulation of the IllustrisTNG suite. We find an excellent agreement between the stellar mass surface density profiles of MaNGA and TNG100 ETGs, both in shape and normalisation. Moreover, TNG100 reproduces the shapes of the profiles of stellar metallicity and age, as well as the normalisation of velocity dispersion distributions of MaNGA ETGs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The homogeneity of chemical abundances in H II regions of the Magellanic Clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_homogeneity_of_chemical_abundances_in_h_ii_regions_of_the_magellanic_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_homogeneity_of_chemical_abundances_in_h_ii_regions_of_the_magellanic_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Domínguez-Guzmán
We use very deep spectra obtained with the Ultraviolet-Visual Echelle Spectrograph at the Very Large Telescope to derive physical conditions and chemical abundances of four H II regions of the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) and four H II regions of the Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC). The observations cover the spectral range 3100-10400 \A with a spectral resolution of $\Delta\lambda\ge\lambda/11600$, and we measure 95-225 emission lines in each object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic evolution of grain size distribution in galaxies using the $ν^2$GC semi-analytic model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_evolution_of_grain_size_distribution_in_galaxies_using_the_%CE%BD2gc_semi-analytic_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_evolution_of_grain_size_distribution_in_galaxies_using_the_%CE%BD2gc_semi-analytic_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryu Makiya
We investigate the cosmological evolution of interstellar dust with a semi-analytical galaxy formation model ($\nu^2$GC), focusing on the evolution of grain size distribution. The model predicts the statistical properties of dust mass and grain size distribution in galaxies across cosmic history. We confirm that the model reproduces the relation between dust-to-gas ratio and metallicity in the local Universe, and that the grain size distributions of the Milky Way (MW)-like sample become similar to the so-called MRN distribution that reproduces the observed MW extinction curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field evolution in cosmic filaments with LOFAR data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_evolution_in_cosmic_filaments_with_lofar_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_evolution_in_cosmic_filaments_with_lofar_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Carretti
Measuring the magnetic field in cosmic filaments reveals how the Universe is magnetised and the process that magnetised it. Using the Rotation Measures (RM) at 144-MHz from the LoTSS DR2 data, we analyse the rms of the RM extragalactic component as a function of redshift to investigate the evolution with redshift of the magnetic field in filaments. From previous results, we find that the extragalactic term of the RM rms at 144-MHz is dominated by the contribution from filaments (more than 90 percent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of HCO$^{&#43;}$ in molecular clouds using a novel chemical post-processing algorithm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_hco&#43;_in_molecular_clouds_using_a_novel_chemical_post-processing_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_hco&#43;_in_molecular_clouds_using_a_novel_chemical_post-processing_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Panessa
Modeling the internal chemistry of molecular clouds is critical to accurately simulating their evolution. To reduce computational expense, 3D simulations generally restrict their chemical modeling to species with strong heating and cooling effects. We address this by post-processing tracer particles in the SILCC-Zoom molecular cloud simulations. Using a chemical network of 39 species and 299 reactions (including freeze-out of CO and H$2$O), and a novel iterative algorithm to reconstruct a filled density grid from sparse tracer particle data, we produce time-dependent density distributions for various species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal evolution and rigidity dependence of the solar modulation lag of Galactic cosmic rays</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temporal_evolution_and_rigidity_dependence_of_the_solar_modulation_lag_of_galactic_cosmic_rays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temporal_evolution_and_rigidity_dependence_of_the_solar_modulation_lag_of_galactic_cosmic_rays/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicola Tomassetti
When traveling in the heliosphere, Galactic cosmic rays (GCRs) are subjected to the solar modulation effect, a quasi-periodical change of their intensity caused by the 11-year cycle of solar activity. Here we investigate the association of solar activity and cosmic radiation over five solar cycles, from 1965 to 2020, using a collection of multichannel data from neutron monitors, space missions, and solar observatories. In particular, we focus on the time lag between the monthly sunspot number and the GCR flux variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on the contributions to the observed binary black hole population from individual evolutionary pathways in isolated binary evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_contributions_to_the_observed_binary_black_hole_population_from_individual_evolutionary_pathways_in_isolated_binary_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_contributions_to_the_observed_binary_black_hole_population_from_individual_evolutionary_pathways_in_isolated_binary_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Stevenson
Gravitational waves from merging binary black holes can be used to shed light on poorly understood aspects of massive binary stellar evolution, such as the evolution of massive stars (including their mass-loss rates), the common envelope phase, and the rate at which massive stars form throughout the cosmic history of the Universe. In this paper we explore the \emph{correlated} impact of these phases on predictions for the merger rate and chirp mass distribution of merging binary black holes, aiming to identify possible degeneracies between model parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SCUBA-2 Cosmology Legacy Survey: The EGS deep field -- III. The evolution of faint submillimeter galaxies at $z&lt;4$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_scuba-2_cosmology_legacy_survey_the_egs_deep_field_--_iii._the_evolution_of_faint_submillimeter_galaxies_at_z4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_scuba-2_cosmology_legacy_survey_the_egs_deep_field_--_iii._the_evolution_of_faint_submillimeter_galaxies_at_z4/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Cardona-Torres
We present a demographic analysis of the physical and morphological properties of $450/850~\mu\rm m$-selected galaxies from the deep observations of the SCUBA-2 Cosmology Legacy Survey in the Extended Groth Strip that are detected below the classical submillimeter-galaxy regime ($S_{850 \mu\rm m}\lesssim 6~\rm mJy$/beam) and compare them with a sample of optically-selected star-forming galaxies detected in the Cosmic Assembly Near-infrared Deep Extragalactic Legacy Survey in the same field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet nuclei composition and evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_nuclei_composition_and_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_nuclei_composition_and_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gianrico Filacchione
Thanks to Rosetta orbiter&amp;rsquo;s and Philae lander&amp;rsquo;s data our knowledge of cometary nuclei composition has experienced a great advancement. The properties of 67P/CG nucleus are discussed and compared with other comets explored in the past by space missions. Cometary nuclei are made by a collection of ices, minerals, organic matter, and salts resulting in very dark and red-colored surfaces. When far from the Sun, exposed water and carbon dioxide ices are found only in few locations of 67P/CG where the exposure of pristine subsurface layers or the recondensation of volatile species driven by the solar heating and local terrain morphology can sustain their temporary presence on the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf galaxy archaeology from chemical abundances and star formation histories</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxy_archaeology_from_chemical_abundances_and_star_formation_histories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxy_archaeology_from_chemical_abundances_and_star_formation_histories/</guid>
      <description>First author: James W. Johnson
We model the stellar abundances and ages of two disrupted dwarf galaxies in the Milky Way stellar halo: Gaia-Sausage Enceladus (GSE) and Wukong/LMS-1. Using a statistically robust likelihood function, we fit one-zone models of galactic chemical evolution with exponential infall histories to both systems, deriving e-folding timescales of $\tau_\text{in} = 1.01 \pm 0.13$ Gyr for GSE and $\tau_\text{in} = 3.08^{+3.19}{-1.16}$ Gyr for Wukong/LMS-1. GSE formed stars for $\tau\text{tot} = 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus Stars: Numerical investigations of stellar evolution with star-lifting</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lazarus_stars_numerical_investigations_of_stellar_evolution_with_star-lifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lazarus_stars_numerical_investigations_of_stellar_evolution_with_star-lifting/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew Scoggins
The aging and gradual brightening of the Sun will challenge Earth&amp;rsquo;s habitability in the next few billion years. If life exists elsewhere in the Universe, the aging of their host star will similarly pose an existential threat. One solution to this threat, which we dub a Lazarus star, is for an advanced civilization to remove (or &amp;ldquo;star-lift&amp;rdquo;) mass from their host star at a rate which offsets the increase in luminosity, keeping the flux on the habitable planet(s) constant and extending the lifetime of their star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetohydrodynamics evolution of three-dimensional magnetic null in NOAA active region 11515 initiated using non-force-free field extrapolation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetohydrodynamics_evolution_of_three-dimensional_magnetic_null_in_noaa_active_region_11515_initiated_using_non-force-free_field_extrapolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetohydrodynamics_evolution_of_three-dimensional_magnetic_null_in_noaa_active_region_11515_initiated_using_non-force-free_field_extrapolation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sanjay Kumar
Magnetohydrodynamics simulation of active region NOAA 11515 is performed to examine the initiation of the M5.6 flaring event that starts around 10:43 UT on 2012 July 2. The simulation is conducted using an extrapolated non-force-free magnetic field generated from the photospheric vector magnetogram of the active region as the initial magnetic field. The magnetic field shows the presence of a three-dimensional (3D) magnetic null with the corresponding dome overlying a filament and a low-lying magnetic flux rope, observed in 304~\AA~ and 131~\AA~ respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling of the scandium abundance evolution in AmFm stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_of_the_scandium_abundance_evolution_in_amfm_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_of_the_scandium_abundance_evolution_in_amfm_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Hui-Bon-Hoa
Scandium is a key element of the Am star phenomenon since its surface under-abundance is one of the criteria that characterise such stars. Thanks to the availability of a sufficiently complete set of theoretical atomic data for this element, reliable radiative accelerations for Sc can now be computed, which allows its behaviour under the action of atomic diffusion to be modelled. We explore the required conditions, in terms of mixing processes or mass loss, for our models to reproduce the observed surface abundances of Sc in Am stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noble gases and stable isotopes track the origin and early evolution of the Venus atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/noble_gases_and_stable_isotopes_track_the_origin_and_early_evolution_of_the_venus_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/noble_gases_and_stable_isotopes_track_the_origin_and_early_evolution_of_the_venus_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guillaume Avice
The composition the atmosphere of Venus results from the integration of many processes entering into play over the entire geological history of the planet. Determining the elemental abundances and isotopic ratios of noble gases (He, Ne, Ar, Kr, Xe) and stable isotopes (H, C, N, O, S) in the Venus atmosphere is a high priority scientific target since it could open a window on the origin and early evolution of the entire planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the evolution of pebble-accreting planets in evolving protoplanetary discs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_evolution_of_pebble-accreting_planets_in_evolving_protoplanetary_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_evolution_of_pebble-accreting_planets_in_evolving_protoplanetary_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arnaud Pierens
We examine the migration of luminous low-mass cores in laminar protoplanetary discs where accretion occurs mainly because of disc winds and where the planet luminosity is generated by pebble accretion. Using 2D hydrodynamical simulations, we determine the eccentricities induced by thermal forces as a function of gas and pebble accretion rates, and also evaluate the importance of the torque exerted by the solid component relative to the gas torque.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on the quantity and brightness evolution characteristics of Photospheric Bright Points groups</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/research_on_the_quantity_and_brightness_evolution_characteristics_of_photospheric_bright_points_groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/research_on_the_quantity_and_brightness_evolution_characteristics_of_photospheric_bright_points_groups/</guid>
      <description>First author: HaiCheng Bai
Context. Photospheric bright points (BPs), as the smallest magnetic element of the photosphere and the footpoint tracer of the magnetic flux tube, are of great significance to the study of BPs. Compared with the study of the characteristics and evolution of a few specific BPs, the study of BPs groups can provide us with a better understanding of the characteristics and overall activities of BPs groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of CNO elements in galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_cno_elements_in_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_cno_elements_in_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Donatella Romano
After hydrogen and helium, oxygen, carbon, and nitrogen - hereinafter, the CNO elements - are the most abundant species in the universe. They are observed in all kinds of astrophysical environments, from the smallest to the largest scales, and are at the basis of all known forms of life, hence, the constituents of any biomarker. As such, their study proves crucial in several areas of contemporary astrophysics, extending to astrobiology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
