<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic evolution of grain size distribution in galaxies using the $ν^2$GC semi-analytic model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_evolution_of_grain_size_distribution_in_galaxies_using_the_%CE%BD2gc_semi-analytic_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_evolution_of_grain_size_distribution_in_galaxies_using_the_%CE%BD2gc_semi-analytic_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryu Makiya
We investigate the cosmological evolution of interstellar dust with a semi-analytical galaxy formation model ($\nu^2$GC), focusing on the evolution of grain size distribution. The model predicts the statistical properties of dust mass and grain size distribution in galaxies across cosmic history. We confirm that the model reproduces the relation between dust-to-gas ratio and metallicity in the local Universe, and that the grain size distributions of the Milky Way (MW)-like sample become similar to the so-called MRN distribution that reproduces the observed MW extinction curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field evolution in cosmic filaments with LOFAR data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_evolution_in_cosmic_filaments_with_lofar_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_evolution_in_cosmic_filaments_with_lofar_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Carretti
Measuring the magnetic field in cosmic filaments reveals how the Universe is magnetised and the process that magnetised it. Using the Rotation Measures (RM) at 144-MHz from the LoTSS DR2 data, we analyse the rms of the RM extragalactic component as a function of redshift to investigate the evolution with redshift of the magnetic field in filaments. From previous results, we find that the extragalactic term of the RM rms at 144-MHz is dominated by the contribution from filaments (more than 90 percent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of HCO$^{&#43;}$ in molecular clouds using a novel chemical post-processing algorithm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_hco&#43;_in_molecular_clouds_using_a_novel_chemical_post-processing_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_hco&#43;_in_molecular_clouds_using_a_novel_chemical_post-processing_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Panessa
Modeling the internal chemistry of molecular clouds is critical to accurately simulating their evolution. To reduce computational expense, 3D simulations generally restrict their chemical modeling to species with strong heating and cooling effects. We address this by post-processing tracer particles in the SILCC-Zoom molecular cloud simulations. Using a chemical network of 39 species and 299 reactions (including freeze-out of CO and H$2$O), and a novel iterative algorithm to reconstruct a filled density grid from sparse tracer particle data, we produce time-dependent density distributions for various species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal evolution and rigidity dependence of the solar modulation lag of Galactic cosmic rays</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temporal_evolution_and_rigidity_dependence_of_the_solar_modulation_lag_of_galactic_cosmic_rays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temporal_evolution_and_rigidity_dependence_of_the_solar_modulation_lag_of_galactic_cosmic_rays/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicola Tomassetti
When traveling in the heliosphere, Galactic cosmic rays (GCRs) are subjected to the solar modulation effect, a quasi-periodical change of their intensity caused by the 11-year cycle of solar activity. Here we investigate the association of solar activity and cosmic radiation over five solar cycles, from 1965 to 2020, using a collection of multichannel data from neutron monitors, space missions, and solar observatories. In particular, we focus on the time lag between the monthly sunspot number and the GCR flux variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on the contributions to the observed binary black hole population from individual evolutionary pathways in isolated binary evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_contributions_to_the_observed_binary_black_hole_population_from_individual_evolutionary_pathways_in_isolated_binary_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_contributions_to_the_observed_binary_black_hole_population_from_individual_evolutionary_pathways_in_isolated_binary_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Stevenson
Gravitational waves from merging binary black holes can be used to shed light on poorly understood aspects of massive binary stellar evolution, such as the evolution of massive stars (including their mass-loss rates), the common envelope phase, and the rate at which massive stars form throughout the cosmic history of the Universe. In this paper we explore the \emph{correlated} impact of these phases on predictions for the merger rate and chirp mass distribution of merging binary black holes, aiming to identify possible degeneracies between model parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SCUBA-2 Cosmology Legacy Survey: The EGS deep field -- III. The evolution of faint submillimeter galaxies at $z&lt;4$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_scuba-2_cosmology_legacy_survey_the_egs_deep_field_--_iii._the_evolution_of_faint_submillimeter_galaxies_at_z4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_scuba-2_cosmology_legacy_survey_the_egs_deep_field_--_iii._the_evolution_of_faint_submillimeter_galaxies_at_z4/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Cardona-Torres
We present a demographic analysis of the physical and morphological properties of $450/850~\mu\rm m$-selected galaxies from the deep observations of the SCUBA-2 Cosmology Legacy Survey in the Extended Groth Strip that are detected below the classical submillimeter-galaxy regime ($S_{850 \mu\rm m}\lesssim 6~\rm mJy$/beam) and compare them with a sample of optically-selected star-forming galaxies detected in the Cosmic Assembly Near-infrared Deep Extragalactic Legacy Survey in the same field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet nuclei composition and evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_nuclei_composition_and_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_nuclei_composition_and_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gianrico Filacchione
Thanks to Rosetta orbiter&amp;rsquo;s and Philae lander&amp;rsquo;s data our knowledge of cometary nuclei composition has experienced a great advancement. The properties of 67P/CG nucleus are discussed and compared with other comets explored in the past by space missions. Cometary nuclei are made by a collection of ices, minerals, organic matter, and salts resulting in very dark and red-colored surfaces. When far from the Sun, exposed water and carbon dioxide ices are found only in few locations of 67P/CG where the exposure of pristine subsurface layers or the recondensation of volatile species driven by the solar heating and local terrain morphology can sustain their temporary presence on the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf galaxy archaeology from chemical abundances and star formation histories</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxy_archaeology_from_chemical_abundances_and_star_formation_histories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxy_archaeology_from_chemical_abundances_and_star_formation_histories/</guid>
      <description>First author: James W. Johnson
We model the stellar abundances and ages of two disrupted dwarf galaxies in the Milky Way stellar halo: Gaia-Sausage Enceladus (GSE) and Wukong/LMS-1. Using a statistically robust likelihood function, we fit one-zone models of galactic chemical evolution with exponential infall histories to both systems, deriving e-folding timescales of $\tau_\text{in} = 1.01 \pm 0.13$ Gyr for GSE and $\tau_\text{in} = 3.08^{+3.19}{-1.16}$ Gyr for Wukong/LMS-1. GSE formed stars for $\tau\text{tot} = 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus Stars: Numerical investigations of stellar evolution with star-lifting</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lazarus_stars_numerical_investigations_of_stellar_evolution_with_star-lifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lazarus_stars_numerical_investigations_of_stellar_evolution_with_star-lifting/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew Scoggins
The aging and gradual brightening of the Sun will challenge Earth&amp;rsquo;s habitability in the next few billion years. If life exists elsewhere in the Universe, the aging of their host star will similarly pose an existential threat. One solution to this threat, which we dub a Lazarus star, is for an advanced civilization to remove (or &amp;ldquo;star-lift&amp;rdquo;) mass from their host star at a rate which offsets the increase in luminosity, keeping the flux on the habitable planet(s) constant and extending the lifetime of their star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetohydrodynamics evolution of three-dimensional magnetic null in NOAA active region 11515 initiated using non-force-free field extrapolation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetohydrodynamics_evolution_of_three-dimensional_magnetic_null_in_noaa_active_region_11515_initiated_using_non-force-free_field_extrapolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetohydrodynamics_evolution_of_three-dimensional_magnetic_null_in_noaa_active_region_11515_initiated_using_non-force-free_field_extrapolation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sanjay Kumar
Magnetohydrodynamics simulation of active region NOAA 11515 is performed to examine the initiation of the M5.6 flaring event that starts around 10:43 UT on 2012 July 2. The simulation is conducted using an extrapolated non-force-free magnetic field generated from the photospheric vector magnetogram of the active region as the initial magnetic field. The magnetic field shows the presence of a three-dimensional (3D) magnetic null with the corresponding dome overlying a filament and a low-lying magnetic flux rope, observed in 304~\AA~ and 131~\AA~ respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling of the scandium abundance evolution in AmFm stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_of_the_scandium_abundance_evolution_in_amfm_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_of_the_scandium_abundance_evolution_in_amfm_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Hui-Bon-Hoa
Scandium is a key element of the Am star phenomenon since its surface under-abundance is one of the criteria that characterise such stars. Thanks to the availability of a sufficiently complete set of theoretical atomic data for this element, reliable radiative accelerations for Sc can now be computed, which allows its behaviour under the action of atomic diffusion to be modelled. We explore the required conditions, in terms of mixing processes or mass loss, for our models to reproduce the observed surface abundances of Sc in Am stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noble gases and stable isotopes track the origin and early evolution of the Venus atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/noble_gases_and_stable_isotopes_track_the_origin_and_early_evolution_of_the_venus_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/noble_gases_and_stable_isotopes_track_the_origin_and_early_evolution_of_the_venus_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guillaume Avice
The composition the atmosphere of Venus results from the integration of many processes entering into play over the entire geological history of the planet. Determining the elemental abundances and isotopic ratios of noble gases (He, Ne, Ar, Kr, Xe) and stable isotopes (H, C, N, O, S) in the Venus atmosphere is a high priority scientific target since it could open a window on the origin and early evolution of the entire planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the evolution of pebble-accreting planets in evolving protoplanetary discs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_evolution_of_pebble-accreting_planets_in_evolving_protoplanetary_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_evolution_of_pebble-accreting_planets_in_evolving_protoplanetary_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arnaud Pierens
We examine the migration of luminous low-mass cores in laminar protoplanetary discs where accretion occurs mainly because of disc winds and where the planet luminosity is generated by pebble accretion. Using 2D hydrodynamical simulations, we determine the eccentricities induced by thermal forces as a function of gas and pebble accretion rates, and also evaluate the importance of the torque exerted by the solid component relative to the gas torque.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on the quantity and brightness evolution characteristics of Photospheric Bright Points groups</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/research_on_the_quantity_and_brightness_evolution_characteristics_of_photospheric_bright_points_groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/research_on_the_quantity_and_brightness_evolution_characteristics_of_photospheric_bright_points_groups/</guid>
      <description>First author: HaiCheng Bai
Context. Photospheric bright points (BPs), as the smallest magnetic element of the photosphere and the footpoint tracer of the magnetic flux tube, are of great significance to the study of BPs. Compared with the study of the characteristics and evolution of a few specific BPs, the study of BPs groups can provide us with a better understanding of the characteristics and overall activities of BPs groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of CNO elements in galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_cno_elements_in_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_cno_elements_in_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Donatella Romano
After hydrogen and helium, oxygen, carbon, and nitrogen - hereinafter, the CNO elements - are the most abundant species in the universe. They are observed in all kinds of astrophysical environments, from the smallest to the largest scales, and are at the basis of all known forms of life, hence, the constituents of any biomarker. As such, their study proves crucial in several areas of contemporary astrophysics, extending to astrobiology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
