<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An analytic solution to measure the gas size in protoplanetary discs in the viscous self-similar scenario</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_analytic_solution_to_measure_the_gas_size_in_protoplanetary_discs_in_the_viscous_self-similar_scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_analytic_solution_to_measure_the_gas_size_in_protoplanetary_discs_in_the_viscous_self-similar_scenario/</guid>
      <description>First author: Claudia Toci
In order to understand which mechanism is responsible for accretion in protoplanetary discs, a robust knowledge of the observed disc radius using gas tracers such as $^{12}$CO and other CO isotopologues is pivotal. Indeed, the two main theories proposed, viscous accretion and wind-driven accretion, predict different time evolution for the disc radii. In this Letter, we present an analytical solution for the evolution of the disc radii in viscously evolving protoplanetary discs using $^{12}$CO as a tracer, under the assumption that the $^{12}$CO radius is the radius where the surface density of the disc is equal to the threshold for CO photo-dissociation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking beneath the precision floor I: metallicity spreads and multiple elemental dispersions in the globular clusters NGC 288 and NGC 362</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/peeking_beneath_the_precision_floor_i_metallicity_spreads_and_multiple_elemental_dispersions_in_the_globular_clusters_ngc_288_and_ngc_362/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/peeking_beneath_the_precision_floor_i_metallicity_spreads_and_multiple_elemental_dispersions_in_the_globular_clusters_ngc_288_and_ngc_362/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stephanie Monty
The view of globular clusters (GCs) as simple systems continues to unravel, revealing complex objects hosting multiple chemical peculiarities. Using differential abundance analysis, we probe the chemistry of the Type I GC, NGC 288 and the Type II GC, NGC 362 at the 2% level for the first time. We measure 20 elements and find differential measurement uncertainties on the order 0.01-0.02 dex in both clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion variability in RU Lup</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/accretion_variability_in_ru_lup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/accretion_variability_in_ru_lup/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camille Stock
The process of accretion in classical T Tauri stars (CTTSs) has been observed to vary on different timescales. Studying this variability is vital to understanding a star&amp;rsquo;s evolution and provides insight into the complex processes at work within. Understanding the dichotomy between continuum veiling and emission line veiling is integral to accurately measuring the amount of veiling present in stellar spectra. Here, 15 roughly consecutive nights of optical spectroscopic data from the spectropolarimeter ESPaDOnS are utilised to characterise the short-term accretion activity in the CTTS, RU Lup, and investigate its relationship with the veiling in the LiI 6707A absorption line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bars and boxy/peanut bulges in thin and thick discs. II. Can bars form in hot thick discs?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/bars_and_boxy_peanut_bulges_in_thin_and_thick_discs._ii._can_bars_form_in_hot_thick_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/bars_and_boxy_peanut_bulges_in_thin_and_thick_discs._ii._can_bars_form_in_hot_thick_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Soumavo Ghosh
The Milky Way as well as external galaxies possess a thick disc. However, the dynamical role of the (geometrically) thick disc on the bar formation and evolution is not fully understood. Here, we investigate the effect of thick discs in bar formation and evolution by means of a suite of $N$-body models of (kinematically cold) thin-(kinematically hot) thick discs. We systematically vary the mass fraction of the thick disc, the thin-to-thick disc scale length ratio as well as thick disc&amp;rsquo;s scale height to examine the bar formation under diverse dynamical scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a reliable calculation of relic radiation from primordial gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/towards_a_reliable_calculation_of_relic_radiation_from_primordial_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/towards_a_reliable_calculation_of_relic_radiation_from_primordial_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Giarè
Inflationary gravitational waves, behaving as additional radiation in the Early Universe, can increase the effective number of relativistic species ($N_{\rm eff}$) by a further correction that depends on the integrated energy-density in gravitational waves over all scales. This effect is typically used to constrain (blue-tilted) models of inflation in light of the bounds resulting from the Big Bang Nucleosynthesis. In this paper, we recompute this contribution, discussing some caveats of the state-of-the-art analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Averaged Solar Torque Rotational Dynamics for Defunct Satellites</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/averaged_solar_torque_rotational_dynamics_for_defunct_satellites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/averaged_solar_torque_rotational_dynamics_for_defunct_satellites/</guid>
      <description>First author: Conor J. Benson
Spin state predictions for defunct satellites in geosynchronous earth orbit (GEO) are valuable for active debris removal and servicing missions as well as material shedding studies and attitude-dependent solar radiation pressure (SRP) modeling. Previous studies have shown that solar radiation torques can explain the observed spin state evolution of some GEO objects via the Yarkovsky-O&amp;rsquo;Keefe-Radzievskii-Paddack (YORP) effect. These studies have focused primarily on uniform rotation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphology driven evolution of barred galaxies in OMEGAWINGS Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/morphology_driven_evolution_of_barred_galaxies_in_omegawings_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/morphology_driven_evolution_of_barred_galaxies_in_omegawings_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amira A. Tawfeek
We present a study of barred galaxies in the cluster environment, exploiting a sample of galaxies drawn from the extended WIde-field Nearby Galaxy-cluster Survey (OmegaWINGS) that covers up to the outer regions of 32 local X-ray selected clusters. Barred galaxies are identified through a semi-automatic analysis of ellipticity and position angle profiles. We find, in agreement with previous studies, a strong co-dependence of the bar fraction with the galaxy stellar mass and morphological type, being maximum for massive late-type galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the dust of tailless Oort-cloud comet C/2020 T2 (Palomar)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_dust_of_tailless_oort-cloud_comet_c_2020_t2_palomar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_dust_of_tailless_oort-cloud_comet_c_2020_t2_palomar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuna Grace Kwon
We report our new analysis of Oort-cloud comet C/2020 T2 (Palomar) (T2) observed at 2.06 au from the Sun (phase angle of 28.5 deg) about two weeks before perihelion. T2 lacks a significant dust tail in scattered light, showing a strong central condensation of the coma throughout the apparition, reminiscent of so-called Manx comets. Its spectral slope of polarized light increases and decreases in the J (1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin State Evolution of (99942) Apophis during its 2029 Earth Encounter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spin_state_evolution_of_99942_apophis_during_its_2029_earth_encounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/spin_state_evolution_of_99942_apophis_during_its_2029_earth_encounter/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. J. Benson
We explore the effects of the 2029 Earth encounter on asteroid (99942) Apophis&amp;rsquo; non-principal axis spin state, leveraging refined orbit, spin state, and inertia information provided by more recent optical and radar observations. Propagating the asteroids&amp;rsquo; coupled orbit and rigid body attitude dynamics through the flyby, we present the range of possible post-flyby spin states. These spin state distributions will be valuable for planning Apophis observation campaigns and spacecraft missions, most notably OSIRIS-APEX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar age determination in the Mass-Luminosity Plane</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/stellar_age_determination_in_the_mass-luminosity_plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/stellar_age_determination_in_the_mass-luminosity_plane/</guid>
      <description>First author: Erin R. Higgins
The ages of stars have historically relied on isochrone fitting of standardised grids of models. While these stellar models have provided key constraints on observational samples of massive stars, they inherit many systematic uncertainties, mainly in the internal mixing mechanisms applied throughout the grid, fundamentally undermining the isochrone method. In this work, we utilise the M-L plane of Higgins &amp;amp; Vink as a method of determining stellar age, with mixing-corrected models applying a calibrated core overshooting alpha_ov and rotation rate to fit the observational data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of flux rope heating models on solar prominence formation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_influence_of_flux_rope_heating_models_on_solar_prominence_formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_influence_of_flux_rope_heating_models_on_solar_prominence_formation/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Brughmans
Aims. We begin by exploring the influence of two classes of commonly adopted heating models on the formation behaviour of solar prominences. These models consider either an exponential variation dependent on height alone, or local density and magnetic field conditions. We highlight and address some of the limitations inherent to these early approximations by proposing a new, dynamic 2D flux rope heating model that qualitatively accounts for the 3D topology of the twisted flux rope field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyaromatic Hydrocarbons with an Imperfect Aromatic System as Catalysts of Interstellar H$_{2}$ Formation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polyaromatic_hydrocarbons_with_an_imperfect_aromatic_system_as_catalysts_of_interstellar_h__2__formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polyaromatic_hydrocarbons_with_an_imperfect_aromatic_system_as_catalysts_of_interstellar_h__2__formation/</guid>
      <description>First author: David P. Jelenfi
Although H${2}$ is the simplest and the most abundant molecule in the Universe, its formation in the interstellar medium, especially in the photodissociation regions is far from being fully understood. According to suggestions, the formation of H${2}$ is catalyzed by polyaromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) on the surface of interstellar grains. In the present study, we have investigated the catalytic effect of small PAHs with an imperfect aromatic system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Engulfment Detections are Rare According to Observations and Stellar Modeling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planet_engulfment_detections_are_rare_according_to_observations_and_stellar_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planet_engulfment_detections_are_rare_according_to_observations_and_stellar_modeling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aida Behmard
Dynamical evolution within planetary systems can cause planets to be engulfed by their host stars. Following engulfment, the stellar photosphere abundance pattern will reflect accretion of rocky material from planets. Multi-star systems are excellent environments to search for such abundance trends because stellar companions form from the same natal gas cloud and are thus expected to share primordial chemical compositions to within 0.03$-$0.05 dex. Abundance measurements have occasionally yielded rocky enhancements, but few observations targeted known planetary systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of collisional erosion on the composition of Earth-analog planets in Grand Tack models: Implications for the formation of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_collisional_erosion_on_the_composition_of_earth-analog_planets_in_grand_tack_models_implications_for_the_formation_of_the_earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_collisional_erosion_on_the_composition_of_earth-analog_planets_in_grand_tack_models_implications_for_the_formation_of_the_earth/</guid>
      <description>First author: Allibert L.
Impact-induced erosion of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s early crust during accretion of terrestrial bodies can significantly modify the primordial chemical composition of the Bulk Silicate Earth (BSE, that is, the composition of the crust added to the present-day mantle). In particular, it can be particularly efficient in altering the abundances of elements having a strong affinity for silicate melts (i.e. incompatible elements) as the early differentiated crust was preferentially enriched in those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIROPA II: Modeling Instrumental Aberrations for Off-Axis Point Spread Functions in Adaptive Optics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/airopa_ii_modeling_instrumental_aberrations_for_off-axis_point_spread_functions_in_adaptive_optics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/airopa_ii_modeling_instrumental_aberrations_for_off-axis_point_spread_functions_in_adaptive_optics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Ciurlo
Images obtained with single-conjugate adaptive optics (AO) show spatial variation of the point spread function (PSF) due to both atmospheric anisoplanatism and instrumental aberrations. The poor knowledge of the PSF across the field of view strongly impacts the ability to take full advantage of AO capabilities. The AIROPA project aims to model these PSF variations for the NIRC2 imager at the Keck Observatory. Here, we present the characterization of the instrumental phase aberrations over the entire NIRC2 field of view and we present a new metric for quantifying the quality of the calibration, the fraction of variance unexplained (FVU).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary neutron star merger simulations with neutrino transport and turbulent viscosity: impact of different schemes and grid resolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/binary_neutron_star_merger_simulations_with_neutrino_transport_and_turbulent_viscosity_impact_of_different_schemes_and_grid_resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/binary_neutron_star_merger_simulations_with_neutrino_transport_and_turbulent_viscosity_impact_of_different_schemes_and_grid_resolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francesco Zappa
We present a systematic numerical relativity study of the impact of different treatment of microphysics and grid resolution in binary neutron star mergers. We consider series of simulations at multiple resolutions comparing hydrodynamics, neutrino leakage scheme, leakage augmented with the M0 scheme and the more consistent M1 transport scheme. Additionally, we consider the impact of a sub-grid scheme for turbulent viscosity. We find that viscosity helps to stabilise the remnant against gravitational collapse but grid resolution has a larger impact than microphysics on the remnant&amp;rsquo;s stability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on planetary tidal dissipation from a detailed study of Kepler 91b</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_planetary_tidal_dissipation_from_a_detailed_study_of_kepler_91b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_planetary_tidal_dissipation_from_a_detailed_study_of_kepler_91b/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Fellay
Context. With the detection of thousands of exoplanets, characterising their dynamical evolution in detail represents a key step in the understanding of their formation. Studying the dissipation of tides occurring both in the host star and in the planets is of great relevance in order to investigate the distribution of the angular momentum occurring among the objects populating the system and to studying the evolution of the orbital parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Interstellar Medium as an Evolutionary Tracer in ALMA-Observed Local Dusty Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cool_interstellar_medium_as_an_evolutionary_tracer_in_alma-observed_local_dusty_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cool_interstellar_medium_as_an_evolutionary_tracer_in_alma-observed_local_dusty_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David H. W. Glass
The content and distribution of cool interstellar medium (ISM, &amp;lt;30K) can indicate the evolutionary mechanisms that transform late type to early type galaxies (ETGs). To investigate this, ALMA observations of 12CO[2-1] line emission were obtained for five dusty ETGs from a complete sample in low-density environments. Four of the ETGs have massive (approximately 10^9 Msolar), extended molecular gas reservoirs with effective radii of approximately 3 to 5 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of two new interstellar molecules with QUIJOTE: HCCCHCCC and HCCCCS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_two_new_interstellar_molecules_with_quijote_hccchccc_and_hccccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_two_new_interstellar_molecules_with_quijote_hccchccc_and_hccccs/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Fuentetaja
We report on the discovery of two new molecules, HCCCHCCC and HCCCCS, towards the starless core TMC-1 in the Taurus region from the QUIJOTE line survey in the 31.1-50.2 GHz frequency range. We identify a total of twenty-nine lines of HCCCHCCC and six rotational transitions of HCCCCS. The rotational quantum numbers range from Ju=10 up to 15 and Ka &amp;lt;=2 for HCCCHCCC and Ju=21/2 up to 31/2 for HCCCCS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If dark matter is fuzzy, the first stars form in massive pancakes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/if_dark_matter_is_fuzzy_the_first_stars_form_in_massive_pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/if_dark_matter_is_fuzzy_the_first_stars_form_in_massive_pancakes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mihir Kulkarni
Fuzzy dark matter (FDM) is a proposed modification for the standard cold dark matter (CDM) model motivated by small-scale discrepancies in low-mass galaxies. Composed of ultra-light (mass $\sim 10^{-22}$ eV) axions with kpc-scale de Broglie wavelengths, this is one of a class of candidates that predicts that the first collapsed objects form in relatively massive dark matter halos. This implies that the formation history of the first stars and galaxies would be very different, potentially placing strong constraints on such models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface instabilities in hydrodynamic relativistic jets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interface_instabilities_in_hydrodynamic_relativistic_jets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interface_instabilities_in_hydrodynamic_relativistic_jets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pavel Abolmasov
Both the dynamics and the observational properties of relativistic jets are determined by their interaction with the ambient medium. A crucial role is played by the contact discontinuity at the jet boundary, which in the presence of jet collimation may become subject to Rayleigh-Taylor instability (RTI) and Richtmyer-Meshkov instability (RMI). Here, we study the evolution of these instabilities in non-magnetized relativistic jets using special relativistic three-dimensional hydrodynamic simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower-than-expected flare temperatures for TRAPPIST-1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lower-than-expected_flare_temperatures_for_trappist-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lower-than-expected_flare_temperatures_for_trappist-1/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Maas
Although high energetic radiation from flares is a potential threat to exoplanet atmospheres and may lead to surface sterilization, it might also provide the extra energy for low-mass stars needed to trigger and sustain prebiotic chemistry. We investigate two flares on TRAPPIST-1, an ultra-cool dwarf star that hosts seven exoplanets of which three lie within its habitable zone. The flares are detected in all four passbands of the MuSCAT2 allowing a determination of their temperatures and bolometric energies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the origin of the dichotomy of stellar activity cycles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_origin_of_the_dichotomy_of_stellar_activity_cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_origin_of_the_dichotomy_of_stellar_activity_cycles/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alfio Bonanno
The presence of possible correlations between stellar rotation rate $\Omega$ and the frequency of the activity cycle $\omega_\mathrm{cyc}$ is still much debated. We implement a new Bayesian classification algorithm based on a simultaneous regression analysis of multiple scaling laws and we demonstrate the existence of two different scalings in the $\log_{10} \omega_\mathrm{cyc}$ &amp;ndash; $\log_{10} \Omega$ plane for an extended Mt.~Wilson sample of 67 stars. Thanks to metallicity measurements obtained from both ESA Gaia and high-resolution spectroscopy, we argue that the origin of this dichotomy is likely related to the chemical composition: stars whose magnetic cycle frequency increases with rotation rate are less metallic than stars whose magnetic cycle frequency decreases with stellar rotation rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Initial Magnetic Field Distribution in AB Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_initial_magnetic_field_distribution_in_ab_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_initial_magnetic_field_distribution_in_ab_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eoin Farrell
Stars are born with magnetic fields, but the distribution of their initial field strengths remains uncertain. We combine observations with theoretical models of magnetic field evolution to infer the initial distribution of magnetic fields for AB stars in the mass range of 1.6 - 3.4 M$_{\odot}$. We tested a variety of distributions with different shapes and found that a distribution with a mean of $\sim$800 G and a full width of $\sim$600 G is most consistent with the observed fraction of strongly magnetized stars as a function of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Treatise on Converting Stellar Mass Fractions to Abundances to Molar Ratios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_concise_treatise_on_converting_stellar_mass_fractions_to_abundances_to_molar_ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_concise_treatise_on_converting_stellar_mass_fractions_to_abundances_to_molar_ratios/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalie R. Hinkel
Understanding stellar composition is fundamental not only to our comprehension of the galaxy, especially chemical evolution, but it can also shed light on the interior structure and mineralogy of exoplanets, which are formed from the same material as their host stars. Unfortunately, the underlying mathematics describing stellar mass fractions and stellar elemental abundances is difficult to parse, fragmented across the literature, and contains vexing omissions that makes any calculation far from trivial, especially for non-experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Low-Mass, Pre-Main Sequence Eclipsing Binary in the 40 Myr Columba Association -- Fundamental Stellar Parameters and Modeling the Effect of Star Spots</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_low-mass_pre-main_sequence_eclipsing_binary_in_the_40_myr_columba_association_--_fundamental_stellar_parameters_and_modeling_the_effect_of_star_spots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_low-mass_pre-main_sequence_eclipsing_binary_in_the_40_myr_columba_association_--_fundamental_stellar_parameters_and_modeling_the_effect_of_star_spots/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin M. Tofflemire
Young eclipsing binaries (EBs) are powerful probes of early stellar evolution. Current models are unable to simultaneously reproduce the measured and derived properties that are accessible for EB systems (e.g., mass, radius, temperature, luminosity). In this study we add a benchmark EB to the pre-main sequence population with our characterization of TOI 450 (TIC 77951245). Using \gaia\ astrometry to identify its comoving, coeval companions, we confirm TOI 450 is a member of the $\sim$40 Myr Columba association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Ring Galaxies Detected Using Deep Learning with Real and Simulated Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/analysis_of_ring_galaxies_detected_using_deep_learning_with_real_and_simulated_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/analysis_of_ring_galaxies_detected_using_deep_learning_with_real_and_simulated_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Harish Krishnakumar
Understanding the formation and evolution of ring galaxies, galaxies with an atypical ring-like structure, will improve understanding of black holes and galaxy dynamics as a whole. Current catalogs of rings are extremely limited: manual analysis takes months to accumulate an appreciable sample of rings and existing computational methods are vastly limited in terms of accuracy and detection rate. Without a sizable sample of rings, further research into their properties is severely restricted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequency Agile Solar Radiotelescope: A Next-Generation Radio Telescope for Solar Physics and Space Weather</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/frequency_agile_solar_radiotelescope_a_next-generation_radio_telescope_for_solar_physics_and_space_weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/frequency_agile_solar_radiotelescope_a_next-generation_radio_telescope_for_solar_physics_and_space_weather/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dale E. Gary
The Frequency Agile Solar Radiotelescope (FASR) has been strongly endorsed as a top community priority by both Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics Decadal Surveys and Solar &amp;amp; Space Physics Decadal Surveys in the past two decades. Although it was developed to a high state of readiness in previous years (it went through a CATE analysis and was declared ``doable now&amp;quot;), the NSF has not had the funding mechanisms in place to fund this mid-scale program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble WFC3 Spectroscopy of the Rocky Planet L 98-59 b: No Evidence for a Cloud-Free Primordial Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_wfc3_spectroscopy_of_the_rocky_planet_l_98-59_b_no_evidence_for_a_cloud-free_primordial_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_wfc3_spectroscopy_of_the_rocky_planet_l_98-59_b_no_evidence_for_a_cloud-free_primordial_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Li Zhou
We are using archived data from HST of transiting exoplanet L~98-59~b to place constraints on its potentially hot atmosphere. We analyze the data from five transit visits and extract the final combined transmission spectrum using Iraclis. Then we use the inverse atmospheric retrieval code TauREx to analyze the combined transmission spectrum. There is a weak absorption feature near 1.40~$\mu m$ and 1.55~$\mu m$ in the transmission spectrum, which can be modeled by a cloudy atmosphere with abundant HCN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference finds consistency between a neutrino flavor evolution model and Earth-based solar neutrino measurements</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_finds_consistency_between_a_neutrino_flavor_evolution_model_and_earth-based_solar_neutrino_measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_finds_consistency_between_a_neutrino_flavor_evolution_model_and_earth-based_solar_neutrino_measurements/</guid>
      <description>First author: Caroline Laber-Smith
We continue examining statistical data assimilation (SDA), an inference methodology, to infer solutions to neutrino flavor evolution, for the first time using real - rather than simulated - data. The model represents neutrinos streaming from the Sun&amp;rsquo;s center and undergoing a Mikheyev-Smirnov-Wolfenstein (MSW) resonance in flavor space, due to the radially-varying electron number density. The model neutrino energies are chosen to correspond to experimental bins in the Sudbury Neutrino Observatory (SNO) and Borexino experiments, which measure electron-flavor survival probability at Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionisation of inner T Tauri star discs: effects of in-situ energetic particles produced by strong magnetic reconnection events</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ionisation_of_inner_t_tauri_star_discs_effects_of_in-situ_energetic_particles_produced_by_strong_magnetic_reconnection_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ionisation_of_inner_t_tauri_star_discs_effects_of_in-situ_energetic_particles_produced_by_strong_magnetic_reconnection_events/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brunn V
Magnetic reconnection is one of the major particle acceleration processes in space and astrophysical plasmas. Low-energy supra-thermal particles emitted by magnetic reconnection are a source of ionisation for circumstellar discs, influencing their chemical, thermal and dynamical evolution. The aim of this work is to propose a first investigation to evaluate how energetic particles can propagate in the circumstellar disc of a T Tauri star and how they affect the ionisation rate of the disc plasma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LavAtmos: An open source chemical equilibrium vaporisation code for lava worlds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lavatmos_an_open_source_chemical_equilibrium_vaporisation_code_for_lava_worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lavatmos_an_open_source_chemical_equilibrium_vaporisation_code_for_lava_worlds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christiaan van Buchem
To date, over 500 short-period rocky planets with equilibrium temperatures above 1500 K have been discovered. Such planets are expected to support magma oceans, providing a direct interface between the interior and atmosphere. This provides a unique opportunity to gain insight into their interior compositions through atmospheric observations. A key process in doing such work is the vapor outgassing from the lava surface. LavAtmos is an open-source code that calculates the equilibrium chemical composition of vapor above a melt for a given composition and temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Ring Mission: Building a Panorama of the Sun and Inner-heliosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solar_ring_mission_building_a_panorama_of_the_sun_and_inner-heliosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solar_ring_mission_building_a_panorama_of_the_sun_and_inner-heliosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuming Wang
Solar Ring (SOR) is a proposed space science mission to monitor and study the Sun and inner heliosphere from a full 360{\deg} perspective in the ecliptic plane. It will deploy three 120{\deg}-separated spacecraft on the 1-AU orbit. The first spacecraft, S1, locates 30{\deg} upstream of the Earth, the second, S2, 90{\deg} downstream, and the third, S3, completes the configuration. This design with necessary science instruments, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Lensing by Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_lensing_by_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_lensing_by_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Shajib
Strong lensing at the galaxy-scale is useful for numerous applications in Astrophysics and Cosmology. Some of the principal applications are studying the mass structure of elliptical galaxies, their formation and evolution, constraining the stellar initial mass function, and measuring cosmological parameters. Since the first discovery of a galaxy-scale strong lens in the eighties, this field has come a long way in terms of data quality and availability, and techniques to model the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The integrated perturbation theory for cosmological tensor fields I: Basic formulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_integrated_perturbation_theory_for_cosmological_tensor_fields_i_basic_formulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_integrated_perturbation_theory_for_cosmological_tensor_fields_i_basic_formulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takahiko Matsubara
In order to extract maximal information about cosmology from the large-scale structure of the Universe, one needs to use every bit of signals that can be observed. Beyond the spatial distributions of astronomical objects, the spatial correlations of tensor fields, such as galaxy spins and shapes, are ones of promising sources that we can access in the era of large surveys in near future. The perturbation theory is a powerful tool to analytically describe the behaviors and evolutions of correlation statistics for a given cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of Pop III stars and early black holes in the 21cm signal from Cosmic Dawn</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_role_of_pop_iii_stars_and_early_black_holes_in_the_21cm_signal_from_cosmic_dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_role_of_pop_iii_stars_and_early_black_holes_in_the_21cm_signal_from_cosmic_dawn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emanuele M. Ventura
Modeling the 21cm global signal from the Cosmic Dawn is challenging due to the many poorly constrained physical processes that come into play. We address this problem using the semi-analytical code &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Archaeology Tool&amp;rdquo; (CAT). CAT follows the evolution of dark matter halos tracking their merger history and provides an ab initio description of their baryonic evolution, starting from the formation of the first (Pop III) stars and black holes (BHs) in mini-halos at z &amp;gt; 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The stability of galaxies in an expanding universe obtained by Newtonian dynamics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_stability_of_galaxies_in_an_expanding_universe_obtained_by_newtonian_dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_stability_of_galaxies_in_an_expanding_universe_obtained_by_newtonian_dynamics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Søren Toxvaerd
The dynamics of galaxies in an expanding universe is often determined for gravitational and dark matter in an Einstein-de Sitter universe, or alternatively by modifying the gravitational long-range attractions in the Newtonian dynamics (MOND). Here the time evolution of galaxies is determined by simulations of systems with pure gravitational forces by classical Molecular Dynamic simulations. A time reversible algorithm for formation and aging of gravitational systems by self-assembly of baryonic objects, recently derived (Eur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional numerical simulations of ambipolar diffusion in NS cores in the one-fluid approximation: instability of poloidal magnetic field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three-dimensional_numerical_simulations_of_ambipolar_diffusion_in_ns_cores_in_the_one-fluid_approximation_instability_of_poloidal_magnetic_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three-dimensional_numerical_simulations_of_ambipolar_diffusion_in_ns_cores_in_the_one-fluid_approximation_instability_of_poloidal_magnetic_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrei P. Igoshev
We numerically model evolution of magnetic fields inside a neutron star under the influence of ambipolar diffusion in the weak-coupling mode in the one-fluid MHD approximation. Our simulations are three-dimensional and performed in spherical coordinates. Our model covers the neutron star core and includes crust where the magnetic field decay is due to Ohmic decay. We discover an instability of poloidal magnetic field under the influence of ambipolar diffusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lagrangian construction of rotating stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lagrangian_construction_of_rotating_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lagrangian_construction_of_rotating_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Misa Ogata
We present a new formulation for numerically obtaining axisymmetric equilibrium structures of rotating stars in two spatial dimensions. With a view to apply it to the secular evolution of rotating stars, we base it on the Lagrangian description, i.e., we solve the force-balance equations to find the spatial positions of fluid elements endowed individually with a mass, specific entropy and angular momentum. The system of nonlinear equations obtained by finite-differencing the basic equations are solved with the W4 method, which is a new multi-dimensional root-finding scheme of our own devising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HD 222925: a New Opportunity to Explore the Astrophysical and Nuclear Conditions of r-process Sites</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hd_222925_a_new_opportunity_to_explore_the_astrophysical_and_nuclear_conditions_of_r-process_sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hd_222925_a_new_opportunity_to_explore_the_astrophysical_and_nuclear_conditions_of_r-process_sites/</guid>
      <description>First author: Erika M. Holmbeck
With the most trans-iron elements detected of any star outside the Solar System, HD 222925 represents the most complete chemical inventory among r-process-enhanced, metal-poor stars. While the abundance pattern of the heaviest elements identified in HD 222925 agrees with the scaled Solar r-process residuals, as is characteristic of its r-process-enhanced classification, the newly measured lighter r-process elements display marked differences from their Solar counterparts. In this work, we explore which single astrophysical site (if any) produced the entire range of elements ($34\leq Z\leq 90$) present in HD 222925.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal rotation and buoyancy travel time of 60 gamma Doradus stars from uninterrupted TESS light curves spanning 352 days</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/internal_rotation_and_buoyancy_travel_time_of_60_gamma_doradus_stars_from_uninterrupted_tess_light_curves_spanning_352_days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/internal_rotation_and_buoyancy_travel_time_of_60_gamma_doradus_stars_from_uninterrupted_tess_light_curves_spanning_352_days/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stefano Garcia
Context. Gamma Doradus (hereafter $\gamma$~Dor) stars are gravity-mode pulsators whose periods carry information about the internal structure of the star. These periods are especially sensitive to the internal rotation and chemical mixing, two processes that are currently not well constrained in the theory of stellar evolution. Aims. We aim to identify the pulsation modes and deduce the internal rotation and buoyancy travel time for 106 $\gamma$ Dor stars observed by the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission in its southern continuous viewing zone (hereafter S-CVZ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean opacities of a strongly magnetized high temperature plasma</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mean_opacities_of_a_strongly_magnetized_high_temperature_plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mean_opacities_of_a_strongly_magnetized_high_temperature_plasma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Valery F. Suleimanov
Geometry and dynamical structure of emission regions in accreting pulsars are shaped by the interplay between gravity, radiation, and strong magnetic field, which significantly affects the opacities of a plasma and radiative pressure under such extreme conditions. Quantitative consideration of magnetic plasma opacities is, therefore, an essential ingredient of any self-consistent modeling of emission region structure of X-ray pulsars. We present results of computations of the Rosseland and Planck mean opacities of a strongly magnetized plasma with a simple chemical composition,namely the solar hydrogen/helium mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling solutions of wiggly cosmic strings: II. Time-varying coarse-graining scale solutions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings_ii._time-varying_coarse-graining_scale_solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings_ii._time-varying_coarse-graining_scale_solutions/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Almeida
We continue our exploration of the wiggly generalisation of the Velocity-Dependent One Scale Model for cosmic strings, through the study of its allowed asymptotic scaling solutions. We extend the work of a previous paper [Almeida $&amp;amp;$ Martins, Phys. Rev. D 104 (2021) 043524] by considering the more comprehensive case of a time-varying coarse-graining scale for the string wiggles. The modeling of the evolution of the network therefore relies on three main mechanisms: Hubble expansion, energy transfer mechanisms (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The orbital evolution of Atira asteroids</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_orbital_evolution_of_atira_asteroids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_orbital_evolution_of_atira_asteroids/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hsuan-Ting Lai
Asteroids having perihelion distance $q$ $&amp;lt;$ 1.3 AU are classified as near-Earth objects (NEOs), which are divided into different sub-groups: Vatira-class, Atira-class, Aten-class, Apollo-class, and Amor-class. 2020 $AV_2$, the first Vatira (Orbiting totally inside Venus&amp;rsquo; orbit) was discovered by the Twilight project of the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) on January 4, 2020. Upon the discovery of 2020 $AV_2$, a couple of orbital studies of the short-term orbital evolution of 2020 $AV_2$ have been performed and published (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The physical drivers of gas turbulence in simulated disc galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_drivers_of_gas_turbulence_in_simulated_disc_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_drivers_of_gas_turbulence_in_simulated_disc_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Esteban Jiménez
We use the EAGLE cosmological simulations to study the evolution of the vertical velocity dispersion of cold gas, $\sigma_{z}$, in central disc galaxies and its connection to stellar feedback, gravitational instabilities, cosmological gas accretion and galaxy mergers. To isolate the impact of feedback, we analyse runs that turn off stellar and (or) AGN feedback in addition to a run that includes both. The evolution of $\sigma_z$ and its dependence on stellar mass and star formation rate in EAGLE are in good agreement with observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A population of Type Ibc supernovae with massive progenitors; broad lightcurves not uncommon in (i)PTF</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_population_of_type_ibc_supernovae_with_massive_progenitors_broad_lightcurves_not_uncommon_in_iptf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_population_of_type_ibc_supernovae_with_massive_progenitors_broad_lightcurves_not_uncommon_in_iptf/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Karamehmetoglu
If high-mass stars (&amp;gt;20-25 Msun) are the progenitors of stripped-envelope (SE) supernovae (SNe), their massive ejecta should lead to broad, long-duration lightcurves (LCs). Instead, literature samples of SE~SNe have reported relatively narrow LCs with ejecta masses between 1-4 Msun that favor progenitors &amp;lt;20-25 Msun. Working with the untargeted sample of (i)PTF SNe to better constrain their rates, we search for SE~SNe with broad LCs. Using a simple LC stretch compared to a template to measure broadness, we identified eight significantly broader Type~Ibc SNe after applying quantitative sample selection criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Statistical Comparison of EUV Brightenings Observed by SO/EUI with Simulated Brightenings in Non-potential Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_comparison_of_euv_brightenings_observed_by_so_eui_with_simulated_brightenings_in_non-potential_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_comparison_of_euv_brightenings_observed_by_so_eui_with_simulated_brightenings_in_non-potential_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Krzysztof Barczynski
The High Resolution Imager (HRI_EUV) telescope of the Extreme Ultraviolet Imager (EUI) instrument onboard Solar Orbiter has observed EUV brightenings, so-called campfires, as fine-scale structures at coronal temperatures. The goal of this paper is to compare the basic geometrical (size, orientation) and physical (intensity, lifetime) properties of the EUV brightenings with regions of energy dissipation in a non-potential coronal magnetic field simulation. In the simulation, HMI line-of-sight magnetograms are used as input to drive the evolution of solar coronal magnetic fields and energy dissipation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALMACAL IX: multi-band ALMA survey for dusty star-forming galaxies and the resolved fractions of the cosmic infrared background</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/almacal_ix_multi-band_alma_survey_for_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_and_the_resolved_fractions_of_the_cosmic_infrared_background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/almacal_ix_multi-band_alma_survey_for_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_and_the_resolved_fractions_of_the_cosmic_infrared_background/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jianhang Chen
Wide, deep, blind continuum surveys at submillimetre/millimetre (submm/mm) wavelengths are required to provide a full inventory of the dusty, distant Universe. However, conducting such surveys to the necessary depth, with sub-arcsec angular resolution, is prohibitively time-consuming, even for the most advanced submm/mm telescopes. Here, we report the most recent results from the ALMACAL project, which exploits the &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; calibration data from the Atacama Large Millimetre/submillimetre Array (ALMA) to map the lines of sight towards and beyond the ALMA calibrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the gamma-ray binary LS I &#43;61 303 harbour a magnetar?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_gamma-ray_binary_ls_i_&#43;61_303_harbour_a_magnetar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_gamma-ray_binary_ls_i_&#43;61_303_harbour_a_magnetar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arthur G. Suvorov
LS I +61{\deg}303 is a high mass X-ray binary that is also catalogued as a gamma-ray binary as a result of frequent outbursts at TeV photon energies. The system has released two soft-gamma flares in the past, suggesting a magnetar interpretation for the compact primary. This inference has recently gained significant traction following the discovery of transient radio pulses, detected in some orbital phases from the system, as the measured rotation and tentative spindown rates imply a polar magnetic field strength of $B_p \gtrsim 10^{14},\mbox{G}$ if the star is decelerating via magnetic dipole braking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Emerging Bipolar Magnetic Regions in Mean-field Dynamo Model of Solar Cycles 23 and 24</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_emerging_bipolar_magnetic_regions_in_mean-field_dynamo_model_of_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_emerging_bipolar_magnetic_regions_in_mean-field_dynamo_model_of_solar_cycles_23_and_24/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. V. Pipin
We model the physical parameters of Solar Cycles 23 and 24 using a nonlinear dynamical mean-field dynamo model that includes the formation and evolution of bipolar magnetic regions (BMR). The Parker-type dynamo model consists of a complete MHD system in the mean-field formulation: the 3D magnetic induction equation, and 2D momentum and energy equations in the anelastic approximation. The initialization of BMR is modeled in the framework of Parker&amp;rsquo;s magnetic buoyancy instability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUMES III: Ultraviolet and Optical Variability of M Dwarf Chromospheres</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fumes_iii_ultraviolet_and_optical_variability_of_m_dwarf_chromospheres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fumes_iii_ultraviolet_and_optical_variability_of_m_dwarf_chromospheres/</guid>
      <description>First author: Girish M. Duvvuri
We obtained ultraviolet and optical spectra for 9 M~dwarfs across a range of rotation periods to determine whether they showed stochastic intrinsic variability distinguishable from flares. The ultraviolet spectra were observed during the Far Ultraviolet M~Dwarf Evolution Survey \emph{Hubble~Space~Telescope} program using the Space Telescope Imaging Spectrograph. The optical observations were taken from the Apache Point Observatory 3.5-meter telescope using the Dual Imaging Spectrograph and from the Gemini South Observatory using the Gemini Multi-Object Spectrograph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint of f(R) gravity in the cosmic magnification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imprint_of_fr_gravity_in_the_cosmic_magnification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imprint_of_fr_gravity_in_the_cosmic_magnification/</guid>
      <description>First author: Didam Duniya
f(R) gravity is one of the simplest viable modifications to General Relativity: it passes local astrophysical tests, predicts both the early-time cosmic inflation and the late-time cosmic acceleration, and also describes dark matter. In this paper, we probe cosmic magnification on large scales in f (R) gravity, using the well-known Hu-Sawicki model as an example. Our results indicate that at redshifts z &amp;lt; 3, values of the model exponent n &amp;gt; 1 lead to inconsistent behaviour in the evolution of scalar perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectro-spatial evolution of the CMB I: discretisation of the thermalisation Green&#39;s function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_i_discretisation_of_the_thermalisation_greens_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_i_discretisation_of_the_thermalisation_greens_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jens Chluba
Spectral distortions of the cosmic microwave background (CMB) have been recognized as an important future probe of the early Universe. Existing theoretical studies primarily focused on describing the evolution and creation of average distortions, ignoring spatial perturbations in the plasma. One of the main reasons for this choice is that a treatment of the spectro-spatial evolution of the photon field deep into the primordial Universe requires solving a radiative transfer problem for the distortion signals, which in full detail is computationally challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stability analysis of planetary systems via second-order Rényi entropy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stability_analysis_of_planetary_systems_via_second-order_r%C3%A9nyi_entropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stability_analysis_of_planetary_systems_via_second-order_r%C3%A9nyi_entropy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tamás Kovács
The long-term dynamical evolution is a crucial point in recent planetary research. Although the amount of observational data is continuously growing and the precision allows us to obtain accurate planetary orbits, the canonical stability analysis still requires N-body simulations and phase space trajectory investigations. We propose a method for stability analysis of planetary motion based on the generalized R&#39;enyi entropy obtained from a scalar measurement. The radial velocity data of the central body in the gravitational three-body problem is used as the basis of a phase space reconstruction procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Turbulent Vertical Mixing in the Venus Clouds on Chemical Tracers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_turbulent_vertical_mixing_in_the_venus_clouds_on_chemical_tracers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_turbulent_vertical_mixing_in_the_venus_clouds_on_chemical_tracers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maxence Lefèvre
Venus clouds host a convective layer between roughly 50 and 60 km that mixes heat, momentum, and chemical species. Observations and numerical modelling have helped to understand the complexity of this region. However, the impact on chemistry is still not known. Here, we use for the first time a three-dimensional convection-resolving model with passive tracers to mimic SO$_2$ and H$_2$O for two latitudinal cases. The tracers are relaxed towards a vertical profile in agreement with measured values, with a timescale varying over several orders of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal and Reionisation History within a Large-volume Semi-Analytic Galaxy Formation Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thermal_and_reionisation_history_within_a_large-volume_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thermal_and_reionisation_history_within_a_large-volume_semi-analytic_galaxy_formation_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sreedhar Balu
We predict the 21-cm global signal and power spectra during the Epoch of Reionisation using the MERAXES semi-analytic galaxy formation and reionisation model, updated to include X-ray heating and thermal evolution of the intergalactic medium. Studying the formation and evolution of galaxies together with the reionisation of cosmic hydrogen using semi-analytic models (such as MERAXES) requires N-body simulations within large volumes and high mass resolutions. For this, we use a simulation of side-length $210$ $h^{-1}$ Mpc with $4320^3$ particles resolving dark matter haloes to masses of $5\times10^8$ $h^{-1}$ $M_\odot$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-969: a late-K dwarf with a hot mini-Neptune in the desert and an eccentric cold Jupiter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-969_a_late-k_dwarf_with_a_hot_mini-neptune_in_the_desert_and_an_eccentric_cold_jupiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-969_a_late-k_dwarf_with_a_hot_mini-neptune_in_the_desert_and_an_eccentric_cold_jupiter/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Lillo-Box
The current architecture of a given multi-planetary system is a key fingerprint of its past formation and dynamical evolution history. Long-term follow-up observations are key to complete their picture. In this paper we focus on the confirmation and characterization of the components of the TOI-969 planetary system, where TESS detected a Neptune-size planet candidate in a very close-in orbit around a late K-dwarf star. We use a set of precise radial velocity observations from HARPS, PFS and CORALIE instruments covering more than two years in combination with the TESS photometric light curve and other ground-based follow-up observations to confirm and characterize the components of this planetary system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature Gas Opacities with AESOPUS 2.0</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-temperature_gas_opacities_with_aesopus_2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-temperature_gas_opacities_with_aesopus_2.0/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paola Marigo
This work introduces new low-temperature gas opacities, in the range 3.2 &amp;lt;= log(T/K) &amp;lt;= 4.5, computed with the AESOPUS code under the assumption of thermodynamic equilibrium (Marigo &amp;amp;_Aringer_2009). In comparison to the previous version AESOPUS 1.0, we updated and expanded molecular absorption to include 80 species, mostly using the recommended line lists currently available from the ExoMol and HITRAN databases. Furthermore, in light of a recent study, we revised the H- photodetachment cross section, added the free-free absorption of other negative ions of atoms and molecules, and updated the collision-induced absorption due to H2/H2, H2/H, H2/He, and H/He pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M31N 1926-07c: A Recurrent Nova in M31 with a 2.8 Year Recurrence Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/m31n_1926-07c_a_recurrent_nova_in_m31_with_a_2.8_year_recurrence_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/m31n_1926-07c_a_recurrent_nova_in_m31_with_a_2.8_year_recurrence_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Allen W. Shafter
The M31 recurrent nova M31N 1926-07c has had five recorded eruptions. Well-sampled light curves of the two most recent outbursts, in January of 2020 (M31N 2020-01b) and September 2022 (M31N 2022-09a), are presented showing that the photometric evolution of the two events were quite similar, with peak magnitudes of $R=17.2\pm0.1$ and $R=17.1\pm0.1$, and $t_2$ times of $9.7\pm0.9$ and $8.1\pm0.5$ days for the 2020 and 2022 eruptions, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Solutions of Wiggly Cosmic Strings</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/scaling_solutions_of_wiggly_cosmic_strings/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. R. R. Almeida
Cosmic string networks form during cosmological phase transitions as a consequence of the Kibble mechanism. The evolution of the simplest networks is accurately described by the canonical Velocity Dependent One-Scale (VOS) model. However, numerical simulations have demonstrated the existence of significant quantities of short-wavelength propagation modes on the strings, known as wiggles, which motivated the recent development of a wiggly string extension of the VOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission spectroscopy of WASP-7 b with UVES -- Detection of Na I D$_2$ and tentative D$_1$ line absorption</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/transmission_spectroscopy_of_wasp-7_b_with_uves_--_detection_of_na_i_d__2__and_tentative_d__1__line_absorption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/transmission_spectroscopy_of_wasp-7_b_with_uves_--_detection_of_na_i_d__2__and_tentative_d__1__line_absorption/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hossein Rahmati
Transmission spectroscopy is a prime technique to study the chemical composition and structure of exoplanetary atmospheres. Strong excess absorption signals have been detected in the optical Na I D1, 2 Fraunhofer lines during transits of hot Jupiters, which are attributed to the planetary atmospheres and allow us to constrain its structure. We study the atmosphere of WASP-7 b by means of high-resolution transit spectroscopy in the sodium lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A sub-Neptune transiting the young field star HD 18599 at 40 pc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sub-neptune_transiting_the_young_field_star_hd_18599_at_40_pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sub-neptune_transiting_the_young_field_star_hd_18599_at_40_pc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jerome P. de Leon
Transiting exoplanets orbiting young nearby stars are ideal laboratories for testing theories of planet formation and evolution. However, to date only a handful of stars with age &amp;lt;1 Gyr have been found to host transiting exoplanets. Here we present the discovery and validation of a sub-Neptune around HD 18599, a young (300 Myr), nearby (d=40 pc) K star. We validate the transiting planet candidate as a bona fide planet using data from the TESS, Spitzer, and Gaia missions, ground-based photometry from IRSF, LCO, PEST, and NGTS, speckle imaging from Gemini, and spectroscopy from CHIRON, NRES, FEROS, and Minerva-Australis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of collisional neutrino flavor instabilities in spherically symmetric supernova models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_collisional_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_spherically_symmetric_supernova_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_collisional_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_spherically_symmetric_supernova_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zewei Xiong
We implement a multi-group and discrete-ordinate neutrino transport model in spherical symmetry which allows to simulate collective neutrino oscillations by including realistic collisional rates in a self-consistent way. We utilize this innovative model, based on strategic parameter rescaling, to study a recently proposed collisional flavor instability caused by the asymmetry of emission and absorption rates between $\nu_e$ and $\bar\nu_e$ for four different static backgrounds taken from different stages in a core-collapse supernova simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Structure and Evolution of BASS AGN through Eddington Ratios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_structure_and_evolution_of_bass_agn_through_eddington_ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_structure_and_evolution_of_bass_agn_through_eddington_ratios/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tonima Tasnim Ananna
We constrain the intrinsic Eddington ratio (\lamEdd ) distribution function for local AGN in bins of low and high obscuration (log NH &amp;lt;= 22 and 22 &amp;lt; log NH &amp;lt; 25), using the Swift-BAT 70-month/BASS DR2 survey. We interpret the fraction of obscured AGN in terms of circum-nuclear geometry and temporal evolution. Specifically, at low Eddington ratios (log lamEdd &amp;lt; -2), obscured AGN outnumber unobscured ones by a factor of ~4, reflecting the covering factor of the circum-nuclear material (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Evolution and Eruption of the Coronal Magnetic Field through a Data-Driven MHD Simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_evolution_and_eruption_of_the_coronal_magnetic_field_through_a_data-driven_mhd_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_evolution_and_eruption_of_the_coronal_magnetic_field_through_a_data-driven_mhd_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Satoshi Inoue
We present a newly developed data-driven magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) simulation code under a zero-beta approximation based on a method proposed by Hayashi et al. 2018 and 2019. Although many data-driven MHD simulations have been developed and conducted, there are not many studies on how accurately those simulations can reproduce the phenomena observed in the solar corona. In this study, we investigated the performance of our data-driven simulation quantitatively using ground-truth data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO2-driven surface changes in the Hapi region on Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co2-driven_surface_changes_in_the_hapi_region_on_comet_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co2-driven_surface_changes_in_the_hapi_region_on_comet_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</guid>
      <description>First author: Björn J. R. Davidsson
Between 2014 December 31 and 2015 March 17, the OSIRIS cameras on Rosetta documented the growth of a 140m wide and 0.5m deep depression in the Hapi region on Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko. This shallow pit is one of several that later formed elsewhere on the comet, all in smooth terrain that primarily is the result of airfall of coma particles. We have compiled observations of this region in Hapi by the microwave instrument MIRO on Rosetta, acquired during October and November 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on Evolutionary Timescales for M Dwarf Planets from Dynamical Stability Arguments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_evolutionary_timescales_for_m_dwarf_planets_from_dynamical_stability_arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_evolutionary_timescales_for_m_dwarf_planets_from_dynamical_stability_arguments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Katie Teixeira
The diversity of dynamical conditions among exoplanets is now well established. Yet, the relevance of orbital dynamical timescales to biological evolutionary timescales is poorly understood. Given that even minor orbital changes may place significant pressure on any organisms living on a planet, dynamical sculpting has important implications for the putative evolution of life. In this manuscript, we employ a Monte Carlo framework to investigate how a range of exoplanetary dynamical sculpting timescales affects timescales for biological evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy Aquarius: evolution of a Milky-way like system in the Fuzzy Dark Matter scenario</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fuzzy_aquarius_evolution_of_a_milky-way_like_system_in_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fuzzy_aquarius_evolution_of_a_milky-way_like_system_in_the_fuzzy_dark_matter_scenario/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matteo Nori
We present the first high-resolution zoom-in simulation of a Milky-way-like halo extracted from the Aquarius Project in the Fuzzy Dark Matter (FDM) framework. We use the N-body code AX-GADGET, based on a particle oriented solution of the Schr&amp;quot;{o}dinger-Poisson equations, able to detail the complexity of structure formation while keeping track of the quantum effects in FDM. The halo shows a cored density profile, with a core size of several kpc for a FDM mass of $m_{\chi}=2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-energy neutrino emission from magnetised jets of rapidly rotating protomagnetars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_magnetised_jets_of_rapidly_rotating_protomagnetars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_magnetised_jets_of_rapidly_rotating_protomagnetars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mukul Bhattacharya
Relativistic jets originating from protomagnetar central engines can lead to long duration gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) and are considered potential sources of ultrahigh-energy cosmic rays and secondary neutrinos. We explore the propagation of such jets through a broad range of progenitors, from stars which have shed their envelopes to supergiants which have not. We use a semi-analytical spindown model for the strongly magnetised and rapidly rotating PNS to investigate the role of central engine properties such as the surface dipole field strength, initial rotation period, and jet opening angle on the interactions and dynamical evolution of the jet-cocoon system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical simulations for the common-envelope wind model for Type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_for_the_common-envelope_wind_model_for_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_for_the_common-envelope_wind_model_for_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yingzhen Cui
The single-degenerate (SD) model is one of the leading models for the progenitors of Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia). Recently, a new version of the SD model, the common-envelope wind (CEW) model, has been proposed, which, in principle, has the potential to resolve most of the difficulties encountered by previous SD models. This model is still being developed and a number of open issues remain, such as the details of the mass-loss mechanism from the surface of the common envelope (CE), the main observational properties, and the spiral-in timescale of the binary inside the envelope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Saturation of the Bell Instability using Hybrid Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_saturation_of_the_bell_instability_using_hybrid_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_saturation_of_the_bell_instability_using_hybrid_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Georgios Zacharegkas
The nonresonant streaming instability (Bell instability) plays a pivotal role in the acceleration and confinement of cosmic rays (CRs); yet, the exact mechanism responsible for its saturation and the magnitude of the final amplified magnetic field have not been assessed from first-principles. Using a survey of hybrid simulations (with kinetic ions and fluid electrons), we study the evolution of the Bell instability as a function of the parameters of the CR population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the time lag between solar wind dynamic parameters and solar activity UV proxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_time_lag_between_solar_wind_dynamic_parameters_and_solar_activity_uv_proxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_time_lag_between_solar_wind_dynamic_parameters_and_solar_activity_uv_proxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Reda
The solar activity displays variability and periodic behaviours over a wide range of timescales, with the presence of a most prominent cycle with a mean length of 11 years. Such variability is transported within the heliosphere by solar wind, radiation and other processes, affecting the properties of the interplanetary medium. The presence of solar activity-related periodicities is well visible in different solar wind and geomagnetic indices, although with time lags with respect to the solar one, leading to hysteresis cycles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photochemistry and Heating/Cooling of the Multiphase Interstellar Medium with UV Radiative Transfer for Magnetohydrodynamic Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photochemistry_and_heating_cooling_of_the_multiphase_interstellar_medium_with_uv_radiative_transfer_for_magnetohydrodynamic_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photochemistry_and_heating_cooling_of_the_multiphase_interstellar_medium_with_uv_radiative_transfer_for_magnetohydrodynamic_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeong-Gyu Kim
We present an efficient heating/cooling method coupled with chemistry and ultraviolet (UV) radiative transfer, which can be applied to numerical simulations of the interstellar medium (ISM). We follow the time-dependent evolution of hydrogen species (H$_2$, H, H$^+$), assume carbon/oxygen species (C, C$^+$, CO, O, and O$^+$) are in formation-destruction balance given the non-steady hydrogen abundances, and include essential heating/cooling processes needed to capture thermodynamics of all ISM phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar feedback impact on the ionized gas kinematics in the dwarf galaxy Sextans A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_feedback_impact_on_the_ionized_gas_kinematics_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_sextans_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_feedback_impact_on_the_ionized_gas_kinematics_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_sextans_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivan S. Gerasimov
Feedback from massive stars shapes the ISM and affects the evolution of galaxies, but its mechanisms acting at the small scales ($\sim 10$ pc) are still not well constrained observationally, especially in the low-metallicity environments. We present the analysis of the ionized gas (focusing on its kinematics, which were never studied before), and its connection to the massive stars in the nearby ($D \sim 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Contribution of In-situ and Ex-situ Star Formation in Early-Type Galaxies: MaNGA versus IllustrisTNG</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_contribution_of_in-situ_and_ex-situ_star_formation_in_early-type_galaxies_manga_versus_illustristng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_contribution_of_in-situ_and_ex-situ_star_formation_in_early-type_galaxies_manga_versus_illustristng/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carlo Cannarozzo
We compare stellar mass surface density, metallicity, age, and line-of-sight velocity dispersion profiles in massive ($M_\geq10^{10.5},\mathrm{M_\odot}$) present-day early-type galaxies (ETGs) from the MaNGA survey with simulated galaxies from the TNG100 simulation of the IllustrisTNG suite. We find an excellent agreement between the stellar mass surface density profiles of MaNGA and TNG100 ETGs, both in shape and normalisation. Moreover, TNG100 reproduces the shapes of the profiles of stellar metallicity and age, as well as the normalisation of velocity dispersion distributions of MaNGA ETGs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The homogeneity of chemical abundances in H II regions of the Magellanic Clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_homogeneity_of_chemical_abundances_in_h_ii_regions_of_the_magellanic_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_homogeneity_of_chemical_abundances_in_h_ii_regions_of_the_magellanic_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Domínguez-Guzmán
We use very deep spectra obtained with the Ultraviolet-Visual Echelle Spectrograph at the Very Large Telescope to derive physical conditions and chemical abundances of four H II regions of the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) and four H II regions of the Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC). The observations cover the spectral range 3100-10400 \A with a spectral resolution of $\Delta\lambda\ge\lambda/11600$, and we measure 95-225 emission lines in each object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PhotoDissociation Region Toolbox: Software and Models for Astrophysical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_photodissociation_region_toolbox_software_and_models_for_astrophysical_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_photodissociation_region_toolbox_software_and_models_for_astrophysical_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marc W. Pound
The PhotoDissociation Region Toolbox provides comprehensive, easy-to-use, public software tools and models that enable an understanding of the interaction of the light of young, luminous, massive stars with the gas and dust in the Milky Way and in other galaxies. It consists of an open-source Python toolkit and photodissociation region models for analysis of infrared and millimeter/submillimeter line and continuum observations obtained by ground-based and sub-orbital telescopes, and astrophysics space missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-179: a young system with a transiting compact Neptune-mass planet and a low-mass companion in outer orbit</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-179_a_young_system_with_a_transiting_compact_neptune-mass_planet_and_a_low-mass_companion_in_outer_orbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-179_a_young_system_with_a_transiting_compact_neptune-mass_planet_and_a_low-mass_companion_in_outer_orbit/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Desidera
Transiting planets around young stars are key benchmarks for our understanding of planetary systems. One of such candidates was identified around the K dwarf HD 18599 by TESS, labeled as TOI-179. We present the confirmation of the transiting planet and the characterization of the host star and of the TOI-179 system over a broad range of angular separations. To this aim, we exploited the TESS photometric time series, intensive radial velocity monitoring performed with HARPS, and deep high-contrast imaging observations obtained with SPHERE and NACO at VLT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Red Giants&#39; Toy Story</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_red_giants_toy_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_red_giants_toy_story/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marcelo M. Miller Bertolami
In spite of the spectacular progress accomplished by stellar evolution theory some simple questions remain unanswered. One of these questions is ``Why do stars become Red Giants?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;. Here we present a relatively simple analytical answer to this question. We validate our analysis by constructing a quantitative toy-model of a red giant and comparing its predictions to full stellar evolutionar models. We find that the envelope forces the value of $\nabla=d \ln T/d \ln P$ at, and above, the burning shell into a very narrow range of possible values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bump Morphology of the CMAGIC Diagram</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bump_morphology_of_the_cmagic_diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bump_morphology_of_the_cmagic_diagram/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Aldoroty
We apply the color-magnitude intercept calibration method (CMAGIC) to the Nearby Supernova Factory SNe Ia spectrophotometric dataset. The currently existing CMAGIC parameters are the slope and intercept of a straight line fit to the first linear region in the color-magnitude diagram, which occurs over a span of approximately 30 days after maximum brightness. We define a new parameter, $\omega_{XY}$, the size of the ``bump&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; feature near maximum brightness for arbitrary filters $X$ and $Y$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions of structural variations to the asymptotic mixed-mode coupling Factor in red giant stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/contributions_of_structural_variations_to_the_asymptotic_mixed-mode_coupling_factor_in_red_giant_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/contributions_of_structural_variations_to_the_asymptotic_mixed-mode_coupling_factor_in_red_giant_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chen Jiang
The advent of ultra-precise photometry space missions enable the possibility of investigating stellar interior with mixed modes. The structural variations induced by the discontinuity of the chemical composition left behind during the first dredge&amp;ndash;up is an important feature in the stellar mid-layers located between the hydrogen-burning shell and the base of the convective zone of red giants, as the mixed-mode properties can be significantly affected by these variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of barium in the atmospheres of the ultra-hot gas giants WASP-76b and WASP-121b</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_barium_in_the_atmospheres_of_the_ultra-hot_gas_giants_wasp-76b_and_wasp-121b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_barium_in_the_atmospheres_of_the_ultra-hot_gas_giants_wasp-76b_and_wasp-121b/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Azevedo Silva
High-resolution spectroscopy studies of ultra-hot Jupiters have been key in our understanding of exoplanet atmospheres. Observing into the atmospheres of these giant planets allows for direct constraints on their atmospheric compositions and dynamics while laying the groundwork for new research regarding their formation and evolution environments. Two of the most well-studied ultra-hot Jupiters are WASP-76b and WASP-121b, with multiple detected chemical species and strong signatures of their atmospheric dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-infrared Chemical Abundances of Stars in the Sculptor Dwarf Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/near-infrared_chemical_abundances_of_stars_in_the_sculptor_dwarf_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/near-infrared_chemical_abundances_of_stars_in_the_sculptor_dwarf_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Baitian Tang
Owing to the recent identification of major substructures in our Milky Way (MW), the astronomical community start to reevaluate the importance of dissolved and existing dwarf galaxies. In this work, we investigate up to 13 elements in 43 giant stars of Sculptor dwarf galaxy (Scl) using high signal-to-noise ratio near-infrared APOGEE spectra. Thanks to the strong feature lines in the near-infrared, high resolution O, Si, and Al abundances are determined at such large group of sample stars for the first time in Scl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the N/O abundance ratio and the progenitor mass for the most luminous planetary nebulae of M 31</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_n_o_abundance_ratio_and_the_progenitor_mass_for_the_most_luminous_planetary_nebulae_of_m_31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_n_o_abundance_ratio_and_the_progenitor_mass_for_the_most_luminous_planetary_nebulae_of_m_31/</guid>
      <description>First author: Toshiya Ueta
Plasma diagnostics are the bases of investigation into the physical and chemical properties of line-emitting gaseous systems. To perform plasma diagnostics properly, it is essential to correct the input spectrum for extinction properly. This is simply because determining the degree of extinction is dependent on the physical properties of the line-emitting gas. Hence, both extinction correction and plasma diagnostics have to be performed simultaneously and self-consistently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the interaction between dark energy and dark matter with future fast radio burst observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_interaction_between_dark_energy_and_dark_matter_with_future_fast_radio_burst_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_interaction_between_dark_energy_and_dark_matter_with_future_fast_radio_burst_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ze-Wei Zhao
Interacting dark energy (IDE) scenario assumes that there exists a direct interaction between dark energy and cold dark matter, but this interaction is hard to be tightly constrained by the current data. Finding new cosmological probes to precisely measure this interaction could deepen our understanding of dark energy and dark matter. Fast radio bursts (FRBs) will be seen in large numbers by future radio telescopes, and thus they have potential to become a promising low-redshift cosmological probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid grains ejected from terrestrial exoplanets as a probe of the abundance of life in the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solid_grains_ejected_from_terrestrial_exoplanets_as_a_probe_of_the_abundance_of_life_in_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solid_grains_ejected_from_terrestrial_exoplanets_as_a_probe_of_the_abundance_of_life_in_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tomonori Totani
Searching for extrasolar biosignatures is important to understand life on Earth and its origin. Astronomical observations of exoplanets may find such signatures, but it is difficult and may be impossible to claim unambiguous detection of life by remote sensing of exoplanet atmospheres. Here, another approach is considered: collecting grains ejected by asteroid impacts from habitable exoplanets in the Milky Way and then traveling to the Solar System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of HD 106906 debris disc: A binary&#39;s revenge</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_case_of_hd_106906_debris_disc_a_binarys_revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_case_of_hd_106906_debris_disc_a_binarys_revenge/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mohammad Farhat
Debris disc architecture presents [exo-]planetary scientists with precious clues for processes of planet formation and evolution, including constraints on planetary mass perturbers (hidden or not). This is particularly true of the disc in HD 106906 which in early HST, then follow up polarimetric observations, presented asymmetries and needle-like features that have been attributed to perturbations by a massive, and unusually distant planetary companion external to the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Solar and Stellar Flares/CMEs: Expanding Heliophysics to Encompass Exoplanetary Space Weather</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/connecting_solar_and_stellar_flares_cmes_expanding_heliophysics_to_encompass_exoplanetary_space_weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/connecting_solar_and_stellar_flares_cmes_expanding_heliophysics_to_encompass_exoplanetary_space_weather/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. J. Lynch
The aim of this white paper is to briefly summarize some of the outstanding gaps in the observations and modeling of stellar flares, CMEs, and exoplanetary space weather, and to discuss how the theoretical and computational tools and methods that have been developed in heliophysics can play a critical role in meeting these challenges. The maturity of data-inspired and data-constrained modeling of the Sun-to-Earth space weather chain provides a natural starting point for the development of new, multidisciplinary research and applications to other stars and their exoplanetary systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic evolution of grain size distribution in galaxies using the $ν^2$GC semi-analytic model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_evolution_of_grain_size_distribution_in_galaxies_using_the__%CE%BD2_gc_semi-analytic_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_evolution_of_grain_size_distribution_in_galaxies_using_the__%CE%BD2_gc_semi-analytic_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryu Makiya
We investigate the cosmological evolution of interstellar dust with a semi-analytical galaxy formation model ($\nu^2$GC), focusing on the evolution of grain size distribution. The model predicts the statistical properties of dust mass and grain size distribution in galaxies across cosmic history. We confirm that the model reproduces the relation between dust-to-gas ratio and metallicity in the local Universe, and that the grain size distributions of the Milky Way (MW)-like sample become similar to the so-called MRN distribution that reproduces the observed MW extinction curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a probable very fast extragalactic nova in a symbiotic binary</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_probable_very_fast_extragalactic_nova_in_a_symbiotic_binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_probable_very_fast_extragalactic_nova_in_a_symbiotic_binary/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Modiano
Very fast novae are novae which evolve exceptionally quickly (on timescales of only days). Due to their rapid evolution, very fast novae are challenging to detect and study, especially at early times. Here we report the discovery, which was made as part of our Transient UV Objects project, of a probable very fast nova in the nearby spiral galaxy NGC 300. We detected the rise to the peak (which is rarely observed for very fast novae) in the near-ultraviolet (NUV), with the first detection just ~2 hours after the eruption started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Manifold: Characterizing and understanding galaxies with two parameters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_manifold_characterizing_and_understanding_galaxies_with_two_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_manifold_characterizing_and_understanding_galaxies_with_two_parameters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suchetha Cooray
We report the discovery of a two-dimensional Galaxy Manifold within the multi-dimensional luminosity space of local galaxies. The multi-dimensional luminosity space is constructed using 11 bands that span from far ultraviolet to near-infrared for redshift &amp;lt; 0.1 galaxies observed with GALEX, SDSS, and UKIDSS. The two latent parameters are sufficient to express 93.2% of the variance in the galaxy sample, suggesting that this Galaxy Manifold is one of the most efficient representations of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field evolution in cosmic filaments with LOFAR data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_evolution_in_cosmic_filaments_with_lofar_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_evolution_in_cosmic_filaments_with_lofar_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Carretti
Measuring the magnetic field in cosmic filaments reveals how the Universe is magnetised and the process that magnetised it. Using the Rotation Measures (RM) at 144-MHz from the LoTSS DR2 data, we analyse the rms of the RM extragalactic component as a function of redshift to investigate the evolution with redshift of the magnetic field in filaments. From previous results, we find that the extragalactic term of the RM rms at 144-MHz is dominated by the contribution from filaments (more than 90 percent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested Dust Shells around the Wolf-Rayet Binary WR 140 observed with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nested_dust_shells_around_the_wolf-rayet_binary_wr_140_observed_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nested_dust_shells_around_the_wolf-rayet_binary_wr_140_observed_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan M. Lau
Massive colliding-wind binaries that host a Wolf-Rayet (WR) star present a potentially important source of dust and chemical enrichment in the interstellar medium (ISM). However, the chemical composition and survival of dust formed from such systems is not well understood. The carbon-rich WR (WC) binary WR~140 presents an ideal astrophysical laboratory for investigating these questions given its well-defined orbital period and predictable dust-formation episodes every 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAD@home citizen science discovery of an AGN spewing a large unipolar radio bubble onto its merging companion galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radhome_citizen_science_discovery_of_an_agn_spewing_a_large_unipolar_radio_bubble_onto_its_merging_companion_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radhome_citizen_science_discovery_of_an_agn_spewing_a_large_unipolar_radio_bubble_onto_its_merging_companion_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ananda Hota
AGN feedback during galaxy merger has been the most favoured model to explain black hole-galaxy co-evolution. However, how the AGN-driven jet/wind/radiation is coupled with the gas of the merging galaxies, which leads to positive feedback, momentarily enhanced star formation, and subsequently negative feedback, a decline in star formation, is poorly understood. Only a few cases are known where the jet and companion galaxy interaction leads to minor off-axis distortions in the jets and enhanced star formation in the gas-rich minor companions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of HCO$^{&#43;}$ in molecular clouds using a novel chemical post-processing algorithm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_hco_&#43;__in_molecular_clouds_using_a_novel_chemical_post-processing_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_hco_&#43;__in_molecular_clouds_using_a_novel_chemical_post-processing_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Panessa
Modeling the internal chemistry of molecular clouds is critical to accurately simulating their evolution. To reduce computational expense, 3D simulations generally restrict their chemical modeling to species with strong heating and cooling effects. We address this by post-processing tracer particles in the SILCC-Zoom molecular cloud simulations. Using a chemical network of 39 species and 299 reactions (including freeze-out of CO and H$2$O), and a novel iterative algorithm to reconstruct a filled density grid from sparse tracer particle data, we produce time-dependent density distributions for various species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interplay between forming planets and photo-evaporating discs I: Forbidden line diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_forming_planets_and_photo-evaporating_discs_i_forbidden_line_diagnostics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_interplay_between_forming_planets_and_photo-evaporating_discs_i_forbidden_line_diagnostics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael L. Weber
Disc winds and planet formation are considered to be two of the most important mechanisms that drive the evolution and dispersal of protoplanetary discs and in turn define the environment in which planets form and evolve. While both have been studied extensively in the past, we combine them into one model by performing three-dimensional radiation-hydrodynamic simulations of giant planet hosting discs that are undergoing X-ray photo-evaporation, with the goal to analyse the interactions between both mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold gas mass measurements for the era of large optical spectroscopic surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cold_gas_mass_measurements_for_the_era_of_large_optical_spectroscopic_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cold_gas_mass_measurements_for_the_era_of_large_optical_spectroscopic_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dirk Scholte
Gas plays an important role in many processes in galaxy formation and evolution, but quantifying the importance of gas has been hindered by the challenge to measure gas masses for large samples of galaxies. Datasets of direct atomic and molecular gas measurements are sufficient to establish simple scaling relations, but often not large enough to quantify three-parameter relations, or second order dependencies. As an alternative approach, we derive here indirect cold gas measurements from optical emission lines using photoionization models for galaxies in the SDSS main galaxy sample and the PHANGS-MUSE survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of a cyclic period change in the contact binary TU UMi</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_a_cyclic_period_change_in_the_contact_binary_tu_umi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_a_cyclic_period_change_in_the_contact_binary_tu_umi/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dicle Zengin Çamurdan
This study aims at timing the eclipses of the binary star TU UMi. The times of minima are taken from the literature, from our observations in April 2004 and from TESS observations between 2019 and 2022. The orbital period analysis of the system indicates that there is a cyclic oscillation with an amplitude of 0.0081d and a period of 9.03 yr, accompanied by a continuous decrease at a rate of $dP/dt =-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Accretion Properties of Black Hole X-Ray Binaries: A Phenomenological Perspective</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/global_accretion_properties_of_black_hole_x-ray_binaries_a_phenomenological_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/global_accretion_properties_of_black_hole_x-ray_binaries_a_phenomenological_perspective/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arghajit Jana
Black hole X-ray binaries (BHXBs) show rich phenomenology in the spectral and timing properties. We collected the spectral data of 20 BHXBs from the literature across different spectral states. The spectral properties are studied in the forms of the inner disc temperature ($T_{\rm in}$), photon index ($\Gamma$), hot electron temperature ($kT_{\rm e}$), X-ray flux ($F_{\rm X}$) and luminosity ($L_{\rm X}$). We studied various correlations among different spectral parameters to understand the accretion process on a global scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KIC 7955301: a hierarchical triple system with eclipse timing variations and an oscillating red giant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kic_7955301_a_hierarchical_triple_system_with_eclipse_timing_variations_and_an_oscillating_red_giant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kic_7955301_a_hierarchical_triple_system_with_eclipse_timing_variations_and_an_oscillating_red_giant/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Gaulme
KIC 7955301 is a hierarchical triple system with eclipse timing and depth variations discovered by the Kepler mission. It is composed of a non-eclipsing primary star at the bottom of the red giant branch on a 209-day orbit with a K/G-type main-sequence inner eclipsing binary, orbiting in 15.3 days. This system was noted for the large amplitude of its eclipse timing variations (4 hours), and the clear solar-like oscillations of the red-giant component, including p-modes of degree up to l=3 and mixed l=1 modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lithospheric loading model for large impact basin where mantle plug presents</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lithospheric_loading_model_for_large_impact_basin_where_mantle_plug_presents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lithospheric_loading_model_for_large_impact_basin_where_mantle_plug_presents/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qingyun Deng
Lithosphere is the outer rigid part of terrestrial body, usually consisting of the crust and part of the mantle. Characterizing the physical properties of lithosphere is critical in the investigation to its evolution history. Through the modeling of mass-related loads within lithosphere, physical parameters such as elastic thickness of lithosphere can be inferred by gravity and topography data. At impact basin region, however, the low correlation between topography and gravity makes this model inapplicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-infrared and Optical Nebular-phase Spectra of Type Ia Supernovae SN 2013aa and SN 2017cbv in NGC 5643</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/near-infrared_and_optical_nebular-phase_spectra_of_type_ia_supernovae_sn_2013aa_and_sn_2017cbv_in_ngc_5643/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/near-infrared_and_optical_nebular-phase_spectra_of_type_ia_supernovae_sn_2013aa_and_sn_2017cbv_in_ngc_5643/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sahana Kumar
We present multi-wavelength time-series spectroscopy of SN 2013aa and SN 2017cbv, two Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) on the outskirts of the same host galaxy, NGC 5643. This work utilizes new nebular-phase near-infrared (NIR) spectra obtained by the Carnegie Supernova Project-II, in addition to previously published optical and NIR spectra. By measuring nebular-phase [Fe II] lines in both the optical and NIR, we examine the explosion kinematics and test the efficacy of several emission line fitting techniques commonly used in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New insights from cross-correlation studies between Solar activity and Cosmic-ray fluxes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_insights_from_cross-correlation_studies_between_solar_activity_and_cosmic-ray_fluxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_insights_from_cross-correlation_studies_between_solar_activity_and_cosmic-ray_fluxes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicola Tomassetti
The observed variability of the cosmic-ray intensity in the interplanetary space is driven by the evolution of the Sun&amp;rsquo;s magnetic activity over its 11-year quasiperiodical cycle. Investigating the relationship between solar activity indices and cosmic-ray intensity measurements is then essential for understanding the fundamental processes of particle transport in the heliosphere. Here we have performed a global characterization the solar modulation of cosmic rays over the solar activity cycle and for different energies of the cosmic particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 6153: Reality is complicated</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ngc_6153_reality_is_complicated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ngc_6153_reality_is_complicated/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael G. Richer
We study the kinematics of emission lines that arise from many physical processes in NGC 6153 based upon deep, spatially-resolved, high resolution spectra acquired with the UVES spectrograph at the ESO VLT. Our most basic finding is that the plasma in NGC 6153 is complex, especially its temperature structure. The kinematics of most emission lines defines a classic expansion law, with the outer part expanding fastest (normal nebular plasma).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuSTAR observation of X-ray pulsar 1E 1145.1-6141</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observation_of_x-ray_pulsar_1e_1145.1-6141/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nustar_observation_of_x-ray_pulsar_1e_1145.1-6141/</guid>
      <description>First author: Manoj Ghising
In this paper, we report on the hard X-ray observation of the X-ray pulsar 1E 1145.1-6141 performed with the Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array mission (NuSTAR). The coherent pulsation of the source with a period of $\sim296.653;\pm;0.021;s $ is detected. The source may be in the equilibrium phase, according to the most recent measurements of its pulse period. The pulse profile reveals a mild energy dependence and generally hints at a pencil-beam pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the low-mass end of core-collapse supernovae using a sample of strongly-stripped Calcium-rich Type IIb Supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_core-collapse_supernovae_using_a_sample_of_strongly-stripped_calcium-rich_type_iib_supernovae_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_core-collapse_supernovae_using_a_sample_of_strongly-stripped_calcium-rich_type_iib_supernovae_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kaustav K. Das
The fate of stars in the zero-age main-sequence (ZAMS) range $\approx 8-12$ Msun is unclear. They could evolve to form white dwarfs or explode as electron-capture supernovae (SNe) or iron core-collapse SNe (CCSNe). Even though the initial mass function indicates that this mass range should account for over 40% of all CCSNe progenitors, few have been observationally confirmed, likely owing to the faintness and rapid evolution of these transients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Conformity Across Cosmic Time with Local Group and Local Volume Star Formation Histories</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_conformity_across_cosmic_time_with_local_group_and_local_volume_star_formation_histories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_conformity_across_cosmic_time_with_local_group_and_local_volume_star_formation_histories/</guid>
      <description>First author: Charlotte Olsen
Conformity denotes the correlation of properties between pairs of galaxies as a function of separation. Correlations between properties such as star formation rate (SFR), stellar mass, and specific star formation rate (sSFR) have implications for the impact of environment upon galaxy formation and evolution. Conformity between primary galaxies and satellites within the same dark matter halo has been well documented in simulations and observations. However, the existence of conformity at greater distances - known as two-halo conformity - remains uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B-fields do not suppress star formation in low metallicity dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/b-fields_do_not_suppress_star_formation_in_low_metallicity_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/b-fields_do_not_suppress_star_formation_in_low_metallicity_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David J. Whitworth
Many studies have looked at the impact of magnetic fields on star formation in molecular clouds and Milky Way like galaxies, concluding that the field suppresses star formation. However, most of these studies are based on fully developed fields that have reached the saturation level, with little work on investigating how the growth phase of a primordial field affects star formation in low metallicity environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beamforming approaches toward detecting the 21-cm global signal from Cosmic Dawn with radio array telescopes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beamforming_approaches_toward_detecting_the_21-cm_global_signal_from_cosmic_dawn_with_radio_array_telescopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beamforming_approaches_toward_detecting_the_21-cm_global_signal_from_cosmic_dawn_with_radio_array_telescopes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Danny C. Price
The formation of the first stars and galaxies during &amp;lsquo;Cosmic Dawn&amp;rsquo; is thought to have imparted a faint signal onto the 21-cm spin temperature from atomic Hydrogen gas in the early Universe. Observationally, an absorption feature should be measurable as a frequency-dependence in the sky-averaged (i.e. global) temperature at meter wavelengths. This signal should be separable from the smooth &amp;ndash; but orders of magnitude brighter &amp;ndash; foregrounds by jointly fitting a log-polynomial and absorption trough to radiometer spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on populations of neutrino sources from searches in the directions of IceCube neutrino alerts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_populations_of_neutrino_sources_from_searches_in_the_directions_of_icecube_neutrino_alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_populations_of_neutrino_sources_from_searches_in_the_directions_of_icecube_neutrino_alerts/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Abbasi
Beginning in 2016, the IceCube Neutrino Observatory has sent out alerts in real time containing the information of high-energy ($E \gtrsim 100$~TeV) neutrino candidate events with moderate-to-high ($\gtrsim 30$%) probability of astrophysical origin. In this work, we use a recent catalog of such alert events, which, in addition to events announced in real-time, includes events that were identified retroactively, and covers the time period of 2011-2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Mars&#39; habitability and global cooling by H2-based methanogens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early_mars_habitability_and_global_cooling_by_h2-based_methanogens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early_mars_habitability_and_global_cooling_by_h2-based_methanogens/</guid>
      <description>First author: Boris Sauterey
During the Noachian, Mars&amp;rsquo; crust may have provided a favorable environment for microbial life. The porous brine-saturated regolith would have created a physical space sheltered from UV and cosmic radiations and provided a solvent, while the below-ground temperature and diffusion of a dense reduced atmosphere may have supported simple microbial organisms that consume H2 and CO2 as energy and carbon sources and produce methane as a waste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Espresso observations of HE 0107$-$5240 and other CEMP-no stars with $\rm [Fe/H]\le -4.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/espresso_observations_of_he_0107_-_5240_and_other_cemp-no_stars_with___rm_fe_h_le_-4.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/espresso_observations_of_he_0107_-_5240_and_other_cemp-no_stars_with___rm_fe_h_le_-4.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Aguado
HE 0107$-$5240 is a hyper metal-poor star with $\rm [Fe/H]=-5.39$. We performed high-res observations with the ESPRESSO spectrograph at the VLT to constrain the kinematical properties of the binary system HE 0107$-$5240 and to probe the binarity of the sample of 8 most metal-poor stars with $\rm [Fe/H]&amp;lt;-4.5$. Radial velocities are obtained by using cross-correlation in the interval 4200$-$4315A, which contains the strong CH band, against a template in an iterative process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of different recipes for chromospheric radiative losses in solar flares</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evaluation_of_different_recipes_for_chromospheric_radiative_losses_in_solar_flares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evaluation_of_different_recipes_for_chromospheric_radiative_losses_in_solar_flares/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Tian
Context. Radiative losses are an indispensable part in the numerical simulation of flares. Detailed calculations could be computationally expensive, especially in the chromosphere. There have been some approximate recipes for chromospheric radiative losses in flares, yet their feasibility in flare simulations needs further evaluation. Aims. We aim to evaluate the performance of different recipes for chromospheric radiative losses in flare simulations. Methods. We compare the atmospheric structure and line profiles in beam-heated flares calculated with detailed radiative losses and the approximate recipes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Star Formation in Overdense Regions of the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/massive_star_formation_in_overdense_regions_of_the_early_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/massive_star_formation_in_overdense_regions_of_the_early_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: John Regan
Both the origin of, and the population demographics of, massive black holes (MBHs) remains an open question in modern day astrophysics. Here we introduce the BlackDemon suite of cosmological simulations using the Enzo code. The suite consists of three, high resolution, distinct regions, each with a side length of 1 $\rm{h}^{-1}$ Mpc, evolving within a larger overdense region. The simulation suite has spatial and mass resolution capable of resolving the formation of the first galaxies and MBHs within each region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIGHTEE-HI: The $M_{\rm HI}-M_{\star}$ relation over the last billion years</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mightee-hi_the__m__rm_hi-m__star__relation_over_the_last_billion_years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mightee-hi_the__m__rm_hi-m__star__relation_over_the_last_billion_years/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hengxing Pan
We measure the $M_{\rm HI}-M_{\star}$ relation over the last billion years down to $M_{\rm HI}\sim 10^7 M_{\odot}$ using the MIGHTEE Early Science data with a Bayesian technique. This technique is applied to the HI detections, without binning the datasets, while taking account of the intrinsic scatter in the $M_{\rm HI}-M_{\star}$ relation. We divide the full sample of 249 galaxies into 161 spirals, 64 irregulars, 15 mergers, and 9 elliptical galaxies to measure their $M_{\rm HI}-M_{\star}$ relations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dense $\mathbf{0.1 M_{\rm \odot}}$ star in a 51-minute orbital period eclipsing binary</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_dense___mathbf0.1_m__rm__odot__star_in_a_51-minute_orbital_period_eclipsing_binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_dense___mathbf0.1_m__rm__odot__star_in_a_51-minute_orbital_period_eclipsing_binary/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kevin B. Burdge
In over a thousand known cataclysmic variables (CVs), where a white dwarf is accreting from a hydrogen-rich star, only a dozen have orbital periods below 75 minutes. One way to achieve these short periods requires the donor star to have undergone substantial nuclear evolution prior to interacting with the white dwarf, and it is expected that these objects will transition to helium accretion. These transitional CVs have been proposed as progenitors of helium CVs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lower bound on intergalactic magnetic fields from time variability of 1ES 0229&#43;200 from MAGIC and Fermi/LAT observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lower_bound_on_intergalactic_magnetic_fields_from_time_variability_of_1es_0229&#43;200_from_magic_and_fermi_lat_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lower_bound_on_intergalactic_magnetic_fields_from_time_variability_of_1es_0229&#43;200_from_magic_and_fermi_lat_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: MAGIC Collaboration
Extended and delayed emission around distant TeV sources induced by the effects of propagation of gamma rays through the intergalactic medium can be used for the measurement of the intergalactic magnetic field (IGMF). We search for delayed GeV emission from the hard-spectrum TeV blazar 1ES 0229+200 with the goal to detect or constrain the IGMF-dependent secondary flux generated during the propagation of TeV gamma rays through the intergalactic medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new approach to kinetic energy flux at the different frequencies above the IRIS Bright Points</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_approach_to_kinetic_energy_flux_at_the_different_frequencies_above_the_iris_bright_points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_approach_to_kinetic_energy_flux_at_the_different_frequencies_above_the_iris_bright_points/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rayhane Sadeghi
Various bright structures abound in the chromosphere playing an essential role in the dynamics and evolution therein. Tentatively identifying the wave characteristics in the outer solar atmosphere helps to understand this layer better. One of the most significant aspects of these characteristics is the wave phase speed (PS), which is a dominant contribution to solar coronal heating and Energy distribution in the Sun&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere layers. To obtain energy flux (EF), it is necessary to calculate the filling factor (FF) and the PS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A possible 250-second X-ray quasi-periodicity in the fast blue optical transient AT2018cow</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_250-second_x-ray_quasi-periodicity_in_the_fast_blue_optical_transient_at2018cow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_250-second_x-ray_quasi-periodicity_in_the_fast_blue_optical_transient_at2018cow/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wenjie Zhang
The fast blue optical transients (FBOTs) are a new population of extragalactic transients of unclear physical origin. A variety of mechanisms have been proposed including failed supernova explosion, shock interaction with a dense medium, young magnetar, accretion onto a compact object, and stellar tidal disruption event, but none is conclusive. Here we report the discovery of a possible X-ray quasi-periodicity signal with a period of $\sim$250 second (at a significance level of 99.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quarter Century of Guitar Nebula/Filament Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_quarter_century_of_guitar_nebula_filament_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_quarter_century_of_guitar_nebula_filament_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martijn de Vries
We have collected a new deep {\it Chandra X-ray Observatory} ({\it CXO}) exposure of PSR B2224+65 and the `Guitar Nebula&amp;rsquo;, mapping the complex X-ray structure. This is accompanied by a new {\it HST} H$\alpha$ image of the head of the Guitar. Comparing the {\it HST} and {\it CXO} structures in 4 epochs over 25 years, we constrain the evolution of the TeV particles that light up the filament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceleration of cosmic rays in presence of magnetohydrodynamic fluctuations at small scales</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/acceleration_of_cosmic_rays_in_presence_of_magnetohydrodynamic_fluctuations_at_small_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/acceleration_of_cosmic_rays_in_presence_of_magnetohydrodynamic_fluctuations_at_small_scales/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sayan Kundu
This work investigates the evolution of the distribution of charged particles (cosmic rays) due to the mechanism of stochastic turbulent acceleration (STA) in presence of small-scale turbulence with a mean magnetic field. STA is usually modelled as a biased random walk process in the momentum space of the non-thermal particles. This results in an advection-diffusion type transport equation for the non-thermal particle distribution function. Under quasilinear approximation, and by assuming a turbulent spectrum with single scale injection at sub-gyroscale, we find that the Fokker-Planck diffusion coefficients $D_{\gamma\gamma}$ and $D_{\mu\mu}$ scale with the Lorentz factor $\gamma$ as: $D_{\gamma\gamma}\propto\gamma^{-2/3}$ and $D_{\mu\mu}\propto\gamma^{-8/3}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An extreme blue nugget, UV-bright starburst at z=3.613 with ninety per cent of Lyman continuum photon escape</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extreme_blue_nugget_uv-bright_starburst_at_z3.613_with_ninety_per_cent_of_lyman_continuum_photon_escape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extreme_blue_nugget_uv-bright_starburst_at_z3.613_with_ninety_per_cent_of_lyman_continuum_photon_escape/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Marques-Chaves
We present the discovery and analysis of J1316+2614 at z=3.6130, a UV-bright star-forming galaxy ($M_{\rm UV} \simeq -24.7$) with large escape of Lyman continuum (LyC) radiation. J1316+2614 is a young ($\simeq 10$ Myr) star-forming galaxy with $SFR \simeq 500 M_{\odot}$ yr$^{-1}$ and a starburst mass of log($M_{\star}/M_{\odot}) \simeq 9.7$. It shows a very steep UV continuum, $\beta_{\rm UV} \simeq -2.59 \pm 0.05$, consistent with residual dust obscuration, $E(B-V)\simeq 0$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interpretable Machine Learning Framework for Modeling High-Resolution Spectroscopic Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_interpretable_machine_learning_framework_for_modeling_high-resolution_spectroscopic_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_interpretable_machine_learning_framework_for_modeling_high-resolution_spectroscopic_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael A. Gully-Santiago
Comparison of echelle spectra to synthetic models has become a computational statistics challenge, with over ten thousand individual spectral lines affecting a typical cool star echelle spectrum. Telluric artifacts, imperfect line lists, inexact continuum placement, and inflexible models frustrate the scientific promise of these information-rich datasets. Here we debut an interpretable machine-learning framework &amp;ldquo;blas&#39;e&amp;rdquo; that addresses these and other challenges. The semi-empirical approach can be viewed as &amp;ldquo;transfer learning&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; first pre-training models on noise-free precomputed synthetic spectral models, then learning the corrections to line depths and widths from whole-spectrum fitting to an observed spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of a new sub-grid model for magneto-hydrodynamical turbulence. I. Magnetorotational instability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/assessment_of_a_new_sub-grid_model_for_magneto-hydrodynamical_turbulence._i._magnetorotational_instability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/assessment_of_a_new_sub-grid_model_for_magneto-hydrodynamical_turbulence._i._magnetorotational_instability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Miquel Miravet-Tenés
Insufficient numerical resolution of grid-based, direct numerical simulations (DNS) hampers the development of instabilitydriven turbulence at small (unresolved) scales. As an alternative to DNS, sub-grid models can potentially reproduce the effects of turbulence at small scales in terms of the resolved scales, and hence can capture physical effects with less computational resources. We present a new sub-grid model, the MHD-instability-induced-turbulence (MInIT) mean-field model. MInIT is a physically motivated model based on the evolution of the turbulent (Maxwell, Reynolds, and Faraday) stress tensors and their relation with the turbulent energy densities of the magneto-rotational (MRI) and parasitic instabilities, modeled with two partial differential evolution equations with stiff source terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Born this way: thin disc, thick disc, and isotropic spheroid formation in FIRE-2 Milky-Way-mass galaxy simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/born_this_way_thin_disc_thick_disc_and_isotropic_spheroid_formation_in_fire-2_milky-way-mass_galaxy_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/born_this_way_thin_disc_thick_disc_and_isotropic_spheroid_formation_in_fire-2_milky-way-mass_galaxy_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sijie Yu
We investigate the formation of Milky-Way-mass galaxies using FIRE-2 LCDM cosmological zoom-in simulations by studying the orbital evolution of stars formed in the main progenitor of the galaxy, from birth to the present day. We classify in situ stars as isotropic spheroid, thick-disc, and thin-disc according to their orbital circularities and show that these components are assembled in a time-ordered sequence from early to late times, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet nuclei composition and evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_nuclei_composition_and_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_nuclei_composition_and_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gianrico Filacchione
Thanks to Rosetta orbiter&amp;rsquo;s and Philae lander&amp;rsquo;s data our knowledge of cometary nuclei composition has experienced a great advancement. The properties of 67P/CG nucleus are discussed and compared with other comets explored in the past by space missions. Cometary nuclei are made by a collection of ices, minerals, organic matter, and salts resulting in very dark and red-colored surfaces. When far from the Sun, exposed water and carbon dioxide ices are found only in few locations of 67P/CG where the exposure of pristine subsurface layers or the recondensation of volatile species driven by the solar heating and local terrain morphology can sustain their temporary presence on the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences of dynamically unstable moons in extrasolar systems</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/consequences_of_dynamically_unstable_moons_in_extrasolar_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/consequences_of_dynamically_unstable_moons_in_extrasolar_systems/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bradley M. S. Hansen
Moons orbiting rocky exoplanets in compact orbits about other stars experience an accelerated tidal evolution, and can either merge with their parent planet or reach the limit of dynamical instability within a Hubble time. We review the parameter space over which moons become unbound, including the effects of atmospheric tides on the planetary spin. We find that such tides can change the final outcome from merger to escape, albeit over a limited parameter space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on Cosmological Parameters with a Sample of Type Ia Supernovae from JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_cosmological_parameters_with_a_sample_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_cosmological_parameters_with_a_sample_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jia Lu
We investigate the potential of using a sample of very high-redshift ($2\lesssim z \lesssim6$) (VHZ) Type Ia supernovae (SNe~Ia) attainable by the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) on constraining cosmological parameters. At such high redshifts, the age of the universe is young enough that the VHZ SNIa sample comprises the very first SNe~Ia of the universe, with progenitors among the very first generation of low mass stars that the universe has made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on the phase transition of Early Dark Energy with the CMB anisotropies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_phase_transition_of_early_dark_energy_with_the_cmb_anisotropies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_the_phase_transition_of_early_dark_energy_with_the_cmb_anisotropies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shintaro Hayashi
Early dark energy models have attracted attention in the context of the recent problem of the Hubble tension. Here we extend these models by taking into account the new density fluctuations generated by the dark energy decays around the recombination phase. We solve the evolution of the density perturbations in dark energy fluid generated at the phase transition of early dark energy as isocurvature perturbations. Assuming that the isocurvature mode is characterized by a power-law power spectrum and is uncorrelated with the standard adiabatic mode, we calculate the CMB angular power spectra and compare them to the Planck data using the Markov-Chain Monte Carlo method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Simulation Data Stream: A dynamical timescale-dependent output scheme for simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/continuous_simulation_data_stream_a_dynamical_timescale-dependent_output_scheme_for_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/continuous_simulation_data_stream_a_dynamical_timescale-dependent_output_scheme_for_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Loic Hausammann
Exa-scale simulations are on the horizon but almost no new design for the output has been proposed in recent years. In simulations using individual time steps, the traditional snapshots are over resolving particles/cells with large time steps and are under resolving the particles/cells with short time steps. Therefore, they are unable to follow fast events and use efficiently the storage space. The Continuous Simulation Data Stream (CSDS) is designed to decrease this space while providing an accurate state of the simulation at any time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological gas accretion history onto the stellar discs of Milky Way-like galaxies in the Auriga simulations -- (I) Temporal dependency</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_gas_accretion_history_onto_the_stellar_discs_of_milky_way-like_galaxies_in_the_auriga_simulations_--_i_temporal_dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_gas_accretion_history_onto_the_stellar_discs_of_milky_way-like_galaxies_in_the_auriga_simulations_--_i_temporal_dependency/</guid>
      <description>First author: Federico G. Iza
We use the 30 simulations of the Auriga Project to estimate the temporal dependency of the inflow, outflow and net accretion rates onto the discs of Milky Way-like galaxies. The net accretion rates are found to be similar for all galaxies at early times, increasing rapidly up to $\sim 10~\mathrm{M}\odot , \mathrm{yr}^{-1}$. After $\sim 6~\mathrm{Gyr}$ of evolution, however, the net accretion rates are diverse: in most galaxies, these exhibit an exponential-like decay, but some systems instead present increasing or approximately constant levels up to the present time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark matter halo cores and the tidal survival of Milky Way satellites</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_matter_halo_cores_and_the_tidal_survival_of_milky_way_satellites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_matter_halo_cores_and_the_tidal_survival_of_milky_way_satellites/</guid>
      <description>First author: Raphaël Errani
The cuspy central density profiles of cold dark matter (CDM) haloes make them highly resilient to disruption by tides. Self-interactions between dark matter particles, or the cycling of baryons during galaxy formation, may result in the formation of a constant density core which would make haloes more susceptible to tidal disruption. We use N-body simulations to study the evolution of NFW-like &amp;ldquo;cored&amp;rdquo; subhaloes in the tidal field of a massive host, and identify the criteria and timescales for full tidal disruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Ca II Absorption Lines With a Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovering_ca_ii_absorption_lines_with_a_neural_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovering_ca_ii_absorption_lines_with_a_neural_network/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iona Xia
Quasar absorption line analysis is critical for studying gas and dust components and their physical and chemical properties as well as the evolution and formation of galaxies in the early universe. Ca II absorbers, which are one of the dustiest absorbers and are located at lower redshifts than most other absorbers, are especially valuable when studying physical processes and conditions in recent galaxies. However, the number of known quasar Ca II absorbers is relatively low due to the difficulty of detecting them with traditional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Echoes from Luminous Fast Blue Optical Transients</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_echoes_from_luminous_fast_blue_optical_transients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_echoes_from_luminous_fast_blue_optical_transients/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brian D. Metzger
Luminous fast blue optical transients (LFBOTs) such as AT2018cow form a rare class of engine-powered explosions of uncertain origin. A hallmark feature of these events is radio/millimeter synchrotron emission powered by the interaction of fast (v &amp;gt; 0.1 c) ejecta and dense circumstellar material (CSM) extending to large radii &amp;gt; 1e16 cm surrounding the progenitor. Assuming this CSM to be an outflow from the progenitor, we show that dust grains up to ~1 micron in size can form in the outflow in the years before the explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical masses of the primary Be star and the secondary sdB star in the single-lined binary kappa Dra (B6 IIIe)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamical_masses_of_the_primary_be_star_and_the_secondary_sdb_star_in_the_single-lined_binary_kappa_dra_b6_iiie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamical_masses_of_the_primary_be_star_and_the_secondary_sdb_star_in_the_single-lined_binary_kappa_dra_b6_iiie/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Klement
Because many classical Be stars may owe their nature to mass and angular-momentum transfer in a close binary, the present masses, temperatures, and radii of their components are of high interest for comparison to stellar evolution models. Kappa Dra is a 61.5-day single-lined binary with a B6 IIIe primary. With the CHARA Array instruments MIRC/MIRC-X and MYSTIC, we detected the secondary at (approximately photospheric) flux ratios of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Solar Activity, Solar Insolation and the Lower Atmospheric Dust on the Martian Thermosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_solar_activity_solar_insolation_and_the_lower_atmospheric_dust_on_the_martian_thermosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_solar_activity_solar_insolation_and_the_lower_atmospheric_dust_on_the_martian_thermosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. V. Rao
A diagnosis of the Ar densities measured by the Neutral Gas and Ion Mass Spectrometer aboard the Mars Atmosphere and Volatile EvolutioN (MAVEN) and the temperatures derived from these densities shows that solar activity, solar insolation, and the lower atmospheric dust are the dominant forcings of the Martian thermosphere. A methodology, based on multiple linear regression analysis, is developed to quantify the contributions of the dominant forcings to the densities and temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAST observations of an extremely active episode of FRB 20201124A: III. Polarimetry</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_iii._polarimetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_iii._polarimetry/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jin-Chen Jiang
As the third paper in the multiple-part series, we report the statistical properties of radio bursts detected from the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20201124A with the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio telescope (FAST) during an extremely active episode between the 25th and the 28th of September 2021 (UT). We focus on the polarisation properties of 536 bright bursts with $\mathrm{S/N}&amp;gt;50$. We found that the Faraday rotation measures (RMs) monotonically dropped from $-579 \ {\rm rad \ m^{-2}}$ to $-605 \ {\rm rad \ m^{-2}}$ in the 4-day window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immediate origin of the Moon as a post-impact satellite</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/immediate_origin_of_the_moon_as_a_post-impact_satellite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/immediate_origin_of_the_moon_as_a_post-impact_satellite/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacob A. Kegerreis
The Moon is traditionally thought to have coalesced from the debris ejected by a giant impact onto the early Earth. However, such models struggle to explain the similar isotopic compositions of Earth and lunar rocks at the same time as the system&amp;rsquo;s angular momentum, and the details of potential impact scenarios are hotly debated. Above a high resolution threshold for simulations, we find that giant impacts can immediately place a satellite with similar mass and iron content to the Moon into orbit far outside the Earth&amp;rsquo;s Roche limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of inhomogeneous reionization on post-reionization 21 cm intensity mapping measurement of cosmological parameters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_inhomogeneous_reionization_on_post-reionization_21_cm_intensity_mapping_measurement_of_cosmological_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_inhomogeneous_reionization_on_post-reionization_21_cm_intensity_mapping_measurement_of_cosmological_parameters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Heyang Long
21 cm intensity mapping (IM) has the potential to be a strong and unique probe of cosmology from redshift of order unity to redshift potentially as high as 30. For post-reionization 21 cm observations, the signal is modulated by the thermal and dynamical reaction of gas in the galaxies to the passage of ionization fronts during the Epoch of Reionization. In this work, we investigate the impact of inhomogeneous reionization on the post-reionization 21 cm power spectrum and the induced shifts of cosmological parameters at redshifts $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of convective plasma and small-scale magnetic fields in the lower solar atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interaction_of_convective_plasma_and_small-scale_magnetic_fields_in_the_lower_solar_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interaction_of_convective_plasma_and_small-scale_magnetic_fields_in_the_lower_solar_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Santiago Vargas Domínguez
In the following short review we will outline some of the possible interaction processes of lower solar atmospheric plasma with the embedded small-scale solar magnetic fields. After introducing the topic, important types of small-scale solar magnetic field elements are outlined to then focus on their creation and evolution, and finally end up describing foremost processes these magnetic fields are involved in, such as the reconnection of magnetic field lines and the creation of magneto-hydrodynamic waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lava World: Exoplanet Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lava_world_exoplanet_surfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lava_world_exoplanet_surfaces/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marc-Antoine Fortin
The recent first measurements of the reflection of the surface of a lava world provides an unprecedented opportunity to investigate different stages of rocky planet evolution. The spectral features of the surfaces of rocky lava world exoplanets give insights into their evolution, mantle composition and inner workings. However, no database exists yet that contains spectral reflectivity and emission of a wide range of potential exoplanet surface materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus Stars: Numerical investigations of stellar evolution with star-lifting</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lazarus_stars_numerical_investigations_of_stellar_evolution_with_star-lifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lazarus_stars_numerical_investigations_of_stellar_evolution_with_star-lifting/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew Scoggins
The aging and gradual brightening of the Sun will challenge Earth&amp;rsquo;s habitability in the next few billion years. If life exists elsewhere in the Universe, the aging of their host star will similarly pose an existential threat. One solution to this threat, which we dub a Lazarus star, is for an advanced civilization to remove (or &amp;ldquo;star-lift&amp;rdquo;) mass from their host star at a rate which offsets the increase in luminosity, keeping the flux on the habitable planet(s) constant and extending the lifetime of their star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetohydrodynamics evolution of three-dimensional magnetic null in NOAA active region 11515 initiated using non-force-free field extrapolation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetohydrodynamics_evolution_of_three-dimensional_magnetic_null_in_noaa_active_region_11515_initiated_using_non-force-free_field_extrapolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetohydrodynamics_evolution_of_three-dimensional_magnetic_null_in_noaa_active_region_11515_initiated_using_non-force-free_field_extrapolation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sanjay Kumar
Magnetohydrodynamics simulation of active region NOAA 11515 is performed to examine the initiation of the M5.6 flaring event that starts around 10:43 UT on 2012 July 2. The simulation is conducted using an extrapolated non-force-free magnetic field generated from the photospheric vector magnetogram of the active region as the initial magnetic field. The magnetic field shows the presence of a three-dimensional (3D) magnetic null with the corresponding dome overlying a filament and a low-lying magnetic flux rope, observed in 304~\AA~ and 131~\AA~ respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mode Mixing and Rotational Splittings: I. Near-Degeneracy Effects Revisited</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mode_mixing_and_rotational_splittings_i._near-degeneracy_effects_revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mode_mixing_and_rotational_splittings_i._near-degeneracy_effects_revisited/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. Joel Ong
Rotation is typically assumed to induce strictly symmetric rotational splitting into the rotational multiplets of pure p- and g-modes. However, for evolved stars exhibiting mixed modes, avoided crossings between different multiplet components are known to yield asymmetric rotational splitting, particularly for near-degenerate mixed-mode pairs, where notional pure p-modes are fortuitiously in resonance with pure g-modes. These near-degeneracy effects have been described in subgiants, but their consequences for the characterisation of internal rotation in red giants has not previously been investigated in detail, in part owing to theoretical intractability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Extragalactic Background Light and the Cosmic Star Formation History</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_extragalactic_background_light_and_the_cosmic_star_formation_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_extragalactic_background_light_and_the_cosmic_star_formation_history/</guid>
      <description>First author: Justin D. Finke
We present an updated model for the extragalactic background light (EBL) from stars and dust, over wavelengths approximately 0.1 to 1000 $\mu$m. This model uses accurate theoretical stellar spectra, and tracks the evolution of star formation, stellar mass density, metallicity, and interstellar dust extinction and emission in the universe with redshift. Dust emission components are treated self-consistently, with stellar light absorbed by dust reradiated in the infrared as three blackbody components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling of the scandium abundance evolution in AmFm stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_of_the_scandium_abundance_evolution_in_amfm_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_of_the_scandium_abundance_evolution_in_amfm_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Hui-Bon-Hoa
Scandium is a key element of the Am star phenomenon since its surface under-abundance is one of the criteria that characterise such stars. Thanks to the availability of a sufficiently complete set of theoretical atomic data for this element, reliable radiative accelerations for Sc can now be computed, which allows its behaviour under the action of atomic diffusion to be modelled. We explore the required conditions, in terms of mixing processes or mass loss, for our models to reproduce the observed surface abundances of Sc in Am stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-messenger characterization of Mrk 501 during historically low X-ray and $γ$-ray activity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-messenger_characterization_of_mrk_501_during_historically_low_x-ray_and__%CE%B3_-ray_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-messenger_characterization_of_mrk_501_during_historically_low_x-ray_and__%CE%B3_-ray_activity/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. Abe
We study the broadband emission of the TeV blazar Mrk501 using multi-wavelength (MWL) observations from 2017 to 2020 performed with a multitude of instruments, involving, among others, MAGIC, Fermi-LAT, NuSTAR, Swift, GASP-WEBT, and OVRO. During this period, Mrk501 showed an extremely low broadband activity, which may help to unravel its baseline emission. Despite the low activity, significant flux variations are detected at all wavebands, with the highest variations occurring at X-rays and VHE $\gamma$-rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural network for determining an asteroid mineral composition from reflectance spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/neural_network_for_determining_an_asteroid_mineral_composition_from_reflectance_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/neural_network_for_determining_an_asteroid_mineral_composition_from_reflectance_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Korda
Chemical and mineral compositions of asteroids reflect the formation and history of our Solar System. This knowledge is also important for planetary defence and in-space resource utilisation. We aim to develop a fast and robust neural-network-based method for deriving the mineral modal and chemical compositions of silicate materials from their visible and near-infrared spectra. The method should be able to process raw spectra without significant pre-processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGTS-21b: An Inflated Super-Jupiter Orbiting a Metal-poor K dwarf</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ngts-21b_an_inflated_super-jupiter_orbiting_a_metal-poor_k_dwarf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ngts-21b_an_inflated_super-jupiter_orbiting_a_metal-poor_k_dwarf/</guid>
      <description>First author: Douglas R. Alves
We report the discovery of NGTS-21b, a massive hot Jupiter orbiting a low-mass star as part of the Next Generation Transit Survey (NGTS). The planet has a mass and radius of $2.36 \pm 0.21$ M${\rm J}$, and $1.33 \pm 0.03$ R${\rm J}$, and an orbital period of 1.543 days. The host is a K3V ($T_{\rm eff}=4660 \pm 41$, K) metal-poor (${\rm [Fe/H]}=-0.26 \pm 0.07$, dex) dwarf star with a mass and radius of $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noble gases and stable isotopes track the origin and early evolution of the Venus atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/noble_gases_and_stable_isotopes_track_the_origin_and_early_evolution_of_the_venus_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/noble_gases_and_stable_isotopes_track_the_origin_and_early_evolution_of_the_venus_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guillaume Avice
The composition the atmosphere of Venus results from the integration of many processes entering into play over the entire geological history of the planet. Determining the elemental abundances and isotopic ratios of noble gases (He, Ne, Ar, Kr, Xe) and stable isotopes (H, C, N, O, S) in the Venus atmosphere is a high priority scientific target since it could open a window on the origin and early evolution of the entire planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the evolution of pebble-accreting planets in evolving protoplanetary discs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_evolution_of_pebble-accreting_planets_in_evolving_protoplanetary_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_evolution_of_pebble-accreting_planets_in_evolving_protoplanetary_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Arnaud Pierens
We examine the migration of luminous low-mass cores in laminar protoplanetary discs where accretion occurs mainly because of disc winds and where the planet luminosity is generated by pebble accretion. Using 2D hydrodynamical simulations, we determine the eccentricities induced by thermal forces as a function of gas and pebble accretion rates, and also evaluate the importance of the torque exerted by the solid component relative to the gas torque.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panchromatic HST/WFC3 Imaging Studies of Young, Rapidly Evolving Planetary Nebulae. II. NGC 7027</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/panchromatic_hst_wfc3_imaging_studies_of_young_rapidly_evolving_planetary_nebulae._ii._ngc_7027/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/panchromatic_hst_wfc3_imaging_studies_of_young_rapidly_evolving_planetary_nebulae._ii._ngc_7027/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paula Moraga Baez
The iconic planetary nebula (PN) NGC 7027 is bright, nearby (D ~ 1 kpc), highly ionized, intricately structured, and well observed. This nebula is hence an ideal case study for understanding PN shaping and evolution processes. Accordingly, we have conducted a comprehensive imaging survey of NGC 7027 comprised of twelve HST Wide Field Camera 3 images in narrow-band and continuum filters spanning the wavelength range 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partition function approach to non-Gaussian likelihoods: Formalism and expansions for weakly non-Gaussian cosmological inference</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/partition_function_approach_to_non-gaussian_likelihoods_formalism_and_expansions_for_weakly_non-gaussian_cosmological_inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/partition_function_approach_to_non-gaussian_likelihoods_formalism_and_expansions_for_weakly_non-gaussian_cosmological_inference/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lennart Röver
Non-Gaussian likelihoods, ubiquitous throughout cosmology, are a direct consequence of nonlinearities in the physical model. Their treatment requires Monte-Carlo Markov-chain or more advanced sampling methods for the determination of confidence contours. As an alternative, we construct canonical partition functions as Laplace-transforms of the Bayesian evidence, from which MCMC-methods would sample microstates. Cumulants of order $n$ of the posterior distribution follow by direct $n$-fold differentiation of the logarithmic partition function, recovering the classic Fisher-matrix formalism at second order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-maximum spectroscopic diversity of hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pre-maximum_spectroscopic_diversity_of_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pre-maximum_spectroscopic_diversity_of_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Réka Könyves-Tóth
We search for the reasons behind the spectroscopic diversity of hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae (SLSNe-I) in the pre-maximum phase. Our analysis is a continuation of the paper of \citet{ktr21}, who disclosed two new subtypes of SLSNe-I characterized by the presence/absence of a W-shaped absorption feature in their pre-maximum spectra between 4000 and 5000 \AA (called Type~W and Type~15bn, respectively). However, the physical cause of this bimodality is still uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propagation of Coronal Mass Ejections from the Sun to Earth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/propagation_of_coronal_mass_ejections_from_the_sun_to_earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/propagation_of_coronal_mass_ejections_from_the_sun_to_earth/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wageesh Mishra
Coronal Mass Ejections (CMEs), as they can inject a large amounts of mass and magnetic flux into the interplanetary space, are the primary source of space weather phenomena on the Earth. The present review first briefly introduces the solar surface signatures of the origins of CMEs and then focuses on the attempts to understand the kinematic evolution of CMEs from the Sun to the Earth. CMEs have been observed in the solar corona in white-light from a series of space missions over the last five decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redshift Evolution and Non-Universal Dispersion of Quasar Luminosity Correlation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/redshift_evolution_and_non-universal_dispersion_of_quasar_luminosity_correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/redshift_evolution_and_non-universal_dispersion_of_quasar_luminosity_correlation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhuoyang Li
The standard $\Lambda$CDM model is recently reported to deviate from the high-redshift Hubble diagram of type Ia supernovae (SNe) and quasars (QSOs) at $\sim4\sigma$ confidence level. In this work, we combine the PAge approximation (a nearly model-independent parameterization) and a high-quality QSO sample to search for the origins of the deviation. By visualizing the $\Lambda$CDM model and the marginalized $3\sigma$ constraints of SNe+QSOs into PAge space, we confirm that the SNe+QSOs constraints in both flat and non-flat PAge cases are in remarkable tension with the standard $\Lambda$CDM cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roaring Storms in the Planetary-Mass Companion VHS 1256-1257 b: Hubble Space Telescope Multi-epoch Monitoring Reveals Vigorous Evolution in an Ultra-cool Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/roaring_storms_in_the_planetary-mass_companion_vhs_1256-1257_b_hubble_space_telescope_multi-epoch_monitoring_reveals_vigorous_evolution_in_an_ultra-cool_atmosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/roaring_storms_in_the_planetary-mass_companion_vhs_1256-1257_b_hubble_space_telescope_multi-epoch_monitoring_reveals_vigorous_evolution_in_an_ultra-cool_atmosphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yifan Zhou
Photometric and spectral variability of brown dwarfs probes heterogeneous temperature and cloud distribution and traces the atmospheric circulation patterns. We present a new 42-hr Hubble Space Telescope (HST) Wide Field Camera 3 G141 spectral time series of VHS 1256$-$1257 b, a late L-type planetary-mass companion that has been shown to have one of the highest variability amplitudes among substellar objects. The light curve is rapidly evolving and best-fit by a combination of three sine waves with different periods and a linear trend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size and Spectroscopic Evolution of HectoMAP Quiescent Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/size_and_spectroscopic_evolution_of_hectomap_quiescent_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/size_and_spectroscopic_evolution_of_hectomap_quiescent_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivana Damjanov
The HectoMAP survey provides a complete, mass-limited sample of 30,231 quiescent galaxies with $i-$band Hyper Suprime-Cam Subaru Strategic Program (HSC SSP) imaging that spans the redshift range $0.2 &amp;lt;z &amp;lt; 0.6$. We combine half-light radii based on HSC SSP imaging with redshifts and D$n4000$ to explore the size - mass relation, $R{e} = A \times M_{*}^{\alpha}$, and its evolution for the entire HectoMAP quiescent population and for two subsets of the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2022oqm -- a Ca-rich explosion of a compact progenitor embedded in C/O circumstellar material</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2022oqm_--_a_ca-rich_explosion_of_a_compact_progenitor_embedded_in_c_o_circumstellar_material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2022oqm_--_a_ca-rich_explosion_of_a_compact_progenitor_embedded_in_c_o_circumstellar_material/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. Irani
We present the discovery and analysis of SN 2022oqm, a Type Ic supernova (SN) detected &amp;lt;1 day after explosion. The SN rises to a blue and short-lived (2 days) initial peak. Early spectral observations of SN 2022oqm show a hot (40,000 K) continuum with high-ionization C and O absorption features at velocities of 4,000 km s$^{-1}$, while its photospheric radius expands at 20,000 km s$^{-1}$, indicating a pre-existing distribution of expanding C/O material, likely ejected around 2 weeks before the explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Diffraction of LIGO-Band Gravitational Waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solar_diffraction_of_ligo-band_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/solar_diffraction_of_ligo-band_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sunghoon Jung
We show that chirping gravitational waves in the LIGO frequency band $f=1 - 5000$ Hz can be gravitationally diffracted by the Sun, due to the coincidence of its Fresnel length $r_F \propto \sqrt{1, {\rm AU}/f}$ and the solar radius $r_\odot$. This solar diffraction is detectable through its frequency-dependent amplification of the wave, albeit with low event rates. We also advocate that solar diffraction allows probing the inner solar profile with the chirping evolution of frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star formation timescale in the molecular filament WB 673</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_timescale_in_the_molecular_filament_wb_673/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_formation_timescale_in_the_molecular_filament_wb_673/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. L. Ryabukhina
We present observations of ammonia emission lines toward the interstellar filament WB~673 hosting the dense clumps WB~673, WB~668, S233-IR and G173.57+2.43. LTE analysis of the lines allows us to estimate gas kinetic temperature ($\lesssim$ 30~K in all the clumps), number density ($7-17\times10^3$~cm$^{-3}$), and ammonia column density ($\approx 1-1.5\times 10^{15}$~cm$^{-2}$) in the dense clumps. We find signatures of collapse in WB 673 and presence of compact spatially unresolved dense clumps in S233-IR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar evolution, SN explosion, and nucleosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_evolution_sn_explosion_and_nucleosynthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_evolution_sn_explosion_and_nucleosynthesis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Massive stars evolve toward the catastrophic collapse of their innermost core, producing core-collapse supernova (SN) explosions as the end products. White dwarfs, formed through evolution of the less massive stars, also explode as thermonuclear SNe if certain conditions are met during the binary evolution. Inflating opportunities in transient observations now provide an abundance of data, with which we start addressing various unresolved problems in stellar evolution and SN explosion mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Assembly of Black Hole Mass and Luminosity Functions of High-redshift Quasars via Multiple Accretion Episodes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_assembly_of_black_hole_mass_and_luminosity_functions_of_high-redshift_quasars_via_multiple_accretion_episodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_assembly_of_black_hole_mass_and_luminosity_functions_of_high-redshift_quasars_via_multiple_accretion_episodes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wenxiu Li
The early evolution of the quasar luminosity function (QLF) and black hole mass function (BHMF) encodes key information on the physics determining the radiative and accretion processes of supermassive black holes (BHs) in high-$z$ quasars. Although the QLF shape has been constrained by recent observations, it remains challenging to develop a theoretical model that explains its redshift evolution associated with BH growth self-consistently. In this study, based on a semi-analytical model for the BH formation and growth, we construct the QLF and BHMF of the early BH population that experiences multiple accretion bursts, in each of which a constant Eddington ratio is assigned following a Schechter distribution function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The detection of magnetic chemically peculiar stars using Gaia BP/RP spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_detection_of_magnetic_chemically_peculiar_stars_using_gaia_bp_rp_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_detection_of_magnetic_chemically_peculiar_stars_using_gaia_bp_rp_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Paunzen
The magnetic chemically peculiar (mCP) stars of the upper main sequence are perfectly suited to studying the effects of rotation, diffusion, mass-loss, accretion, and pulsation in the presence of an organized stellar magnetic field. Therefore, many important models can only be tested with this star group. In this case study we investigate the possibility of detecting the characteristic 520 nm flux depression of mCP stars using low-resolution BP/RP spectra of the Gaia mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of nanoflare flows on EUV spectral lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_nanoflare_flows_on_euv_spectral_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_nanoflare_flows_on_euv_spectral_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marcelo López Fuentes
The nanoflare model of coronal heating is one of the most successful scenarios to explain, within a single framework, the diverse set of coronal observations available with the present instrument resolutions. The model is based on the idea that the coronal structure is formed by elementary magnetic strands which are tangled and twisted by the displacement of their photospheric footpoints by convective motions. These displacements inject magnetic stress between neighbor strands that promotes current sheet formation, reconnection, plasma heating, and possibly also particle acceleration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of CNO elements in galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_cno_elements_in_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_evolution_of_cno_elements_in_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Donatella Romano
After hydrogen and helium, oxygen, carbon, and nitrogen - hereinafter, the CNO elements - are the most abundant species in the universe. They are observed in all kinds of astrophysical environments, from the smallest to the largest scales, and are at the basis of all known forms of life, hence, the constituents of any biomarker. As such, their study proves crucial in several areas of contemporary astrophysics, extending to astrobiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SAMI Galaxy Survey: Physical drivers of stellar-gas kinematic misalignments in the nearby Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sami_galaxy_survey_physical_drivers_of_stellar-gas_kinematic_misalignments_in_the_nearby_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sami_galaxy_survey_physical_drivers_of_stellar-gas_kinematic_misalignments_in_the_nearby_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Ristea
Misalignments between the rotation axis of stars and gas are an indication of external processes shaping galaxies throughout their evolution. Using observations of 3068 galaxies from the SAMI Galaxy Survey, we compute global kinematic position angles for 1445 objects with reliable kinematics and identify 169 (12%) galaxies which show stellar-gas misalignments. Kinematically decoupled features are more prevalent in early-type/passive galaxies compared to late-type/star-forming systems. Star formation is the main source of gas ionisation in only 22% of misaligned galaxies; 17% are Seyfert objects, while 61% show Low-Ionisation Nuclear Emission-line Region features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking magnetic flux and helicity from Sun to Earth -- Multi-spacecraft analysis of a magnetic cloud and its solar source</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracking_magnetic_flux_and_helicity_from_sun_to_earth_--_multi-spacecraft_analysis_of_a_magnetic_cloud_and_its_solar_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracking_magnetic_flux_and_helicity_from_sun_to_earth_--_multi-spacecraft_analysis_of_a_magnetic_cloud_and_its_solar_source/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. K. Thalmann
We analyze the complete chain of effects caused by a solar eruptive event in order to better understand the dynamic evolution of magnetic-field related quantities in interplanetary space, in particular that of magnetic flux and helicity. We study a series of connected events (a confined C4.5 flare, a flare-less filament eruption and a double-peak M-class flare) that originated in NOAA active region (AR) 12891 on 2021 November 1 and November 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
