<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chemical evolution on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/chemical-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Radioactivity and Galactic Chemical Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_radioactivity_and_galactic_chemical_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_radioactivity_and_galactic_chemical_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roland Diehl
The description of the tempo-spatial evolution of the composition of cosmic gas on galactic scales is called &amp;lsquo;modelling galactic chemical evolution&amp;rsquo;. It aims to use knowledge about sources of nucleosynthesis and how they change the composition of interstellar gas, following the formation of stars and the ejection of products from nuclear fusion during their evolution and terminating explosions. Sources of nucleosynthesis are diverse: Stars with hydrostatic nuclear burning eject some of the products, and core-collapse supernovae add ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting interstellar radiation fields from chemical evolution models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.04782/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.04782/</guid>
      <description>Mario Romero
We present a self-consistent prediction of the interstellar radiation field (ISRF), from the extreme ultraviolet (EUV) to sub-mm range, based on two chemical evolution models of a Milky Way-like galaxy (MWG). To this end, we develop a new tool called Mixclask to include gas emission, absorption and scattering from the photoionization code Cloudy into the Monte Carlo radiative transfer code Skirt. Both algorithms are invoked iteratively, until the physical properties of the ISM converge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gaia-ESO Survey: Preparing the ground for 4MOST &amp; WEAVE galactic surveys. Chemical evolution of lithium with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.08874/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.08874/</guid>
      <description>S. Nepal
With its origin coming from several sources (Big Bang, stars, cosmic rays) and given its strong depletion during its stellar lifetime, the lithium element is of great interest as its chemical evolution in the Milky Way is not well understood at present. To help constrain stellar and galactic chemical evolution models, numerous and precise lithium abundances are necessary for a large range of evolutionary stages, metallicities, and Galactic volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of high-redshift $[OIII]$ emitters: Chemical evolution and multi-line diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02416/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02416/</guid>
      <description>Yurina Nakazato
Recent observations by James Webb Space Telescope discovered a number of high-redshift galaxies with strong emission lines from doubly ionized oxygen. Combined with ALMA observations of far-infrared lines, multi-line diagnostics can be applied to the high-redshift galaxies in order to probe the physical conditions of the inter-stellar medium. We study the formation and evolution of galaxies using the FirstLight simulation suite, which provides outputs of 62 high-resolution, zoom-in galaxy simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GalCEM I -- An Open-Source Detailed Isotopic Chemical Evolution Code</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02257/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02257/</guid>
      <description>Eda Gjergo
This is the first of a series of papers that will introduce a user-friendly, detailed, and modular GALactic Chemical Evolution Model, GalCEM, that tracks isotope masses as a function of time in a given galaxy. The list of tracked isotopes automatically adapts to the complete set provided by the input yields. The present iteration of GalCEM tracks 86 elements broken down in 451 isotopes. The prescription includes massive stars, low-to-intermediate mass stars, and Type Ia supernovae as enrichment channels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
