<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>most recent update (Wed Feb 22 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-wed-feb-22-2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in most recent update (Wed Feb 22 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-wed-feb-22-2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3D Radiation Hydrodynamic Simulations of Gravitational Instability in AGN Accretion Disks: Effects of Radiation Pressure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_gravitational_instability_in_agn_accretion_disks_effects_of_radiation_pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_gravitational_instability_in_agn_accretion_disks_effects_of_radiation_pressure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yi-Xian Chen
We perform 3D radiation hydrodynamic local shearing box simulations to study the outcome of gravitational instability (GI) in optically thick Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) accretion disks. GI develops when the Toomre parameter QT \leq 1, and may lead to turbulent heating that balances radiative cooling. However, when radiative cooling is too efficient, the disk may undergo runaway gravitational fragmentation. In the fully gas-pressure-dominated case, we confirm the classical result that such a thermal balance holds when the Shakura-Sunyaev viscosity parameter (alpha) due to the gravitationally-driven turbulence is \sim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HST imaging of star-forming clumps in 6 GASP ram-pressure stripped galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_imaging_of_star-forming_clumps_in_6_gasp_ram-pressure_stripped_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_imaging_of_star-forming_clumps_in_6_gasp_ram-pressure_stripped_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eric Giunchi
Exploiting broad- and narrow-band images of the \textit{Hubble Space Telescope} from near-UV to I-band restframe, we study the star-forming clumps of six galaxies of the GASP sample undergoing strong ram-pressure stripping (RPS). Clumps are detected in H$\alpha$ and near-UV, tracing star formation on different timescales. We consider clumps located in galaxy disks, in the stripped tails and those formed in stripped gas but still close to the disk, called extraplanar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limits on compression of cosmic rays in supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/limits_on_compression_of_cosmic_rays_in_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/limits_on_compression_of_cosmic_rays_in_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iurii Sushch
The spectral shape of the gamma-ray emission observed for dynamically old supernova remnants that interact with molecular clouds triggered an exciting scenario of adiabatic compression and farther re-acceleration of Galactic cosmic rays (GCRs) in radiative shells of the remnants, which was extensively discussed and applied to various sources over recent years. Indeed, the observed gamma-ray spectrum from a number of remnants strongly resembles the expected spectrum of the gamma-ray emission from the compressed population of Galactic cosmic rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UV-FIR SED modeling of AGN in IR-luminous galaxies up to z~2.5: Understanding the effects of torus models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/uv-fir_sed_modeling_of_agn_in_ir-luminous_galaxies_up_to_z~2.5_understanding_the_effects_of_torus_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/uv-fir_sed_modeling_of_agn_in_ir-luminous_galaxies_up_to_z~2.5_understanding_the_effects_of_torus_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alyssa D. Sokol
UV-FIR SED modeling is an effective way to disentangle emission between star formation (SF) and active galactic nuclei (AGN) in galaxies; however, this approach becomes uncertain for composite AGN/SF galaxies that comprise 50-70% of IR-samples. Cosmic X-ray background (XRB) models require a large fraction of obscured AGN to reproduce the observed XRB peak, motivating reliable SED analyses in objects where the AGN may be ``buried&amp;quot; in the galaxy and in the mid-IR to far-IR SED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A physically-motivated perspective of the Fanaroff-Riley classification of radio galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_physically-motivated_perspective_of_the_fanaroff-riley_classification_of_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_physically-motivated_perspective_of_the_fanaroff-riley_classification_of_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gopal-Krishna
A small subset of extragalactic double radio sources, termed HYMORS (HYbrid MOrpholgy Radio Sources), is distinguished by a very unusual, hybrid morphology in terms of the Fanaroff-Riley (FR) classification. In HYMORS, one radio lobe appears edge-darkened (FR I), while the other shows a well-defined emission peak near its outer edge (edge-brightened, FR II). Such sources are rare but critical for constraining the mechanism responsible for the FR dichotomy, a widely debated issue in extragalactic astrophysics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraint on the minimally extended varying speed of light using time dilations in type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraint_on_the_minimally_extended_varying_speed_of_light_using_time_dilations_in_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraint_on_the_minimally_extended_varying_speed_of_light_using_time_dilations_in_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Seokcheon Lee
The Friedmann-Lema^{i}tre-Robertson-Walker model establishes the correlation between redshifts and distances. It has a metric expansion of space. As a result, the wavelength of photons propagating through the expanding space is stretched, creating the cosmological redshift, $z$. It also relates the frequency of light detected by a local observer to that emitted from a distant source. In standard cosmology (\textit{i.e.} a constant speed light model, $c =$ constant), this relation is given by a factor $1/(1+z)$$[1]$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of optical emission associated with the supernova remnant G107.5-1.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_optical_emission_associated_with_the_supernova_remnant_g107.5-1.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_optical_emission_associated_with_the_supernova_remnant_g107.5-1.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hicran Bakis
We present the first results from an imaging and a spectroscopic survey of the optical emission associated with supernova remnant (SNR) G107.5$-$1.5. We discovered optical diffuse and filamentary emission from G107.5$-$1.5 using the 1.5-m and 1-m telescopes. The optical emission from the North East (NE) and North West (NW) regions show the diffuse structure, while the South East (SE) and East (E) regions show filamentary structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Eddington Ratios for Star-Forming Galaxy Subregions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_eddington_ratios_for_star-forming_galaxy_subregions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_eddington_ratios_for_star-forming_galaxy_subregions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ian Blackstone
Radiation pressure on dust is an important feedback process around star clusters and may eject gas from bright sub-regions in star-forming galaxies. The Eddington ratio has previously been constructed for galaxy-averaged observations, individual star clusters, and Galactic HII regions. Here we assess the role of radiation pressure in thousands of sub-regions across two local star-forming galaxies, NGC 6946 and NGC 5194. Using a model for the spectral energy distribution from stellar population synthesis and realistic dust grain scattering and absorption, we compute flux- and radiation pressure-mean opacities and population-averaged optical depth $\langle\tau_{\rm RP}\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA): Low-redshift Quasars and Inactive Galaxies Have Similar Neighbors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_low-redshift_quasars_and_inactive_galaxies_have_similar_neighbors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_low-redshift_quasars_and_inactive_galaxies_have_similar_neighbors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maria B. Stone
We explore the properties of galaxies in the proximity (within a $\sim$2 Mpc radius sphere) of Type I quasars at 0.1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;0.35, to check whether and how an active galaxy influences the properties of its neighbors. We further compare these with the properties of neighbors around inactive galaxies of the same mass and redshift within the same volume of space, using the Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA) spectroscopic survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating supermassive black hole mass measurements for a sample of ultra massive galaxies using ELT/HARMONI high spatial resolution integral-field stellar kinematics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulating_supermassive_black_hole_mass_measurements_for_a_sample_of_ultra_massive_galaxies_using_elt_harmoni_high_spatial_resolution_integral-field_stellar_kinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulating_supermassive_black_hole_mass_measurements_for_a_sample_of_ultra_massive_galaxies_using_elt_harmoni_high_spatial_resolution_integral-field_stellar_kinematics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dieu D. Nguyen
As the earliest relics of star formation episodes in the history of the Universe, the most massive galaxies are the key to our understanding of the evolution of the stellar population, cosmic structure, and SMBHs. However, the details of their formation histories remain uncertain. We address these problems by planning a large survey sample of ultramassive galaxies ($z\le0.3$, $|\delta+24^{\circ}|&amp;lt;45$\deg, $|b|&amp;gt;8$\deg), including 76% E, 17% S0, and 7% S brighter than $M_K\le-27$ mag (stellar mass $2\times10^{12}&amp;lt;M_\star&amp;lt;5\times10^{12}$ M$\odot$) with the HARMONI instrument on ELT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Scalarization as a New Core-Collapse Supernova Mechanism and its Multi-Messenger Signals</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spontaneous_scalarization_as_a_new_core-collapse_supernova_mechanism_and_its_multi-messenger_signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spontaneous_scalarization_as_a_new_core-collapse_supernova_mechanism_and_its_multi-messenger_signals/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takami Kuroda
We perform multi-dimensional core-collapse supernova (CCSN) simulations in a massive scalar-tensor theory for the first time with a realistic equation of state and multi-energy neutrino radiation. Among the set of our models varying the scalar mass and the coupling strength between the scalar and gravitational fields, a particular model allows for recurrent spontaneous scalarizations (SSs) in the proto-neutron star (PNS). Each SS induces the PNS collapse and subsequent bounce, from which devastating shock waves emanate and eject the PNS envelope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submillimeter Galaxies do trace Galaxy Protoclusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/submillimeter_galaxies_do_trace_galaxy_protoclusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/submillimeter_galaxies_do_trace_galaxy_protoclusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Calvi
There is controversy whether dusty starbursts selected at submillimeter wavelengths can trace galaxy overdensities. We perform the first systematic search for protoclusters around a homogeneously selected sample of 12 spectroscopically confirmed submillimeter galaxies (SMGs) at $z\sim1.2-5.3$ in the GOODS-N field. We applied the Poisson Probability Method (PPM) to search for Mpc scale overdensities around these SMGs using three photometric redshift catalogs. We detect galaxy overdensities for 11 out of the 12 SMGs ($92%\pm8$%), distributed over eight protoclusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cosmic Timeline Implied by the JWST High-redshift Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cosmic_timeline_implied_by_the_jwst_high-redshift_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cosmic_timeline_implied_by_the_jwst_high-redshift_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fulvio Melia
The so-called impossibly early galaxy&#39; problem, first identified via the Hubble Space Telescope&#39;s observation of galaxies at redshifts z &amp;gt; 10, appears to have been exacerbated by the more recent James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) discovery of galaxy candidates at even higher redshifts (z ~ 17) which, however, are yet to be confirmed spectroscopically. These candidates would have emerged only ~ 230 million years after the big bang in the context of LCDM, requiring a more rapid star formation in the earliest galaxies than appears to be permitted by simulations adopting the concordance model parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Star-Formation-Rate Surface Density on the Electron Density and Ionization Parameter of High-Redshift Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_star-formation-rate_surface_density_on_the_electron_density_and_ionization_parameter_of_high-redshift_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_star-formation-rate_surface_density_on_the_electron_density_and_ionization_parameter_of_high-redshift_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Naveen A. Reddy
We use the large spectroscopic dataset of the MOSFIRE Deep Evolution Field (MOSDEF) survey to investigate some of the key factors responsible for the elevated ionization parameters (U) inferred for high-redshift galaxies, focusing in particular on the role of star-formation-rate surface density (Sigma_SFR). Using a sample of 317 galaxies with spectroscopic redshifts z~1.9-3.7, we construct composite rest-frame optical spectra in bins of Sigma_SFR and infer electron densities, n_e, using the ratio of the $[OII]$ 3727, 3730 doublet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JWST Advanced Deep Extragalactic Survey: Discovery of an Extreme Galaxy Overdensity at $z = 5.4$ with JWST/NIRCam in GOODS-S</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jwst_advanced_deep_extragalactic_survey_discovery_of_an_extreme_galaxy_overdensity_at__z__5.4__with_jwst_nircam_in_goods-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jwst_advanced_deep_extragalactic_survey_discovery_of_an_extreme_galaxy_overdensity_at__z__5.4__with_jwst_nircam_in_goods-s/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jakob M. Helton
We report the discovery of an extreme galaxy overdensity at $z = 5.4$ in the GOODS-S field using JWST/NIRCam imaging from JADES and JEMS alongside JWST/NIRCam wide field slitless spectroscopy from FRESCO. We identified potential members of the overdensity using HST+JWST photometry spanning $\lambda = 0.4-5.0\ \mu\mathrm{m}$. These data provide accurate and well-constrained photometric redshifts down to $m \approx 29-30,\mathrm{mag}$. We subsequently confirmed $N = 96$ potential members of the overdensity using JWST slitless spectroscopy over $\lambda = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most massive Population III stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.09763/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.09763/</guid>
      <description>Teeraparb Chantavat
Recent data from the James Webb Space Telescope suggest that there are realistic prospects for detecting the earliest generation of stars at redshift ~20. These metal-poor, gaseous Population III stars are likely in the mass range $10-10^3 M_\odot$. We develop a framework for calculating the abundances of Pop III stars as well as the distribution of the most massive Pop III stars based on an application of extreme-value statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Ia supernovae in NS&#43;He star systems and the isolated mildly recycled pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_in_ns&#43;he_star_systems_and_the_isolated_mildly_recycled_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_in_ns&#43;he_star_systems_and_the_isolated_mildly_recycled_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yun-Lang Guo
Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are successful cosmological distance indicators and important element factories in the chemical evolution of galaxies. They are generally thought to originate from thermonuclear explosions of carbon-oxygen white dwarfs in close binaries. However, the observed diversity among SNe Ia implies that they have different progenitor models. In this article, we performed the long-term evolution of NS+He star binaries with different initial He star masses ($M_{\rm He}^{\rm i}$) and orbital periods ($P_{\rm orb}^{\rm i}$) for the first time, in which the He star companions can explode as SNe Ia eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mini-Chemical Scheme with Net Reactions for 3D GCMs II. 3D thermochemical modelling of WASP-39b and HD 189733b</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_mini-chemical_scheme_with_net_reactions_for_3d_gcms_ii._3d_thermochemical_modelling_of_wasp-39b_and_hd_189733b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_mini-chemical_scheme_with_net_reactions_for_3d_gcms_ii._3d_thermochemical_modelling_of_wasp-39b_and_hd_189733b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elspeth K. H. Lee
The chemical inventory of hot Jupiter (HJ) exoplanets atmospheres continue to be observed by various ground and space based instruments in increasing detail and precision. It is expected that some HJs will exhibit strong non-equilibrium chemistry characteristics in their atmospheres, which might be inferred from spectral observations. We aim to model the three dimensional thermochemical non-equilibrium chemistry in the atmospheres of the HJs WASP-39b and HD 189733b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Possible Chemical Clock in High-mass Star-forming Regions: N(HC3N)/N(N2H&#43;)?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_chemical_clock_in_high-mass_star-forming_regions_nhc3n_nn2h&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_chemical_clock_in_high-mass_star-forming_regions_nhc3n_nn2h&#43;/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. X. Wang
We conducted observations of multiple HC3N (J = 10-9, 12-11, and 16-15) lines and the N2H+ (J = 1-0) line toward a large sample of 61 ultracompact (UC) H II regions, through the Institutde Radioastronomie Millmetrique 30 m and the Arizona Radio Observatory 12 m telescopes. The N2H+ J = 1-0 line is detected in 60 sources and HC3N is detected in 59 sources, including 40 sources with three lines, 9 sources with two lines, and 10 sources with one line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronology of the chemical enrichment of the old Galactic stellar populations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chronology_of_the_chemical_enrichment_of_the_old_galactic_stellar_populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chronology_of_the_chemical_enrichment_of_the_old_galactic_stellar_populations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Riano E. Giribaldi
The Milky Way accreted several smaller satellite galaxies in its history. These mergers added stars and gas to the Galaxy and affected the properties of the pre-existing stellar populations. Stellar chemical abundances and ages are needed to establish the chronological order of events that occur before, during, and after such mergers. We report precise ages ($\sim$6.5%) and chemical abundances for the Titans, a sample of old metal-poor dwarfs and subgiants with accurate atmospheric parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Fine Tuning and Physical Origin of Line-Locked Absorption Systems in Active Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_fine_tuning_and_physical_origin_of_line-locked_absorption_systems_in_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_fine_tuning_and_physical_origin_of_line-locked_absorption_systems_in_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. R. Lewis
Line locking (LL) of absorption line systems is a clear signature of the dynamical importance of radiation pressure force in driving astrophysical flows, with recent findings suggesting that it may be common in quasars exhibiting multiple intrinsic narrow absorption-line (NAL) systems. In this work we probe the phase space conducive to LL and follow the detailed kinematics of those systems that may lock at the velocity separation of the CIV $\lambda\lambda 1548.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abundance matching analysis of the emission line galaxy sample in the extended Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/abundance_matching_analysis_of_the_emission_line_galaxy_sample_in_the_extended_baryon_oscillation_spectroscopic_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/abundance_matching_analysis_of_the_emission_line_galaxy_sample_in_the_extended_baryon_oscillation_spectroscopic_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sicheng Lin
We present the measurements of the small-scale clustering for the emission line galaxy (ELG) sample from the extended Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey (eBOSS) in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey IV (SDSS-IV). We use conditional abundance matching method to interpret the clustering measurements from $0.34h^{-1}\textrm{Mpc}$ to $70h^{-1}\textrm{Mpc}$. In order to account for the correlation between properties of emission line galaxies and their environment, we add a secondary connection between star formation rate of ELGs and halo accretion rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapsars as Sites of r-process Nucleosynthesis: Systematic Near-Infrared Follow-up of Type Ic-BL Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapsars_as_sites_of_r-process_nucleosynthesis_systematic_near-infrared_follow-up_of_type_ic-bl_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapsars_as_sites_of_r-process_nucleosynthesis_systematic_near-infrared_follow-up_of_type_ic-bl_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shreya Anand
One of the open questions following the discovery of GW170817 is whether neutron star mergers are the only astrophysical sites capable of producing r-process elements. Simulations have shown that 0.01-0.1M$_\odot$ of r-process material could be generated in the outflows originating from the accretion disk surrounding the rapidly rotating black hole that forms as a remnant to both neutron star mergers and collapsing massive stars associated with long-duration gamma-ray bursts (collapsars).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the accretion and feedback of supermassive black hole binaries in gas-rich galaxy mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.11788/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.11788/</guid>
      <description>Shihong Liao
We introduce a new model for the accretion and feedback of supermassive black hole (SMBH) binaries to the KETJU code, which enables us to resolve the evolution of SMBH binaries down to separations of tens of Schwarzschild radii in gas-rich galaxy mergers. Our subgrid binary accretion model extends the widely used Bondi--Hoyle--Lyttleton accretion into the binary phase and incorporates preferential mass accretion onto the secondary SMBH, which is motivated by results from small-scale hydrodynamical circumbinary disc simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comparison of millisecond pulsar populations between globular clusters and the Galactic field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08776/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08776/</guid>
      <description>Jongsu Lee
We have performed a systematic study of the rotational, orbital and X-ray properties of millisecond pulsars (MSPs) in globular clusters (GCs) and compared their nature with those of the MSPs in the Galactic field (GF). We found that GC MSPs generally rotate slower than their counterparts in the GF. Different from the expectation of a simple recycling scenario, no evidence for the correlation between the orbital period and the rotation period can be found from the MSP binaries in GCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A z=1.85 galaxy group in CEERS: evolved, dustless, massive Intra-Halo Light and a Brightest Group Galaxy in the making</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_z1.85_galaxy_group_in_ceers_evolved_dustless_massive_intra-halo_light_and_a_brightest_group_galaxy_in_the_making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_z1.85_galaxy_group_in_ceers_evolved_dustless_massive_intra-halo_light_and_a_brightest_group_galaxy_in_the_making/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rosemary T. Coogan
We present CEERS JWST/NIRCam imaging of a massive galaxy group at z=1.85, to explore the early JWST view on massive group formation in the distant Universe. The group contains &amp;gt;16 members (including 6 spectros. confirmations) down to log10(Mstar/Msun)=8.5, including the Brightest Group Galaxy (BGG) in the process of actively assembling at this redshift. The BGG is comprised of multiple merging components extending ~3.6&amp;quot; (30kpc) across the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic Simulations and Time-dependent Photoionization Modeling of Starburst-driven Superwinds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_and_time-dependent_photoionization_modeling_of_starburst-driven_superwinds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_and_time-dependent_photoionization_modeling_of_starburst-driven_superwinds/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Danehkar
Thermal energies deposited by OB stellar clusters in starburst galaxies lead to the formation of galactic superwinds. Multi-wavelength observations of starburst-driven superwinds pointed at complex thermal and ionization structures which cannot adequately be explained by simple adiabatic assumptions. In this study, we perform hydrodynamic simulations of a fluid model coupled to radiative cooling functions, and generate time-dependent non-equilibrium photoionization models to predict physical conditions and ionization structures of superwinds using the MAIHEM atomic and cooling package built on the program FLASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving initialization and evolution accuracy of cosmological neutrino simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improving_initialization_and_evolution_accuracy_of_cosmological_neutrino_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improving_initialization_and_evolution_accuracy_of_cosmological_neutrino_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: James M. Sullivan
Neutrino mass constraints are a primary focus of current and future large-scale structure (LSS) surveys. Non-linear LSS models rely heavily on cosmological simulations &amp;ndash; the impact of massive neutrinos should therefore be included in these simulations in a realistic, computationally tractable, and controlled manner. A recent proposal to reduce the related computational cost employs a symmetric neutrino momentum sampling strategy in the initial conditions. We implement a modified version of this strategy into the Hardware/Hybrid Accelerated Cosmology Code (HACC) and perform convergence tests on its internal parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LISC Catalog of Open Clusters.III. 83 Newly found Galactic disk open clusters using Gaia EDR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08926/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08926/</guid>
      <description>Huanbin Chi
As groups of coeval stars born from the same molecular cloud, an Open cluster (OC) is an ideal laboratory for studying the structure and dynamical evolution of the Milky Way. The release of High-Precision Gaia Early Data Release 3 (Gaia EDR3) and modern machine-learning methods offer unprecedented opportunities to identify OCs. In this study, we extended conventional HDBSCAN (e-HDBSCAN) for searching for new OCs in Gaia EDR3. A pipeline was developed based on the parallel computing technique to blindly search for open clusters from Gaia EDR3 within Galactic latitudes $\left| b \right|$ $&amp;amp;lt;$25 $^\circ$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal line emission from galaxy haloes at z~1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/metal_line_emission_from_galaxy_haloes_at_z~1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/metal_line_emission_from_galaxy_haloes_at_z~1/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rajeshwari Dutta
We present a study of the metal-enriched halo gas, traced using MgII and $[OII]$ emission lines, in two large, blind galaxy surveys conducted using Multi Unit Spectroscopic Explorer (MUSE) optical integral field unit observations, namely the MUSE Analysis of Gas around Galaxies (MAGG) and the MUSE Ultra Deep Field (MUDF). By stacking a sample of ~600 galaxies with stellar masses M* ~10^{6-12} Msun (median M* ~2x10^9 Msun) at redshifts z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observations of R-Process Stars in the Milky Way and Dwarf Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.09188/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.09188/</guid>
      <description>Anna Frebel
This chapter presents an overview of the recent progress on spectroscopic observations of metal-poor stars with r-process element signatures found in the Milky Way&amp;amp;#39;s stellar halo and satellite dwarf galaxies. Major empirical lessons related to the origins of the r-process are discussed, including the universality of the observed r-process pattern and deviations from universality among the light r-process elements and actinides. Different astrophysical sites of the r-process based on theoretical expectations are presented, including common and rare supernovae and neutron star mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observations of R-Process Stars in the Milky Way and Dwarf Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observations_of_r-process_stars_in_the_milky_way_and_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/observations_of_r-process_stars_in_the_milky_way_and_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Frebel
This chapter presents an overview of the recent progress on spectroscopic observations of metal-poor stars with r-process element signatures found in the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s stellar halo and satellite dwarf galaxies. Major empirical lessons related to the origins of the r-process are discussed, including the universality of the observed r-process pattern and deviations from universality among the light r-process elements and actinides. Different astrophysical sites of the r-process based on theoretical expectations are presented, including common and rare supernovae and neutron star mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Ultraheavy Dark Matter from Observations of Dwarf Spheroidal Galaxies with VERITAS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08784/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08784/</guid>
      <description>VERITAS collaboration
Dark matter is a key piece of the current cosmological scenario, with weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs) a leading dark matter candidate. WIMPs have not been detected in their conventional parameter space (100 GeV $\lesssim M_χ \lesssim$ 100 TeV), a mass range accessible with current Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes. As ultraheavy dark matter (UHDM; $M_χ \gtrsim$ 100 TeV) has been suggested as an under-explored alternative to the WIMP paradigm, we search for an indirect dark matter annihilation signal in a higher mass range (up to 30 PeV) with the VERITAS gamma-ray observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Ultraheavy Dark Matter from Observations of Dwarf Spheroidal Galaxies with VERITAS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_ultraheavy_dark_matter_from_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies_with_veritas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_ultraheavy_dark_matter_from_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies_with_veritas/</guid>
      <description>First author: VERITAS collaboration
Dark matter is a key piece of the current cosmological scenario, with weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs) a leading dark matter candidate. WIMPs have not been detected in their conventional parameter space (100 GeV $\lesssim M_{\chi} \lesssim$ 100 TeV), a mass range accessible with current Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes. As ultraheavy dark matter (UHDM; $M_{\chi} \gtrsim$ 100 TeV) has been suggested as an under-explored alternative to the WIMP paradigm, we search for an indirect dark matter annihilation signal in a higher mass range (up to 30 PeV) with the VERITAS gamma-ray observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic research of low redshift optically selected SDSS Type-2 AGN but with apparent long-term optical variabilities from Catalina Sky Survey, I: data sample and basic results</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/systematic_research_of_low_redshift_optically_selected_sdss_type-2_agn_but_with_apparent_long-term_optical_variabilities_from_catalina_sky_survey_i_data_sample_and_basic_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/systematic_research_of_low_redshift_optically_selected_sdss_type-2_agn_but_with_apparent_long-term_optical_variabilities_from_catalina_sky_survey_i_data_sample_and_basic_results/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhang XueGuang
The main objective of the paper, the first paper in a dedicated series, is to report basic results on systematic research of low-redshift optically selected SDSS Type-2 AGN but with apparent optical variabilities. For all the pipeline classified Type-2 AGN in SDSS DR16 with $z&amp;lt;0.3$ and $SN&amp;gt;10$, long-term optical V-band light curves are collected from Catalina Sky Survey. Through all light curves described by Damped Random Walk process with process parameters of $\sigma/(mag/days^{0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Isaac Newton Telescope Monitoring Survey of Local Group Dwarf Galaxies. VI. The Star Formation History and Dust Production in Andromeda IX</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07674/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07674/</guid>
      <description>Hedieh Abdollahi
We present a photometric study of the resolved stellar populations in And IX, the closest satellite to the M31, a metal-poor and low-mass dwarf spheroidal galaxy. We estimate a distance modulus of $24.56_{-0.15}^{+0.05}$ mag based on the tip of the red giant branch (TRGB). By probing the variability of asymptotic giant branch stars (AGB), we study the star formation history of And IX. We identified 50 long period variables (LPVs) in And IX using the Isaac Newton Telescope (INT) in two filters, Sloan $i&amp;amp;#39;$ and Harris $V$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Messy Nature of Fiber Spectra: Star-Quasar Pairs Masquerading as Dual Type 1 AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_messy_nature_of_fiber_spectra_star-quasar_pairs_masquerading_as_dual_type_1_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_messy_nature_of_fiber_spectra_star-quasar_pairs_masquerading_as_dual_type_1_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan W. Pfeifle
Theoretical studies predict that the most significant growth of supermassive black holes occurs in late-stage mergers, coinciding with the manifestation of dual active galactic nuclei (AGNs), and both major and minor mergers are expected to be important for dual AGN growth. In fact, dual AGNs in minor mergers should be signposts for efficient minor merger-induced SMBH growth for both the more and less massive progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the cosmic architecture in the vicinity of Grand-design and Flocculent spiral galaxies with Local Geometric Index</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/analyzing_the_cosmic_architecture_in_the_vicinity_of_grand-design_and_flocculent_spiral_galaxies_with_local_geometric_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/analyzing_the_cosmic_architecture_in_the_vicinity_of_grand-design_and_flocculent_spiral_galaxies_with_local_geometric_index/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suman Sarkar
We explore the environment of 351 grand-design and 541 flocculent spiral galaxies recently identified employing convolutional neural networks from the $17^{th}$ data release of Sloan Digital Sky Survey. We introduce a novel estimator called the Local Geometric Index to quantify the morphology of the local environment of these 892 spirals. Based on the local geometric index of the galaxies, we identify their local environments to be voids, sheets, filaments or clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying the full SDSS-IV MaNGA Survey using optical diagnostic diagrams: presentation of AGN catalogs in flexible apertures</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classifying_the_full_sdss-iv_manga_survey_using_optical_diagnostic_diagrams_presentation_of_agn_catalogs_in_flexible_apertures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classifying_the_full_sdss-iv_manga_survey_using_optical_diagnostic_diagrams_presentation_of_agn_catalogs_in_flexible_apertures/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marco Albán
Accurate active galactic nucleus (AGN) identifications in large galaxy samples are crucial to assess the role of AGN and AGN feedback in the coevolution of galaxies and their central supermassive black holes. Emission line flux ratio diagnostics are the most common technique for identifying AGN in optical spectra. New large samples of integral field unit observations allow The exploration of the role of aperture size used for the classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Variance and the Inhomogeneous UV Luminosity Function of Galaxies During Reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_variance_and_the_inhomogeneous_uv_luminosity_function_of_galaxies_during_reionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_variance_and_the_inhomogeneous_uv_luminosity_function_of_galaxies_during_reionization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Taha Dawoodbhoy
When the first galaxies formed and starlight escaped into the intergalactic medium to reionize it, galaxy formation and reionization were both highly inhomogeneous in time and space, and fully-coupled by mutual feedback. To show how this imprinted the UV luminosity function (UVLF) of reionization-era galaxies, we use our large-scale, radiation-hydrodynamics simulation CoDa II to derive the time- and space-varying halo mass function and UVLF, from $z\simeq6$-15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for globular clusters collapse after a dwarf-dwarf merger: A nuclear star-cluster in formation?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08516/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08516/</guid>
      <description>J. Román
Direct observational evidence for the creation of nuclear star clusters (NSCs) is needed to support the proposed scenarios for their formation. We have analyzed the dwarf galaxy UGC 7346, located in the peripheral regions of the Virgo Cluster, to highlight a series of properties that indicate the formation of a NSC caught in its earlier stages. First, we report remnants of a past interaction in the form of diffuse streams or shells, suggesting a recent merge of two dwarf galaxies with a 1:5 stellar mass ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring binary black hole mergers and host galaxies with {\sc Shark} and COMPAS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_binary_black_hole_mergers_and_host_galaxies_with__sc_shark_and_compas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_binary_black_hole_mergers_and_host_galaxies_with__sc_shark_and_compas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liana Rauf
In this work, we explore the connection between the gravitational wave (GW) merger rates of stellar-mass binary black holes (BBH) and galaxy properties. We do this by generating populations of stars using the binary synthesis code COMPAS and evolving them in galaxies from the semi-analytic galaxy formation model {\sc Shark}, to determine the number of mergers occurring in each simulation time-step. We find that large, metal-rich galaxies with high star formation rates are more likely to have gravitational wave (GW) events compared to younger, more metal poor galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Fabrication and Characterization of Chemically-Etched Silicon Slits for KOSMOS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/initial_fabrication_and_characterization_of_chemically-etched_silicon_slits_for_kosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/initial_fabrication_and_characterization_of_chemically-etched_silicon_slits_for_kosmos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Debby Tran
KOSMOS is a low-resolution, long-slit, optical spectrograph that has been upgraded at the University of Washington for its move from Kitt Peak National Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Mayall 4m telescope to the Apache Point Observatory&amp;rsquo;s ARC 3.5m telescope. One of the additions to KOSMOS is a slitviewer, which requires the fabrication of reflective slits, as KOSMOS previously used matte slits machined via wire EDM. We explore a novel method of slit fabrication using nanofabrication methods and compare the slit edge roughness, width uniformity, and the resulting scattering of the new fabricated slits to the original slits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the large-scale structure traced by the BOSS LOWZ galaxies consistent with $\textit{Planck}$?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_the_large-scale_structure_traced_by_the_boss_lowz_galaxies_consistent_with___textitplanck_/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_the_large-scale_structure_traced_by_the_boss_lowz_galaxies_consistent_with___textitplanck_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhiwei Shao
Recently, several studies reported a significant discrepancy between the clustering and lensing of the Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey (BOSS) galaxies in the $\textit{Planck}$ cosmology. We construct a simple yet powerful model based on the linear theory to assess whether this discrepancy points toward deviations from $\textit{Planck}$. Focusing on scales $10&amp;lt;R&amp;lt;30$ $h^{-1}\mathrm{Mpc}$, we model the amplitudes of clustering and lensing of BOSS LOWZ galaxies using three parameters: galaxy bias $b_\mathrm{g}$, galaxy-matter cross-correlation coefficient $r_\mathrm{gm}$, and $A$, defined as the ratio between the true and $\textit{Planck}$ values of $\sigma_8$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing IC/CMB Interpretation for the X-ray knots of AGN through VHE observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_ic_cmb_interpretation_for_the_x-ray_knots_of_agn_through_vhe_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_ic_cmb_interpretation_for_the_x-ray_knots_of_agn_through_vhe_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amal A. Rahman
Detection of hard X-ray spectrum from the kilo-parsec scale jet of active galactic nuclei cannot be accounted to the synchrotron emission mechanism from the electron distribution responsible for the radio/optical emission. Alternate explanations are the inverse Compton scattering of cosmic microwave background photons (IC/CMB) or synchrotron emission from a second electron population. When the X-ray emission is interpreted as IC/CMB process, the Compton spectrum peak at GeV energy and were predicted to be the Fermi candidate sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing massive neutrinos with the Minkowski functionals of the galaxy distribution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_massive_neutrinos_with_the_minkowski_functionals_of_the_galaxy_distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_massive_neutrinos_with_the_minkowski_functionals_of_the_galaxy_distribution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wei Liu
The characteristic signatures of massive neutrinos on large-scale structure (LSS), if fully captured, can be used to put a stringent constraint on their mass sum, $M_{\nu}$. Previous work utilizing N-body simulations has shown the Minkowski functionals (MFs) of LSS can reveal the imprints of massive neutrinos on LSS, provide important complementary information to two-point statistics and significantly improve constraints on $M_{\nu}$. In this work, we take a step forward and apply the statistics to the biased tracers of LSS, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermassive black holes in UCDs formed from the nuclei of disrupted galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supermassive_black_holes_in_ucds_formed_from_the_nuclei_of_disrupted_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supermassive_black_holes_in_ucds_formed_from_the_nuclei_of_disrupted_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rebecca Mayes
We use the hydrodynamic EAGLE simulation to predict the numbers and masses of supermassive black holes in stripped nuclei and compare these to confirmed measurements of black holes in observed UCDs. We find that black holes in stripped nuclei are consistent with the numbers and masses of those in observed UCDs. Approximately 50 per cent of stripped nuclei with $M &amp;gt; 2 \times 10^6 M_\odot$ should contain supermassive black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The universal shape of the X-ray variability power spectrum of AGN up to $z\sim 3$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_universal_shape_of_the_x-ray_variability_power_spectrum_of_agn_up_to__z_sim_3_/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_universal_shape_of_the_x-ray_variability_power_spectrum_of_agn_up_to__z_sim_3_/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Paolillo
We study the ensemble X-ray variability properties of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) over a large range of timescales (20 ks $\leq T\leq$ 14 yrs), redshift ($0\leq z \lesssim 3$), luminosities ($10^{40}$ erg s$^{-1}\leq L_X\leq 10^{46}$ erg s$^{-1}$) and black hole (BH) masses ($10^6 \leq $M$_\odot \leq 10^9$). We propose the use of the variance-frequency diagram, as a viable alternative to the study of the power spectral density (PSD), which is not yet accessible for distant, faint and/or sparsely sampled AGN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging Black Holes in Dwarf Galaxies: Calculating Binary Black Hole Coalescence Timescales from Simulations for LISA Detection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.15035/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.15035/</guid>
      <description>Victoria I. De Cun
Supermassive black holes (SMBHs) merging in dwarf galaxies will be detectable by the Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA) in the mid-2030s. Previous cosmological hydrodynamic simulations have shown the prediction of massive black holes merging in dwarf galaxies, but these simulations are limited by their resolution and cannot follow black hole pairs all the way to coalescence. We calculate the delay time between black hole pairing and merger based on the properties of the black holes and their host galaxies, and use these properties to calculate gravitational wave strains for eleven different binary black holes that merge inside dwarf galaxies from eight cosmological simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
