<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>galactic disk on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/galactic-disk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in galactic disk on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/galactic-disk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The hydrodynamic evolution of binary black holes embedded within the vertically stratified disks of active galactic nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2103.12088/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2103.12088/</guid>
      <description>Nicholas Kaaz
Stellar-mass black holes can become embedded within the gaseous disks of active galactic nuclei (AGNs). Afterwards, their interactions are mediated by their gaseous surroundings. In this work, we study the evolution of stellar-mass binary black holes (BBHs) embedded within AGN disks using a combination of three-dimensional hydrodynamic simulations and analytic methods, focusing on environments in which the AGN disk scale height $H$ is [arXiv:2301.03629](https://arxiv.org/abs/2301.03629)$\gtrsim$ the BBH sphere of influence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04503/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.04503/</guid>
      <description>Roark Habegger
In galactic disks, the Parker instability results when non-thermal pressure support exceeds a certain threshold. The non-thermal pressures considered in the Parker instability are cosmic ray pressure and magnetic pressure. This instability takes a long time to saturate $(&amp;gt;500 , \mathrm{Myr})$ and assumes a background with fixed cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio. In reality, galactic cosmic rays are injected into localized regions $(&amp;lt; 100 ,\mathrm{pc})$ by events like supernovae, increasing the cosmic ray pressure to gas pressure ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DUVET: Spatially Resolved Observations of Star Formation Regulation via Galactic Outflows in a Starbursting Disk Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02063/</guid>
      <description>Bronwyn Reichardt Chu
We compare 500~pc scale, resolved observations of ionised and molecular gas for the $z\sim0.02$ starbursting disk galaxy IRAS08339+6517, using measurements from KCWI and NOEMA. We explore the relationship of the star formation driven ionised gas outflows with colocated galaxy properties. We find a roughly linear relationship between the outflow mass flux ($\dotΣ_{\rm out}$) and star formation rate surface density ($Σ_{\rm SFR}$), $\dotΣ_{\rm out}\proptoΣ_{\rm SFR}^{1.06\pm0.10}$, and a strong correlation between $\dotΣ_{\rm out}$ and the gas depletion time, such that $\dotΣ_{\rm out} \propto t_{dep}^{-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting Kilonovae: Long-lasting Electromagnetic Counterparts to Binary Mergers in the Accretion Disks of Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03097/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03097/</guid>
      <description>Jia Ren
We investigate the dynamics and electromagnetic (EM) signatures of neutron star-neutron star (NS-NS) or neutron star-black hole (NS-BH) merger ejecta that occurs in the accretion disk of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We find that the interaction between ejecta and disk gas leads to important effects on the dynamics and radiation. We show five stages of the ejecta dynamics: gravitational slowing down, coasting, Sedov-Taylor deceleration in the disk, re-acceleration after the breakout from the disk surface, and momentum-conserved snowplow phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic-Chemical analysis and Time tagging for the Diagonal Ridge Structure of the Galactic Outer Disk with LAMOST Red Giant Branch Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.09227/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.09227/</guid>
      <description>Peng Yang
We investigate the kinematic-chemical distribution of Red Giant Branch (RGB)stars from the LAMOST survey crossed matched with Gaia DR2 proper motions, and present time tagging for the well-known ridge structures (diagonal distributions for $V_R$ in the $R$, $V_φ$ plane) in the range of Galactocentric distance $R$ = 8 to 15 kpc. We detect six ridge structures, including five ridges apparent in the radial velocity distribution and three ridges apparent in the vertical velocity, the sensitive time of which to the perturbations are from young population (0$-$3 Gyr) to old population (9$-$14 Gyr).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical analyses of M31 dark matter profiles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03252/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03252/</guid>
      <description>Kuantay Boshkayev
We reproduce the rotation curve of the Andromeda galaxy (M31) by taking into account its bulge, disk, and halo components, considering the last one to contain the major part of dark matter mass. Hence, our prescription is to split the galactic bulge into two components, namely, the inner and main bulges, respectively. Both bulges are thus modeled by exponential density profiles since we underline that the widely accepted de Vaucouleurs law fails to reproduce the whole galactic bulge rotation curve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
