<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>galactic disk on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/galactic-disk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in galactic disk on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/galactic-disk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A family of potential-density pairs for galactic bars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_family_of_potential-density_pairs_for_galactic_bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_family_of_potential-density_pairs_for_galactic_bars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Walter Dehnen
We present a family of analytical potential-density pairs for barred discs, which can be combined to describe galactic bars in a realistic way, including boxy/peanut components. We illustrate this with two reasonable compound models. Computer code for the evaluation of potential, forces, density, and projected density is freely provided.
arxiv link
pdf link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hybrid map-$C_ll$ component separation method for primordial CMB $B$-mode searches</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_hybrid_map-_c__ell__component_separation_method_for_primordial_cmb__b_-mode_searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_hybrid_map-_c__ell__component_separation_method_for_primordial_cmb__b_-mode_searches/</guid>
      <description>First author: Susanna Azzoni
The observation of the polarised emission from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) from future ground-based and satellite-borne experiments holds the promise of indirectly detecting the elusive signal from primordial tensor fluctuations in the form of large-scale $B$-mode polarisation. Doing so, however, requires an accurate and robust separation of the signal from polarised Galactic foregrounds. We present a component separation method for multi-frequency CMB observations that combines some of the advantages of map-based and power-spectrum-based techniques, and which is direcly applicable to data in the presence of realistic foregrounds and instrumental noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Predicted Astrometric Microlensing Events by Nearby Brown Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_search_for_predicted_astrometric_microlensing_events_by_nearby_brown_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_search_for_predicted_astrometric_microlensing_events_by_nearby_brown_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Judah Luberto
Gravitational microlensing has the potential to provide direct gravitational masses of single, free-floating brown dwarfs, independent of evolutionary and atmospheric models. The proper motions and parallaxes of nearby brown dwarfs can be used to predict close future alignments with distant background stars that cause a microlensing event. Targeted astrometric follow up of the predicted microlensing events permits the brown dwarf&amp;rsquo;s mass to be measured. Predicted microlensing events are typically found via searching for a peak threshold signal using an estimate of the lens mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular Momentum Loss Rates in Be Stars Determined by the Viscous Decretion Disc Model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/angular_momentum_loss_rates_in_be_stars_determined_by_the_viscous_decretion_disc_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/angular_momentum_loss_rates_in_be_stars_determined_by_the_viscous_decretion_disc_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. R. Ghoreyshi
Circumstellar discs around Be stars are formed by the material ejected by the central star. This process removes excess angular momentum from the star as viscosity facilitates the mass and angular momentum transfer within the disc and its growth. The angular momentum loss rates (AMLR) of Be stars is a subject of debate in the literature. Through the modelling of the disc formation and dissipation phases observed from Be stars, their average AMLR can be determined and this is the goal of this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequency dependence of the thermal dust $E/B$ ratio and $EB$ correlation: insights from the spin-moment expansion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/frequency_dependence_of_the_thermal_dust__e_b__ratio_and__eb__correlation_insights_from_the_spin-moment_expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/frequency_dependence_of_the_thermal_dust__e_b__ratio_and__eb__correlation_insights_from_the_spin-moment_expansion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Léo Vacher
The change of physical conditions across the turbulent and magnetized interstellar medium (ISM) induces a 3D spatial variation of the properties of Galactic polarized emission. The observed signal results from the averaging of different spectral energy distributions (SED) and polarization angles, along and between lines of sight. As a consequence, the total Stokes parameters $Q$ and $U$ will have different distorted SEDs, so that the polarization angle becomes frequency dependent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep orbital search for additional planets in the HR 8799 system</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/deep_orbital_search_for_additional_planets_in_the_hr_8799_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/deep_orbital_search_for_additional_planets_in_the_hr_8799_system/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Thompson
The HR 8799 system hosts four massive planets orbiting 15 and 80 AU. Studies of the system&amp;rsquo;s orbital stability and its outer debris disk open the possibility of additional planets, both interior to and exterior to the known system. Reaching a sufficient sensitivity to search for interior planets is very challenging due to the combination of bright quasi static speckle noise close to the stellar diffraction core and relatively fast orbital motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halting Migration in Magnetospherically Sculpted Protoplanetary Disks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/halting_migration_in_magnetospherically_sculpted_protoplanetary_disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/halting_migration_in_magnetospherically_sculpted_protoplanetary_disks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tze Yeung Mathew Yu
We present a physically motivated model for the manner in which a stellar magnetic field sculpts the inner edge of a protoplanetary disk, and examine the consequence for the migration and stopping of sub-Neptune and super-Earth planets. This model incorporates a transition zone exterior to the inner truncation of the disk, where the surface density profile is modified by the diffusion of the stellar magnetic field into the disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbit-Superposition Dynamical Modelling of Barred Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orbit-superposition_dynamical_modelling_of_barred_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orbit-superposition_dynamical_modelling_of_barred_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Behzad Tahmasebzadeh
Barred structures are important in understanding galaxy evolution, but they were not included explicitly in most dynamical models for nearby galaxies due to their complicated morphological and kinematic properties. We modify the triaxial orbit-superposition Schwarzschild implementation by Van den Bosch et al. (2008) to include barred structures explicitly. The gravitational potential is a combination of a spherical dark matter halo and stellar mass; with the 3D stellar density distribution de-projected from the observed 2D image using a two-component de-projection method, including an axisymmetric disk and a triaxial barred bulge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$	exttt{Mangrove}$: Learning Galaxy Properties from Merger Trees</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/__textttmangrove__learning_galaxy_properties_from_merger_trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/__textttmangrove__learning_galaxy_properties_from_merger_trees/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christian Kragh Jespersen
Efficiently mapping baryonic properties onto dark matter is a major challenge in astrophysics. Although semi-analytic models (SAMs) and hydrodynamical simulations have made impressive advances in reproducing galaxy observables across cosmologically significant volumes, these methods still require significant computation times, representing a barrier to many applications. Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) have recently proven to be the natural choice for learning physical relations. Among the most inherently graph-like structures found in astrophysics are the dark matter merger trees that encode the evolution of dark matter halos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clusters of heavy particles in two-dimensional Keplerian turbulence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/clusters_of_heavy_particles_in_two-dimensional_keplerian_turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/clusters_of_heavy_particles_in_two-dimensional_keplerian_turbulence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabiola Antonietta Gerosa
Protoplanetary disks are gaseous systems in Keplerian rotation around young stars, known to be turbulent. They include a small fraction of dust from which planets form. In the incremental scenario for planet growth, the formation of kilometer-size objects (planetesimals) from pebbles is a major open question. Clustering of particles is necessary for solids to undergo a local gravitational collapse. To address this question, the dynamic of inertial particles in turbulent flows with Keplerian rotation and shear is studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Dynamics in AGN Winds: A New Mechanism For Multiwavelength AGN Variability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dust_dynamics_in_agn_winds_a_new_mechanism_for_multiwavelength_agn_variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dust_dynamics_in_agn_winds_a_new_mechanism_for_multiwavelength_agn_variability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nadine H. Soliman
Partial dust obscuration in active galactic nuclei (AGN) has been proposed as a potential explanation for some cases of AGN variability. The dust-gas mixture present in AGN torii is accelerated by radiation pressure leading to the launching of an AGN wind. Dust under these conditions has been shown to be unstable to a generic class of fast growing resonant drag instabilities (RDIs). We present the first set of numerical simulations of radiation driven outflows that include explicit dust dynamics in conditions resembling AGN winds and discuss the implications of the RDIs on the morphology of the AGN torus, AGN variability, and the ability of the radiation to effectively launch a wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphine in the Venusian Atmosphere: A Strict Upper Limit from SOFIA GREAT Observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/phosphine_in_the_venusian_atmosphere_a_strict_upper_limit_from_sofia_great_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/phosphine_in_the_venusian_atmosphere_a_strict_upper_limit_from_sofia_great_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. A. Cordiner
The presence of phosphine (PH$_3$) in the atmosphere of Venus was reported by Greaves et al. (2021a), based on observations of the J=1-0 transition at 267 GHz using ground-based, millimeter-wave spectroscopy. This unexpected discovery presents a challenge for our understanding of Venus&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere, and has led to a reappraisal of the possible sources and sinks of atmospheric phosphorous-bearing gases. Here we present results from a search for PH$_3$ on Venus using the GREAT instrument aboard the SOFIA aircraft, over three flights conducted in November 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Razor-thin dust layers in protoplanetary disks: Limits on the vertical shear instability</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/razor-thin_dust_layers_in_protoplanetary_disks_limits_on_the_vertical_shear_instability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/razor-thin_dust_layers_in_protoplanetary_disks_limits_on_the_vertical_shear_instability/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. P. Dullemond
Context: Recent observations with the Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) have shown that the large dust aggregates observed at millimeter wavelengths settle to the midplane into a remarkably thin layer. Aims: We intend to find out if the geometric thinness of these layers is evidence against the vertical shear instability (VSI) operating in these disks. Methods: We performed hydrodynamic simulations of a protoplanetary disk with a locally isothermal equation of state, and let the VSI fully develop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Distributions of Gas and Solids in Protoplanetary Disks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/structured_distributions_of_gas_and_solids_in_protoplanetary_disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/structured_distributions_of_gas_and_solids_in_protoplanetary_disks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jaehan Bae
Recent spatially-resolved observations of protoplanetary disks revealed a plethora of substructures, including concentric rings and gaps, inner cavities, misalignments, spiral arms, and azimuthal asymmetries. This is the major breakthrough in studies of protoplanetary disks since Protostars and Planets VI and is reshaping the field of planet formation. However, while the capability of imaging substructures in protoplanetary disks has been steadily improving, the origin of many substructures are still largely debated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GRAVITY Young Stellar Object survey -- IX. Spatially resolved kinematics of hot hydrogen gas in the star/disk interaction region of T Tauri stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_gravity_young_stellar_object_survey_--_ix._spatially_resolved_kinematics_of_hot_hydrogen_gas_in_the_star_disk_interaction_region_of_t_tauri_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_gravity_young_stellar_object_survey_--_ix._spatially_resolved_kinematics_of_hot_hydrogen_gas_in_the_star_disk_interaction_region_of_t_tauri_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. A. Wojtczak
Aims: We aim to spatially and spectrally resolve the Br-gamma hydrogen emission line with the methods of interferometry in order to examine the kinematics of the hydrogen gas emission region in the inner accretion disk of a sample of solar-like young stellar objects. The goal is to identify trends and categories among the sources of our sample and to discuss whether or not they can be tied to different origin mechanisms associated with Br-gamma emission in T Tauri stars, chiefly and most prominently magnetospheric accretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-point correlation function studies for the Milky Way: discovery of spatial clustering from disk excitations and substructure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/two-point_correlation_function_studies_for_the_milky_way_discovery_of_spatial_clustering_from_disk_excitations_and_substructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/two-point_correlation_function_studies_for_the_milky_way_discovery_of_spatial_clustering_from_disk_excitations_and_substructure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Austin Hinkel
We introduce a two-particle correlation function (2PCF) for the Milky Way, constructed to probe spatial correlations in the orthogonal directions of the stellar disk in the Galactic cylindrical coordinates of $R$, $\phi$, and $z$. We use this new tool to probe the structure and dynamics of the Galaxy using the carefully selected set of solar neighborhood stars ($d \lesssim 3, \rm kpc$) from Gaia Data Release 2 we previously employed for studies of axial symmetry breaking in stellar number counts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ices toward Massive YSOs: I. OCS, CO, OCN-, and CH3OH</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/ices_toward_massive_ysos_i._ocs_co_ocn-_and_ch3oh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/ices_toward_massive_ysos_i._ocs_co_ocn-_and_ch3oh/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. C. A. Boogert
An important tracer of the origin and evolution of cometary ices is the comparison with ices found in dense clouds and towards Young Stellar Objects (YSOs). We present a survey of ices in the 2-5 micron spectra of 23 massive YSOs, taken with the NASA InfraRed Telescope Facility SpeX spectrometer. The 4.90 micron absorption band of OCS ice is detected in 20 sight-lines, more than five times the previously known detections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical and chemical vertical structure of magnetostatic accretion disks of young stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/physical_and_chemical_vertical_structure_of_magnetostatic_accretion_disks_of_young_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/physical_and_chemical_vertical_structure_of_magnetostatic_accretion_disks_of_young_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergey A. Khaibrakhmanov
The vertical structure of the accretion disks of young stars with fossil large-scale magnetic field is studied. The equations of magnetostatic equilibrium of the disk are solved taking into account the stellar gravity, gas and magnetic pressure, turbulent heating, and heating by stellar radiation. The modelled physical structure of the disk is used to simulate its chemical structure, in particular, to study the spatial distribution of CN molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primary disks and their observational appearance in collapsing magnetic rotating protostellar clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/primary_disks_and_their_observational_appearance_in_collapsing_magnetic_rotating_protostellar_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/primary_disks_and_their_observational_appearance_in_collapsing_magnetic_rotating_protostellar_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalya S. Kargaltseva
The collapse of the magnetic rotating protostellar cloud with mass of $10,M_{\odot}$ is numerically studied. The initial ratios of the thermal, magnetic, and rotational energies of the cloud to the modulus of its gravitational energy are 0.3, 0.2 and 0.01, respectively. The emphasis is on the evolution and properties of the quasi-magnetostatic primary disk formed at the isothermal stage of the collapse. Simulations show that the primary disk size and mass increase during evolution from $1500$ au to $7400$ au and from $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An empirical analysis of the dynamics of both individual galaxies and gravitational lensing in galaxy clusters without dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_empirical_analysis_of_the_dynamics_of_both_individual_galaxies_and_gravitational_lensing_in_galaxy_clusters_without_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_empirical_analysis_of_the_dynamics_of_both_individual_galaxies_and_gravitational_lensing_in_galaxy_clusters_without_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Pascoli
The existence of the flat rotation curves of galaxies is still perplexing. The dark matter paradigm was proposed long ago to solve this conundrum; however, this proposal is still under debate. In this paper, we search for universal relationships solely involving the baryonic density that incorporate both galactic dynamics and gravitational lensing in galaxy clusters without requiring dark matter. If this type of formula exists, we show that it is possible that it can clearly indicate that dark matter is either perfectly tailored to baryonic matter or, from a more radical point of view, even perhaps useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying globular clusters and applying them to estimate the mass of the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: GuangChen Sun
We combine the kinematics of 159 globular clusters (GCs) provided by the Gaia Early Data Release 3 (EDR 3) with other observational data to classify the GCs, and to estimate the mass of Milky Way (MW). We use the age-metallicity relation, integrals of motion, action space and the GC orbits to identify the GCs as either formed in-situ (Bulge and Disk) or ex-situ (via accretion). We find that $45.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of the isothermal collapse of magnetic rotating protostellar clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/simulations_of_the_isothermal_collapse_of_magnetic_rotating_protostellar_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/simulations_of_the_isothermal_collapse_of_magnetic_rotating_protostellar_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergey A. Khaibrakhmanov
We investigate collapse of magnetic protostellar clouds of mass $10$ and $1 M_{\odot}$. The collapse is simulated numerically using the two-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) code `Enlil&amp;rsquo;. The simulations show that protostellar clouds acquire a hierarchical structure by the end of the isothermal stage of collapse. Under the action of the electromagnetic force, the protostellar cloud takes the form of an oblate envelope with the half-thickness to radius ratio $Z/R \sim (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An X-ray Dim Isolated Neutron Star in Binary?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_x-ray_dim_isolated_neutron_star_in_binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_x-ray_dim_isolated_neutron_star_in_binary/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jie Lin
We report the discovery of a dark companion to 2MASS J15274848+3536572 with an orbital period of 6.14 hours. Combining the radial velocity of LAMOST observation and the modelling of the multi-band light curve, one has a mass function of 0.135 Msun, an inclination of 43.94+0.33-0.21, and a mass ratio of 0.58+0.048-0.018, which demonstrate the binary nature of a dark companion with mass of 1.01+-0.08Msun and a main-sequence K star of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delayed teraelectronvolt emission from GRB 980425/SN 1998bw and the origin of ultra-high-energy cosmic rays</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/delayed_teraelectronvolt_emission_from_grb_980425_sn_1998bw_and_the_origin_of_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_rays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/delayed_teraelectronvolt_emission_from_grb_980425_sn_1998bw_and_the_origin_of_ultra-high-energy_cosmic_rays/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nestor Mirabal
The origin of ultra-high-energy cosmic rays (UHECRs, E $&amp;gt; 10^{18}$ eV) is one of the great mysteries of modern astrophysics. It has been suggested that UHECRs could be accelerated in gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) and engine-driven supernovae (SNe). Here we report the discovery of a 1.4 teraelectronvolt (TeV) photon offset 0.97$^{\circ}$ from the site of the nearby (36.9 megaparsecs) GRB 980425/SN 1998bw explosion. The Large Area Telescope (LAT) on board the Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope detected the TeV emission on 17 November 2018, more than 20 years after the original GRB 980425/SN 1998bw trigger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection Rate of Fast Radio Bursts in the Milky Way with BURSTT</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_rate_of_fast_radio_bursts_in_the_milky_way_with_burstt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_rate_of_fast_radio_bursts_in_the_milky_way_with_burstt/</guid>
      <description>First author: Decmend Fang-Jie Ling
Fast radio bursts (FRBs) are intense bursts of radio emission with durations of milliseconds. Although researchers have found them happening frequently all over the sky, they are still in the dark to understand what causes the phenomena because the existing radio observatories have encountered certain challenges during the discovery of FRB progenitors. The construction of Bustling Universe Radio Survey Telescope in Taiwan (BURSTT) is being proposed to solve these challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light speed variation from GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_speed_variation_from_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_speed_variation_from_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jie Zhu
It is postulated in Einstein&amp;rsquo;s relativity that the speed of light in vacuum is a constant for all observers. However, the effect of quantum gravity could bring an energy dependence of light speed, and a series of previous researches on high-energy photon events from gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) and active galactic nuclei (AGNs) suggest a light speed variation $v(E)=c\left(1-E / E_{\mathrm{LV}}\right)$ with $E_{\mathrm{LV}}=3.6 \times 10^{17} ~\mathrm{GeV}$. From the newly detected gamma-ray burst GRB 221009A, we find that a $99.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steady jet ejections from the innermost region of advection-dominated accretion flow around a black hole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/steady_jet_ejections_from_the_innermost_region_of_advection-dominated_accretion_flow_around_a_black_hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/steady_jet_ejections_from_the_innermost_region_of_advection-dominated_accretion_flow_around_a_black_hole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hajime Inoue
We study ejection mechanisms for two kinds of steady jets: one observed from black hole binaries in the low/hard state and the other from SS433. The specific energy of the ejected gas is required to be positive for the jets to get to infinity, while that of the accreted gas is naively considered to be negative at the outermost boundary of the accretion flow. To reconcile the opposite sign of the specific energies, we propose a situation where two layers exist in the accretion flow and one layer receives energy from the other sufficiently for the specific energy to be positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of 3 accreting binaries with VLT/X-Shooter spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classification_of_3_accreting_binaries_with_vlt_x-shooter_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classification_of_3_accreting_binaries_with_vlt_x-shooter_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tristan Bouchet
Since its launch, the INTErnational Gamma-Ray Astrophysics Laboratory (INTEGRAL) satellite has discovered hundreds of X-ray sources, many of which lack proper classification. This mission also led to the discovery of new categories of high mass X-ray binaries (HMXB). We use the spectra of the X-Shooter instrument at the Very Large Telescope (VLT) of the European Southern Observatory (ESO) to better understand the nature of 3 accreting binaries (IGR J10101-5654, IGR J11435-6109 and IGR J12489-6243) discovered by INTEGRAL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep absorption in SDSS J110511.15&#43;530806.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_absorption_in_sdss_j110511.15&#43;530806.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_absorption_in_sdss_j110511.15&#43;530806.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marcin Marculewicz
We study the origin of the anomalous deep absorption in a spectrum of the SDSS J110511.15+530806.5 distant quasar (z=1.929) obtained by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey in Data Release 7 of the optical catalog. We aim to estimate the velocity of absorbing material, and we show that this material considerably affects our measurements of the black hole (BH) mass in massive quasars with the use of common virial mass estimators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming Stars in a Dual AGN Host: Molecular and Ionized Gas in the Nearby, Luminous Infrared Merger, Mrk 266</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forming_stars_in_a_dual_agn_host_molecular_and_ionized_gas_in_the_nearby_luminous_infrared_merger_mrk_266/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forming_stars_in_a_dual_agn_host_molecular_and_ionized_gas_in_the_nearby_luminous_infrared_merger_mrk_266/</guid>
      <description>First author: Damien Beaulieu
We present star formation rates based on cold and ionized gas measurements of Mrk 266 (NGC 5256), a system composed of two colliding gas-rich galaxies, each hosting an active galactic nucleus. Using $^{12}$CO (1-0) observations with the Combined Array for Research in Millimeter-Wave Astronomy (CARMA), we find a total H$2$ mass in the central region of $1.1\pm0.3\times10^{10}$ $M\odot$ which leads to a possible future star formation rate of $25\pm10 M_\odot$ yr$^{-1}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Galaxy-Galaxy Strong Lens Candidates in the DECam Local Volume Exploration Survey Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identification_of_galaxy-galaxy_strong_lens_candidates_in_the_decam_local_volume_exploration_survey_using_machine_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identification_of_galaxy-galaxy_strong_lens_candidates_in_the_decam_local_volume_exploration_survey_using_machine_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Zaborowski
We perform a search for galaxy-galaxy strong lens systems using a convolutional neural network (CNN) applied to imaging data from the first public data release of the DECam Local Volume Exploration Survey (DELVE), which contains $\sim 520$ million astronomical sources covering $\sim 4,000$ $\mathrm{deg}^2$ of the southern sky to a $5\sigma$ point-source depth of $g=24.3$, $r=23.9$, $i=23.3$, and $z=22.8$ mag. Following the methodology of similar searches using DECam data, we select a catalog of $\sim 11$ million extended astronomical sources with $16 &amp;lt; g &amp;lt; 22$, $17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying LISA verification binaries amongst the Galactic population of double white dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_lisa_verification_binaries_amongst_the_galactic_population_of_double_white_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_lisa_verification_binaries_amongst_the_galactic_population_of_double_white_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eliot Finch
Double white dwarfs (DWDs) will be the most numerous gravitational-wave (GW) sources for the Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA). Most of the Galactic DWDs will be unresolved and will superpose to form a confusion noise foreground, the dominant LISA noise source around $\sim 0.5\mathrm{-}3,\mathrm{mHz}$. A small fraction of these sources will stand out from the background and be individually detectable. Uniquely among GW sources, a handful of these binaries will be known in advance from electromagnetic observations and will be guaranteed sources of detectable GWs in the LISA band; these are known as verification binaries (VBs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation pressure-driven outflows from dusty AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation_pressure-driven_outflows_from_dusty_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation_pressure-driven_outflows_from_dusty_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Arakawa
Radiation pressure-driven outflows from luminous accreting supermassive black holes are an important part of active galactic nucleus (AGN) feedback. The effective Eddington limit, based on absorption of radiation by dust, not electron scattering, is revealed in the plane of AGN absorption column density $N_{\mathrm{H}}$ as a function of Eddington fraction $\lambda_{\mathrm{Edd}} = L_{\mathrm{bol}}/L_{\mathrm{Edd}}$, where a lack of objects is seen in the region where the effective limit is exceeded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving the Vicinity of Supermassive Black Holes with Gravitational Microlensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolving_the_vicinity_of_supermassive_black_holes_with_gravitational_microlensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolving_the_vicinity_of_supermassive_black_holes_with_gravitational_microlensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Henry Best
In the near future, wide field surveys will discover 1000&amp;rsquo;s of new strongly lensed quasars, and these will be monitored with unprecedented cadence by the Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST). Many of these will undergo caustic-crossing microlensing events over the 10-year LSST survey, in which a sharp caustic feature from a stellar body in the lensing galaxy crosses the inner accretion disk. Caustic-crossing events offer the unique opportunity to probe the vicinity of the central supermassive black hole for 100s of quasars with multi-platform follow-up triggered by LSST monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Conduction in Clumpy Disks and BLR clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thermal_conduction_in_clumpy_disks_and_blr_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thermal_conduction_in_clumpy_disks_and_blr_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hussein Ayad
We investigate the dynamics of clumps that coexisted with/in advection-dominated accretion flows by considering thermal conductivity. Thermal conduction can be one of the effective factors in the energy transportation of ADAFs; hence it may indirectly affect the dynamics of clumps by means of a contact force between them and their host medium. We first study the ensemble of clumps by assuming them as collision-less particles and secondly we find the orbital motion of these clouds as individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbulent Transport of Dust Particles in Protostellar Disks: The Effect of Upstream Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/turbulent_transport_of_dust_particles_in_protostellar_disks_the_effect_of_upstream_diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/turbulent_transport_of_dust_particles_in_protostellar_disks_the_effect_of_upstream_diffusion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ting-Tao Zhou
We study the long-term radial transport of micron to mm-size grain in protostellar disks (PSDs) based on diffusion and viscosity coefficients measured from 3D global stratified-disk simulations with a Lagrangian hydrodynamic method. While gas-drag tend to transport dust species radially inwards, stochastic diffusion can spread a considerable fraction of dust radially outwards (upstream) depending on the nature of turbulence. In gravitationally unstable disks, we measure a high radial diffusion coefficient Dr with little dependence on altitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using $^{44}$Ti Emission to Differentiate Between Thermonuclear Supernova Progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_44ti_emission_to_differentiate_between_thermonuclear_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_44ti_emission_to_differentiate_between_thermonuclear_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Kosakowski
The radiosotope $^{44}$Ti is produced through $\alpha$-rich freezeout and explosive helium burning in type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia). In this paper, we discuss how the detection of $^{44}$Ti, either through late-time light curves of SNe Ia, or directly via gamma rays, can uniquely constrain the origin of SNe Ia. In particular, building upon recent advances in the hydrodynamical simulation of helium-ignited double white dwarf binaries, we demonstrate that the detection of $^{44}$Ti in a nearby SN Ia or in a young galactic supernova remnant (SNR) can discriminate between the double-detonation and double-degenerate channels of sub-Chandrasekhar (sub-$M_{\rm Ch}$) and near-Chandrasekhar (near-$M_{\rm Ch}$) SNe Ia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray Sources in the SSA22 Chandra Field</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_sources_in_the_ssa22_chandra_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_sources_in_the_ssa22_chandra_field/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brandon T. Radzom
The Hawaii Survey Field SSA22 is the fourth deepest Chandra X-ray field. To allow for the fullest exploration of this field, we present new optical spectroscopy from Keck/DEIMOS and Keck/LRIS, which, in combination with the literature, brings the spectroscopic completeness of the 2&amp;ndash;8 keV sample to 62%. We also make optical spectral classifications and estimate photometric redshifts for the sources without spectroscopic redshifts. We then determine hard X-ray luminosity functions (XLFs) for the full sample of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGNs), as well as for the broad-line AGNs (BLAGNs) and the non-BLAGNs separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray spectroscopy of the accretion disk corona source 2S 0921-630 with Suzaku archival data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_spectroscopy_of_the_accretion_disk_corona_source_2s_0921-630_with_suzaku_archival_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_spectroscopy_of_the_accretion_disk_corona_source_2s_0921-630_with_suzaku_archival_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tomokage Yoneyama
2S 0921$-$630 is an eclipsing low-mass X-ray binary (LMXB) with an orbital period of $\sim$ 9 days. Past X-ray observations have revealed that 2S 0921$-$630 has an extended accretion disk corona (ADC), from which most of the X-rays from the system are emitted. We report the result of our Suzaku archival data analysis of 2S 0921$-$630. The average X-ray spectrum is reproduced with a blackbody emission ($kT_{\rm bb} \sim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A survey for variable young stars with small telescopes: VII -- Spot Properties on YSOs in IC5070</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_survey_for_variable_young_stars_with_small_telescopes_vii_--_spot_properties_on_ysos_in_ic5070/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_survey_for_variable_young_stars_with_small_telescopes_vii_--_spot_properties_on_ysos_in_ic5070/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carys Herbert
We present measurements of spot properties on 31 young stellar objects, based on multi-band data from the HOYS (Hunting Outbursting Young Stars) project. On average the analysis for each object is based on 270 data points during 80 days in at least 3 bands. All the young low-mass stars in our sample show periodic photometric variations. We determine spot temperatures and coverage by comparing the measured photometric amplitudes in optical bands with simulated amplitudes based on atmosphere models, including a complete error propagation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An extended [CII] halo around a massive star-forming galaxy at z = 5.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extended_cii_halo_around_a_massive_star-forming_galaxy_at_z__5.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_extended_cii_halo_around_a_massive_star-forming_galaxy_at_z__5.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. S. Lambert
High-redshift observations are often biased towards massive and bright galaxies that are not necessarily representative of the full population. In order to accurately study galaxy evolution and mass assembly at these redshifts, observations of normal&#39;&#39; main sequence galaxies are required. Here we present Atacama Large Millimeter/Submillimeter Array (ALMA) 0.3&amp;quot; resolution observations of the [CII] emission line at 158$\mu$m of HZ7, a main sequence galaxy at $z=5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intermediate-field Fast Radio Burst Model and the Quasi-periodic Oscillation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_intermediate-field_fast_radio_burst_model_and_the_quasi-periodic_oscillation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_intermediate-field_fast_radio_burst_model_and_the_quasi-periodic_oscillation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jie-Shuang Wang
Quasi-periodic oscillation (QPO) signals are discovered in some fast radio bursts (FRBs) such as FRB 20191221A, as well as in the X-ray burst associated with the galactic FRB from SGR 1935+2154. We revisit the intermediate-field FRB model where the radio waves are generated as fast-magnetosonic waves through magnetic reconnection near the light cylinder. The current sheet in the magnetar wind is compressed by a low frequency pulse emitted from the inner magnetosphere to trigger magnetic reconnection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the origin of stellar binary black hole mergers by detections of their lensed host galaxies and gravitational wave signals</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_origin_of_stellar_binary_black_hole_mergers_by_detections_of_their_lensed_host_galaxies_and_gravitational_wave_signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_origin_of_stellar_binary_black_hole_mergers_by_detections_of_their_lensed_host_galaxies_and_gravitational_wave_signals/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhiwei Chen
A significant number of stellar binary black hole (sBBH) mergers may be lensed and detected by the third generation gravitational wave (GW) detectors. Their lensed host galaxies may be detectable, which thus helps to accurately localize these sources and provide a new approach to study the origin of sBBHs. In this paper, we investigate the detectability of the lensed host galaxies for the lensed sBBH mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a filamentary synchrotron structure connected to the coherent magnetic field in the outer Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_filamentary_synchrotron_structure_connected_to_the_coherent_magnetic_field_in_the_outer_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_filamentary_synchrotron_structure_connected_to_the_coherent_magnetic_field_in_the_outer_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. L. West
Using data from the Galactic Arecibo L-band Feed Array Continuum Transit Survey (GALFACTS), we report the discovery of two previously unidentified, very compressed, thin, and straight polarized filaments approximately centred at Galactic coordinates, $(l,b)=(182.5^\circ,-4.0^\circ)$, which we call G182.5&amp;ndash;4.0. Using data from the Isaac Newton Telescope Galactic Plane Survey (IGAPS), we also find straight, long, and extremely thin H$\alpha$ filaments coincident with the radio emission. These filaments are positioned in projection at the edge of the Orion-Eridanus superbubble and we find evidence indicating that the filaments align with the coherent magnetic field of the outer Galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust extinction map of the Galactic plane based on the VVV survey data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_extinction_map_of_the_galactic_plane_based_on_the_vvv_survey_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_extinction_map_of_the_galactic_plane_based_on_the_vvv_survey_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Miaomiao Zhang
Dust extinction is one of the most reliable tracers of the gas distribution in the Milky Way. The near-infrared (NIR) Vista Variables in the Via Lactea (VVV) survey enables extinction mapping based on stellar photometry over a large area in the Galactic plane. We devise a novel extinction mapping approach, XPNICER, by bringing together VVV photometric catalogs, stellar parameter data from StarHorse catalogs, and previously published Xpercentile and PNICER extinction mapping techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence of fresh cosmic ray in galactic plane based on DAMPE measurement of B/C and B/O ratios</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_of_fresh_cosmic_ray_in_galactic_plane_based_on_dampe_measurement_of_b_c_and_b_o_ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_of_fresh_cosmic_ray_in_galactic_plane_based_on_dampe_measurement_of_b_c_and_b_o_ratios/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pei-Pei Zhang
More and more experiments have identified that the energy spectra of both primary and secondary cosmic-rays exhibit a hardening above $\sim 200$ GV. Most recently, the DAMPE experiment has reported a hardening of boron-to-carbon ratio at $200$ GV. These signs call for modifications of the conventional cosmic-ray (CR) picture. In this work, we propose that the plethoric secondary cosmic rays, for example, boron, antiprotons, originate from the hadronic interactions of freshly accelerated cosmic rays with the interstellar gas near the sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFU observations of the inner 200 pc of NGC 4546: gas rotation, non-circular motions and ionised outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ifu_observations_of_the_inner_200_pc_of_ngc_4546_gas_rotation_non-circular_motions_and_ionised_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ifu_observations_of_the_inner_200_pc_of_ngc_4546_gas_rotation_non-circular_motions_and_ionised_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kelly F. Heckler
We present a detailed analysis of the ionised gas distribution and kinematics in the inner ~ 200 pc of NGC 4546, host of a Low Luminosity Active Galactic Nucleus (LLAGN). Using GMOS-IFU observations, with a spectral coverage of 4736-6806 A and an angular resolution of 0.7 arcsec, we confirm that the nuclear emission is consistent with photoionisation by an AGN, while the gas in the circumnuclear region may be ionised by hot low-mass evolved stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field draping around clumpy high-velocity clouds in galactic halo</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_draping_around_clumpy_high-velocity_clouds_in_galactic_halo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_field_draping_around_clumpy_high-velocity_clouds_in_galactic_halo/</guid>
      <description>First author: Seoyoung Lyla Jung
Throughout the passage within the Galactic halo, high-velocity clouds (HVCs) sweep up ambient magnetic fields and form stretched and draped configurations of magnetic fields around them. This magnetized layer at the cloud-halo interface can suppress the mixing between the cloud and the surrounding halo gas. For simplicity, many earlier numerical studies adopt spherically symmetric uniform-density clouds as initial conditions. However, observations of HVCs indicate that the clouds are clumpy and turbulent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nozzle Shocks, Disk Tearing and Streamers Drive Rapid Accretion in 3D GRMHD Simulations of Warped Thin Disks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nozzle_shocks_disk_tearing_and_streamers_drive_rapid_accretion_in_3d_grmhd_simulations_of_warped_thin_disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nozzle_shocks_disk_tearing_and_streamers_drive_rapid_accretion_in_3d_grmhd_simulations_of_warped_thin_disks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicholas Kaaz
The angular momentum of gas feeding a black hole (BH) is typically misaligned with respect to the BH spin, resulting in a tilted accretion disk. Rotation of the BH drags the surrounding space-time, manifesting as Lense-Thirring torques that lead to disk precession and warping. We study these processes by simulating a thin ($H/r=0.02$), highly tilted ($\mathcal{T}=65^\circ$) accretion disk around a rapidly rotating ($a=0.9375$) BH at extremely high resolutions, which we performed using the general-relativistic magnetohydrodynamic (GRMHD) code H-AMR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the genesis of spiral galaxies -- Classical and pseudo bulges as extremities of a continuous sequence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_genesis_of_spiral_galaxies_--_classical_and_pseudo_bulges_as_extremities_of_a_continuous_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_genesis_of_spiral_galaxies_--_classical_and_pseudo_bulges_as_extremities_of_a_continuous_sequence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iris Breda
A tantalizing enigma in extragalactic astronomy concerns the chronology and driving mechanisms of the build-up of late-type galaxies (LTGs). The standard scenario envisages two formation routes, with classical bulges (CBs) assembling first in a quick quasi-monolithic episode followed by gradual disk assembly, and pseudo-bulges (PBs) forming over the Gyr-long secular evolution of LTGs. The expectation is, therefore, the segregation of present-day LTG bulges into two distinct groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation Transport Two-Temperature GRMHD Simulations of Warped Accretion Disks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation_transport_two-temperature_grmhd_simulations_of_warped_accretion_disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation_transport_two-temperature_grmhd_simulations_of_warped_accretion_disks/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. T. P. Liska
In many black hole systems, the accretion disk is expected to be misaligned with respect to the black hole spin axis. If the scale height of the disk is much smaller than the misalignment angle, the spin of the black hole can tear the disk into multiple, independently precessing `sub-disks&amp;rsquo;. This is most likely to happen during outbursts in black hole X-Ray binaries (BHXRBs) and in active galactic nuclei (AGN) accreting above a few percent of the Eddington limit, because the disk becomes razor-thin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey for Distant Solar Twins (SDST) -- II. Design, observations and data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/survey_for_distant_solar_twins_sdst_--_ii._design_observations_and_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/survey_for_distant_solar_twins_sdst_--_ii._design_observations_and_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fan Liu
Studies of solar twins have key impacts on the astronomical community, but only $\sim$100&amp;ndash;200 nearby solar twins ($&amp;lt;$ 1 kpc) have been reliably identified over the last few decades. The aim of our survey (SDST) is to identify $\sim$150&amp;ndash;200 distant solar twins and analogues (up to $\lesssim$ 4 kpc) closer to the Galactic Centre. We took advantage of the precise Gaia and Skymapper surveys to select Sun-like candidates in a 2-degree field, which were observed with the HERMES spectrograph on the Anglo-Australian Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anisotropic Circumgalactic Medium of Massive Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_anisotropic_circumgalactic_medium_of_massive_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_anisotropic_circumgalactic_medium_of_massive_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Huanian Zhang
Using measurements of the [O III], H$\alpha$ and [N II] emission line fluxes originating in the cool (T $\sim10^4$ K) gas that populates the halos of massive early-type galaxies with stellar mass greater than $10^{10.4}$ M$_\odot$, we explore the recent conjecture that active galactic nucleus (AGN) activity preferentially removes the circumgalactic medium (CGM) along the polar (minor-axis) direction. We find deficits in the mean emission line flux of [O III] and H$\alpha$ (65 and 43%, respectively) along the polar vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Disk Population in a Distant Massive Protocluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disk_population_in_a_distant_massive_protocluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disk_population_in_a_distant_massive_protocluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yu Cheng
The unprecedented angular resolution and sensitivity of ALMA makes it possible to unveil disk populations in distant ($&amp;gt;$2 kpc), embedded young cluster environments. We have conducted an observation towards the central region of the massive protocluster G286.21+0.16 at 1.3 mm. With a spatial resolution of 23 mas and a sensitivity of 15 $\rm \mu Jy~beam^{-1}$, we detect a total of 38 protostellar disks. These disks have dust masses ranging from about 53 to 1825 $M_\oplus$, assuming a dust temperature of 20 K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Volumetric Star Formation Law in the Almost Edge-on Galaxy NGC 4302 Revealed by ALMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_the_almost_edge-on_galaxy_ngc_4302_revealed_by_alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_the_almost_edge-on_galaxy_ngc_4302_revealed_by_alma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kijeong Yim
We observe the almost edge-on (i $\sim$ 90 degrees) galaxy NGC 4302 using ALMA (CO) and VLA (H I) to measure the gas disk thickness for investigating the volumetric star formation law (SFL). The recent star formation rate (SFR) is estimated based on a linear combination of IR 24 micron and H$\alpha$ emissions. The measured scale heights of CO and H I increase significantly with radius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidal Stripping of a White Dwarf by an Intermediate-Mass Black Hole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tidal_stripping_of_a_white_dwarf_by_an_intermediate-mass_black_hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tidal_stripping_of_a_white_dwarf_by_an_intermediate-mass_black_hole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jin-Hong Chen
During the inspiralling of a white dwarf (WD) into an intermediate-mass black hole (~10^{2-5} M_sun), both gravitational waves (GWs) and electromagnetic (EM) radiation are emitted. Once the eccentric orbit&amp;rsquo;s pericenter radius approaches the tidal radius, the WD would be tidally stripped upon each pericenter passage. The accretion of these stripped mass would produce EM radiation. It is suspected that the recently discovered new types of transients, namely the quasi-periodic eruptions and the fast ultraluminous X-ray bursts, might originate from such systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A NuSTAR view of SS433: Precessional evolution of the jet-disk system</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_nustar_view_of_ss433_precessional_evolution_of_the_jet-disk_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_nustar_view_of_ss433_precessional_evolution_of_the_jet-disk_system/</guid>
      <description>First author: Federico A. Fogantini
SS433 is a Galactic microquasar with powerful outflows (double jet, accretion disk and winds) with well known orbital, precessional and nutational period. In this work we characterise different outflow parameters throughout the precessional cycle of the system. We analyse 10 NuSTAR ($3-70$ keV) observations of $\sim$30~ks that span $\sim$1.5 precessional cycles. We extract averaged spectra and model them using a combination of a double thermal jet model (bjet) and pure neutral and relativistic reflection (xillverCp and relxilllpCp) over an accretion disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadband X-ray Spectral Analysis of the Dual AGN System Mrk 739</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/broadband_x-ray_spectral_analysis_of_the_dual_agn_system_mrk_739/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/broadband_x-ray_spectral_analysis_of_the_dual_agn_system_mrk_739/</guid>
      <description>First author: Koki Inaba
We present the result of a broadband (0.5-70 keV) X-ray spectral analysis of the late-merger galaxy Mrk 739, which contains a dual active galactic nucleus (AGN), Mrk 739E and Mrk 739W, with a separation of $\sim$3.4 kpc. The spectra obtained with NuSTAR, Chandra, XMM-Newton and Swift/BAT are simultaneously analyzed by separating the contributions from the two AGNs and extended emission with the Chandra data. To evaluate the reflection components from the AGN tori, we consider two models, a phenomenological one (pexrav and zgauss) and a more physically motivated one (XCLUMPY; Tanimoto et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for an abundant old population of Galactic Ultra long period magnetars and implications for fast radio bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_an_abundant_old_population_of_galactic_ultra_long_period_magnetars_and_implications_for_fast_radio_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_an_abundant_old_population_of_galactic_ultra_long_period_magnetars_and_implications_for_fast_radio_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Beniamini
Two recent discoveries, namely PSR J0901-4046 and GLEAM-X J162759.5-523504.3 (hereafter GLEAM-X J1627), have corroborated an extant population of radio-loud periodic sources with long periods (76 s and 1091 s respectively) whose emission can hardly be explained by rotation losses. We argue that GLEAM-X J1627 is a highly-magnetized object consistent with a magnetar (an ultra long period magnetar - ULPM), and demonstrate it is unlikely to be either a magnetically or a rotationally-powered white dwarf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared variability of young solar analogs in the Lagoon Nebula</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_variability_of_young_solar_analogs_in_the_lagoon_nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_variability_of_young_solar_analogs_in_the_lagoon_nebula/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Ordenes-Huanca
T Tauri stars are low-mass pre-main sequence stars that are intrinsically variable. Due to the intense magnetic fields they possess, they develop dark spots on their surface that, because of rotation, introduce a periodic variation of brightness.In addition, the presence of surrounding disks could generate flux variations by variable extinction or accretion. Both can lead to a brightness decrease or increase, respectively. Here, we have compiled a catalog of light curves for 379 T Tauri stars in the Lagoon Nebula (M8) region, using VVVX survey data in the Ks-band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretations of the cosmic ray secondary-to-primary ratios measured by DAMPE</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpretations_of_the_cosmic_ray_secondary-to-primary_ratios_measured_by_dampe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpretations_of_the_cosmic_ray_secondary-to-primary_ratios_measured_by_dampe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peng-Xiong Ma
Precise measurements of the boron-to-carbon and boron-to-oxygen ratios by DAMPE show clear hardenings around $100$ GeV/n, which provide important implications on the production, propagation, and interaction of Galactic cosmic rays. In this work we investigate a number of models proposed in literature in light of the DAMPE findings. These models can roughly be classified into two classes, the propagation effect and the source effect. Among these models discussed, we find that the re-acceleration of cosmic rays during their propagation by random magnetohydrodynamic waves may not reproduce significant enough hardenings of B/C and B/O, and an additional spectral break of the diffusion coefficient is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameters of axion-like particles required to explain high-energy photons from GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/parameters_of_axion-like_particles_required_to_explain_high-energy_photons_from_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/parameters_of_axion-like_particles_required_to_explain_high-energy_photons_from_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. V. Troitsky
Recent astrophysical transient Swift J1913.1+1946 is possibly associated with the gamma-ray burst GRB 221009A at the redshift z=0.151. The transient was accompanied by very high-energy gamma rays up to 18 TeV observed by LHAASO and a photon-like air shower of 251 TeV detected by Carpet-2. These energetic gamma rays cannot reach us from the claimed distance of the source because of the pair production on cosmic background radiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar feedback-regulated black hole growth: driving factors from nuclear to halo scales</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_feedback-regulated_black_hole_growth_driving_factors_from_nuclear_to_halo_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_feedback-regulated_black_hole_growth_driving_factors_from_nuclear_to_halo_scales/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lindsey Byrne
Several recent simulations of galaxy formation predict two main phases of supermassive black hole (BH) accretion: an early, highly intermittent phase (during which BHs are under-massive relative to local scaling relations), followed by a phase of accelerated growth. We investigate physical factors that drive the transition in BH accretion in cosmological zoom-in simulations from the FIRE project, ranging from dwarf galaxies to galaxies sufficiently massive to host luminous quasars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The optically elusive, changing-look active nucleus in NGC 4156</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_optically_elusive_changing-look_active_nucleus_in_ngc_4156/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_optically_elusive_changing-look_active_nucleus_in_ngc_4156/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giulia Tozzi
We report on the changing-look nature of the active galactic nucleus (AGN) in the galaxy NGC 4156, as serendipitously discovered thanks to data acquired in 2019 at the Telescopio Nazionale Galileo (TNG) during a students&amp;rsquo; observing programme. Previous optical spectra had never shown any signatures of broad-line emission, and evidence of the AGN had come only from X-ray observations, being the optical narrow-line flux ratios unable to unambiguously denote this galaxy as a Seyfert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second set of pulsar discoveries by CHIME/FRB/Pulsar: 14 Rotating Radio Transients and 7 pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_second_set_of_pulsar_discoveries_by_chime_frb_pulsar_14_rotating_radio_transients_and_7_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_second_set_of_pulsar_discoveries_by_chime_frb_pulsar_14_rotating_radio_transients_and_7_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fengqiu Adam Dong
The Canadian Hydrogen Mapping Experiment (CHIME) is a radio telescope located in British Columbia, Canada. The large field of view (FOV) of $\sim$ 200 square degrees has enabled the CHIME/FRB instrument to produce the largest FRB catalog to date. The large FOV also allows CHIME/FRB to be an exceptional pulsar and Rotating Radio Transient (RRAT) finding machine, despite saving only the metadata information of incoming Galactic events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spectroscopic Classification of Astronomical Transients (SCAT) Survey: Overview, Pipeline Description, Initial Results, and Future Plans</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spectroscopic_classification_of_astronomical_transients_scat_survey_overview_pipeline_description_initial_results_and_future_plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spectroscopic_classification_of_astronomical_transients_scat_survey_overview_pipeline_description_initial_results_and_future_plans/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. A. Tucker
We present the Spectroscopic Classification of Astronomical Transients (SCAT) survey, which is dedicated to spectrophotometric observations of transient objects such as supernovae and tidal disruption events. SCAT uses the SuperNova Integral-Field Spectrograph (SNIFS) on the University of Hawai&amp;rsquo;i 2.2-meter (UH2.2m) telescope. SNIFS was designed specifically for accurate transient spectrophotometry, including absolute flux calibration and host-galaxy removal. We describe the data reduction and calibration pipeline including spectral extraction, telluric correction, atmospheric characterization, nightly photometricity, and spectrophotometric precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titanium abundances in late-type stars I. 1D non-LTE modelling in benchmark dwarfs and giants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/titanium_abundances_in_late-type_stars_i._1d_non-lte_modelling_in_benchmark_dwarfs_and_giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/titanium_abundances_in_late-type_stars_i._1d_non-lte_modelling_in_benchmark_dwarfs_and_giants/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. W. E. Mallinson
The titanium abundances of late-type stars are important tracers of Galactic formation history. However, abundances inferred from Ti I and Ti II lines can be in stark disagreement in very metal-poor giants. Departures from local thermodynamic equilibrium (LTE) have a large impact on the minority neutral species and thus influences the ionisation imbalance, but satisfactory non-LTE modelling for both dwarfs and giants has not been achieved in previous literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-1136 is a Young, Coplanar, Aligned Planetary System in a Pristine Resonant Chain</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-1136_is_a_young_coplanar_aligned_planetary_system_in_a_pristine_resonant_chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-1136_is_a_young_coplanar_aligned_planetary_system_in_a_pristine_resonant_chain/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fei Dai
Convergent disk migration has long been suspected to be responsible for forming planetary systems with a chain of mean-motion resonances (MMR). Dynamical evolution over time could disrupt the delicate resonant configuration. We present TOI-1136, a 700-Myr-old G star hosting at least 6 transiting planets between $\sim$2 and 5 $R_\oplus$. The orbital period ratios deviate from exact commensurability by only $10^{-4}$, smaller than the $\sim$,$10^{-2}$ deviations seen in typical Kepler near-resonant systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Look at z &gt; 1 Bars in the Rest-Frame Near-Infrared with JWST Early CEERS Imaging</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_look_at_z__1_bars_in_the_rest-frame_near-infrared_with_jwst_early_ceers_imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_look_at_z__1_bars_in_the_rest-frame_near-infrared_with_jwst_early_ceers_imaging/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuchen Guo
Stellar bars are key drivers of secular evolution in galaxies and can be effectively studied using rest-frame near-infrared (NIR) images, which trace the underlying stellar mass and are less impacted by dust and star formation than rest-frame UV or optical images. We leverage the power of James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) CEERS NIRCam images to present the first quantitative identification and characterization of stellar bars at $z&amp;gt;1$ based on rest-frame NIR F444W images of high resolution ($\sim$1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He-star donor AM CVn stars and their progenitors as LISA sources</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/he-star_donor_am_cvn_stars_and_their_progenitors_as_lisa_sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/he-star_donor_am_cvn_stars_and_their_progenitors_as_lisa_sources/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wei-Min Liu
Ultracompact cataclysmic variables (CVs) of the AM CVn type are deemed to be important verification sources for the future space gravitational wave detectors such as the Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA). We model the present-day Galactic population of AM CVn stars with He-star donors. Such a population has long expected to exist, though only a couple of candidates are known. We applied the hybrid method of binary population synthesis (BPS) which combines a simulation of the population of immediate precursors of AM CVn stars by a fast BPS code with subsequent tracking of their evolution by a full evolutionary code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gaia-ESO Survey: old super metal-rich visitors from the inner Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gaia-eso_survey_old_super_metal-rich_visitors_from_the_inner_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gaia-eso_survey_old_super_metal-rich_visitors_from_the_inner_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. L. L. Dantas
We report the identification of a set of old super metal-rich dwarf stars with orbits of low eccentricity that reach a maximum height from the Galactic plane between ~0.5-1.5 kpc. We discuss their properties to understand their origins. We use data from the internal data release 6 of the Gaia-ESO Survey. We selected stars observed at high resolution with abundances of 21 species of 18 individual elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST&#39;s PEARLS: A JWST/NIRCam view of ALMA sources</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwsts_pearls_a_jwst_nircam_view_of_alma_sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwsts_pearls_a_jwst_nircam_view_of_alma_sources/</guid>
      <description>First author: Cheng Cheng
We report the results of James Webb Space Telescope/NIRCam observations of 19 (sub)millimeter (submm/mm) sources detected by the Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA). The accurate ALMA positions allowed unambiguous identifications of their NIRCam counterparts. Taking gravitational lensing into account, these represent 16 distinct galaxies in three fields and constitute the largest sample of its kind to date. The counterparts&amp;rsquo; spectral energy distributions from rest-frame ultraviolet to near infrared provide photometric redshifts ($1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing Galactic variations in the fine-structure constant using solar twin stars: methodology and results</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_galactic_variations_in_the_fine-structure_constant_using_solar_twin_stars_methodology_and_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_galactic_variations_in_the_fine-structure_constant_using_solar_twin_stars_methodology_and_results/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel A. Berke
The rich absorption spectra of Sun-like stars are enticing probes for variations in the fine-structure constant, $\alpha$, which gauges the strength of electromagnetism. While individual line wavelengths are sensitive to $\alpha$, they are also sensitive to physical processes in the stellar atmospheres, which has precluded their use so far. Here we demonstrate a new, differential approach using solar twins: velocity separations between close pairs of transitions are compared across stars with very similar physical properties, strongly suppressing astrophysical and instrumental systematic errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing Galactic variations in the fine-structure constant using solar twin stars: systematic errors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_galactic_variations_in_the_fine-structure_constant_using_solar_twin_stars_systematic_errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_galactic_variations_in_the_fine-structure_constant_using_solar_twin_stars_systematic_errors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel A. Berke
Sun-like stars are a new probe of variations in the fine-structure constant, $\alpha$, via the solar twins approach: velocity separations of close pairs of absorption lines are compared between stars with very similar stellar parameters, i.e. effective temperature, metallicity and surface gravity within 100K, 0.1 dex and 0.2 dex of the Sun&amp;rsquo;s values. Here we assess possible systematic errors in this approach by analysing $\gtrsim$10,000 archival exposures from the High-Accuracy Radial velocity Planetary Searcher (HARPS) of 130 stars covering a much broader range of stellar parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving a merger in a hyper-luminous submillimeter galaxy at z=2.82</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolving_a_merger_in_a_hyper-luminous_submillimeter_galaxy_at_z2.82/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolving_a_merger_in_a_hyper-luminous_submillimeter_galaxy_at_z2.82/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. W. Perry
We present the resolved properties of the $z=2.82$ Hyper Luminous Infrared Galaxy (HyLIRG) HS170850.1, the brightest 850$\mu$m source found in the SCUBA-2 followup to the Keck Baryonic Structure Survey fields (S${\rm 850 \mu m}=$19.5 mJy), and amongst the most luminous starbursts known at any redshift. Using the IRAM-NOEMA interferometer in the highest resolution A-configuration, we resolve the source into two components separated by $\sim$8 kpc, visible as blue shifted and red shifted $^{12}$CO(5-4) lines, exhibiting the expected kinematic properties of a major merger between two gas-rich galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Outer spiral arm of the Milky Way using Red Clump stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_outer_spiral_arm_of_the_milky_way_using_red_clump_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_outer_spiral_arm_of_the_milky_way_using_red_clump_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Namita Uppal
Aims: Our aim is to provide an observational view of the old Disk structure of the Milky Way galaxy using the distribution of red clump stars. The spiral arms, warp structure, and other asymmetries present in the Disk are re-visited using a systematic study of red clump star counts over the disk of the Galaxy. Methods: We developed a method to systematically extract the red clump stars from 2MASS ($J-K_s, ~J$) colour-magnitude diagram of $1^\circ \times 1^\circ$ bins in $\ell \times b$ covering the range $40^\circ \le \ell \le 320^\circ$ and $-10^\circ \le b \le 10^\circ$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>300: An ACA 870 $μ$m Continuum Survey of Orion Protostars and their Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/300_an_aca_870_%CE%BCm_continuum_survey_of_orion_protostars_and_their_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/300_an_aca_870_%CE%BCm_continuum_survey_of_orion_protostars_and_their_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samuel Federman
We present an 870 $\mu$m continuum survey of 300 protostars from the Herschel Orion Protostar Survey (HOPS) using the Atacama Compact Array (ACA). These data measure protostellar flux densities on envelope scales $\le$ 8000 AU (20&amp;quot;) and resolve the structure of envelopes with 1600 AU (4&amp;quot;) resolution, a factor of 3-5 improvement in angular resolution over existing single dish 870 $\mu$m observations. We compare the ACA observations to Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) 12m array observations at 870 $\mu$m with $\sim$0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blueprint for the Milky Way&#39;s Stellar Populations. IV. Spectrum-based Empirical Corrections and the Galactic Starburst Sequence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_blueprint_for_the_milky_ways_stellar_populations._iv._spectrum-based_empirical_corrections_and_the_galactic_starburst_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_blueprint_for_the_milky_ways_stellar_populations._iv._spectrum-based_empirical_corrections_and_the_galactic_starburst_sequence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Deokkeun An
We continue our series of papers on phase-space distributions of stars in the Milky Way based on photometrically derived metallicities and Gaia astrometry, with a focus on the halo-disk interface in the local volume. To exploit various photometric databases, we develop a method of empirically calibrating synthetic stellar spectra based on a comparison with observations of stellar sequences and individual stars in SDSS, SMSS, and PS1, overcoming band-specific corrections employed in our previous work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A model for the infrared-radio correlation of main-sequence galaxies at GHz frequencies and its dependence on redshift and stellar mass</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_model_for_the_infrared-radio_correlation_of_main-sequence_galaxies_at_ghz_frequencies_and_its_dependence_on_redshift_and_stellar_mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_model_for_the_infrared-radio_correlation_of_main-sequence_galaxies_at_ghz_frequencies_and_its_dependence_on_redshift_and_stellar_mass/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Schober
The infrared-radio correlation (IRRC) of star-forming galaxies can be used to estimate their star formation rate (SFR) based on the radio continuum luminosity at MHz-GHz frequencies. For application in future deep radio surveys, it is crucial to know whether the IRRC persists at high redshift z. Delvecchio et al. (2021) observed that the 1.4 GHz IRRC correlation of star-forming galaxies is nearly z-invariant up to z~4, but depends strongly on the stellar mass M_star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Scale Picture of Magnetic Field and Gravity from Large-Scale Filamentary Envelope to Core-Accreting Dust Lanes in the High-Mass Star-Forming Region W51</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multi-scale_picture_of_magnetic_field_and_gravity_from_large-scale_filamentary_envelope_to_core-accreting_dust_lanes_in_the_high-mass_star-forming_region_w51/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multi-scale_picture_of_magnetic_field_and_gravity_from_large-scale_filamentary_envelope_to_core-accreting_dust_lanes_in_the_high-mass_star-forming_region_w51/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick M. Koch
We present 230 GHz continuum polarization observations with the Atacama Large Milimeter/Submillimeter Array (ALMA) at a resolution of 0$\farcs1$ ($\sim 540$~au) in the high-mass star-forming regions W51 e2 and e8. These observations resolve a network of core-connecting dust lanes, marking a departure from earlier coarser more spherical continuum structures. At the same time, the cores do not appear to fragment further. Polarized dust emission is clearly detected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion-Induced Collapse of White Dwarfs as an Alternative Symbiotic Channel to Millisecond Pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion-induced_collapse_of_white_dwarfs_as_an_alternative_symbiotic_channel_to_millisecond_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion-induced_collapse_of_white_dwarfs_as_an_alternative_symbiotic_channel_to_millisecond_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ali Taani
Recently, extra motivation has been given to the investigations of an unresolved problem of millisecond pulsars (MSPs) produced by the recycling process, as an apparent role of the accretion-induced collapse (AIC) in white dwarfs (WDs) was suggested to this concern. I have found that the distribution of the orbital periods of binary MSPs in the Galactic disk closely follows an exponential distribution. I have also determined the best-fit mean value of Nobs by fitting our data with an exponential distribution for the MSP population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHANG-ES XXVI: Insights into cosmic-ray transport from radio halos in edge-on galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chang-es_xxvi_insights_into_cosmic-ray_transport_from_radio_halos_in_edge-on_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chang-es_xxvi_insights_into_cosmic-ray_transport_from_radio_halos_in_edge-on_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Stein
Galactic winds play a key role in regulating the evolution of galaxies over cosmic time. In recent years, the role of cosmic rays (CR) in the formation of the galactic wind has increasingly gained attention. Therefore, we use radio continuum data to analyse the cosmic ray transport in edge-on galaxies. Data from the LOFAR Two-metre Sky Survey (LoTSS) data release 2 at 144 MHz (HBA) and reprocessed VLA data at 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemodynamical Analysis of Metal-rich High-eccentricity Stars in the Milky Way&#39;s Disk</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemodynamical_analysis_of_metal-rich_high-eccentricity_stars_in_the_milky_ways_disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemodynamical_analysis_of_metal-rich_high-eccentricity_stars_in_the_milky_ways_disk/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ayeon Lee
We present a chemodynamical analysis of 11,562 metal-rich, high-eccentricity halo-like main-sequence (MS) stars, which has been referred to as the Splash or Splashed Disk, selected from Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) and Large Sky Area Multi-Object Fiber Spectroscopic Telescope (LAMOST). When divided into two groups, a low-[$\alpha$/Fe] population (LAP) and a high-[$\alpha$/Fe] population (HAP), based on kinematics and chemistry, we find that they exhibit very distinct properties, indicative of different origins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux eruption events drive angular momentum transport in magnetically arrested accretion flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flux_eruption_events_drive_angular_momentum_transport_in_magnetically_arrested_accretion_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flux_eruption_events_drive_angular_momentum_transport_in_magnetically_arrested_accretion_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Koushik Chatterjee
We evolve two high-resolution general relativistic magnetohydrodynamic (GRMHD) simulations of advection-dominated accretion flows around non-spinning black holes (BHs), each over a duration $\sim 3\times 10^5,GM_{\rm BH}/c^3$. One model captures the evolution of a weakly magnetized (SANE) disk and the other a magnetically arrested disk (MAD). Magnetic flux eruptions in the MAD model push out gas from the disk and launch strong winds with outflow efficiencies at times reaching $10%$ of the incoming accretion power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grantecan spectroscopic observations and confirmations of Planetary Nebulae candidates in the Northern Galactic Plane</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/grantecan_spectroscopic_observations_and_confirmations_of_planetary_nebulae_candidates_in_the_northern_galactic_plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/grantecan_spectroscopic_observations_and_confirmations_of_planetary_nebulae_candidates_in_the_northern_galactic_plane/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Ritter
We present Grantecan 10 m telescope (GTC) spectroscopic confirmations of 55 faint Planetary Nebulae (PNe) candidates discovered largely in the INT Photometric H$_\alpha$ Survey of the Northern Galactic Plane (IPHAS) by our pro-am collaboration. We confirm 46 of them as &amp;lsquo;True&amp;rsquo; (T), 4 as &amp;lsquo;Likely&amp;rsquo; (L) and 5 as &amp;lsquo;Possible&amp;rsquo; (P) PNe and including 5 new PNe central star (CSPN) discoveries. This was from observations of 62 new candidates yielding a maximum PN discovery success rate of 89%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the cosmic evolution of AGN obscuration and the X-ray luminosity function: XMM-Newton and Chandra spectral analysis of the 31.3 deg$^2$ Stripe 82X</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_cosmic_evolution_of_agn_obscuration_and_the_x-ray_luminosity_function_xmm-newton_and_chandra_spectral_analysis_of_the_31.3_deg2_stripe_82x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_cosmic_evolution_of_agn_obscuration_and_the_x-ray_luminosity_function_xmm-newton_and_chandra_spectral_analysis_of_the_31.3_deg2_stripe_82x/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alessandro Peca
We present X-ray spectral analysis of XMM and Chandra observations in the 31.3 deg$^2$ Stripe-82X (S82X) field. Of the 6181 unique X-ray sources in this field, we select and analyze a sample of 2937 candidate active galactic nuclei (AGN) with solid redshifts and sufficient counts determined by simulations. Our results show an observed population with median values of spectral index $\Gamma=1.94_{-0.39}^{+0.31}$, column density log $N_H/\rm{cm}^{-2}=20.7_{-0.5}^{+1.2}$ ($21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the underestimation of dust mass in protoplanetary disks: Effects of disk structure and dust properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_underestimation_of_dust_mass_in_protoplanetary_disks_effects_of_disk_structure_and_dust_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_underestimation_of_dust_mass_in_protoplanetary_disks_effects_of_disk_structure_and_dust_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yao Liu
The total amount of dust grains in protoplanetary disks is one of the key properties that characterize the potential for planet formation. With (sub-)millimeter flux measurements, literature studies usually derive the dust mass using an analytic form under the assumption of optically thin emission, which may lead to substantial underestimation. In this work, we conduct a parameter study with the goal of investigating the effects of disk structure and dust properties on the underestimation through self-consistent radiative transfer models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quasi-periodic eruptions from mildly eccentric unstable mass transfer in galactic nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quasi-periodic_eruptions_from_mildly_eccentric_unstable_mass_transfer_in_galactic_nuclei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quasi-periodic_eruptions_from_mildly_eccentric_unstable_mass_transfer_in_galactic_nuclei/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wenbin Lu
We propose that the recently observed quasi-periodic eruptions (QPEs) in galactic nuclei are produced by unstable mass transfer due to Roche lobe overflow of a low-mass (&amp;lt; 0.5Msun) main-sequence star in a mildly eccentric (e ~ 0.5) orbit. We argue that the QPE emission is powered by circularization shocks, but not directly by black hole accretion. Our model predicts the presence of a time-steady accretion disk that is bolometrically brighter than the time-averaged QPE luminosity, but primarily emits in the extreme-UV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robustness of cosmic birefringence measurement against Galactic foreground emission and instrumental systematics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robustness_of_cosmic_birefringence_measurement_against_galactic_foreground_emission_and_instrumental_systematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robustness_of_cosmic_birefringence_measurement_against_galactic_foreground_emission_and_instrumental_systematics/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Diego-Palazuelos
The polarization of the cosmic microwave background (CMB) can be used to search for parity-violating processes like that predicted by a Chern-Simons coupling to a light pseudoscalar field. Such an interaction rotates $E$ modes into $B$ modes in the observed CMB signal by an effect known as cosmic birefringence. Even though isotropic birefringence can be confused with the rotation produced by a miscalibration of the detectors&amp;rsquo; polarization angles the degeneracy between both effects is broken when Galactic foreground emission is used as a calibrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ly$α$, CIV, and HeII nebulae around J1000&#43;0234: a galaxy pair at the center of a galaxy overdensity at $z=4.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_ly%CE%B1_civ_and_heii_nebulae_around_j1000&#43;0234_a_galaxy_pair_at_the_center_of_a_galaxy_overdensity_at_z4.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_ly%CE%B1_civ_and_heii_nebulae_around_j1000&#43;0234_a_galaxy_pair_at_the_center_of_a_galaxy_overdensity_at_z4.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. F. Jiménez-Andrade
Ly$\alpha$ emission extending over $\gtrsim,\rm 10,kiloparsec,(kpc)$ around dusty, massive starbursts at $z\gtrsim3$ might represent a short-lived phase in the evolution of present-day, massive quiescent galaxies. To obtain empirical constraints on this emerging scenario, we present Ly$\alpha$, CIV, and HeII observations taken with the Multi Unit Spectroscopic Explorer towards J1000$+$0234: a galaxy pair at $z=4.5$ composed of a low-mass starburst (J1000$+$0234$-$South) neighboring a massive Submillimeter Galaxy (SMG; J1000$+$0234$-$North) that harbors a rotationally supported gas disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of hot galactic winds launched from non-uniform starburst cores</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_of_hot_galactic_winds_launched_from_non-uniform_starburst_cores/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_of_hot_galactic_winds_launched_from_non-uniform_starburst_cores/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dustin D. Nguyen
The galactic wind model of Chevalier1985 (CC85) assumes $\textit{uniform}$ energy and mass-injection within the starburst galaxy nucleus. However, the structure of nuclear star clusters, bulges, and star-forming knots are inherently non-uniform. We generalize to cases with non-uniform energy/mass injection that scale as $r^{-\Delta}$ within the starburst volume $R$, providing solutions for $\Delta = 0$, 1/2, 1, 3/2, and 2. In marked contrast with the CC85 model ($\Delta=0$), which predicts zero velocity at the center, for a singular isothermal sphere profile ($\Delta=2$), we find that the flow maintains a $\textit{constant}$ Mach number of $\mathcal{M}=\sqrt{3/5} \simeq 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using debris disk observations to infer substellar companions orbiting within or outside a parent planetesimal belt</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_debris_disk_observations_to_infer_substellar_companions_orbiting_within_or_outside_a_parent_planetesimal_belt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_debris_disk_observations_to_infer_substellar_companions_orbiting_within_or_outside_a_parent_planetesimal_belt/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. A. Stuber
Aims. We analyze whether the effects of secular perturbations, originating from a substellar companion, on the dust dynamics in a debris disk can be investigated with spatially resolved observations. Methods. We numerically simulated the collisional evolution of narrow and eccentric cold planetesimal belts around a star of spectral type A3V that are secularly perturbed by a companion that orbits either closer to or farther from the star than the belt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing the accuracy of asteroseismic mass and radius estimates of giant stars III. KIC4054905, an eclipsing binary with two 10 Gyr thick disk RGB stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/establishing_the_accuracy_of_asteroseismic_mass_and_radius_estimates_of_giant_stars_iii._kic4054905_an_eclipsing_binary_with_two_10_gyr_thick_disk_rgb_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/establishing_the_accuracy_of_asteroseismic_mass_and_radius_estimates_of_giant_stars_iii._kic4054905_an_eclipsing_binary_with_two_10_gyr_thick_disk_rgb_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. Brogaard
Eclipsing binary stars with an oscillating giant component allow accurate stellar parameters to be derived and asteroseismic methods to be tested and calibrated. To this aim, suitable systems need to be firstly identified and secondly measured precisely and accurately. KIC 4054905 is one such system, which has been identified, but with measurements of a relatively low precision and with some confusion regarding its parameters and evolutionary state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterative Angular Differential Imaging (IADI): An exploration of recovering disk structures in scattered light with an iterative ADI approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/iterative_angular_differential_imaging_iadi_an_exploration_of_recovering_disk_structures_in_scattered_light_with_an_iterative_adi_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/iterative_angular_differential_imaging_iadi_an_exploration_of_recovering_disk_structures_in_scattered_light_with_an_iterative_adi_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. M. Stapper
Distinguishing signal of young gas rich circumstellar disks from stellar signal in near infrared light is a difficult task. Current techniques such as Angular Differential Imaging (ADI) and Polarimetric Differential Imaging (PDI) cope with drawbacks such as self-subtraction. To address these drawbacks we explore Iterative Angular Differential Imaging (IADI) techniques to increase signal throughput in total intensity observations. This work aims to explore the effectiveness of IADI to recover the self-subtracted regions of disks by applying ADI techniques iteratively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-wavelength study of the galactic PeVatron candidate LHAASO J2108&#43;5157</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-wavelength_study_of_the_galactic_pevatron_candidate_lhaaso_j2108&#43;5157/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-wavelength_study_of_the_galactic_pevatron_candidate_lhaaso_j2108&#43;5157/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Abe
LHAASO J2108+5157 is one of the few known unidentified Ultra-High-Energy (UHE) gamma-ray sources with no Very-High-Energy (VHE) counterpart, recently discovered by the LHAASO collaboration. We observed LHAASO J2108+5157 in the X-ray band with XMM-Newton in 2021 for a total of 3.8 hours and at TeV energies with the Large-Sized Telescope prototype (LST-1), yielding 49 hours of good quality data. In addition, we analyzed 12 years of Fermi-LAT data, to better constrain emission of its High-Energy (HE) counterpart 4FGL J2108.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-gaussianity of optical emission lines in SDSS star-forming galaxies and its implications on galactic outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussianity_of_optical_emission_lines_in_sdss_star-forming_galaxies_and_its_implications_on_galactic_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussianity_of_optical_emission_lines_in_sdss_star-forming_galaxies_and_its_implications_on_galactic_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. P. Brian Yu
The shape of emission lines in the optical spectra of star-forming galaxies reveals the kinematics of the diffuse gaseous component. We analyse the shape of prominent emission lines in a sample of ~53,000 star-forming galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, focusing on departures from gaussianity. Departures from a single gaussian profile allow us to probe the motion of gas and to assess the role of outflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of environment on the lives of disk galaxies as revealed by SDSS-IV MaNGA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_environment_on_the_lives_of_disk_galaxies_as_revealed_by_sdss-iv_manga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_environment_on_the_lives_of_disk_galaxies_as_revealed_by_sdss-iv_manga/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuang Zhou
Environment has long been known to have significant impact on the evolution of galaxies, but here we seek to quantify the subtler differences that might be found in disk galaxies, depending on whether they are isolated, the most massive galaxy in a group (centrals), or a lesser member (satellites). The MaNGA survey allows us to define a large mass-matched sample of 574 galaxies with high-quality integrated spectra in each category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The metallicity&#39;s fundamental dependence on both local and global galactic quantities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_metallicitys_fundamental_dependence_on_both_local_and_global_galactic_quantities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_metallicitys_fundamental_dependence_on_both_local_and_global_galactic_quantities/</guid>
      <description>First author: William M. Baker
We study the scaling relations between gas-phase metallicity, stellar mass surface density ($\Sigma $), star formation rate surface density ($\Sigma {SFR}$), and molecular gas surface density ($\Sigma{H_2}$) in local star-forming galaxies on scales of a kpc. We employ optical integral field spectroscopy from the MaNGA survey, and ALMA data for a subset of MaNGA galaxies. We use Partial Correlation Coefficients and Random Forest regression to determine the relative importance of local and global galactic properties in setting the gas-phase metallicity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
