<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/2month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/2month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A framework to measure the properties of intergalactic metal systems with two-point flux statistics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_framework_to_measure_the_properties_of_intergalactic_metal_systems_with_two-point_flux_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_framework_to_measure_the_properties_of_intergalactic_metal_systems_with_two-point_flux_statistics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Naim Göksel Karaçaylı
The abundance, temperature, and clustering of metals in the intergalactic medium are important parameters for understanding their cosmic evolution and quantifying their impact on cosmological analysis with the Ly $\alpha$ forest. The properties of these systems are typically measured from individual quasar spectra redward of the quasar&amp;rsquo;s Ly $\alpha$ emission line, yet that approach may provide biased results due to selection effects. We present an alternative approach to measure these properties in an unbiased manner with the two-point statistics commonly employed to quantify large-scale structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemo-Dynamical Evolution of Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemo-dynamical_evolution_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemo-dynamical_evolution_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chiaki Kobayashi
Stars are fossils that retain the history of their host galaxies. Elements heavier than helium are created inside stars and are ejected when they die. From the spatial distribution of elements in galaxies, it is therefore possible to constrain the physical processes during galaxy formation and evolution. This approach, Galac- tic archaeology, has been popularly used for our Milky Way Galaxy with a vast amount of data from Gaia satellite and multi-object spectrographs to understand the origins of sub-structures of the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational capture of magnetic monopoles by primordial black holes in the early universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07002/</guid>
      <description>Chen Zhang
It is intriguing to ask whether the existence of primordial black holes (PBHs) in the early universe could significantly reduce the abundance of certain stable massive particles (SMP) via gravitational capture, after which the PBHs evaporate before BBN to avoid conflict with stringent bounds. For example, this mechanism is relevant to an alternative solution of the monopole problem proposed by Stojkovic and Freese, in which magnetic monopoles produced in the early universe are captured by PBHs, thus freeing inflation from having to occur during or after the corresponding phase transitions that produced the monopoles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halo Occupation Distribution of Emission Line Galaxies: fitting method with Gaussian Processes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/halo_occupation_distribution_of_emission_line_galaxies_fitting_method_with_gaussian_processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/halo_occupation_distribution_of_emission_line_galaxies_fitting_method_with_gaussian_processes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Antoine Rocher
The halo occupation distribution (HOD) framework is an empirical method to describe the connection between dark matter halos and galaxies, which is constrained by small scale clustering data. Efficient fitting procedures are required to scan the HOD parameter space. This paper describes such a method based on Gaussian Processes to iteratively build a surrogate model of the posterior of the likelihood surface from a reasonable amount of likelihood computations, typically two orders of magnitude less than standard Monte Carlo Markov chain algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induced non-local cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/induced_non-local_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/induced_non-local_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Leonardo Giani
We investigate the cosmological implications of an effective gravitational action, inspired by Sakharov&amp;rsquo;s idea of induced gravity, containing non-local contributions from the operator $\left(\Box +\beta \right)^{-1} R$. The $\beta$ term is a novel feature in the panorama of non-local models of gravity, and arises naturally within Sakharov theory from the potential of a non-minimally coupled scalar field after a spontaneous symmetry breaking takes place. In this class of models the non-local contribution can acquire an oscillatory behaviour, thereby avoiding the divergence of the Hubble parameter at late times, which is another characteristic feature of the non-local models treated in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JADES Imaging of GN-z11: Revealing the Morphology and Environment of a Luminous Galaxy 430 Myr After the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jades_imaging_of_gn-z11_revealing_the_morphology_and_environment_of_a_luminous_galaxy_430_myr_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jades_imaging_of_gn-z11_revealing_the_morphology_and_environment_of_a_luminous_galaxy_430_myr_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sandro Tacchella
We present JWST NIRCam 9-band near-infrared imaging of the luminous $z=10.6$ galaxy GN-z11 from the JWST Advanced Deep Extragalactic Survey (JADES) of the GOODS-N field. We find a spectral energy distribution (SED) entirely consistent with the expected form of a high-redshift galaxy: a clear blue continuum from 1.5 to 4 microns with a complete dropout in F115W. The core of GN-z11 is extremely compact in JWST imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JADES NIRSpec Spectroscopy of GN-z11: Lyman-$α$ emission and possible enhanced nitrogen abundance in a $z=10.60$ luminous galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jades_nirspec_spectroscopy_of_gn-z11_lyman-_%CE%B1__emission_and_possible_enhanced_nitrogen_abundance_in_a__z10.60__luminous_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jades_nirspec_spectroscopy_of_gn-z11_lyman-_%CE%B1__emission_and_possible_enhanced_nitrogen_abundance_in_a__z10.60__luminous_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew J. Bunker
We present JADES JWST/NIRSpec spectroscopy of GN-z11, the most luminous candidate $z&amp;gt;10$ Lyman break galaxy in the GOODS-North field with $M_{UV}=-21.5$. We derive a redshift of $z=10.603$ (lower than previous determinations) based on multiple emission lines in our low and medium resolution spectra over $0.8-5.3,\mu$m. We significantly detect the continuum and measure a blue rest-UV spectral slope of $\beta=-2.4$. Remarkably, we see spatially-extended Lyman-$\alpha$ in emission (despite the highly-neutral IGM expected at this early epoch), offset 555 km/s redward of the systemic redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for Signatures of AGN Feedback in Radio-Quiet AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/looking_for_signatures_of_agn_feedback_in_radio-quiet_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/looking_for_signatures_of_agn_feedback_in_radio-quiet_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Preeti Kharb
(Abridged) In this article, we discuss the state of AGN feedback&#39;&#39; in radio-quiet (RQ) AGN. This study involves heterogeneous samples of nearby Seyfert and LINER galaxies as well as QSOs that have been observed at low radio frequencies (few ~100 MHz) with the GMRT and ~GHz frequencies with the VLA and VLBA. These multi-frequency, multi-resolution observations detect a range of arcsecond-scale radio spectral indices that are consistent with the presence of multiple contributors including starburst winds and AGN jets or winds; steep spectrum relic&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; emission is observed as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New constraints on cosmological modified gravity theories from anisotropic three-point correlation functions of BOSS DR12 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_constraints_on_cosmological_modified_gravity_theories_from_anisotropic_three-point_correlation_functions_of_boss_dr12_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_constraints_on_cosmological_modified_gravity_theories_from_anisotropic_three-point_correlation_functions_of_boss_dr12_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Naonori S. Sugiyama
We report a new test of modified gravity theories using the large-scale structure of the Universe. This paper is the first attempt to (1) apply a joint analysis of the anisotropic components of galaxy two- and three-point correlation functions (2 and 3PCFs) to actual galaxy data and (2) constrain the nonlinear effects of degenerate higher-order scalar-tensor (DHOST) theories on cosmological scales. Applying this analysis to the Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey (BOSS) data release 12, we obtain the lower bounds of $-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quark nuggets, QCD vacuum and the cosmological $^7$Li, Dark Matter and Dark Energy problems</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quark_nuggets_qcd_vacuum_and_the_cosmological__7_li_dark_matter_and_dark_energy_problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quark_nuggets_qcd_vacuum_and_the_cosmological__7_li_dark_matter_and_dark_energy_problems/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rachid Ouyed
We propose a non-exotic electromagnetic solution to the cosmological $^7$Li problem based upon a 2 MeV photo-emission line from color superconducting quark nuggets (CSCQN) that destroys Big-Bang nucleosynthesis (BBN) $^7$Be without affecting other abundances or Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) physics. Conversion of CSCQN gluonic (rest-mass) energy to 2 MeV photons in the radiation-dominated post-BBN epoch reduces the primordial abundance of $^7$Be (and thus cosmological $^7$Li) by 2/3, provided the combined mass of the nuggets is greater than the total baryonic mass in the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistive Heating Induced by Streaming Cosmic Rays Around a Galaxy in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07028/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07028/</guid>
      <description>Shota L. Yokoyama
It is expected that cosmic rays (CRs) escape from high-redshift galaxies at redshift $z\sim 10 \, - \, 20$ because CRs are accelerated by supernova remnants of the first stars. Although ultraviolet and X-ray photons are widely considered the main source of heating of the intergalactic medium, CRs can also contribute to it. When the CRs propagate in the intergalactic medium, in addition to the heating process due to CR ionization, resistive heating occurs due to the electron return current induced by the streaming CRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistive Heating Induced by Streaming Cosmic Rays Around a Galaxy in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resistive_heating_induced_by_streaming_cosmic_rays_around_a_galaxy_in_the_early_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resistive_heating_induced_by_streaming_cosmic_rays_around_a_galaxy_in_the_early_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shota L. Yokoyama
It is expected that cosmic rays (CRs) escape from high-redshift galaxies at redshift $z\sim 10 , - , 20$ because CRs are accelerated by supernova remnants of the first stars. Although ultraviolet and X-ray photons are widely considered the main source of heating of the intergalactic medium, CRs can also contribute to it. When the CRs propagate in the intergalactic medium, in addition to the heating process due to CR ionization, resistive heating occurs due to the electron return current induced by the streaming CRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The foreground transfer function for HI intensity mapping signal reconstruction: MeerKLASS and precision cosmology applications</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_foreground_transfer_function_for_hi_intensity_mapping_signal_reconstruction_meerklass_and_precision_cosmology_applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_foreground_transfer_function_for_hi_intensity_mapping_signal_reconstruction_meerklass_and_precision_cosmology_applications/</guid>
      <description>First author: Steven Cunnington
Blind cleaning methods are currently the preferred strategy for handling foreground contamination in single-dish HI intensity mapping surveys. Despite the increasing sophistication of blind techniques, some signal loss will be inevitable across all scales. Constructing a corrective transfer function using mock signal injection into the contaminated data has been a practice relied on for HI intensity mapping experiments. However, assessing whether this approach is viable for future intensity mapping surveys where precision cosmology is the aim, remains unexplored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A massive black hole in a low-metallicity AGN at $z\sim5.55$ revealed by JWST/NIRSpec IFS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_massive_black_hole_in_a_low-metallicity_agn_at__z_sim5.55__revealed_by_jwst_nirspec_ifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_massive_black_hole_in_a_low-metallicity_agn_at__z_sim5.55__revealed_by_jwst_nirspec_ifs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hannah Übler
We present JWST/NIRSpec Integral Field Spectrograph rest-frame optical data of the compact $z=5.55$ galaxy GS_3073. Its prominent broad components in several hydrogen and helium lines (while absent in the forbidden lines), and the detection of a large equivalent width of He II $\lambda4686$, EW(He II) $\sim20$ Angstrom, unambiguously identify it as an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We measure a gas-phase metallicity of $Z_{\rm gas}/Z_\odot\sim0.21^{+0.08}{-0.04}$, lower than what has been inferred for both more luminous AGN at similar redshift and lower redshift AGN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Statistical Analysis of Galactic Radio Supernova Remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_analysis_of_galactic_radio_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_analysis_of_galactic_radio_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Ranasinghe
We present an revised table of 390 Galactic radio supernova remnants (SNRs) and their basic parameters. Statistical analyses are performed on SNR diameters, ages, spectral indices, Galactic heights and spherical symmetries. Furthermore, the accuracy of distances estimated using the $\Sigma$-D relation is examined. The arithmetic mean of the Galactic SNR diameters is $30.5$ pc with standard error $1.7$ pc and standard deviation $25.4$ pc. The geometric mean and geometric standard deviation factor of Galactic SNR diameters is $21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological forecast of the 21-cm power spectrum using the halo model of reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_forecast_of_the_21-cm_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_model_of_reionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_forecast_of_the_21-cm_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_model_of_reionization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aurel Schneider
The 21-cm power spectrum of reionization is a promising probe for cosmology and fundamental physics. Exploiting this new observable, however, requires fast predictors capable of efficiently scanning the very large parameter space of cosmological and astrophysical uncertainties. In this paper, we introduce the halo model of reionization (HMreio), a new analytical tool that combines the halo model of the cosmic dawn with the excursion-set bubble model for reionization, assuming an empirical correction factor to deal with overlapping ionization bubbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of magnetic fields in the circumgalactic medium of nearby galaxies using Faraday rotation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_magnetic_fields_in_the_circumgalactic_medium_of_nearby_galaxies_using_faraday_rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_magnetic_fields_in_the_circumgalactic_medium_of_nearby_galaxies_using_faraday_rotation/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. Heesen
Context. The existence of magnetic fields in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) is largely unconstrained. Their detection is important as magnetic fields can have a significant impact on the evolution of the CGM and, in turn, the fields can serve as tracers for dynamical processes in the CGM. Aims. With Faraday rotation of polarised background sources, we aim to detect a possible excess of the rotation measure in the surrounding area of nearby galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate-mass black holes: finding of episodic, large-scale and powerful jet activity in a dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06214/</guid>
      <description>Jun Yang
Dwarf galaxies are characterised by a very low luminosity and low mass. Because of significant accretion and ejection activity of massive black holes, some dwarf galaxies also host low-luminosity active galactic nuclei (AGNs). In a few dwarf AGNs, very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) observations have found faint non-thermal radio emission. SDSS J090613.77+561015.2 is a dwarf AGN owning an intermediate-mass black hole (IMBH) with a mass of $M_{BH} = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate-mass black holes: finding of episodic, large-scale and powerful jet activity in a dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intermediate-mass_black_holes_finding_of_episodic_large-scale_and_powerful_jet_activity_in_a_dwarf_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intermediate-mass_black_holes_finding_of_episodic_large-scale_and_powerful_jet_activity_in_a_dwarf_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jun Yang
Dwarf galaxies are characterised by a very low luminosity and low mass. Because of significant accretion and ejection activity of massive black holes, some dwarf galaxies also host low-luminosity active galactic nuclei (AGNs). In a few dwarf AGNs, very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) observations have found faint non-thermal radio emission. SDSS J090613.77+561015.2 is a dwarf AGN owning an intermediate-mass black hole (IMBH) with a mass of $M_{BH} = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On cosmological Inflation In Palatini $F(R,φ)$ Gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_cosmological_inflation_in_palatini__fr%CF%86__gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_cosmological_inflation_in_palatini__fr%CF%86__gravity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mahmoud AlHallak
Single field inflationary models are investigated within Palatini quadratic gravity represented by $R+\alpha R^2$ along with a non-minimal coupling of the form $f(\phi) R$ between the inflaton field $\phi$ and the gravity. The treatment is performed in the Einstein frame, where the minimal coupling to gravity is recovered through conformal transformation. We consider various limits of the model with different inflationary scenarios characterized as canonical slow-roll inflation in the limit $\alpha \dot{\phi}^2\ll (1+f(\phi)) $, constant-roll k-inflation for $\alpha \ll 1$, and slow-roll K-inflation for$ \alpha \gg 1$ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking beneath the precision floor -- II. Probing the chemo-dynamical histories of the potential globular cluster siblings, NGC 288 and NGC 362</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06644/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06644/</guid>
      <description>Stephanie Monty
The assembly history of the Milky Way (MW) is a rapidly evolving subject, with numerous small accretion events and at least one major merger proposed in the MW&amp;amp;#39;s history. Accreted alongside these dwarf galaxies are globular clusters (GCs), which act as spatially coherent remnants of these past events. Using high precision differential abundance measurements from our recently published study, we investigate the likelihood that the MW clusters NGC 362 and NGC 288 are galactic siblings, accreted as part of the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poisson Cluster Process Models for Detecting Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/poisson_cluster_process_models_for_detecting_ultra-diffuse_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/poisson_cluster_process_models_for_detecting_ultra-diffuse_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dayi Li
We propose a novel set of Poisson Cluster Process models to detect Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies (UDGs), a recently-discovered class of galaxies that are challenging to detect and are of substantial interests in modern astrophysics. We construct an improved spatial birth-death-move MCMC algorithm to make inferences about the locations of these otherwise un-observable galaxies. Our novel models significantly out-perform existing approaches based on the Log-Gaussian Cox Process; the novel marked point process we propose can also improve the detection performance for UDGs in noisy environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reanalysis of the spin direction distribution of Galaxy Zoo SDSS spiral galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reanalysis_of_the_spin_direction_distribution_of_galaxy_zoo_sdss_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reanalysis_of_the_spin_direction_distribution_of_galaxy_zoo_sdss_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Darius McAdam
The distribution of the spin directions of spiral galaxies in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey has been a topic of debate in the past two decades, with conflicting conclusions reported even in cases where the same data was used. Here we follow one of the previous experiments by applying the SpArcFiRe algorithm to annotate the spin directions in original dataset of Galaxy Zoo 1. The annotation of the galaxy spin directions is done after a first step of selecting the spiral galaxies in three different manners: manual analysis by Galaxy Zoo classifications, by a model-driven computer analysis, and with no selection of spiral galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relaxed blue ellipticals: accretion-driven stellar growth is a key evolutionary channel for low mass elliptical galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/relaxed_blue_ellipticals_accretion-driven_stellar_growth_is_a_key_evolutionary_channel_for_low_mass_elliptical_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/relaxed_blue_ellipticals_accretion-driven_stellar_growth_is_a_key_evolutionary_channel_for_low_mass_elliptical_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ilin Lazar
How elliptical galaxies form is a key question in observational cosmology. While the formation of massive ellipticals is strongly linked to mergers, the low mass (Mstar &amp;lt; 10^9.5 MSun) regime remains less well explored. In particular, studying elliptical populations when they are blue, and therefore rapidly building stellar mass, offers strong constraints on their formation. Here, we study 108 blue, low-mass ellipticals (which have a median stellar mass of 10^8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation of spiral instabilities in disk galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_of_spiral_instabilities_in_disk_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_of_spiral_instabilities_in_disk_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chris Hamilton
Spiral density waves can arise in galactic disks as linear instabilities of the underlying stellar distribution function. Such instabilities grow exponentially in amplitude at some fixed growth rate $\beta$ before saturating nonlinearly. However, the mechanisms behind nonlinear saturation, and the resulting saturated spiral amplitude, have not received much attention. Here we argue that the most important nonlinear saturation mechanism is likely trapping of stars near the spiral&amp;rsquo;s corotation resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of structural parameters and systemic proper motion of Sextans dwarf spheroidal galaxy with Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_structural_parameters_and_systemic_proper_motion_of_sextans_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxy_with_subaru_hyper_suprime-cam_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_structural_parameters_and_systemic_proper_motion_of_sextans_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxy_with_subaru_hyper_suprime-cam_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Akira Tokiwa
We use the Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) data to study structural parameters and systemic proper motion of the Sextans dwarf spheroidal galaxy at the heliocentric distance of 86 kpc, which is one of the most important targets for studies of dark matter nature and galaxy formation physics. Thanks to the superb image quality and wide area coverage of the Sextans field, the HSC data enables a secure selection of member star candidates based on the colour-magnitude cut, yielding about 10,000 member candidates at magnitudes down to $i\sim 24$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The relation between morphology, star formation history, and environment in local universe galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_relation_between_morphology_star_formation_history_and_environment_in_local_universe_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_relation_between_morphology_star_formation_history_and_environment_in_local_universe_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Pérez-Millán
The observed properties of galaxies are strongly dependent on both their total stellar mass and their morphology. Furthermore, the environment is known to play a strong role in shaping them. The galaxy population in the local universe that is located in virialized clusters is found to be red, poorly star-forming, and mostly composed of early morphological types. Towards a holistic understanding of the mechanisms that drive galaxy evolution, we exploit the spectrophotometric data from the WINGS and OmegaWINGS local galaxy cluster surveys, and study the role of both the local and the large-scale environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERITAS and Fermi-LAT constraints on the Gamma-ray Emission from Superluminous Supernovae SN2015bn and SN2017egm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/veritas_and_fermi-lat_constraints_on_the_gamma-ray_emission_from_superluminous_supernovae_sn2015bn_and_sn2017egm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/veritas_and_fermi-lat_constraints_on_the_gamma-ray_emission_from_superluminous_supernovae_sn2015bn_and_sn2017egm/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Acharyya
Superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) are a rare class of stellar explosions with luminosities ~10-100 times greater than ordinary core-collapse supernovae. One popular model to explain the enhanced optical output of hydrogen-poor (Type I) SLSNe invokes energy injection from a rapidly spinning magnetar. A prediction in this case is that high-energy gamma rays, generated in the wind nebula of the magnetar, could escape through the expanding supernova ejecta at late times (months or more after optical peak).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of structural parameters and systemic proper motion of Sextans dwarf spheroidal galaxy with Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06071/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06071/</guid>
      <description>Akira Tokiwa
We use the Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) data to study structural parameters and systemic proper motion of the Sextans dwarf spheroidal galaxy at the heliocentric distance of 86 kpc, which is one of the most important targets for studies of dark matter nature and galaxy formation physics. Thanks to the superb image quality and wide area coverage of the Sextans field, the HSC data enables a secure selection of member star candidates based on the colour-magnitude cut, yielding about 10,000 member candidates at magnitudes down to $i\sim 24$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN candidates in the VVV near-IR galaxy catalogue</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_candidates_in_the_vvv_near-ir_galaxy_catalogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_candidates_in_the_vvv_near-ir_galaxy_catalogue/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura D. Baravalle
The goal of this work is to search for Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) in the Galactic disc at very low latitudes with |b| $&amp;lt;$ 2$^\circ$. For this, we studied the five sources from the VVV near-infrared galaxy catalogue that have also WISE counterparts and present variability in the VIrac VAriable Classification Ensemble (VIVACE) catalogue. In the near-infrared colour-colour diagrams, these objects have in general redder colours compared to the rest of the sources in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The anisotropic distribution of the satellites in Milky-Way-like galaxy systems</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_anisotropic_distribution_of_the_satellites_in_milky-way-like_galaxy_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_anisotropic_distribution_of_the_satellites_in_milky-way-like_galaxy_systems/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xinghai Zhao
Aim. The satellite systems of Milky-Way-like galaxies offer a useful means by which to study the galaxy formation process in the cosmological context. It has been suggested that the currently observed anisotropic distribution of the satellites in such galaxy systems is inconsistent with the concordant $\Lambda CDM$ cosmology model on the galactic scale if the observed satellites are random samples of the dark matter (DM) sub-halos that are nearly isotropically distributed around the central galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dwarf Galaxy Debris Stream Associated with Palomar 1 and the Anticenter Stream</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05232/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05232/</guid>
      <description>Yong Yang
We report the discovery of a new stream (dubbed as Yangtze) detected in $Gaia$ Data Release 3. The stream is at a heliocentric distance of $\sim$ 9.12 kpc and spans nearly 27$°$ by 1.9$°$ on sky. The colour-magnitude diagram of Yangtze indicates a stellar population of Age $\sim$ 11 Gyr and $[M/H]$ $\sim$ -0.7 dex. It has a number density of about 5.5 stars degree$^{-2}$ along with a surface brightness of $Σ_G \simeq$ 34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbonaceous dust grains within galaxies seen in the first billion years of cosmic time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/carbonaceous_dust_grains_within_galaxies_seen_in_the_first_billion_years_of_cosmic_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/carbonaceous_dust_grains_within_galaxies_seen_in_the_first_billion_years_of_cosmic_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joris Witstok
Interstellar dust captures a significant fraction of elements heavier than helium in the solid state and is an indispensable component both in theory and observations of galaxy evolution. Dust emission is generally the primary coolant of the interstellar medium (ISM) and facilitates the gravitational collapse and fragmentation of gas clouds from which stars form, while altering the emission spectrum of galaxies from ultraviolet (UV) to far-infrared wavelengths through the reprocessing of starlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on dark energy from the CSST galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_dark_energy_from_the_csst_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_dark_energy_from_the_csst_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yufei Zhang
We study the potential of the galaxy cluster sample expected from the China Space Station Telescope (CSST) survey to constrain dark energy properties. By modelling the distribution of observed cluster mass for a given true mass to be log-normal and adopting a selection threshold in the observed mass $M_{200m} \geq 0.836 \times 10^{14} h^{-1}M_{\odot}$, we find about $4.1 \times 10^{5}$ clusters in the redshift range $0 \leq z \leq 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of intermediate mass black holes in globular cluster. Wander radius and anisotropy profiles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05542/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05542/</guid>
      <description>Pierfrancesco Di Cintio
We recently introduced a new method for simulating collisional gravitational N-body systems with approximately linear time scaling with $N$, based on the Multi-Particle Collision (MPC) scheme, previously applied in Plasma Physics. We simulate globular clusters with a realistic number of stellar particles (at least up to several times $10^6$) on a standard workstation. We simulate clusters hosting an intermediate mass black hole (IMBH), probing a broad range of BH-cluster and BH-average-star mass ratios, unrestricted by the computational constraints affecting direct N-body codes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating AGN Black Hole Masses via Continuum Reverberation Mapping in the Era of LSST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/estimating_agn_black_hole_masses_via_continuum_reverberation_mapping_in_the_era_of_lsst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/estimating_agn_black_hole_masses_via_continuum_reverberation_mapping_in_the_era_of_lsst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shu Wang
Spectroscopic reverberation mapping (RM) is a direct approach widely used to estimate the mass of black holes (BHs) in active galactic nuclei (AGNs). However, it is very time-consuming and difficult to apply to a large AGN sample. The empirical relation between the broad-line region (BLR) size and luminosity (H$\beta$ $R_{\rm BLR}\unicode{x2013}L_{\rm}$) provides a practical alternative yet subject to large scatter and systematic bias. AGN continuum RM (CRM) recently discovered a similar relation between the continuum emitting region (CER) size and luminosity ($R_{\rm CER}\unicode{x2013}L$).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid: Cosmology forecasts from the void-galaxy cross-correlation function with reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_cosmology_forecasts_from_the_void-galaxy_cross-correlation_function_with_reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_cosmology_forecasts_from_the_void-galaxy_cross-correlation_function_with_reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Radinović
We investigate the cosmological constraints that can be expected from measurement of the cross-correlation of galaxies with cosmic voids identified in the Euclid spectroscopic survey, which will include spectroscopic information for tens of millions of galaxies over $15,000$ deg$^2$ of the sky in the redshift range $0.9\leq z&amp;lt;1.8$. We do this using simulated measurements obtained from the Flagship mock catalogue, the official Euclid mock that closely matches the expected properties of the spectroscopic data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Rotating 25 M⊙ Population III star: Physical Properties and Resulting Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</guid>
      <description>Amar Aryan
In this Letter, we report the outcomes of 1-D modelling of a rotating 25 M$_{\odot}$ zero-age main-sequence Population III star up to the stage of the onset of core collapse. Rapidly rotating models display violent and sporadic mass losses after the Main-Sequence stage. In comparison to the solar metallicity model, Pop III models show very small pre-supernova radii. Further, with models at the stage of the onset of core collapse, we simulate the hydrodynamic simulations of resulting supernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Rotating 25 M$_{\odot}$ Population III star: Physical Properties and Resulting Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_25_m___odot__population_iii_star_physical_properties_and_resulting_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_25_m___odot__population_iii_star_physical_properties_and_resulting_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amar Aryan
In this Letter, we report the outcomes of 1-D modelling of a rotating 25 M$_{\odot}$ zero-age main-sequence Population III star up to the stage of the onset of core collapse. Rapidly rotating models display violent and sporadic mass losses after the Main-Sequence stage. In comparison to the solar metallicity model, Pop III models show very small pre-supernova radii. Further, with models at the stage of the onset of core collapse, we simulate the hydrodynamic simulations of resulting supernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Further evidence that galaxy age drives observed type Ia supernova luminosity differences</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/further_evidence_that_galaxy_age_drives_observed_type_ia_supernova_luminosity_differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/further_evidence_that_galaxy_age_drives_observed_type_ia_supernova_luminosity_differences/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Wiseman
Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are explosions of white dwarf stars that facilitate exquisite measurements of cosmological expansion history, but improvements in accuracy and precision are hindered by observational biases. Of particular concern is the apparent difference in the corrected brightnesses of SNe Ia in different host galaxy environments. SNe Ia in more massive, passive, older environments appear brighter after having been standardized by their light-curve properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Zoo: Kinematics of strongly and weakly barred galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_zoo_kinematics_of_strongly_and_weakly_barred_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_zoo_kinematics_of_strongly_and_weakly_barred_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tobias Géron
We study the bar pattern speeds and corotation radii of 225 barred galaxies, using IFU data from MaNGA and the Tremaine-Weinberg method. Our sample, which is divided between strongly and weakly barred galaxies identified via Galaxy Zoo, is the largest that this method has been applied to. We find lower pattern speeds for strongly barred galaxies than for weakly barred galaxies. As simulations show that the pattern speed decreases as the bar exchanges angular momentum with its host, these results suggest that strong bars are more evolved than weak bars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAX-COSMO: An End-to-End Differentiable and GPU Accelerated Cosmology Library</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jax-cosmo_an_end-to-end_differentiable_and_gpu_accelerated_cosmology_library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jax-cosmo_an_end-to-end_differentiable_and_gpu_accelerated_cosmology_library/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jean-Eric Campagne
We present jax-cosmo, a library for automatically differentiable cosmological theory calculations. It uses the JAX library, which has created a new coding ecosystem, especially in probabilistic programming. As well as batch acceleration, just-in-time compilation, and automatic optimization of code for different hardware modalities (CPU, GPU, TPU), JAX exposes an automatic differentiation (autodiff) mechanism. Thanks to autodiff, jax-cosmo gives access to the derivatives of cosmological likelihoods with respect to any of their parameters, and thus enables a range of powerful Bayesian inference algorithms, otherwise impractical in cosmology, such as Hamiltonian Monte Carlo and Variational Inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jet power, intrinsic $γ$-ray luminosity and accretion in jetted AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jet_power_intrinsic__%CE%B3_-ray_luminosity_and_accretion_in_jetted_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jet_power_intrinsic__%CE%B3_-ray_luminosity_and_accretion_in_jetted_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chen Yonhyun
The correlation between the kinetic jet power $P_{\rm jet}$, intrinsic $\gamma$-ray luminosity ($L^{\rm int}$) and accretion ($L_{\rm disk}$) may reveal the underlying jet physics in various black hole systems. We study the relation between kinetic jet power, intrinsic $\gamma$-ray luminosity, and accretion by using a large sample of jetted AGN, including flat-spectrum radio quasars (FSRQs), BL Lacertae objects (BL Lacs), gamma-ray Narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxies ($\gamma$NLS1s) and radio galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman-$α$ polarization from cosmological ionization fronts: II. Implications for intensity mapping</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lyman-_%CE%B1__polarization_from_cosmological_ionization_fronts_ii._implications_for_intensity_mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lyman-_%CE%B1__polarization_from_cosmological_ionization_fronts_ii._implications_for_intensity_mapping/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emily Koivu
This is the second paper in a series whose aim is to predict the power spectrum of intensity and polarized intensity from cosmic reionization fronts. After building the analytic models for intensity and polarized intensity calculations in paper I, here we apply these models to simulations of reionization. We construct a geometric model for identifying front boundaries, calculate the intensity and polarized intensity for each front, and compute a power spectrum of these results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman-α polarization from cosmological ionization fronts: I. Radiative transfer simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05369/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05369/</guid>
      <description>Yuanyuan Yang
In this paper, we present the formalism of simulating Lyman-$α$ emission and polarization around reionization ($z$ = 8) from a plane-parallel ionization front. We accomplish this by using a Monte Carlo method to simulate the production of a Lyman-$α$ photon, its propagation through an ionization front, and the eventual escape of this photon. This paper focuses on the relation of the input parameters of ionization front speed $U$, blackbody temperature $T_{\rm bb}$, and neutral hydrogen density $n_{\rm HI}$, on intensity $I$ and polarized intensity $P$ as seen by a distant observer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman-α polarization from cosmological ionization fronts: I. Radiative transfer simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lyman-%CE%B1_polarization_from_cosmological_ionization_fronts_i._radiative_transfer_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lyman-%CE%B1_polarization_from_cosmological_ionization_fronts_i._radiative_transfer_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuanyuan Yang
In this paper, we present the formalism of simulating Lyman-$\alpha$ emission and polarization around reionization ($z$ = 8) from a plane-parallel ionization front. We accomplish this by using a Monte Carlo method to simulate the production of a Lyman-$\alpha$ photon, its propagation through an ionization front, and the eventual escape of this photon. This paper focuses on the relation of the input parameters of ionization front speed $U$, blackbody temperature $T_{\rm bb}$, and neutral hydrogen density $n_{\rm HI}$, on intensity $I$ and polarized intensity $P$ as seen by a distant observer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phantom scalar-tensor models and cosmological tensions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phantom_scalar-tensor_models_and_cosmological_tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phantom_scalar-tensor_models_and_cosmological_tensions/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Ballardini
We study three different extended scalar-tensor theories of gravity by also allowing a negative sign for the kinetic term for the scalar field in the Jordan frame. Our scope is to understand how the observational constraints for these models cope with the volume of the parameter space in which the theory is healthy. Models with a negative kinetic term lead to decreasing effective gravitational constant with redshift and behave as an effective relativistic component with a negative energy density as opposite to their corresponding version with a standard kinetic term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rates and properties of type Ia supernovae in galaxy clusters within the Dark Energy Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rates_and_properties_of_type_ia_supernovae_in_galaxy_clusters_within_the_dark_energy_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rates_and_properties_of_type_ia_supernovae_in_galaxy_clusters_within_the_dark_energy_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Toy
We use the Dark Energy Survey (DES) 5 year catalogue of photometrically-classified type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) to identify 70 SNe Ia that have occurred within red-sequence selected clusters of galaxies. We compare the cluster SN light-curve properties and environmental properties to 1020 DES SNe Ia located in the field, the largest comparison of two such samples to date. We find an tentative indication (98.5 per cent confidence level) that, on average, SNe Ia located in galaxy clusters are faster declining compared to those located in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star forming brightest cluster galaxies at $z\sim0.4$ in KiDS. Further studies of cold gas and stellar properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_forming_brightest_cluster_galaxies_at__z_sim0.4__in_kids._further_studies_of_cold_gas_and_stellar_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_forming_brightest_cluster_galaxies_at__z_sim0.4__in_kids._further_studies_of_cold_gas_and_stellar_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Castignani
Brightest cluster galaxies (BCGs) are among the most massive galaxies in the Universe. Their star formation (SF) history and stellar mass assembly are debated. Recent studies suggest the presence of an emerging population of intermediate-$z$ star forming and gas-rich BCGs, where the molecular gas reservoirs are impacted by strong environmental processing. We have selected three among the most star-forming $z\sim0.4$ BCGs in the Kilo-Degree Survey (KiDS), and observed them with the IRAM 30m telescope in the first three CO transitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Demographics, Stellar Populations, and Star Formation Histories of Fast Radio Burst Host Galaxies: Implications for the Progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_demographics_stellar_populations_and_star_formation_histories_of_fast_radio_burst_host_galaxies_implications_for_the_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_demographics_stellar_populations_and_star_formation_histories_of_fast_radio_burst_host_galaxies_implications_for_the_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexa C. Gordon
We present a comprehensive catalog of observations and stellar population properties for 23 highly secure host galaxies of fast radio bursts (FRBs). Our sample comprises six repeating FRBs and 17 apparent non-repeaters. We present 82 new photometric and eight new spectroscopic observations of these hosts. Using stellar population synthesis modeling and employing non-parametric star formation histories (SFHs), we find that FRB hosts have a median stellar mass of $\approx 10^{9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of the effective number of active and sterile neutrinos on the determination of the values of cosmological parameters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_influence_of_the_effective_number_of_active_and_sterile_neutrinos_on_the_determination_of_the_values_of_cosmological_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_influence_of_the_effective_number_of_active_and_sterile_neutrinos_on_the_determination_of_the_values_of_cosmological_parameters/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. A. Chernikov
In the presented work we consider the influence of a hypothetical sterile neutrino (with eV-scale mass) on the determination of cosmological parameters. If it is detected, it will be necessary to include it into the $\Lambda \rm CDM$ model with the fixed values of its mass $m_{\rm s}$ and mixing angle $\theta_{s}$, which is the main method used through this paper. Apart from that, the seesaw mechanism requires there to be at least two sterile states, one of them being much heavier than the active ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of radial migration on tracing lithium evolution in the Galactic disk</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.12404/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.12404/</guid>
      <description>Haopeng Zhang
With the calculated guiding center radius $R_{guiding}$ and birth radius $R_{birth}$, we investigate the role of radial migration on the description of lithium evolution in the Galactic disk based on the upper envelope of the A(Li) vs. $[Fe/H]$ diagram. Using migration distances, we find that stars in the solar neighborhood are born at different locations in the galactic disk, and cannot all be explained by models of chemical evolution in the solar neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black hole and host galaxy properties of two z$\simeq$6.8 quasars from the NIRSpec IFU</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_and_host_galaxy_properties_of_two_z__simeq_6.8_quasars_from_the_nirspec_ifu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_and_host_galaxy_properties_of_two_z__simeq_6.8_quasars_from_the_nirspec_ifu/</guid>
      <description>First author: Madeline A. Marshall
Integral Field Spectroscopy (IFS) with JWST NIRSpec will significantly improve our understanding of the first quasars, by providing spatially resolved, infrared spectroscopic capabilities which cover key rest-frame optical emission lines that have been previously unobservable. Here we present our results from the first two z&amp;gt;6 quasars observed as a part of the NIRSpec Galaxy Assembly IFS GTO program, DELS J0411-0907 at z=6.82 and VDES J0020-3653 at z=6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundary conditions in hydrodynamic simulations of isolated galaxies and their impact on the gas-loss processes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/boundary_conditions_in_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_isolated_galaxies_and_their_impact_on_the_gas-loss_processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/boundary_conditions_in_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_isolated_galaxies_and_their_impact_on_the_gas-loss_processes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anderson Caproni
Three-dimensional hydrodynamic simulations are commonly used to study the evolution of the gaseous content in isolated galaxies, besides its connection with galactic star formation histories. Stellar winds, supernova blasts, and black hole feedback are mechanisms usually invoked to drive galactic outflows and decrease the initial galactic gas reservoir. However, any simulation imposes the need of choosing the limits of the simulated volume, which depends, for instance, on the size of the galaxy and the required numerical resolution, besides the available computational capability to perform it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological gravitational particle production of massive spin-2 particles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_gravitational_particle_production_of_massive_spin-2_particles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_gravitational_particle_production_of_massive_spin-2_particles/</guid>
      <description>First author: Edward W. Kolb
The phenomenon of cosmological gravitational particle production (CGPP) is expected to occur during the period of inflation and the transition into a hot big bang cosmology. Particles may be produced even if they only couple directly to gravity, and so CGPP provides a natural explanation for the origin of dark matter. In this work we study the gravitational production of massive spin-2 particles assuming two different couplings to matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology with the Galaxy Bispectrum Multipoles: Optimal Estimation and Application to BOSS Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_with_the_galaxy_bispectrum_multipoles_optimal_estimation_and_application_to_boss_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_with_the_galaxy_bispectrum_multipoles_optimal_estimation_and_application_to_boss_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mikhail M. Ivanov
We present a framework for self-consistent cosmological analyses of the full-shape anisotropic bispectrum, including the quadrupole $(\ell=2)$ and hexadecapole $(\ell=4)$ moments. This features a novel window-free algorithm for extracting the latter quantities from data, derived using a maximum-likelihood prescription. Furthermore, we introduce a theoretical model for the bispectrum multipoles (which does not introduce new free parameters), and test both aspects of the pipeline on several high-fidelity mocks, including the PT Challenge suite of gigantic cumulative volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAGLE-like simulation models do not solve the entropy core problem in groups and clusters of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.09978/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.09978/</guid>
      <description>Edoardo Altamura
Recent high-resolution cosmological hydrodynamic simulations run with a variety of codes systematically predict large amounts of entropy in the intra-cluster medium at low redshift, leading to flat entropy profiles and a suppressed cool-core population. This prediction is at odds with X-ray observations of groups and clusters. We use a new implementation of the EAGLE galaxy formation model to investigate the sensitivity of the central entropy and the shape of the profiles to changes in the sub-grid model applied to a suite of zoom-in cosmological simulations of a group of mass $M_{500} = 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended hard X-ray emission in highly obscured AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extended_hard_x-ray_emission_in_highly_obscured_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extended_hard_x-ray_emission_in_highly_obscured_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jingzhe Ma
Kilo-parsec scale hard ($&amp;gt;$ 3 keV) X-ray continuum and fluorescent Fe K$\alpha$ line emission has been recently discovered in nearby Compton-thick (CT) active galactic nuclei (AGN), which opens new opportunities to improve AGN torus modeling and investigate how the central supermassive black hole interacts with and impacts the host galaxy. Following a pilot Chandra survey of nearby CT AGN, we present in this paper the Chandra spatial analysis results of five uniformly selected non-CT but still heavily obscured AGN to investigate the extended hard X-ray emission by measuring the excess emission counts, excess fractions, and physical scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferred galaxy properties during Cosmic Dawn from early JWST photometry results</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferred_galaxy_properties_during_cosmic_dawn_from_early_jwst_photometry_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferred_galaxy_properties_during_cosmic_dawn_from_early_jwst_photometry_results/</guid>
      <description>First author: Corey Brummel-Smith
Early photometric results from JWST have revealed a number of galaxy candidates above redshift 10. The initial estimates of inferred stellar masses and the associated cosmic star formation rates are above most theoretical model predictions up to a factor of 20 in the most extreme cases, while this has been moderated after the recalibration of NIRCam and subsequent spectroscopic detections. Using these recent JWST observations, we use galaxy scaling relations from cosmological simulations to model the star formation history to very high redshifts, back to a starting halo mass of 10^7 solar masses, to infer the intrinsic properties of the JWST galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Reconstruction of Galaxy-scale Strong Gravitational Lenses Using Broken Power-law Model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_reconstruction_of_galaxy-scale_strong_gravitational_lenses_using_broken_power-law_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mass_reconstruction_of_galaxy-scale_strong_gravitational_lenses_using_broken_power-law_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wei Du
With mock strong gravitational lensing images, we investigate the performance of broken power-law (BPL) model on the mass reconstruction of galaxy-scale lenses. An end-to-end test is carried out, including the creation of mock strong lensing images, the subtraction of lens light, and the reconstruction of lensed images. Based on these analyses, we can reliably evaluate how accurate the lens mass and source light distributions can be measured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remnants of recent mergers in nearby early-type galaxies and their classification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.04471/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.04471/</guid>
      <description>Gourab Giri
We search for signatures of recent galaxy close interactions and mergers in a sample of 202 early-type galaxies in the local universe from the public SDSS Stripe82 deep images ($μ_r \sim 28.5$ mag arcsec$^{-2}$). Using two different methods to remove galaxies&amp;amp;#39; smooth and symmetric light distribution, we identify and characterize eleven distinct types of merger remnants embedded in the diffuse light of these early-type galaxies. We discuss how the morphology of merger remnants can result from different kinds of minor and major mergers, and estimate the fraction of early-type galaxies in the local universe with evidence of recent major (27%) and minor (57%) mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remnants of recent mergers in nearby early-type galaxies and their classification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/remnants_of_recent_mergers_in_nearby_early-type_galaxies_and_their_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/remnants_of_recent_mergers_in_nearby_early-type_galaxies_and_their_classification/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gourab Giri
We search for signatures of recent galaxy close interactions and mergers in a sample of 202 early-type galaxies in the local universe from the public SDSS Stripe82 deep images ($\mu_r \sim 28.5$ mag arcsec$^{-2}$). Using two different methods to remove galaxies&amp;rsquo; smooth and symmetric light distribution, we identify and characterize eleven distinct types of merger remnants embedded in the diffuse light of these early-type galaxies. We discuss how the morphology of merger remnants can result from different kinds of minor and major mergers, and estimate the fraction of early-type galaxies in the local universe with evidence of recent major (27%) and minor (57%) mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral Shapes of the Lya Emission from Galaxies. II. the influence of stellar properties and nebular conditions on the emergent Lya profiles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectral_shapes_of_the_lya_emission_from_galaxies._ii._the_influence_of_stellar_properties_and_nebular_conditions_on_the_emergent_lya_profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectral_shapes_of_the_lya_emission_from_galaxies._ii._the_influence_of_stellar_properties_and_nebular_conditions_on_the_emergent_lya_profiles/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew J. Hayes
We demonstrate how the stellar and nebular conditions in star-forming galaxies modulate the emission and spectral profile of HI Lya emission line. We examine the net Lya output, kinematics, and in particular emission of blue-shifted Lya radiation, using spectroscopy from with the Cosmic Origins Spectrograph on HST, giving a sample of 87 galaxies at redshift z=0.05-0.44. We contrast the Lya spectral measurements with properties of the ionized gas (from optical spectra) and stars (from stellar modeling).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar collisions in globular clusters: Constraints on the initial mass function of the first generation of stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.11288/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.11288/</guid>
      <description>Sami Dib
Globular clusters display an anticorrelation between the fraction of the first generation of stars ($N({\rm G1})/N({\rm tot})$) and the slope of the present-day mass function of the clusters ($α_{pd}$), which is particularly significant for massive clusters. In the framework of the binary-mediated collision scenario for the formation of the second-generation stars in globular clusters, we test the effect of a varying stellar initial mass function (IMF) of the G1 stars on the $(N({\rm G1})/N({\rm tot}))-α_{pd}$ anticorrelation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Superluminous Type IIn Supernova ASASSN-15ua: Part of a continuum in extreme precursor mass loss</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_superluminous_type_iin_supernova_asassn-15ua_part_of_a_continuum_in_extreme_precursor_mass_loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_superluminous_type_iin_supernova_asassn-15ua_part_of_a_continuum_in_extreme_precursor_mass_loss/</guid>
      <description>First author: Danielle Dickinson
We present a series of ground-based photometry and spectroscopy of the superluminous Type IIn supernova (SN) ASASSN-15ua, which shows evidence for strong interaction with pre-existing dense circumstellar material (CSM). Our observations constrain the speed, mass-loss rate, and extent of the progenitor wind shortly before explosion. A narrow P Cygni absorption component reveals a progenitor wind speed of $\sim$100 km s$^{-1}$. As observed in previous SNe IIn, the intermediate-width H$\alpha$ emission became progressively more asymmetric and blueshifted, suggesting either an asymmetric CSM, an asymmetric explosion, or increasing selective extinction from dust within the post-shock shell or SN ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing coincidence search for supernova neutrinos with optical transient surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/timing_coincidence_search_for_supernova_neutrinos_with_optical_transient_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/timing_coincidence_search_for_supernova_neutrinos_with_optical_transient_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sean Heston
Neutrinos allow the probing of stellar interiors during core collapse, helping to understand the different stages and processes in the collapse. To date, supernova neutrinos have only been detected from a single event, SN1987A. Most studies from then on have focused on two distance extremes: Galactic/local supernovae and all past cosmic supernovae forming the diffuse supernova neutrino background. We focus on the intermediate distance regime as a target for detecting core-collapse supernova neutrinos at next generation detectors like Hyper-Kamiokande.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive view of the interstellar medium in a quasar host galaxy at z~6.4</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_comprehensive_view_of_the_interstellar_medium_in_a_quasar_host_galaxy_at_z~6.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_comprehensive_view_of_the_interstellar_medium_in_a_quasar_host_galaxy_at_z~6.4/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roberto Decarli
Characterizing the physical conditions (density, temperature, ionization state, metallicity, etc) of the interstellar medium is critical to our understanding of the formation and evolution of galaxies. Here we present a multi-line study of the interstellar medium in the host galaxy of a quasar at z~6.4, i.e., when the universe was 840 Myr old. This galaxy is one of the most active and massive objects emerging from the dark ages, and therefore represents a benchmark for models of the early formation of massive galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Large Population of Faint 8&lt;z&lt;16 Galaxies Found in the First JWST NIRCam Observations of the NGDEEP Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_large_population_of_faint_8z16_galaxies_found_in_the_first_jwst_nircam_observations_of_the_ngdeep_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_large_population_of_faint_8z16_galaxies_found_in_the_first_jwst_nircam_observations_of_the_ngdeep_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Austin
We present an early analysis on the search for high redshift galaxies using the deepest public JWST imaging to date, the NGDEEP field. This data consists of 6-band NIRCam imaging on the Hubble Ultra Deep Field-Par2, covering a total area of 6.3 arcmin$^{2}$. Based on our initial reduction of the first half of this survey, we reach 5$\sigma$ depths up to mag = 29.5&amp;ndash;29.9 between $1-5$ um.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALMA Detection of 321 GHz water maser emission in the radio galaxy NGC 1052</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/alma_detection_of_321_ghz_water_maser_emission_in_the_radio_galaxy_ngc_1052/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/alma_detection_of_321_ghz_water_maser_emission_in_the_radio_galaxy_ngc_1052/</guid>
      <description>First author: Seiji Kameno
The Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) serendipitously detected H$2$O $J{Ka, Kc} = 10_{2,9} - 9_{3,6}$ emission at 321 GHz in NGC 1052. This is the first submillimeter maser detection in a radio galaxy and the most luminous 321-GHz H$2$O maser known to date with the isotropic luminosity of 1090 $L{\odot}$. The line profile consists of a broad velocity component with FWHM $= 208 \pm 12$ km s$^{-1}$ straddling the systemic velocity and a narrow component with FWHM $= 44 \pm 3$ km s$^{-1}$ blueshifted by 160 km s$^{-1}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical characterisation of the X-shooter Spectral Library (XSL): $[Mg/Fe]$ and $[Ca/Fe]$ abundances</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_characterisation_of_the_x-shooter_spectral_library_xsl_mg_fe_and_ca_fe_abundances/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_characterisation_of_the_x-shooter_spectral_library_xsl_mg_fe_and_ca_fe_abundances/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pablo Santos-Peral
The X-shooter Spectral Library (XSL) is a large empirical stellar library used as a benchmark for the development of stellar population models. The inclusion of $\alpha$-elements abundances is crucial to disentangling the chemical evolution of any stellar system. The aim of this paper is to provide a catalogue of high-precision and accurate magnesium and calcium abundances from a wide variety of stars well distributed in the Hertzsprung-Russell (HR) diagram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical enrichment of the ICM within the Virgo cluster I: radial profiles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_enrichment_of_the_icm_within_the_virgo_cluster_i_radial_profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chemical_enrichment_of_the_icm_within_the_virgo_cluster_i_radial_profiles/</guid>
      <description>First author: Efrain Gatuzz
We present a detailed analysis of the elemental abundances distribution of the Virgo cluster using {\it XMM-Newton} observations. We included in the analysis a new EPIC-pn energy scale calibration which allow us to measure velocities with uncertainties down to $\Delta v \sim 150$ km/s. We investigate the radial distribution of O, Ne, Mg, Si, Ar, S, Ca, Ni and Fe. We found that the best-fit model is close to a single-temperature component for distances $&amp;gt;80$~kpc and the cooler gas is more metal-rich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparisons between fast algorithms for the continuous wavelet transform and applications in cosmology: the one-dimensional case</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comparisons_between_fast_algorithms_for_the_continuous_wavelet_transform_and_applications_in_cosmology_the_one-dimensional_case/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comparisons_between_fast_algorithms_for_the_continuous_wavelet_transform_and_applications_in_cosmology_the_one-dimensional_case/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yun Wang
The continuous wavelet transform (CWT) is very useful for processing signals with intricate and irregular structures in astrophysics and cosmology. It is crucial to propose precise and fast algorithms for the CWT. In this work, we review and compare four different fast CWT algorithms for the 1D signals, including the FFTCWT, the V97CWT, the M02CWT, and the A19CWT. The FFTCWT algorithm implements the CWT using the Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) with a computational complexity of $\mathcal{O}(N\log_2N)$ per scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Machine Learning in Cosmology: Evolution or Revolution?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_machine_learning_in_cosmology_evolution_or_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_machine_learning_in_cosmology_evolution_or_revolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ofer Lahav
Could Machine Learning (ML) make fundamental discoveries and tackle unsolved problems in Cosmology? Detailed observations of the present contents of the universe are consistent with the Cosmological Constant Lambda and Cold Dark Matter model, subject to some unresolved inconsistencies (&amp;rsquo;tensions&amp;rsquo;) among observations of the Hubble Constant and the clumpiness factor. To understand these issues further, large surveys of billions of galaxies and other probes require new statistical approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lack of Bright Supernova Emission in the Brightest Gamma-ray Burst, GRB~221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lack_of_bright_supernova_emission_in_the_brightest_gamma-ray_burst_grb~221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lack_of_bright_supernova_emission_in_the_brightest_gamma-ray_burst_grb~221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Manisha Shrestha
We present photometric and spectroscopic observations of the extraordinary gamma-ray burst (GRB) 221009A in search of an associated supernova. Some past GRBs have shown bumps in the optical light curve that coincide with the emergence of supernova spectral features, but we do not detect any significant light curve features in GRB~221009A, nor do we detect any clear sign of supernova spectral features. Using two well-studied GRB-associated supernovae (SN~2013dx, $M_{r,max} = -19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late growth of early-type galaxies in low-z massive clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/late_growth_of_early-type_galaxies_in_low-z_massive_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/late_growth_of_early-type_galaxies_in_low-z_massive_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. L. B. Ribeiro
We study a sample of 936 early-type galaxies (ETGs) located in 48 low-z regular galaxy clusters with $M_{200}\geq 10^{14}~ M_\odot$ at $z&amp;lt; 0.1$. We examine variations in the concentration index, radius, and color gradient of ETGs as a function of their stellar mass and loci in the projected phase space (PPS) of the clusters. We aim to understand the environmental influence on the growth of ETGs according to the time since infall into their host clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Galaxy Distribution in Clusters using Halo Cores</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_galaxy_distribution_in_clusters_using_halo_cores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_galaxy_distribution_in_clusters_using_halo_cores/</guid>
      <description>First author: Danila Korytov
The galaxy distribution in dark matter-dominated halos is expected to approximately trace the details of the underlying dark matter substructure. In this paper we introduce halo `core-tracking&amp;rsquo; as a way to efficiently follow the small-scale substructure in cosmological simulations and apply the technique to model the galaxy distribution in observed clusters. The method relies on explicitly tracking the set of particles identified as belonging to a halo&amp;rsquo;s central density core, once a halo has attained a certain threshold mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Cosmological Low Entropy After the Big Bang: Universal Expansion and Nucleosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_cosmological_low_entropy_after_the_big_bang_universal_expansion_and_nucleosynthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_cosmological_low_entropy_after_the_big_bang_universal_expansion_and_nucleosynthesis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Charlie F. Sharpe
We investigate the sensitivity of a universe&amp;rsquo;s nuclear entropy after Big Bang nucleosynthesis (BBN) to variations in both the baryon-to-photon ratio and the temporal evolution of cosmological expansion. Specifically, we construct counterfactual cosmologies to quantify the degree by which these two parameters must vary from those in our Universe before we observe a substantial change in the degree of fusion, and thus nuclear entropy, during BBN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting interstellar radiation fields from chemical evolution models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.04782/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.04782/</guid>
      <description>Mario Romero
We present a self-consistent prediction of the interstellar radiation field (ISRF), from the extreme ultraviolet (EUV) to sub-mm range, based on two chemical evolution models of a Milky Way-like galaxy (MWG). To this end, we develop a new tool called Mixclask to include gas emission, absorption and scattering from the photoionization code Cloudy into the Monte Carlo radiative transfer code Skirt. Both algorithms are invoked iteratively, until the physical properties of the ISM converge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability of forming gaps in the GD-1 stream by close encounters of globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.15481/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2203.15481/</guid>
      <description>Yuka Doke
One of the most intriguing properties of the GD-1 stellar stream is the existence of three gaps. If these gaps were formed by close encounters with dark matter subhalos, the GD-1 stream opens an exciting window through which we can see the size, mass, and velocity distributions of the dark matter subhalos in the Milky Way. However, in order to use the GD-1 stream as a probe of the dark matter substructure, we need to disprove that these gaps are not due to the perturbations from baryonic components of the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Measurement of Mass Dependence and Evolution of Galaxy-Halo Alignment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robust_measurement_of_mass_dependence_and_evolution_of_galaxy-halo_alignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robust_measurement_of_mass_dependence_and_evolution_of_galaxy-halo_alignment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kun Xu
We measure the galaxy-ellipticity (GI) correlations for the Slogan Digital Sky Survey DR12 LOWZ and CMASS samples with the shape measurements from the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys. We model the GI correlations in an N-body simulation with our recent accurate stellar-halo mass relation from the Photometric object Around Cosmic webs (PAC) method. The large data set and our accurate modeling turns out an accurate measurement of the alignment angle between central galaxies and their host halos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling hidden active nuclei in MaNGA star-forming galaxies with HeII$λ$4686 line emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unveiling_hidden_active_nuclei_in_manga_star-forming_galaxies_with_heii_%CE%BB_4686_line_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unveiling_hidden_active_nuclei_in_manga_star-forming_galaxies_with_heii_%CE%BB_4686_line_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giulia Tozzi
Nebular HeII$\lambda$4686\AA~line emission is useful to unveil active galactic nuclei (AGN) residing in actively star-forming (SF) galaxies, typically missed by the standard BPT classification. Here we adopt the HeII diagnostic to identify hidden AGN in the Local Universe using for the first time spatially-resolved data from the Data Release 15 of the Mapping Nearby Galaxies at APO survey (MaNGA DR15). By combining results from HeII and BPT diagnostics, we overall select 459 AGN host candidates ($\sim$10% in MaNGA DR15), out of which 27 are identified as AGN by the HeII diagram only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Ray Detection of the Galaxy&#39;s Missing Baryons in the Circum-Galactic Medium of L$^*$ Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_detection_of_the_galaxys_missing_baryons_in_the_circum-galactic_medium_of_l___galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_detection_of_the_galaxys_missing_baryons_in_the_circum-galactic_medium_of_l___galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrizio Nicastro
The amount of baryons hosted in the disks of galaxies is lower than expected based on the mass of their dark-matter halos and the fraction of baryon-to-total matter in the universe, giving rise to the so called galaxy missing-baryon problem. The presence of cool circum-galactic matter gravitationally bound to its galaxy&amp;rsquo;s halo up to distances of at least ten times the size of the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s disk, mitigates the problem but is far from being sufficient for its solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding NGC 7252 as a blue elliptical galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/decoding_ngc_7252_as_a_blue_elliptical_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/decoding_ngc_7252_as_a_blue_elliptical_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Koshy George
Elliptical galaxies with blue optical colours and significant star formation are hypothesised to be major merger remnants of gas rich spiral galaxies or normal elliptical galaxies with a sudden burst of star formation. We present here a scenario where blue elliptical galaxies identified from shallow imaging surveys may fail to recover faint features indicative of a past merger activity using a nearby major merger remnant. Based on deep optical imaging data of a post merger galaxy, NGC 7252, we demonstrate that the galaxy can appear as an elliptical galaxy if observed at higher redshifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST NIRSpec observations of Supernova 1987A -- from the inner ejecta to the reverse shock</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_observations_of_supernova_1987a_--_from_the_inner_ejecta_to_the_reverse_shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_observations_of_supernova_1987a_--_from_the_inner_ejecta_to_the_reverse_shock/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Larsson
We present initial results from JWST NIRSpec integral field unit observations of the nearby Supernova (SN) 1987A. The observations provide the first spatially-resolved spectroscopy of the ejecta and equatorial ring (ER) over the 1-5 $\mu$m range. We construct 3D emissivity maps of the $[Fe I]$ 1.443 $\mu$m line from the inner ejecta and the He I 1.083 $\mu$m line from the reverse shock (RS), where the former probes the explosion geometry and the latter traces the structure of the circumstellar medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on fundamental cosmology from Low Earth Orbit and the Moon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perspectives_on_fundamental_cosmology_from_low_earth_orbit_and_the_moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perspectives_on_fundamental_cosmology_from_low_earth_orbit_and_the_moon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gianfranco Bertone
The next generation of space-based experiments will go hunting for answers to cosmology&amp;rsquo;s key open questions which revolve around inflation, dark matter and dark energy. Low earth orbit and lunar missions within the European Space Agency&amp;rsquo;s Human and Robotic Exploration programme can push our knowledge forward in all of these three fields. A radio interferometer on the Moon, a cold atom interferometer in low earth orbit and a gravitational wave interferometer on the Moon are highlighted as the most fruitful missions to plan and execute in the mid-term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the energetics of molecular superbubbles in PHANGS galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantifying_the_energetics_of_molecular_superbubbles_in_phangs_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantifying_the_energetics_of_molecular_superbubbles_in_phangs_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. J. Watkins
Star formation and stellar feedback are interlinked processes that redistribute energy and matter throughout galaxies. When young, massive stars form in spatially clustered environments, they create pockets of expanding gas termed superbubbles. As these processes play a critical role in shaping galaxy discs and regulating the baryon cycle, measuring the properties of superbubbles provides important input for galaxy evolution models. With wide coverage and high angular resolution ($\sim$50-150 pc) of the PHANGS-ALMA $^{12}$CO (2-1) survey, we can now resolve and identify a statistically representative number of superbubbles with molecular gas in nearby galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fragility of thin discs in galaxies -- I. Building tailored N-body galaxy models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fragility_of_thin_discs_in_galaxies_--_i._building_tailored_n-body_galaxy_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fragility_of_thin_discs_in_galaxies_--_i._building_tailored_n-body_galaxy_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pablo M. Galán-de Anta
Thin stellar discs on both galactic and nuclear, sub-kpc scales are believed to be fragile structures that would be easily destroyed in major mergers. In turn, this makes the age-dating of their stellar populations a useful diagnostics for the assembly history of galaxies. We aim at carefully exploring the fragility of such stellar discs in intermediate- and low- mass encounters, using high-resolution N-body simulations of galaxy models with structural and kinematic properties tailored to actually observed galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLA Legacy Survey of Molecular Gas in Massive Star-forming Galaxies at High Redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vla_legacy_survey_of_molecular_gas_in_massive_star-forming_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vla_legacy_survey_of_molecular_gas_in_massive_star-forming_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marta Frias Castillo
We present initial results of an ongoing survey with the Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array targeting the CO($J$ = 1-0) transition in a sample of 30 submillimeter-selected, dusty star-forming galaxies at $z =$ 2-5 with existing mid&amp;ndash;$J$ CO detections from ALMA and NOEMA, of which 17 have been fully observed. We detect CO(1-0) emission in 11 targets, along with three tentative ($\sim$1.5-2$\sigma$) detections; three galaxies are undetected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A complex dust morphology in the high-luminosity AGN Mrk 876</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_complex_dust_morphology_in_the_high-luminosity_agn_mrk_876/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_complex_dust_morphology_in_the_high-luminosity_agn_mrk_876/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hermine Landt
Recent models for the inner structure of active galactic nuclei (AGN) advocate the presence of a radiatively accelerated, dusty outflow launched from the outer regions of the accretion disk. Here we present the first near-infrared (near-IR) variable (rms) spectrum for the high-luminosity, nearby AGN Mrk 876. We find that it tracks the accretion disk spectrum out to longer wavelengths than the mean spectrum due to a reduced dust emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on compensated isocurvature perturbations from BOSS DR12 galaxy data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_compensated_isocurvature_perturbations_from_boss_dr12_galaxy_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_compensated_isocurvature_perturbations_from_boss_dr12_galaxy_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexandre Barreira
We use the BOSS DR12 galaxy power spectrum to constrain compensated isocurvature perturbations (CIP), which are opposite-sign primordial baryon and dark matter perturbations that leave the total matter density unchanged. Long-wavelength CIP $\sigma(\vec{x})$ enter the galaxy density contrast as $\delta_g(\vec{x}) \supset b_\sigma\sigma(\vec{x})$, with $b_\sigma$ the linear CIP galaxy bias parameter. We parameterize the CIP spectra as $P_{\sigma\sigma} = A^2P_{\mathcal{R}\mathcal{R}}$ and $P_{\sigma\mathcal{R}} = \xi\sqrt{P_{\sigma\sigma}P_{\mathcal{R}\mathcal{R}}}$, where $A$ is the CIP amplitude and $\xi$ is the correlation with the curvature perturbations $\mathcal{R}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fermi-LAT Gamma-ray Emission Discovered from the Composite Supernova Remnant B0453-685 in the Large Magellanic Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fermi-lat_gamma-ray_emission_discovered_from_the_composite_supernova_remnant_b0453-685_in_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fermi-lat_gamma-ray_emission_discovered_from_the_composite_supernova_remnant_b0453-685_in_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jordan Eagle
We report the second extragalactic pulsar wind nebula (PWN) to be detected in the MeV-GeV band by the Fermi-LAT, located within the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC). The only other known PWN to emit in the Fermi band outside of the Milky Way Galaxy is N 157B which lies to the west of the newly detected gamma-ray emission at an angular distance of 4 degrees. Faint, point-like gamma-ray emission is discovered at the location of the composite supernova remnant (SNR) B0453-685 with a ~ 4 sigma significance from energies 300 MeV - 2 TeV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A low frequency sub-arcsecond view of powerful radio galaxies in rich-cluster environments: 3C 34 and 3C 320</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_low_frequency_sub-arcsecond_view_of_powerful_radio_galaxies_in_rich-cluster_environments_3c_34_and_3c_320/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_low_frequency_sub-arcsecond_view_of_powerful_radio_galaxies_in_rich-cluster_environments_3c_34_and_3c_320/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. H. Mahatma
Models of radio galaxy physics have been primarily based on high frequency ($\geqslant$1 GHz) observations of their jets, hotspots, and lobes. Without highly resolved low frequency observations, which provide information on older plasma, our understanding of the dynamics of radio galaxies and their interaction with their environment is limited. Here, we present the first sub-arcsecond (0.3&amp;quot;) resolution images at 144 MHz of two powerful radio galaxies situated in rich cluster environments, namely 3C 34 and 3C 320, using the International Low Frequency Array Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do current cosmological observations hint at the speed of light variability?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/do_current_cosmological_observations_hint_at_the_speed_of_light_variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/do_current_cosmological_observations_hint_at_the_speed_of_light_variability/</guid>
      <description>First author: Purba Mukherjee
The fundamental constants in Nature play a crucial role in the understanding of physical phenomena. Hence, it is of paramount importance to measure them with exquisite precision and to examine whether they present any variability across cosmic time, as a means to test the standard model of Cosmology, as well as fundamental physics. We revisit a consistency test of the speed of light variability proposed by Cai {\it et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does a radio jet drive the massive multi-phase outflow in the ultra-luminous infrared galaxy IRAS 10565&#43;2448?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_a_radio_jet_drive_the_massive_multi-phase_outflow_in_the_ultra-luminous_infrared_galaxy_iras_10565&#43;2448/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_a_radio_jet_drive_the_massive_multi-phase_outflow_in_the_ultra-luminous_infrared_galaxy_iras_10565&#43;2448/</guid>
      <description>First author: Renzhi Su
We present new upgraded Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope (uGMRT) HI 21-cm observations of the ultra-luminous infrared galaxy IRAS 10565+2448, previously reported to show blueshifted, broad, and shallow HI absorption indicating an outflow. Our higher spatial resolution observations have localised this blueshifted outflow, which is $\sim$ 1.36 kpc southwest of the radio centre and has a blueshifted velocity of $\sim 148,\rm km,s^{-1}$ and a full width at half maximum (FWHM) of $\sim 581,\rm km,s^{-1}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for suppression of structure growth in the concordance cosmological model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_suppression_of_structure_growth_in_the_concordance_cosmological_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_suppression_of_structure_growth_in_the_concordance_cosmological_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nhat-Minh Nguyen
We present evidence for a suppressed growth rate of large-scale structure during the dark-energy dominated era. Modeling the growth rate of perturbations with the ``growth index&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; $\gamma$, we find that current cosmological data strongly prefer a higher growth index than the value $\gamma=0.55$ predicted by general relativity in a flat $\Lambda$CDM cosmology. Both the cosmic microwave background data from Planck and the large-scale structure data from weak lensing, galaxy clustering, and cosmic velocities separately favor growth suppression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Nonthermal X-ray Emission in the Ophiuchus Galaxy Cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_nonthermal_x-ray_emission_in_the_ophiuchus_galaxy_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_nonthermal_x-ray_emission_in_the_ophiuchus_galaxy_cluster/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roman Krivonos
We present the results of our study of the X-ray emission from the Ophiuchus galaxy cluster based on INTEGRAL/IBIS data in the energy range 20-120 keV. Our goal is the search for a nonthermal emission component from the cluster. Using the INTEGRAL data over the period of observations 2003-2009, we have constructed the images of the Ophiuchus galaxy cluster in different energy bands from 20 to 120~keV with the extraction of spectral information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Density Parity Model for the Evolution of the Galaxy Inner Spin Alignments with the Cosmic Web</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_density_parity_model_for_the_evolution_of_the_galaxy_inner_spin_alignments_with_the_cosmic_web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_density_parity_model_for_the_evolution_of_the_galaxy_inner_spin_alignments_with_the_cosmic_web/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jun-Sung Moon
We develop a new model within which the radius-dependent transition of the galaxy inner spins with respect to the cosmic web and the variation of the transition threshold radius ($r_{\rm th}$) with galaxy mass ($M_{\rm vir}$), smoothing scale ($r_{f}$), and redshift ($z$) can be coherently explained. The key tenet of this model is that the competition between the pressure effect of the inner mass and the compression effect of the local tidal field determines which principal direction of the tidal field the inner spins are aligned with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The miniJPAS survey: AGN &amp; host galaxy co-evolution of X-ray selected sources</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_minijpas_survey_agn__host_galaxy_co-evolution_of_x-ray_selected_sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_minijpas_survey_agn__host_galaxy_co-evolution_of_x-ray_selected_sources/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. E. López
Studies indicate strong evidence of a scaling relation in the local Universe between the supermassive black hole mass ($M_\rm{BH}$) and the stellar mass of their host galaxies ($M_\star$). They even show similar histories across cosmic times of their differential terms: star formation rate (SFR) and black hole accretion rate (BHAR). However, a clear picture of this coevolution is far from being understood. We select an X-ray sample of active galactic nuclei (AGN) up to $z=2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Non-Axisymmetric Influence: Radius and Angle-Dependent Trends in a Barred Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_non-axisymmetric_influence_radius_and_angle-dependent_trends_in_a_barred_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_non-axisymmetric_influence_radius_and_angle-dependent_trends_in_a_barred_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carrie Filion
Many disc galaxies host galactic bars, which exert time-dependent, non-axisymmetric forces that can alter the orbits of stars. There should be both angle and radius-dependence in the resulting radial re-arrangement of stars (&amp;lsquo;radial mixing&amp;rsquo;) due to a bar; we present here novel results and trends through analysis of the joint impact of these factors. We use an N-body simulation to investigate the changes in the radial locations of star particles in a disc after a bar forms by quantifying the change in orbital radii in a series of annuli at different times post bar-formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topological data analysis reveals differences between simulated galaxies and dark matter haloes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/topological_data_analysis_reveals_differences_between_simulated_galaxies_and_dark_matter_haloes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/topological_data_analysis_reveals_differences_between_simulated_galaxies_and_dark_matter_haloes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aaron Ouellette
We use topological summaries based on Betti curves to characterize the large-scale spatial distribution of simulated dark matter haloes and galaxies. Using the IllustrisTNG and CAMELS-SAM simulations, we show that the topology of the galaxy distribution is significantly different from the topology of the dark matter halo distribution. Further, there are significant differences between the distributions of star-forming and quiescent galaxies. These topological differences are broadly consistent across all simulations, while at the same time there are noticeable differences when comparing between different models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-population Bayesian hierarchical model of type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/two-population_bayesian_hierarchical_model_of_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/two-population_bayesian_hierarchical_model_of_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Radosław Wojtak
The currently used standardisation of type Ia supernovae results in Hubble residuals whose physical origin is unaccounted for. This poses a limitation to the accuracy and precision of distances that can be derived from supernova observations. Here, we present a complete physical interpretation of the Hubble residuals based on a novel Bayesian hierarchical model of type Ia supernovae in which latent variables describing intrinsic and extrinsic (dust related) supernova properties originate from two populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing the host galaxy ages of X-ray selected AGN in COSMOS: Obscured AGN are associated with older galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comparing_the_host_galaxy_ages_of_x-ray_selected_agn_in_cosmos_obscured_agn_are_associated_with_older_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comparing_the_host_galaxy_ages_of_x-ray_selected_agn_in_cosmos_obscured_agn_are_associated_with_older_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. Georgantopoulos
We explore the properties of the host galaxies of X-ray selected AGN in the COSMOS field using the Chandra Legacy sample and the LEGA-C survey VLT optical spectra. Our main goal is to compare the relative ages of the host galaxies of the obscured and unobscured AGN by means of the calcium break Dn(4000) and the Hdelta Balmer line. The host galaxy ages are examined in conjunction with other properties such as the galaxy stellar mass, and star-formation rate as well as the AGN Eddington ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf Galaxies United by Dark Bosons</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxies_united_by_dark_bosons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxies_united_by_dark_bosons/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alvaro Pozo
Low mass galaxies in the Local Group are dominated by dark matter and comprise the well studied dwarf Spheroidal&amp;quot; (dSph) class, with typical masses of $10^{9-10}M_\odot$ and also the equally numerous ultra faint dwarfs&amp;quot; (UFD), discovered recently, that are distinctly smaller and denser with masses of only $10^{7-8}M_\odot$. This bimodality amongst low mass galaxies contrasts with the scale free continuity expected for galaxies formed under gravity, as in the standard Cold Dark Matter (CDM) model for heavy particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid preparation. XXX. Evaluating the weak lensing cluster mass biases using the Three Hundred Project hydrodynamical simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxx._evaluating_the_weak_lensing_cluster_mass_biases_using_the_three_hundred_project_hydrodynamical_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxx._evaluating_the_weak_lensing_cluster_mass_biases_using_the_three_hundred_project_hydrodynamical_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Euclid Collaboration
The photometric catalogue of galaxy clusters extracted from ESA Euclid data is expected to be very competitive for cosmological studies. Using state-of-the-art hydrodynamical simulations, we present systematic analyses simulating the expected weak lensing profiles from clusters in a variety of dynamic states and at wide range of redshifts. In order to derive cluster masses, we use a model consistent with the implementation within the Euclid Consortium of the dedicated processing function and find that, when jointly modelling mass and the concentration parameter of the Navarro-Frenk-White halo profile, the weak lensing masses tend to be, on average, biased low with respect to the true mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term gravitational wave asteroseismology of supernova: from core collapse to 20 seconds postbounce</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_gravitational_wave_asteroseismology_of_supernova_from_core_collapse_to_20_seconds_postbounce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_gravitational_wave_asteroseismology_of_supernova_from_core_collapse_to_20_seconds_postbounce/</guid>
      <description>First author: Masamitsu Mori
We use an asteroseismology method to calculate the frequencies of gravitational waves in a long-term core-collapse supernova simulation, with a mass of 9.6 $M_\odot$. The simulation, which includes neutrino transport in general relativity is performed from core-collapse, bounce, explosion and cooling of protoneutron stars (PNSs) up to 20 s after the bounce self-consistently. Based on the hydrodynamics background, we calculate eigenmodes of the PNS oscillation through a perturbation analysis on fluid and metric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing sub-galactic mass structure with the power spectrum of surface-brightness anomalies in high-resolution observations of galaxy-galaxy strong gravitational lenses. I. Power-spectrum measurement and feasibility study</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_sub-galactic_mass_structure_with_the_power_spectrum_of_surface-brightness_anomalies_in_high-resolution_observations_of_galaxy-galaxy_strong_gravitational_lenses._i._power-spectrum_measurement_and_feasibility_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_sub-galactic_mass_structure_with_the_power_spectrum_of_surface-brightness_anomalies_in_high-resolution_observations_of_galaxy-galaxy_strong_gravitational_lenses._i._power-spectrum_measurement_and_feasibility_study/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Bayer
While the direct detection of the dark-matter particle remains very challenging, the nature of dark matter could be possibly constrained by comparing the observed abundance and properties of small-scale sub-galactic mass structures with predictions from the phenomenological dark-matter models, such as cold, warm or hot dark matter. Galaxy-galaxy strong gravitational lensing provides a unique opportunity to search for tiny surface-brightness anomalies in the extended lensed images (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-kiloparsec empirical relations and excitation conditions of HCN and HCO&#43; J=3-2 in nearby star-forming galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-kiloparsec_empirical_relations_and_excitation_conditions_of_hcn_and_hco&#43;_j3-2_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-kiloparsec_empirical_relations_and_excitation_conditions_of_hcn_and_hco&#43;_j3-2_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Axel Garcia-Rodriguez
We present new HCN and HCO$^+$ ($J$=3-2) images of the nearby star-forming galaxies (SFGs) NGC 3351, NGC 3627, and NGC 4321. The observations, obtained with the Morita ALMA Compact Array, have a spatial resolution of $\sim$290-440 pc and resolve the inner $R_\textrm{gal} \lesssim$ 0.6-1 kpc of the targets, as well as the southern bar end of NGC 3627. We complement this data set with publicly available images of lower excitation lines of HCN, HCO$^+$, and CO and analyse the behaviour of a representative set of line ratios: HCN(3-2)/HCN(1-0), HCN(3-2)/HCO$^+$(3-2), HCN(1-0)/CO(2-1), and HCN(3-2)/CO(2-1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cool circumgalactic medium of low-redshift star-forming galaxies: I -- Empirical model and mean properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cool_circumgalactic_medium_of_low-redshift_star-forming_galaxies_i_--_empirical_model_and_mean_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_cool_circumgalactic_medium_of_low-redshift_star-forming_galaxies_i_--_empirical_model_and_mean_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yakov Faerman
We present an analytic model for the cool, $T \approx 10^4$ K, circumgalactic medium (CGM), describing the gas distribution, thermal and ionization state. Our model assumes (total) pressure equilibrium with the ambient warm/hot CGM, photoionization by the metagalactic radiation field, and allows for non-thermal pressure support, parametrized by the ratio of thermal pressures, $\eta = P_{\rm hot,th}/P_{\rm cool,th}$. We apply the model to the COS-Halos data set and find that a nominal model with $\eta = 3$, gas distribution out to $r \approx 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
