<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>12(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/12month/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 12(month) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/12month/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ghost in the Shell: Evidence for Past AGN Activities in NGC 5195 from a Newly Discovered large-scale Ionized Structure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ghost_in_the_shell_evidence_for_past_agn_activities_in_ngc_5195_from_a_newly_discovered_large-scale_ionized_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ghost_in_the_shell_evidence_for_past_agn_activities_in_ngc_5195_from_a_newly_discovered_large-scale_ionized_structure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaoyu Xu
The early-type galaxy NGC 5195 (alternatively known as M51b) possesses extended gas features detected in multi-wavelength, postulated to be associated with previous activities of the central supermassive black hole (SMBH). Using integral field spectroscopic observations from the Canada-France-Hawaii Telescope (CFHT)/SITELLE, we report on the discovery of a new large-scale ionized gas structure traced by $[O III]$, $[N II]$, and H$\alpha$ line emission, extending to $\sim10\rm,kpc$ from the nucleus of NGC 5195.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing the First Galaxies&#39; Merger Trees</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growing_the_first_galaxies_merger_trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growing_the_first_galaxies_merger_trees/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ethan O. Nadler
Modeling the growth histories of specific galaxies often involves generating the entire population of objects that arise in a given cosmology and selecting systems with appropriate properties. This approach is highly inefficient when targeting rare systems such as the extremely luminous high-redshift galaxy candidates detected by JWST. Here, we present a novel framework for generating merger trees with branches that are guaranteed to achieve a desired halo mass at a chosen redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological Classification of Radio Galaxies with wGAN-supported Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphological_classification_of_radio_galaxies_with_wgan-supported_augmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphological_classification_of_radio_galaxies_with_wgan-supported_augmentation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lennart Rustige
Machine learning techniques that perform morphological classification of astronomical sources often suffer from a scarcity of labelled training data. Here, we focus on the case of supervised deep learning models for the morphological classification of radio galaxies, which is particularly topical for the forthcoming large radio surveys. We demonstrate the use of generative models, specifically Wasserstein GANs (wGANs), to generate data for different classes of radio galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Supernovae in HETDEX Data Release 3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_supernovae_in_hetdex_data_release_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_supernovae_in_hetdex_data_release_3/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Vinko
We have extracted 636 spectra taken at the positions of 583 transient sources from the third Data Release of the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy eXperiment (HETDEX). The transients were discovered by the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) during 2018 - 2022. The HETDEX spectra are useful to classify a large number of objects found by photometric surveys for free. We attempt to explore and classify the spectra by utilizing machine learning (ML) and template matching techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminating a common envelope jets supernova impostor event with a super-Eddington blue supergiant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/terminating_a_common_envelope_jets_supernova_impostor_event_with_a_super-eddington_blue_supergiant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/terminating_a_common_envelope_jets_supernova_impostor_event_with_a_super-eddington_blue_supergiant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tamar Cohen
We conducted one-dimensional stellar evolutionary numerical simulations to build blue supergiant stellar models with a very low-envelope mass and a super-Eddington luminosity of 10^7Lo that mimic the last phase of a common envelope evolution (CEE) where a neutron star (NS) accretes mass from the envelope and launches jets that power the system. Common envelope jets supernovae (CEJSNe) are CEE transient events where a NS spirals-in inside the envelope and then the core of a red supergiant (RSG) star accretes mass and launches jets that power the transient event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hot gas distribution, X-ray luminosity and baryon budget in the L-Galaxies semi-analytic model of galaxy formation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_hot_gas_distribution_x-ray_luminosity_and_baryon_budget_in_the_l-galaxies_semi-analytic_model_of_galaxy_formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_hot_gas_distribution_x-ray_luminosity_and_baryon_budget_in_the_l-galaxies_semi-analytic_model_of_galaxy_formation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wenxin Zhong
Hot ionized gas is important in the baryon cycle of galaxies and contributes the majority of their missing baryons&#39;&#39;. Until now, most semi-analytic models of galaxy formation have paid little attention to hot gaseous haloes and their X-ray emission. In this paper, we adopt the one-dimensional model from Sharma et al. instead of the isothermal sphere to describe the radial distribution of hot gas in the L-Galaxies semi-analytic model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the early stages of galaxy formation using very metal-poor stars from the Hamburg/ESO survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/understanding_the_early_stages_of_galaxy_formation_using_very_metal-poor_stars_from_the_hamburg_eso_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/understanding_the_early_stages_of_galaxy_formation_using_very_metal-poor_stars_from_the_hamburg_eso_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniela Carollo
We explore the chemo-dynamical properties of a sample of very metal-poor (VMP) stars selected from the Hamburg/ESO survey, matched with Gaia EDR3, in the phase-space identified by the three integrals of motion ($L_z$, $E$, $I_3$). Disk and halo orbits are separated by using the criteria defined in Carollo et al. (2021). We found 26 stars with $[Fe/H] \leq -2.5$ possessing disk kinematics, of which 14 are extremely metal-poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$[CII]$ halos in ALPINE galaxies: smoking-gun of galactic outflows?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cii_halos_in_alpine_galaxies_smoking-gun_of_galactic_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cii_halos_in_alpine_galaxies_smoking-gun_of_galactic_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Pizzati
ALMA observations have revealed that many high redshift galaxies are surrounded by extended (10-15 kpc) $[CII]$-emitting halos which are not predicted by even the most advanced zoom-in simulations. Using a semi-analytical model, in a previous work we suggested that such halos are produced by starburst-driven, catastrophically cooling outflows. Here, we further improve the model and compare its predictions with data from 7 star-forming ($10\lesssim \rm SFR/ M_\odot \rm yr^{-1}&amp;lt;100$) galaxies at z=4-6, observed in the ALPINE survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25,000 optical fiber positioning robots for next-generation cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/25000_optical_fiber_positioning_robots_for_next-generation_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/25000_optical_fiber_positioning_robots_for_next-generation_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph H. Silber
Massively parallel multi-object spectrographs are on the leading edge of cosmology instrumentation. The highly successful Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI) which begun survey operations in May 2021, for example, has 5,000 robotically-actuated multimode fibers, which deliver light from thousands of individual galaxies and quasars simultaneously to an array of high-resolution spectrographs off-telescope. The redshifts are individually measured, thus providing 3D maps of the Universe in unprecedented detail, and enabling precise measurement of dark energy expansion and other key cosmological parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First detection of the outer edge of an AGN accretion disc: Very fast multiband optical variability of NGC 4395 with GTC/HiPERCAM and LT/IO:O</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_detection_of_the_outer_edge_of_an_agn_accretion_disc_very_fast_multiband_optical_variability_of_ngc_4395_with_gtc_hipercam_and_lt_ioo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_detection_of_the_outer_edge_of_an_agn_accretion_disc_very_fast_multiband_optical_variability_of_ngc_4395_with_gtc_hipercam_and_lt_ioo/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. M. McHardy
We present fast (~200s sampling) ugriz photometry of the low mass AGN NGC 4395 with the Liverpool Telescope, followed by very fast (3s sampling) us, gs, rs, is and zs simultaneous monitoring with HiPERCAM on the 10.4m GTC. These observations provide the fastest ever AGN multiband photometry and very precise lag measurements. Unlike in all other AGN, gs lags us by a large amount, consistent with disc reprocessing but not with reprocessing in the Broad Line Region (BLR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-redshift cosmological probes of helium reionization at the cosmic (fore)noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-redshift_cosmological_probes_of_helium_reionization_at_the_cosmic_forenoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-redshift_cosmological_probes_of_helium_reionization_at_the_cosmic_forenoon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Selim C. Hotinli
Joint analysis of CMB and large-scale structure at high redshifts provide new and unique windows into unexplored epochs of early structure formation. Here, we demonstrate how cosmic infrared background and high-redshift galaxies can be jointly analysed with CMB to probe the epoch of helium reionization ($2&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4$) on the light cone using kinetic Sunyaev Zel&amp;rsquo;dovich tomography. Characterising this epoch has great potential significance for understanding astrophysics of galaxy formation, quasar activity and formation of the super-massive black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying AGN host galaxies with convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_agn_host_galaxies_with_convolutional_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_agn_host_galaxies_with_convolutional_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ziting Guo
Active galactic nuclei (AGN) are supermassive black holes with luminous accretion disks found in some galaxies, and are thought to play an important role in galaxy evolution. However, traditional optical spectroscopy for identifying AGN requires time-intensive observations. We train a convolutional neural network (CNN) to distinguish AGN host galaxies from non-active galaxies using a sample of 210,000 Sloan Digital Sky Survey galaxies. We evaluate the CNN on 33,000 galaxies that are spectrally classified as composites, and find correlations between galaxy appearances and their CNN classifications, which hint at evolutionary processes that affect both galaxy morphology and AGN activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking the dust and chemical evolution: Taurus and Perseus -- New collisional rates for HCN, HNC, and their C, N, and H isotopologues</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/linking_the_dust_and_chemical_evolution_taurus_and_perseus_--_new_collisional_rates_for_hcn_hnc_and_their_c_n_and_h_isotopologues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/linking_the_dust_and_chemical_evolution_taurus_and_perseus_--_new_collisional_rates_for_hcn_hnc_and_their_c_n_and_h_isotopologues/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Navarro-Almaida
HCN, HNC, and their isotopologues are ubiquitous molecules that can serve as chemical thermometers and evolutionary tracers to characterize star-forming regions. Despite their importance in carrying information that is vital to studies of the chemistry and evolution of star-forming regions, the collision rates of some of these molecules have not been available for rigorous studies in the past. We perform an up-to-date gas and dust chemical characterization of two different star-forming regions, TMC 1-C and NGC 1333-C7, using new collisional rates of HCN, HNC, and their isotopologues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the gamma-ray emission from the core of the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_gamma-ray_emission_from_the_core_of_the_sagittarius_dwarf_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_gamma-ray_emission_from_the_core_of_the_sagittarius_dwarf_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Addy J. Evans
We use data from the Large Area Telescope onboard the Fermi gamma-ray space telescope (Fermi-LAT) to analyze the faint gamma-ray source located at the center of the Sagittarius (Sgr) dwarf spheroidal galaxy. In the 4FGL-DR3 catalog, this source is associated with the globular cluster, M54, which is coincident with the dynamical center of this dwarf galaxy. We investigate the spectral energy distribution and spatial extension of this source, with the goal of testing two hypotheses: (1) the emission is due to millisecond pulsars within M54, or (2) the emission is due to annihilating dark matter from the Sgr halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical polarization and spectral properties of the H-poor superluminous supernovae SN 2021bnw and SN 2021fpl</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_polarization_and_spectral_properties_of_the_h-poor_superluminous_supernovae_sn_2021bnw_and_sn_2021fpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_polarization_and_spectral_properties_of_the_h-poor_superluminous_supernovae_sn_2021bnw_and_sn_2021fpl/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Poidevin
New optical photometric, spectrocopic and imaging polarimetry data are combined with publicly available data to study some of the physical properties of the two H-poor superluminous supernovae (SLSN) SN 2021bnw and SN 2021fpl. For each SLSN, the best-fit parameters obtained from the magnetar model with \texttt{MOSFiT} do not depart from the range of parameter obtained on other SLSNe discussed in the literature. A spectral analysis with \texttt{SYN++} shows that SN 2021bnw is a W Type, Fast evolver, while SN 2021fpl is a 15bn Type, Slow evolver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Cosmological Principle with CatWISE Quasars: A Bayesian Analysis of the Number-Count Dipole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_cosmological_principle_with_catwise_quasars_a_bayesian_analysis_of_the_number-count_dipole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_the_cosmological_principle_with_catwise_quasars_a_bayesian_analysis_of_the_number-count_dipole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lawrence Dam
The Cosmological Principle, that the Universe is homogeneous and isotropic on sufficiently large scales, underpins the standard model of cosmology. However, a recent analysis of 1.36 million infrared-selected quasars has identified a significant tension in the amplitude of the number-count dipole compared to that derived from the CMB, thus challenging the Cosmological Principle. Here we present a Bayesian analysis of the same quasar sample, testing various hypotheses using the Bayesian evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A jolt to the system: ram pressure on low-mass galaxies in simulations of the Local Group</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jolt_to_the_system_ram_pressure_on_low-mass_galaxies_in_simulations_of_the_local_group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jolt_to_the_system_ram_pressure_on_low-mass_galaxies_in_simulations_of_the_local_group/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jenna Samuel
Low-mass galaxies are highly susceptible to environmental effects that can efficiently quench star formation. We explore the role of ram pressure in quenching low-mass galaxies ($M_{}\sim10^{5-9},\rm{M}{\odot}$) within 2 Mpc of Milky Way (MW) hosts using the FIRE-2 simulations. Ram pressure is highly variable across different environments, within individual MW haloes, and for individual low-mass galaxies over time. The impulsiveness of ram pressure &amp;ndash; the maximum ram pressure scaled to the integrated ram pressure prior to quenching &amp;ndash; correlates with whether a galaxy is quiescent or star-forming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiwavelength study of the ongoing Changing-look AGN AT2021fxu</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multiwavelength_study_of_the_ongoing_changing-look_agn_at2021fxu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_multiwavelength_study_of_the_ongoing_changing-look_agn_at2021fxu/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yukta Ajay
We present multiwavelength analyses of an active optical transient AT2021fxu which shows the appearance of previously absent broad emission lines in a recent optical spectrum, suggesting a Changing-look (CL) Active Galactic Nucleus (AGN). During the spectral transition, the brightness in the individual photometric bands increased up to $\approx$0.6 in the optical bands and up to $\approx$1.1 magnitudes in the UV bands. The brightening was accompanied by a blueward shift of the optical spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Classification of Galaxy Morphology: a rotationally invariant supervised machine learning method based on the UML-dataset</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/automatic_classification_of_galaxy_morphology_a_rotationally_invariant_supervised_machine_learning_method_based_on_the_uml-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/automatic_classification_of_galaxy_morphology_a_rotationally_invariant_supervised_machine_learning_method_based_on_the_uml-dataset/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. W. Fang
Classification of galaxy morphology is a challenging but meaningful task for the enormous amount of data produced by the next-generation telescope. By introducing the adaptive polar coordinate transformation, we develop a rotationally invariant supervised machine learning (SML) method that ensures consistent classifications when rotating galaxy images, which is always required to be satisfied physically but difficult to achieve algorithmically. The adaptive polar coordinate transformation, compared with the conventional method of data augmentation by including additional rotated images in the training set, is proved to be an effective and efficient method in improving the robustness of the SML methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics and Equation of State Dependencies of Relevance for Nucleosynthesis in Supernovae and Neutron Star Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_and_equation_of_state_dependencies_of_relevance_for_nucleosynthesis_in_supernovae_and_neutron_star_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_and_equation_of_state_dependencies_of_relevance_for_nucleosynthesis_in_supernovae_and_neutron_star_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. -Thomas Janka
Neutron stars (NSs) and black holes (BHs) are born when the final collapse of the stellar core terminates the lives of stars more massive than about 9 Msun. This can trigger the powerful ejection of a large fraction of the star&amp;rsquo;s material in a core-collapse supernova (CCSN), whose extreme luminosity is energized by the decay of radioactive isotopes such as 56Ni and 56Co. When evolving in close binary systems, the compact relics of such infernal catastrophes spiral towards each other on orbits gradually decaying by gravitational-wave emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Outflowing Warm Absorbers in Narrow-Line Seyfert 1 Galaxy PG 1001&#43;054 Revealed by HST/COS Spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_outflowing_warm_absorbers_in_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_pg_1001&#43;054_revealed_by_hst_cos_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_outflowing_warm_absorbers_in_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_pg_1001&#43;054_revealed_by_hst_cos_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiao-Dan Fu
Narrow-Line Seyfert 1 (NLS1) Galaxies are an important type of active galactic nucleus (AGN), generally expected to be accreting at high Eddington rate. The properties of their outflows and importance of AGN feedback remain intriguing. We report on the discovery of fast outflowing warm absorbers (WAs) in the NLS1 PG 1001+054, with velocities in the range of 7000 to 9000 kilometers per second. They are identified with blueshifted Lyman alpha, N v and Si iv lines in the high resolution ultraviolet (UV) spectra taken with the Cosmic Origins Spectrograph (COS) onboard the Hubble Space Telescope (HST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming Blue Compact Dwarf Galaxy (BCD) through Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forming_blue_compact_dwarf_galaxy_bcd_through_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forming_blue_compact_dwarf_galaxy_bcd_through_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daya Nidhi Chhatkuli
It has long been speculated that Blue Compact Dwarf galaxies (BCDs) are formed through the interaction between low-mass gas-rich galaxies, but a few candidates of such systems have been studied in detail. We study a sample of compact star-forming dwarf galaxies that are selected from a merging dwarf galaxy catalog. We present a detailed study of their spectroscopic and structural properties. We find that these BCDs looking galaxies host extended stellar shells and thus are confirmed to be a dwarf-dwarf merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraction of Stars in Clusters for the LEGUS Dwarf Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fraction_of_stars_in_clusters_for_the_legus_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fraction_of_stars_in_clusters_for_the_legus_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. O. Cook
We study the young star cluster populations in 23 dwarf and irregular galaxies observed by the HST Legacy ExtraGalactic Ultraviolet Survey (LEGUS), and examine relationships between the ensemble properties of the cluster populations and those of their host galaxies: star formation rate (SFR) density ($\Sigma_{\rm SFR}$). A strength of this analysis is the availability of SFRs measured from temporally resolved star formation histories which provide the means to match cluster and host-galaxy properties on several timescales (1-10, 1-100, and 10-100~Myr).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical Simulations of Circumbinary Accretion: Balance between Heating and Cooling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_of_circumbinary_accretion_balance_between_heating_and_cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_of_circumbinary_accretion_balance_between_heating_and_cooling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hai-Yang Wang
Hydrodynamical interaction in circumbinary discs (CBDs) plays a crucial role in various astrophysical systems, ranging from young stellar binaries to supermassive black hole binaries in galactic centers. Most previous simulations of binary-disc systems have adopted locally isothermal equation of state. In this study, we use the grid-based code $\texttt{Athena++}$ to conduct a suite of two-dimensional viscous hydrodynamical simulations of circumbinary accretion on a cartesian grid, resolving the central cavity of the binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting galaxies in the IllustrisTNG simulations -- IV: Enhanced Supermassive Black Hole Accretion Rates in Post-Merger Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interacting_galaxies_in_the_illustristng_simulations_--_iv_enhanced_supermassive_black_hole_accretion_rates_in_post-merger_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interacting_galaxies_in_the_illustristng_simulations_--_iv_enhanced_supermassive_black_hole_accretion_rates_in_post-merger_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shoshannah Byrne-Mamahit
We present an analysis of the instantaneous supermassive black hole (SMBH) accretion rates in a collection of 1563 post-merger galaxies drawn from the IllustrisTNG simulation. Our sample consists of galaxies that have experienced a merger in the last simulation snapshot (within ~160 Myrs of coalescence) in the redshift range 0&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;1, with merger stellar mass ratios &amp;gt;1:10 and post-merger stellar masses &amp;gt; $10^{10} M_{\odot}$. We find that, on average, the accretion rates of the post-mergers are ~1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST catches the assembly of a $z\sim5$ ultra-low-mass galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_catches_the_assembly_of_a__z_sim5__ultra-low-mass_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_catches_the_assembly_of_a__z_sim5__ultra-low-mass_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yoshihisa Asada
Using CANUCS imaging we found an apparent major merger of two $z\sim5$ ultra-low-mass galaxies ($M_\star\sim10^{7}M_\odot$ each) that are doubly imaged and magnified $\sim$12-15$\times$ by the lensing cluster MACS 0417. Both galaxies are experiencing young ($\sim$100 Myr), synchronised bursts of star formation with $\log({\rm sSFR/Gyr^{-1}} )\sim$1.3-1.4, yet SFRs of just $\sim 0.2 M_\odot\ {\rm yr}^{-1}$. They have sub-solar ($Z\sim0.2Z_\odot$) gas-phase metallicities and are connected by an even more metal-poor star-forming bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating the impact of the CIB on galaxy cluster SZ detection with spectrally constrained matched filters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mitigating_the_impact_of_the_cib_on_galaxy_cluster_sz_detection_with_spectrally_constrained_matched_filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mitigating_the_impact_of_the_cib_on_galaxy_cluster_sz_detection_with_spectrally_constrained_matched_filters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Íñigo Zubeldia
Galaxy clusters detected through the thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich (tSZ) effect are a powerful cosmological probe from which constraints on cosmological parameters such as $\Omega_{\mathrm{m}}$ and $\sigma_8$ can be derived. The measured cluster tSZ signal can be, however, contaminated by Cosmic Infrared Background (CIB) emission, as the CIB is spatially correlated with the cluster tSZ field. We quantify the extent of this contamination by applying the iterative multi-frequency matched filter (iMMF) cluster-finding method to mock Planck-like data from the Websky simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Tunneling of Ultralight Dark Matter Out of Satellite Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantum_tunneling_of_ultralight_dark_matter_out_of_satellite_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantum_tunneling_of_ultralight_dark_matter_out_of_satellite_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mark P. Hertzberg
The idea of ultralight scalar (axion) dark matter is theoretically appealing and may resolve some small-scale problems of cold dark matter; so it deserves careful attention. In this work we carefully analyze tunneling of the scalar field in dwarf satellites due to the tidal gravitational force from the host halo. The tidal force is far from spherically symmetric; causing tunneling along the axis from the halo center to the dwarf, while confining in the orthogonal plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of star forming main sequence galaxies in Milgromian gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_star_forming_main_sequence_galaxies_in_milgromian_gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_star_forming_main_sequence_galaxies_in_milgromian_gravity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Srikanth T. Nagesh
We conduct hydrodynamical MOND simulations of isolated disc galaxies over the stellar mass range $M_{\star}/M_\odot = 10^7 - 10^{11}$ using the adaptive mesh refinement code \textsc{phantom of ramses} (\textsc{por}), an adaptation of the \textsc{ramses} code with a Milgromian gravity solver. The scale lengths and gas fractions are based on observed galaxies, and the simulations are run for 5~Gyr. The main aim is to see whether existing sub-grid physics prescriptions for star formation and stellar feedback reproduce the observed main sequence and reasonably match the Kennicutt-Schmidt relation that captures how the local and global star formation rates relate to other properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The accretion history of the Milky Way. I. How it shapes globular clusters and dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_accretion_history_of_the_milky_way._i._how_it_shapes_globular_clusters_and_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_accretion_history_of_the_milky_way._i._how_it_shapes_globular_clusters_and_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Francois Hammer
Halo inhabitants are individual stars, stellar streams, star and globular clusters, and dwarf galaxies. Here we compare the two last categories that include objects of similar stellar mass, which are often studied as self-dynamical equilibrium systems. We discover that the half-light radius of globular clusters depends on their orbital pericenter and total energy, and that Milky Way (MW) tides may explain the observed correlation. We also suggest that the accretion epoch of stellar systems in the MW halo can be calibrated by the total orbital energy, and that such a relation is due to both the mass growth of the MW and dynamical friction affecting mostly satellites with numerous orbits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The outburst of the changing-look AGN IRAS23226-3843 in 2019</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_outburst_of_the_changing-look_agn_iras23226-3843_in_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_outburst_of_the_changing-look_agn_iras23226-3843_in_2019/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wolfram Kollatschny
IRAS23226-3843 has previously been classified as a changing-look AGN based on X-ray and optical spectral variations. In 2019, Swift observations revealed a strong rebrightening in X-ray and UV fluxes in comparison to observations in 2017. We took follow-up Swift, XMM-Newton, and NuSTAR observations together with optical spectra (SALT and SAAO 1.9m telescope) from 2019 until 2021. IRAS23226-3843 showed a strong X-ray and optical outburst in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voids fill us in on rising cosmology tensions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/voids_fill_us_in_on_rising_cosmology_tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/voids_fill_us_in_on_rising_cosmology_tensions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sofia Contarini
We investigate the main tensions within the current standard model of cosmology from the perspective of the void size function in BOSS DR12 data. For this purpose, we present the first cosmological constraints on the parameters $S_8\equiv \sigma_8\sqrt{\Omega_{\rm m}/0.3}$ and $H_0$ obtained from voids as a stand-alone probe. We rely on an extension of the popular volume-conserving model for the void size function, tailored to the application on data, including geometric and dynamic distortions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A High Density of Bright Galaxies at $z\approx10$ in the A2744 region</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_high_density_of_bright_galaxies_at__z_approx10__in_the_a2744_region/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_high_density_of_bright_galaxies_at__z_approx10__in_the_a2744_region/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marco Castellano
We report the detection of a high density of redshift $z\approx 10$ galaxies behind the foreground cluster Abell 2744, selected from imaging data obtained recently with NIRCam onboard JWST by three programs &amp;ndash; GLASS-JWST, UNCOVER, and DDT-2756. To ensure robust estimates of the lensing magnification $\mu$, we use an improved version of our model that exploits the first epoch of NIRCam images and newly obtained MUSE spectra, and avoids regions with $\mu&amp;gt;5$ where the uncertainty may be higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Preferential Growth Channel for Supermassive Black Holes in Elliptical Galaxies at z&lt;2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_preferential_growth_channel_for_supermassive_black_holes_in_elliptical_galaxies_at_z2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_preferential_growth_channel_for_supermassive_black_holes_in_elliptical_galaxies_at_z2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Duncan Farrah
The assembly of stellar and supermassive black hole (SMBH) mass in elliptical galaxies since $z\sim1$ can help to diagnose the origins of locally-observed correlations between SMBH mass and stellar mass. We therefore construct three samples of elliptical galaxies, one at $z\sim0$ and two at $0.7\lesssim z \lesssim2.5$, and quantify their relative positions in the $M_{BH}-M_*$ plane. Using a Bayesian analysis framework, we find evidence for translational offsets in both stellar mass and SMBH mass between the local sample and both higher redshift samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Concentration of Asymmetric Features in Post-starburst Galaxies at $z \sim 0.8$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/central_concentration_of_asymmetric_features_in_post-starburst_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.8_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/central_concentration_of_asymmetric_features_in_post-starburst_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.8_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kazuharu G. Himoto
We present morphological analyses of Post-starburst galaxies (PSBs) at $0.7&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;0.9$ in the COSMOS field. We fitted ultraviolet to mid-infrared multi-band photometry of objects with $i&amp;lt;24$ from COSMOS2020 catalogue with population synthesis models assuming non-parametric, piece-wise constant function of star formation history, and selected 94 those galaxies that have high specific star formation rates (SSFRs) of more than $10^{-9.5}$ yr$^{-1}$ in 321&amp;ndash;1000 Myr before observation and an order of magnitude lower SSFRs within recent 321 Myr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL-LAMPS IV: A Sample of Bright Strongly-Lensed Galaxies at $3 &lt; z &lt; 4$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cool-lamps_iv_a_sample_of_bright_strongly-lensed_galaxies_at__3__z__4_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cool-lamps_iv_a_sample_of_bright_strongly-lensed_galaxies_at__3__z__4_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yunchong Zhang
We report the discovery of five bright strong gravitationally-lensed galaxies at $3 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 4$: COOL J0101$+$2055 ($z = 3.459$), COOL J0104$-$0757 ($z = 3.480$), COOL J0145$+$1018 ($z = 3.310$), COOL J0516$-$2208 ($z = 3.549$), and COOL J1356$+$0339 ($z = 3.753$). These galaxies have magnitudes of $r_{\rm AB}, z_{\rm AB} &amp;lt; 21.81$ mag and are lensed by galaxy clusters at $0.26 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 1$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology with cosmic web environments II. Redshift-space auto and cross power spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_with_cosmic_web_environments_ii._redshift-space_auto_and_cross_power_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmology_with_cosmic_web_environments_ii._redshift-space_auto_and_cross_power_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tony Bonnaire
Degeneracies among parameters of the cosmological model are known to drastically limit the information contained in the matter distribution. In the first paper of this series, we shown that the cosmic web environments; namely the voids, walls, filaments and nodes; can be used as a leverage to improve the real-space constraints on a set of six cosmological parameters, including the summed neutrino mass. Following-upon these results, we propose to study the achievable constraints of environment-dependent power spectra in redshift space where the velocities add up information to the standard two-point statistics by breaking the isotropy of the matter density field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy populations in the most distant SPT-SZ clusters -- II. Galaxy structural properties in massive clusters at 1.4&lt;z&lt;1.7</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_populations_in_the_most_distant_spt-sz_clusters_--_ii._galaxy_structural_properties_in_massive_clusters_at_1.4z1.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_populations_in_the_most_distant_spt-sz_clusters_--_ii._galaxy_structural_properties_in_massive_clusters_at_1.4z1.7/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. Strazzullo
We investigate structural properties of massive galaxy populations in the central regions of five very massive galaxy clusters at z~1.4-1.7 from the South Pole Telescope Sunyaev Zel&amp;rsquo;dovich effect survey. We probe the connection between galaxy structure and broad stellar population properties, at stellar masses log(M/Msun)&amp;gt;10.85. We find that quiescent and star-forming cluster galaxy populations are largely dominated by bulge- and disk-dominated sources, respectively, with relative contributions consistent with those of field counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guess the cheese flavour by the size of its holes: A cosmological test using the abundance of Popcorn voids</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/guess_the_cheese_flavour_by_the_size_of_its_holes_a_cosmological_test_using_the_abundance_of_popcorn_voids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/guess_the_cheese_flavour_by_the_size_of_its_holes_a_cosmological_test_using_the_abundance_of_popcorn_voids/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dante J. Paz
We present a new definition of cosmic void and a publicly available code with the algorithm that implements it. In this void finder, underdense regions are defined as free-form objects, called popcorn voids, made from the union of spheres of maximum volume with a given joint integrated underdensity contrast. This provides, for the first time, a definition of a void in the matter field whose abundance can be faithfully reproduced by excursion set theory, in particular using the Vdn model without any adjustment or cleaning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HI absorption associated with Norma&#39;s brightest cluster galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hi_absorption_associated_with_normas_brightest_cluster_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hi_absorption_associated_with_normas_brightest_cluster_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Manasvee Saraf
ESO 137-G006 is the brightest cluster galaxy (BCG) of the cool-core and dynamically young Norma cluster. We discover an atomic hydrogen (HI) absorption line associated with this BCG using the Australia Telescope Compact Array. We estimate a gas column density of $ \approx (1.3 \pm 0.2) \times 10^{20},T_{\rm{spin}}$ atoms cm$^{-2}$ with spin temperature, $T_{\rm{spin}} \leq 194$ K, consistent with the HI properties of other early-type galaxies and cool-core cluster BCGs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-situ star formation in accretion disk and explanation for correlation between black hole mass and metallicity in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/in-situ_star_formation_in_accretion_disk_and_explanation_for_correlation_between_black_hole_mass_and_metallicity_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/in-situ_star_formation_in_accretion_disk_and_explanation_for_correlation_between_black_hole_mass_and_metallicity_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiao Fan
Recent observations show that the metallicity of the broad line region ($Z_{\rm BLR}$) in active galactic nuclei (AGNs) is solar-to-supersolar, which is positively correlated with the mass of supermassive black holes ($M_{\rm BH}$) and does not evolve with redshift up to $z \sim 7$. We revisit the $M_{\rm BH}-Z_{\rm BLR}$ correlation with more AGNs with $M_{\rm BH}\sim 10^{6-8} M_{\odot}$ and find that the positive correlation become flat in low-mass range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the effect of Milky Way dwarf spheroidal galaxies extension on dark matter searches with Fermi-LAT data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_effect_of_milky_way_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies_extension_on_dark_matter_searches_with_fermi-lat_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_effect_of_milky_way_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies_extension_on_dark_matter_searches_with_fermi-lat_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mattia Di Mauro
Satellite galaxies of the Milky Way with high mass-to-light ratios and little baryon content, i.e. dwarf spheroidal galaxies (dSphs), are among the most promising targets to detect or constrain the nature of dark matter (DM) through its final annihilation products into high-energy photons. Previously, the assumption that DM emission from dSphs is point-like has been used to set strong constraints on DM candidates using data from the Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST and ALMA Multiple-Line Study in and around a Galaxy at $z=8.496$: Optical to FIR Line Ratios and the Onset of an Outflow Promoting Ionizing Photon Escape</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_and_alma_multiple-line_study_in_and_around_a_galaxy_at__z8.496__optical_to_fir_line_ratios_and_the_onset_of_an_outflow_promoting_ionizing_photon_escape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_and_alma_multiple-line_study_in_and_around_a_galaxy_at__z8.496__optical_to_fir_line_ratios_and_the_onset_of_an_outflow_promoting_ionizing_photon_escape/</guid>
      <description>First author: Seiji Fujimoto
We present ALMA deep spectroscopy for a lensed galaxy at $z_{\rm spec}=8.496$ with $\log(M_{\rm star}/M_{\odot})\sim7.8$ whose optical nebular lines and stellar continuum are detected by JWST/NIRSpec and NIRCam Early Release Observations in SMACS0723. Our ALMA spectrum shows $[OIII]$ 88$\mu$m and $[CII]$158$\mu$m line detections at $4.0\sigma$ and $4.5\sigma$, respectively. The redshift and position of the $[OIII]$ line coincide with those of the JWST source, while the $[CII]$ line is blue-shifted by 90 km s$^{-1}$ with a spatial offset of $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning cosmology from void properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/machine_learning_cosmology_from_void_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/machine_learning_cosmology_from_void_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bonny Y. Wang
Cosmic voids are the largest and most underdense structures in the Universe. Their properties have been shown to encode precious information about the laws and constituents of the Universe. We show that machine learning techniques can unlock the information in void features for cosmological parameter inference. We rely on thousands of void catalogs from the GIGANTES dataset, where every catalog contains an average of 11,000 voids from a volume of $1~(h^{-1}{\rm Gpc})^3$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Supernovae as an Optically Thick Fireball</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_supernovae_as_an_optically_thick_fireball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_supernovae_as_an_optically_thick_fireball/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacob Marshall
We calculate the properties of 135 stellar supernovae using data from the Open Supernova Catalog. We generate temperatures, radii, luminosities, and expansion velocities using a spherically symmetric optically thick fireball model. These modeled parameters reveal trends that are common across different types of supernovae. We have identified distinct phases that appear across Type Ia, II, II P, and IIb supernovae. We note that there is a long period of reasonable continuous growth (Phase 1), giving credence to our simple model of an optically thick fireball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHANGS--JWST First Results: ISM structure on the turbulent Jeans scale in four disk galaxies observed by JWST and ALMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs--jwst_first_results_ism_structure_on_the_turbulent_jeans_scale_in_four_disk_galaxies_observed_by_jwst_and_alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs--jwst_first_results_ism_structure_on_the_turbulent_jeans_scale_in_four_disk_galaxies_observed_by_jwst_and_alma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sharon E. Meidt
JWST/MIRI imaging of the nearby galaxies IC 5332, NGC 628, NGC 1365 and NGC 7496 from PHANGS reveals a richness of gas structures that in each case form a quasi-regular network of interconnected filaments, shells and voids. We examine whether this multi-scale network of structure is consistent with the fragmentation of the gas disk through gravitational instability. We use FilFinder to detect the web of filamentary features in each galaxy and determine their characteristic radial and azimuthal spacings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision cosmology with primordial GW backgrounds in presence of astrophysical foregrounds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/precision_cosmology_with_primordial_gw_backgrounds_in_presence_of_astrophysical_foregrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/precision_cosmology_with_primordial_gw_backgrounds_in_presence_of_astrophysical_foregrounds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Davide Racco
The era of Gravitational-Wave (GW) astronomy will grant the detection of the astrophysical GW background from unresolved mergers of binary black holes, and the prospect of probing the presence of primordial GW backgrounds. In particular, the low-frequency tail of the GW spectrum for causally-generated primordial signals (like a phase transition) offers an excellent opportunity to measure unambiguously cosmological parameters as the equation of state of the universe, or free-streaming particles at epochs well before recombination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propagating Uncertainties in the SALT3 Model Training Process to Cosmological Constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/propagating_uncertainties_in_the_salt3_model_training_process_to_cosmological_constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/propagating_uncertainties_in_the_salt3_model_training_process_to_cosmological_constraints/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Dai
Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are standardizable candles that must be modeled empirically to yield cosmological constraints. To understand the robustness of this modeling to variations in the model training procedure, we build an end-to-end pipeline to test the recently developed SALT3 model. We explore the consequences of removing pre-2000s low-$z$ or poorly calibrated $U$-band data, adjusting the amount and fidelity of SN Ia spectra, and using a model-independent framework to simulate the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quasars and the Intergalactic Medium at Cosmic Dawn</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quasars_and_the_intergalactic_medium_at_cosmic_dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quasars_and_the_intergalactic_medium_at_cosmic_dawn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaohui Fan
Quasars at cosmic dawn provide powerful probes of the formation and growth of the earliest supermassive black holes (SMBHs) in the universe, their connections to galaxy and structure formation, and the evolution of the intergalactic medium (IGM) at the epoch of reionization (EoR). Hundreds of quasars have been discovered in the first billion years of cosmic history, with the quasar redshift frontier extended to z~7.6. Observations of quasars at cosmic dawn show that: (1) The number density of luminous quasars declines exponentially at z&amp;gt;5, suggesting that the earliest quasars emerge at z~10; the lack of strong evolution in their average spectral energy distribution indicates a rapid buildup of the AGN environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gas and stel$[CII]$ontent of a metal-poor galaxy at $z=8.496$ revealed by JWST and ALMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gas_and_stellar_content_of_a_metal-poor_galaxy_at__z8.496__revealed_by_jwst_and_alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_gas_and_stellar_content_of_a_metal-poor_galaxy_at__z8.496__revealed_by_jwst_and_alma/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. E. Heintz
We present a joint analysis of the galaxy S04590 at $z=8.496$ based on NIRSpec, NIRCam, and NIRISS observations obtained through as part of Early Release Observations programme of the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) and the far-infrared $[CII]$-$158\mu$m emission line detected by dedicated Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) observations. We determine the physical properties of S04590 from modelling of the spectral energy distribution (SED) and through the redshifted optical nebular emission lines detected with JWST/NIRSpec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracer particles for core-collapse supernova nucleosynthesis: The advantages of moving backward</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer_particles_for_core-collapse_supernova_nucleosynthesis_the_advantages_of_moving_backward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer_particles_for_core-collapse_supernova_nucleosynthesis_the_advantages_of_moving_backward/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andre Sieverding
After decades, the theoretical study of core-collapse supernova explosions is moving from parameterized, spherically symmetric models to increasingly realistic multi-dimensional simulations. Obtaining nucleosynthesis yields based on such multi-dimensional core-collapse supernova (CCSN) simulations, however, is not straightforward and frequently tracer particles are employed. Tracer particles may be tracked in situ during the simulation, but often they are reconstructed in a post-processing step based on the information saved during the hydrodynamics simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Measurement of the CMB Temperature Power Spectrum and Constraints on Cosmology from the SPT-3G 2018 TT/TE/EE Data Set</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_measurement_of_the_cmb_temperature_power_spectrum_and_constraints_on_cosmology_from_the_spt-3g_2018_tt_te_ee_data_set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_measurement_of_the_cmb_temperature_power_spectrum_and_constraints_on_cosmology_from_the_spt-3g_2018_tt_te_ee_data_set/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Balkenhol
We present a sample-variance-limited measurement of the temperature power spectrum ($TT$) of the cosmic microwave background (CMB) using observations of a $\sim! 1500 ,\mathrm{deg}^2$ field made by SPT-3G in 2018. We report multifrequency power spectrum measurements at 95, 150, and 220GHz covering the angular multipole range $750 \leq \ell &amp;lt; 3000$. We combine this $TT$ measurement with the published polarization power spectrum measurements from the 2018 observing season and update their associated covariance matrix to complete the SPT-3G 2018 $TT/TE/EE$ data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Photometric Survey of Globular Cluster Systems in Brightest Cluster Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_photometric_survey_of_globular_cluster_systems_in_brightest_cluster_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_photometric_survey_of_globular_cluster_systems_in_brightest_cluster_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: William E. Harris
Hubble Space Telescope imaging for 26 giant early-type galaxies, all drawn from the MAST archive, is used to carry out photometry of their surrounding globular cluster (GC) systems. Most of these targets are Brightest Cluster Galaxies (BCGs) and their distances range from 24 to 210 Mpc. The catalogs of photometry, completed with DOLPHOT, are publicly available. The GC color indices are converted to $[Fe/H]$ through a combination of 12-Gyr SSP (Single Stellar Population) models and direct spectroscopic calibration of the fiducial color index (F475W-F850LP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion-modified stellar-mass black hole distribution and milli-Hz gravitational wave backgrounds from galaxy centre</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion-modified_stellar-mass_black_hole_distribution_and_milli-hz_gravitational_wave_backgrounds_from_galaxy_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion-modified_stellar-mass_black_hole_distribution_and_milli-hz_gravitational_wave_backgrounds_from_galaxy_centre/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mengye Wang
Gas accretion of embedded stellar-mass black holes,(sBHs) or stars in the accretion disk of active galactic nuclei,(AGNs) will modify the mass distribution of these sBHs and stars, which will also affect the migration of the sBHs/stars. \textbf{With the introduction of the mass accretion effect, we simulate the evolution of the sBH/star distribution function in a consistent way by extending the Fokker-Planck equation of sBH/star distributions to the mass-varying scenario, and explore the mass distribution of sBHs in the nuclear region of the galaxy centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy and precision of triaxial orbit models I: SMBH mass, stellar mass and dark-matter halo</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accuracy_and_precision_of_triaxial_orbit_models_i_smbh_mass_stellar_mass_and_dark-matter_halo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accuracy_and_precision_of_triaxial_orbit_models_i_smbh_mass_stellar_mass_and_dark-matter_halo/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Neureiter
We investigate the accuracy and precision of triaxial dynamical orbit models by fitting two dimensional mock observations of a realistic N-body merger simulation resembling a massive early-type galaxy with a supermassive black hole (SMBH). We show that we can reproduce the triaxial N-body merger remnant&amp;rsquo;s correct black hole mass, stellar mass-to-light ratio and total enclosed mass (inside the half-light radius) for several different tested orientations with an unprecedented accuracy of 5-10%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN cool feedback and analogy with X-ray binaries: from radiation pressure to cosmic ray driven outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_cool_feedback_and_analogy_with_x-ray_binaries_from_radiation_pressure_to_cosmic_ray_driven_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_cool_feedback_and_analogy_with_x-ray_binaries_from_radiation_pressure_to_cosmic_ray_driven_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Ishibashi
Cool outflows are now commonly observed in galaxies, but their physical origin and driving mechanism remain unclear. Active galactic nucleus (AGN) feedback can potentially accelerate cool galactic outflows via cosmic rays (CR) and radiation pressure on dust. Here we investigate the relative importance of CR and radiation feedback in AGNs, and we analyse the physical conditions for outflow launching as a function of the black hole accretion flow mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Gas Scaling Relations of Star-forming Galaxies at $z \approx 1$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/atomic_gas_scaling_relations_of_star-forming_galaxies_at__z__approx_1_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/atomic_gas_scaling_relations_of_star-forming_galaxies_at__z__approx_1_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aditya Chowdhury
We use the Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope (GMRT) Cold-HI AT $z\approx1$ (CAT$z1$) survey, a 510 hr HI 21cm emission survey of galaxies at $z=0.74-1.45$, to report the first measurements of atomic hydrogen (HI) scaling relations at $z\approx1$. We divide our sample of 11,419 blue star-forming galaxies at $z\approx1$ into three stellar mass ($M_$) subsamples and obtain detections (at $\geq 4\sigma$ significance) of the stacked HI 21cm emission signal from galaxies in all three subsamples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Hole Binary Formation in AGN Discs: From Isolation to Merger</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_binary_formation_in_agn_discs_from_isolation_to_merger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_binary_formation_in_agn_discs_from_isolation_to_merger/</guid>
      <description>First author: Connar Rowan
Motivated by the increasing number of gravitational wave detections of merging black holes (BHs) by LIGO-VIRGO-KAGRA, BH binary mergers in the discs of active galactic nuclei (AGN) is investigated as a possible merger channel. In this pathway, BHs in the large gas disc are expected to encounter one another, become mutually bound as a BH binary system through interaction with the gas in the disc and subsequently inspiral through gravitational torques induced by the local gas until merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we constrain galaxy geometry parameters using spatially integrated SED fitting?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_we_constrain_galaxy_geometry_parameters_using_spatially_integrated_sed_fitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_we_constrain_galaxy_geometry_parameters_using_spatially_integrated_sed_fitting/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yisheng Qiu
Sophisticated spectral energy distribution (SED) models describe dust attenuation and emission using geometry parameters. This treatment is natural since dust effects are driven by the underlying star-dust geometry in galaxies. An example is the Starduster SED model, which divides a galaxy into a stellar disk, a stellar bulge, and a dust disk. This work utilises the Starduster SED model to study the efficacy of inferring geometry parameters using spatially integrated SED fitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the bispectrum from bouncing cosmologies with Planck</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_bispectrum_from_bouncing_cosmologies_with_planck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_bispectrum_from_bouncing_cosmologies_with_planck/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bartjan van Tent
Bouncing models of cosmology, as they arise e.g. in loop quantum cosmology, can generate close-to-scale-invariant fluctuation spectra as observed in the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB). However, they are typically not Gaussian and also generate a bispectrum. It was proposed that these models can help to mitigate the large-scale anomalies of the CMB by considering large non-Gaussianities on very large scales, which decay exponentially on sub-horizon scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency of Optical/UV parameters on X-ray spectral index in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dependency_of_optical_uv_parameters_on_x-ray_spectral_index_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dependency_of_optical_uv_parameters_on_x-ray_spectral_index_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Nour
The study of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGNs) is vital in order to understand their respective nuclei bounded activity primarily triggered by the accretion disk and the associated corona. The hard X-ray emission characterised by the spectral index $\Gamma$ emitted by these sources in 2-10 keV band ionizes the nearby physical features like disk, BLR, NLR and provides a radiative configuration. However, based on previous studies, there is degeneracy in the evolution of $\Gamma$ across the redshift, wherein few studies display a systematic trend in the evolution and others rule out the systematic variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust contribution to the panchromatic galaxy emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_contribution_to_the_panchromatic_galaxy_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_contribution_to_the_panchromatic_galaxy_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dian P. Triani
We have developed a pipeline called \mentari to generate the far-ultraviolet to far-infrared spectral energy distribution (SED) of galaxies from the \dustysage semi-analytic galaxy formation model (SAM). \dustysage incorporates dust-related processes directly on top of the basic ingredients of galaxy formation like gas infall, cooling, star formation, feedback, and mergers. We derive a physically motivated attenuation model from the computed dust properties in \dustysage, so each galaxy has a self-consistent set of attenuation parameters based on the complicated dust physics that occurred across the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s assembly history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Molecular Gas Content in Galaxies from PAH Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/estimating_molecular_gas_content_in_galaxies_from_pah_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/estimating_molecular_gas_content_in_galaxies_from_pah_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lulu Zhang
Emission from polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs), a commonly used indicator of star formation activity in galaxies, also has the potential to serve as an effective empirical tracer of molecular gas. We use a sample of 19 nearby galaxies with spatially resolved mid-infrared Spitzer spectroscopy, multi-wavelength optical and mid-infrared imaging, and millimeter interferometric CO(1-0) maps to investigate the feasibility of using PAH emission as an empirical proxy to estimate molecular gas mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J-PLUS DR3: Galaxy-Star-Quasar classification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/j-plus_dr3_galaxy-star-quasar_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/j-plus_dr3_galaxy-star-quasar_classification/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. von Marttens
The Javalambre Photometric Local Universe Survey (J-PLUS) is a 12-band photometric survey using the 83-cm JAST telescope. Data Release 3 includes 47.4 million sources (29.8 million with $r \le 21$) on 3192 deg$^2$ (2881 deg$^2$ after masking). J-PLUS DR3 only provides star-galaxy classification so that quasars are not identified from the other sources. Given the size of the dataset, machine learning methods could provide a valid alternative classification and a solution to the classification of quasars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearby voids and their galaxies: recent progress and prospects</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nearby_voids_and_their_galaxies_recent_progress_and_prospects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nearby_voids_and_their_galaxies_recent_progress_and_prospects/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Pustilnik
Voids occupy about 3/4 of the volume of the Universe and contain about 15% of its mass. Due to various observational selection effects, these structure elements and galaxies populating voids, are highly under-explored. This especially relates to the lowest mass galaxies which comprise the main void population. Studying the nearby voids allows us to improve our understanding of the most elusive void objects. We present the brief overview of the current status and the prospects of the study of the nearest voids and their galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the influence of bars on action-based dynamical modelling of disc galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantifying_the_influence_of_bars_on_action-based_dynamical_modelling_of_disc_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantifying_the_influence_of_bars_on_action-based_dynamical_modelling_of_disc_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Soumavo Ghosh
Action-based dynamical modelling, using stars as dynamical tracers, is an excellent diagnostic to estimate the underlying axisymmetric matter distribution of the Milky Way. However, the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s bar causes non-axisymmetric resonance features in the stellar disc. Using Roadmapping (an action-based dynamical modelling framework to estimate the gravitational potential and the stellar distribution function), we systematically quantify the robustness of action-based modelling in the presence of a bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reionization with star-forming galaxies: insights from the Low-z Lyman Continuum Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reionization_with_star-forming_galaxies_insights_from_the_low-z_lyman_continuum_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reionization_with_star-forming_galaxies_insights_from_the_low-z_lyman_continuum_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maxime Trebitsch
The fraction of ionizing photons escaping from galaxies, $f_{esc}$, is at the same time a crucial parameter in modelling reionization and a very poorly known quantity, especially at high redshift. Recent observations are starting to constrain the values of $f_{esc}$ in low-z star-forming galaxies, but the validity of this comparison remains to be verified. Applying at high-z the empirical relation between $f_{esc}$ and the UV slope trends derived from the Low-z Lyman Continuum Survey, we use the DELPHI semi-analytical galaxy formation model to estimate the global ionizing emissivity of high-z galaxies, which we use to compute the resulting reionization history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searches for Extremely Metal Poor Galaxies using ALFALFA-selected Dwarf Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searches_for_extremely_metal_poor_galaxies_using_alfalfa-selected_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searches_for_extremely_metal_poor_galaxies_using_alfalfa-selected_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: John H. Miller Jr
We present a study of nearby dwarf galaxies selected from the ALFALFA blind HI survey. A primary goal of the project was to utilize a non-standard selection method with the hope of detecting previously unrecognized extremely metal-poor (XMP) galaxies. The study was motivated by the recent discovery of two XMP galaxies $-$ Leo P and Leoncino $-$ which were both originally found via the ALFALFA survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2021fxy: Mid-Ultraviolet Flux Suppression is a Common Feature of Type Ia Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2021fxy_mid-ultraviolet_flux_suppression_is_a_common_feature_of_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2021fxy_mid-ultraviolet_flux_suppression_is_a_common_feature_of_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. DerKacy
We present ultraviolet (UV) to near-infrared (NIR) observations and analysis of the nearby Type Ia supernova SN 2021fxy. Our observations include UV photometry from Swift/UVOT, UV spectroscopy from HST/STIS, and high-cadence optical photometry with the Swope 1-m telescope capturing intra-night rises during the early light curve. Early $B-V$ colours show SN 2021fxy is the first &amp;ldquo;shallow-silicon&amp;rdquo; (SS) SN Ia to follow a red-to-blue evolution, compared to other SS objects which show blue colours from the earliest observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dependence of Galaxy Properties on the Underlying 3D Matter Density Field at 2.0&lt;z&lt;2.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dependence_of_galaxy_properties_on_the_underlying_3d_matter_density_field_at_2.0z2.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dependence_of_galaxy_properties_on_the_underlying_3d_matter_density_field_at_2.0z2.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rieko Momose
We study the environmental effect of galaxy evolution as a function of the underlying 3D dark matter density for the first time at $z=2-2.5$, in which the underlying matter density is reconstructed from galaxy and Ly$\alpha$ forest spectroscopy through dynamical forward modeling techniques. Utilizing these maps, we investigate the dependence of the star formation activities and galaxy types (mergers, submillimeter galaxies, active galactic nuclei, and quiescent galaxies) on the matter overdensity $\Delta$ and stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The X-ray view of optically selected dual AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_x-ray_view_of_optically_selected_dual_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_x-ray_view_of_optically_selected_dual_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alessandra De Rosa
We present a study of optically selected dual AGN with projected separations of 3&amp;ndash;97~kpc. Using multi-wavelength (MWL) information (optical, X-rays, mid-IR), we characterized the intrinsic nuclear properties of this sample and compared them with those of isolated systems. Among the 124 X-ray detected AGN candidates, 52 appear in pairs and 72 as single X-ray sources. Through MWL analysis, we confirmed the presence of the AGN in a fraction &amp;gt;80% of the detected targets in pairs (42 over 52).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Model Tests with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_model_tests_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_model_tests_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nikita Lovyagin
The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), which has recently become operational, is capable of detecting objects at record-breaking redshifts, $z \gtrsim 15$. This is a crucial advance for observational cosmology, as at these redshifts the differences between alternative cosmological models manifest themselves in the most obvious way. In recent years, some observational hints have emerged indicating that the Standard Cosmological Model could require correcting. One of these hints is related to the discovery of remote galaxies whose redshifts correspond to the very young Universe (less than one billion years after the Big Bang) but which are similar to nearby galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxies on graph neural networks: towards robust synthetic galaxy catalogs with deep generative models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxies_on_graph_neural_networks_towards_robust_synthetic_galaxy_catalogs_with_deep_generative_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxies_on_graph_neural_networks_towards_robust_synthetic_galaxy_catalogs_with_deep_generative_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yesukhei Jagvaral
The future astronomical imaging surveys are set to provide precise constraints on cosmological parameters, such as dark energy. However, production of synthetic data for these surveys, to test and validate analysis methods, suffers from a very high computational cost. In particular, generating mock galaxy catalogs at sufficiently large volume and high resolution will soon become computationally unreachable. In this paper, we address this problem with a Deep Generative Model to create robust mock galaxy catalogs that may be used to test and develop the analysis pipelines of future weak lensing surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling halo and central galaxy orientations on the SO(3) manifold with score-based generative models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_halo_and_central_galaxy_orientations_on_the_so3_manifold_with_score-based_generative_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_halo_and_central_galaxy_orientations_on_the_so3_manifold_with_score-based_generative_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yesukhei Jagvaral
Upcoming cosmological weak lensing surveys are expected to constrain cosmological parameters with unprecedented precision. In preparation for these surveys, large simulations with realistic galaxy populations are required to test and validate analysis pipelines. However, these simulations are computationally very costly &amp;ndash; and at the volumes and resolutions demanded by upcoming cosmological surveys, they are computationally infeasible. Here, we propose a Deep Generative Modeling approach to address the specific problem of emulating realistic 3D galaxy orientations in synthetic catalogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphology of Shocked Lateral Outflows in Colliding Hydrodynamic Flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_of_shocked_lateral_outflows_in_colliding_hydrodynamic_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_of_shocked_lateral_outflows_in_colliding_hydrodynamic_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. N. Markwick
Supersonic interacting flows occurring in phenomena such as protostellar jets give rise to strong shocks, and have been demonstrated in several laboratory experiments. To study such colliding flows, we use the AstroBEAR AMR code to conduct hydrodynamic simulations in three dimensions. We introduce variations in the flow parameters of density, velocity, and cross sectional radius of the colliding flows %radius in order to study the propagation and conical shape of the bow shock formed by collisions between two, not necessarily symmetric, hypersonic flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Splashback on Weak Lensing Mass Estimates of Galaxy Clusters and Groups</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_splashback_on_weak_lensing_mass_estimates_of_galaxy_clusters_and_groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_splashback_on_weak_lensing_mass_estimates_of_galaxy_clusters_and_groups/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuanyuan Zhang
The splashback radius of a dark matter halo, which corresponds to the first apocenter radius reached by infalling matter and substructures, has been detected around galaxy clusters using a multitude of observational methods, including weak lensing measurements. In this manuscript, we present how the splashback feature in the halo density profile affects galaxy cluster masses derived through weak lensing measurements if it is not accounted for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The globular cluster system of the nearest Seyfert II galaxy Circinus</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_globular_cluster_system_of_the_nearest_seyfert_ii_galaxy_circinus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_globular_cluster_system_of_the_nearest_seyfert_ii_galaxy_circinus/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Obasi
Context. The globular cluster (GC) system of Circinus galaxy has not been probed previously partly because of the location of the galaxy at - 3.8$^\circ$ Galactic latitude which suffers severely from interstellar extinction, stellar crowding, and Galactic foreground contamination. However, the deep near-infrared (NIR) photometry by the VISTA Variables in the Via L&#39;actea Extended Survey (VVVX) in combination with the precise astrometry of Gaia EDR3 allow us to map GCs in this region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A $γ$-ray emitting NLS1 galaxy SDSS J095909.51&#43;460014.3 identified by multiwavelength flares</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a__%CE%B3_-ray_emitting_nls1_galaxy_sdss_j095909.51&#43;460014.3_identified_by_multiwavelength_flares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a__%CE%B3_-ray_emitting_nls1_galaxy_sdss_j095909.51&#43;460014.3_identified_by_multiwavelength_flares/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yang-Ji Li
We report on the identification of a new $\gamma$-ray emitting narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy ($\gamma$-NLS1), SDSS J095909.51+460014.3 (hereinafter J0959+4600, $z$ = 0.399), by establishing its association with a $\gamma$-ray source 4FGL 0959.6+4606, although its low-energy counterpart was suggested to be a radio galaxy 2MASX J09591976+4603515 (hereinafter J0959+4603). \emph{WISE} long-term light curves of these two sources reveal diverse infrared variability patterns. Violent infrared variations of J0959+4600 with an amplitude up to one order of magnitude has been detected, while variability is mild for the other one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cosmological Fireball with Sixteen-Percent Gamma-Ray Radiative Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_cosmological_fireball_with_sixteen-percent_gamma-ray_radiative_efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_cosmological_fireball_with_sixteen-percent_gamma-ray_radiative_efficiency/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liang Li
Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are the most powerful explosions in the universe. The standard model invokes a relativistic fireball with a bright photosphere emission component. How efficiently the jet converts its energy to radiation is a long-standing problem and it is poorly constrained. A definitive diagnosis of GRB radiation components and measurement of GRB radiative efficiency requires prompt emission and afterglow data with high-resolution and wide-band coverage in time and energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fundamental plane of galaxy assembly and chemical enrichment within the first 700 Myr after the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_fundamental_plane_of_galaxy_assembly_and_chemical_enrichment_within_the_first_700_myr_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_fundamental_plane_of_galaxy_assembly_and_chemical_enrichment_within_the_first_700_myr_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kasper E. Heintz
Galaxies throughout the last 12 Gyr of cosmic time follow a single, universal fundamental plane that relates their star-formation rates (SFRs), stellar masses ($M_\star$) and chemical abundances. Deviation from these fundamental scaling relations would imply a drastic change in the processes that regulate galaxy evolution. Observations have hinted at the possibility that this relation may be broken in the very early universe. However, until recently, chemical abundances of galaxies could be only measured reliably as far back as redshift $z = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A General Framework for Removing Point Spread Function Additive Systematics in Cosmological Weak Lensing Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_general_framework_for_removing_point_spread_function_additive_systematics_in_cosmological_weak_lensing_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_general_framework_for_removing_point_spread_function_additive_systematics_in_cosmological_weak_lensing_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tianqing Zhang
Cosmological weak lensing measurements rely on a precise measurement of the shear two-point correlation function (2PCF) along with a deep understanding of systematics that affect it. In this work, we demonstrate a general framework for describing the impact of PSF systematics on the cosmic shear 2PCF, and mitigating its impact on cosmological analysis. Our framework can describe leakage and modeling error from all spin-2 quantities contributed by the PSF second and higher moments, rather than just the second moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A possible tension between galaxy rotational velocity and observed physical properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_tension_between_galaxy_rotational_velocity_and_observed_physical_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_tension_between_galaxy_rotational_velocity_and_observed_physical_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lior Shamir
The discrepancy between the mass of galaxies and their rotational velocity is one of the most puzzling scientific phenomena. Despite over a century of research, this phenomenon is not fully understood. Common explanations include dark matter and MOND, among other theories. Here we report on another observation that shows tension between the physics of galaxy rotation and its rotational velocity. We compare the brightness of galaxies, and find that galaxies that spin in the same direction as the Milky Way have different brightness than galaxies that spin in the opposite direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A roadmap to cosmological parameter analysis with third-order shear statistics II: Analytic covariance estimate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_roadmap_to_cosmological_parameter_analysis_with_third-order_shear_statistics_ii_analytic_covariance_estimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_roadmap_to_cosmological_parameter_analysis_with_third-order_shear_statistics_ii_analytic_covariance_estimate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laila Linke
Third-order weak lensing statistics are a promising tool for cosmological analyses since they extract cosmological information in the non-Gaussianity of the cosmic large-scale structure. However, such analyses require precise and accurate models for the covariance. In this second paper of a series on third-order weak lensing statistics, we derive and validate an analytic model for the covariance of the third-order aperture statistics $\langle M_\mathrm{ap}^3\rangle$. We derive the covariance model from a real-space estimator for $\langle M_\mathrm{ap}^3\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of linearity of the ratio of dark matter to baryonic matter in galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_linearity_of_the_ratio_of_dark_matter_to_baryonic_matter_in_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_linearity_of_the_ratio_of_dark_matter_to_baryonic_matter_in_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Varenya Upadhyaya
We search for a linearity in the ratio of dark matter to baryonic matter as a function of radius for galaxy clusters, motivated by a recent result by Lovas (arXiv:2206.11431), who has discovered such a linearity for a diverse suite of galaxies in the SPARC sample. For our analysis, we used a sample of 54 non-cool core clusters from the HIFLUGCS sample. We do not find any evidence for a linear trend in the aforementioned ratio as a function of radius for individual clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical study of the time-lags due to Comptonization and the constraints on the X-ray corona in AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_theoretical_study_of_the_time-lags_due_to_comptonization_and_the_constraints_on_the_x-ray_corona_in_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_theoretical_study_of_the_time-lags_due_to_comptonization_and_the_constraints_on_the_x-ray_corona_in_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: W. Zhang
We study the Fourier time-lags due to the Comptonization of disc-emitted photons in a spherical, uniform, and stationary X-ray corona, which located on the rotational axis of the black hole. We use Monk, a general relativistic Monte-Carlo radiative transfer code, to calculate Compton scattering of photons emitted by a thin disc with a Novikov-Thorne temperature profile. We find that the model time-lags due to Comptonization remain constant up to a characteristic frequency and then rapidly decrease to zero at higher frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN Feedback in SDSS-IV MaNGA: AGNs Have Suppressed Central Star-Formation Rates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Caleb Lammers
Despite the importance of feedback from active galactic nuclei (AGN) in models of galaxy evolution, observational constraints on the influence of AGN feedback on star formation remain weak. To this end, we have compared the star formation trends of 279 low-redshift AGN galaxies with 558 non-active control galaxies using integral field unit spectroscopy from the SDSS-IV MaNGA survey. With a Gaussian process-based methodology, we reconstruct non-parametric star formation histories in spatially-resolved spaxels covering the face of each galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASTROPHYSICAL S(0)-FACTORS FOR THE $^{3}{m He}(α, γ)^{7}{m Be}$, $^{3}{m H}(α, γ)^{7}{m Li}$ and $^{7}{m Be}(p, γ)^{8}{m B}$ DIRECT CAPTURE PROCESSES IN A POTENTIAL MODEL</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.00318/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.00318/</guid>
      <description>S. A. Turakulov
Astrophysical S-factors at zero energy for the direct &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;nuclear&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; capture &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;reactions&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; $^{3}{\rm He}(α, γ)^{7}{\rm Be}$, $^{3}{\rm H}(α, γ)^{7}{\rm Li}$ and $^{7}{\rm Be}(p, γ)^{8}{\rm B}$ are estimated within the framework of two-body potential cluster model on the basis of extranuclear capture approximation of D. Baye and E. Brainis. The values of S(0)-factors have been calculated using two different potential models for each process, which were adjusted to the binding energies and empirical values of the asymptotical normalization coefficients from the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can high-redshift Hubble diagrams rule out the standard model of cosmology in the context of cosmographic method?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_high-redshift_hubble_diagrams_rule_out_the_standard_model_of_cosmology_in_the_context_of_cosmographic_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/can_high-redshift_hubble_diagrams_rule_out_the_standard_model_of_cosmology_in_the_context_of_cosmographic_method/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Pourojaghi
Using mock data for the Hubble diagrams of type Ia supernovae (SNIa) and quasars (QSOs) generated based on the standard model of cosmology, and using the least-squares method based on the Markov-Chain-Monte-Carlo (MCMC) algorithm, we first put constraints on the cosmographic parameters in the context of the various model-independent cosmographic methods reconstructed from the Taylor $4^{th}$ and $5^{th}$ order expansions and the Pade (2,2) and (3,2) polynomials of the Hubble parameter, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapse of rotating massive stars leading to black hole formation and energetic supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapse_of_rotating_massive_stars_leading_to_black_hole_formation_and_energetic_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapse_of_rotating_massive_stars_leading_to_black_hole_formation_and_energetic_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sho Fujibayashi
We explore a possible scenario of the explosion as a result of core collapses of rotating massive stars that leave a black hole by performing a radiation-viscous-hydrodynamics simulation in numerical relativity. We take moderately and rapidly rotating compact pre-collapse stellar models derived in stellar evolution calculations as the initial conditions. We find that the viscous heating in the disk formed around the central black hole powers an outflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONCERTO: Simulating the CO, CII, and CI line emission of galaxies in a 117 $\rm deg^2$ field and the impact of field-to-field variance</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/concerto_simulating_the_co_cii_and_ci_line_emission_of_galaxies_in_a_117___rm_deg2__field_and_the_impact_of_field-to-field_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/concerto_simulating_the_co_cii_and_ci_line_emission_of_galaxies_in_a_117___rm_deg2__field_and_the_impact_of_field-to-field_variance/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Gkogkou
In the submm regime, spectral line scans and line intensity mapping (LIM) are new promising probes for the cold gas content and star formation rate of galaxies across cosmic time. However, both of these two measurements suffer from field-to-field variance. We study the effect of field-to-field variance on the predicted CO and CII power spectra from future LIM experiments such as CONCERTO, as well as on the line luminosity functions (LFs) and the cosmic molecular gas mass density that are currently derived from spectral line scans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Sands: The Origin of Dusty, Star-forming Galaxies in the Epoch of Reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_sands_the_origin_of_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_in_the_epoch_of_reionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_sands_the_origin_of_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_in_the_epoch_of_reionization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sidney Lower
We present the Cosmic Sands suite of cosmological zoom-in simulations based on the Simba galaxy formation model in order to study the build up of the first massive and dusty galaxies in the early Universe. Residing in the most massive halos, we find that the compact proto-massive galaxies undergo nearly continuous mergers with smaller subhalos, boosting star formation rates (SFRs) and the build up of stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints from the BOSS DR12 void size function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_the_boss_dr12_void_size_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_the_boss_dr12_void_size_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sofia Contarini
We present the first cosmological constraints derived from the analysis of the void size function. This work relies on the final BOSS DR12 data set, a large spectroscopic galaxy catalog, ideal for the identification of cosmic voids. We extract a sample of voids from the distribution of galaxies and we apply a cleaning procedure aimed at reaching high levels of purity and completeness. We model the void size function by means of an extension of the popular volume-conserving model, based on two additional nuisance parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSMOS2020: The Galaxy Stellar Mass Function: On the assembly and star formation cessation of galaxies at $0.2\lt z \leq 7.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmos2020_the_galaxy_stellar_mass_function_on_the_assembly_and_star_formation_cessation_of_galaxies_at__0.2_lt_z__leq_7.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmos2020_the_galaxy_stellar_mass_function_on_the_assembly_and_star_formation_cessation_of_galaxies_at__0.2_lt_z__leq_7.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. R. Weaver
How galaxies form, assemble, and cease their star-formation is a central question within the modern landscape of galaxy evolution studies. These processes are indelibly imprinted on the galaxy stellar mass function (SMF). We present constraints on the shape and evolution of the SMF, the quiescent galaxy fraction, and the cosmic stellar mass density across 90% of the history of the Universe from $z=7.5\rightarrow0.2$ via the COSMOS survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and properties of the earliest galaxies with confirmed distances</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_and_properties_of_the_earliest_galaxies_with_confirmed_distances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_and_properties_of_the_earliest_galaxies_with_confirmed_distances/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. E. Robertson
Surveys with James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) have discovered candidate galaxies in the first 400 Myr of cosmic time. The properties of these distant galaxies provide initial conditions for understanding early galaxy formation and cosmic reionisation. Preliminary indications have suggested these candidate galaxies may be more massive and abundant than previously thought. However, without spectroscopic confirmation of their distances to constrain their intrinsic brightnesses, their inferred properties remain uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf AGNs from Variability for the Origins of Seeds (DAVOS): Optical Variability of Broad-line Dwarf AGNs from the Zwicky Transient Facility</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_agns_from_variability_for_the_origins_of_seeds_davos_optical_variability_of_broad-line_dwarf_agns_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_agns_from_variability_for_the_origins_of_seeds_davos_optical_variability_of_broad-line_dwarf_agns_from_the_zwicky_transient_facility/</guid>
      <description>First author: Z. Franklin Wang
We study the optical variability of a sample of candidate low-mass (dwarf ang Seyfert) active galactic nuclei (AGNs) using Zwicky Transient Facility g-band light curves. Our sample is compiled from broad-line AGNs in dwarf galaxies reported in the literature with single-epoch virial black hole (BH) masses in the range $M_{\rm{BH}} \sim 10^{4}$&amp;ndash;$10^{8}\ M_{\odot}$. We measure the characteristic ``damping&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; timescale of the optical variability $\tau_{\rm{DRW}}$, beyond which the power spectral density flattens, of a final sample of 79 candidate low-mass AGNs with high-quality light curves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early-type Dwarf Galaxies in the Local Universe. Evidence of Ex-situ Growth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03430/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03430/</guid>
      <description>Sanjaya Paudel
We report the discovery of a rare early-type &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; (dE), SDSS J125651.47+163024.2 (hereafter dE1256), possessing a tidal feature that was likely built up by accretion of an even smaller &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;. dE1256 is located in a nearly isolated environment, at the outskirt of the Virgo cluster. A detailed morphological examination reveals that the accreted stellar population is mainly deposited in the outer part of dE1256, where the tidal tail is most prominent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early-type Dwarf Galaxies in the Local Universe. Evidence of Ex-situ Growth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early-type_dwarf_galaxies_in_the_local_universe._evidence_of_ex-situ_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early-type_dwarf_galaxies_in_the_local_universe._evidence_of_ex-situ_growth/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sanjaya Paudel
We report the discovery of a rare early-type dwarf galaxy (dE), SDSS J125651.47+163024.2 (hereafter dE1256), possessing a tidal feature that was likely built up by accretion of an even smaller dwarf galaxy. dE1256 is located in a nearly isolated environment, at the outskirt of the Virgo cluster. A detailed morphological examination reveals that the accreted stellar population is mainly deposited in the outer part of dE1256, where the tidal tail is most prominent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emission-line properties of IllustrisTNG galaxies: from local diagnostic diagrams to high-redshift predictions for JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emission-line_properties_of_illustristng_galaxies_from_local_diagnostic_diagrams_to_high-redshift_predictions_for_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emission-line_properties_of_illustristng_galaxies_from_local_diagnostic_diagrams_to_high-redshift_predictions_for_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michaela Hirschmann
We compute synthetic, rest-frame optical and ultraviolet (UV) emission-line properties of galaxy populations at redshifts from z$\approx$0 to z=8 in a full cosmological framework. We achieve this by coupling, in post-processing, the cosmological IllustrisTNG simulations with new-generation nebular-emission models, accounting for line emission from young stars, post-asymptotic-giant-branch (PAGB) stars, accreting black holes (BHs) and, for the first time, fast radiative shocks. The optical emission-line properties of simulated galaxies dominated by different ionizing sources are largely consistent with those expected from classical diagnostic diagrams and reflect the observed increase in OIII/H$\beta$ at fixed NII/H$\alpha$ and the evolution of the H$\alpha$, OIII$\lambda5007$ and OII$\lambda3727$ luminosity functions from z$\approx$0 to z$\sim$2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaporation of Primordial Black Holes in the Early Universe: Mass and Spin Distributions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03878/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03878/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Cheek
Many cosmological phenomena lead to the production of primordial black holes in the early Universe. These phenomena often create a population of black holes with extended mass and spin distributions. As these black holes evaporate via Hawking radiation, they can modify various cosmological observables, lead to the production of dark matter, modify the number of effective relativistic degrees of freedom, $N_{\rm eff}$, source a stochastic gravitational wave background and alter the dynamics of baryogenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f(T) cosmology against the cosmographic method: A new study using mock and observational data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ft_cosmology_against_the_cosmographic_method_a_new_study_using_mock_and_observational_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ft_cosmology_against_the_cosmographic_method_a_new_study_using_mock_and_observational_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Sabiee
In this paper, we study the power-law $f(T)$ model using Hubble diagrams of type Ia supernovae (SNIa), quasars (QSOs), Gamma Ray Bursts (GRBs) and the measurements from baryonic acoustic oscillations (BAO) in the framework of the cosmographic method. Using mock data for SNIa, QSOs and GRBs generated based on the power-law $f(T)$ model, we show whether different cosmographic methods are suitable to reconstruct the distance modulus or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas dynamical friction as a binary formation mechanism in AGN discs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_dynamical_friction_as_a_binary_formation_mechanism_in_agn_discs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_dynamical_friction_as_a_binary_formation_mechanism_in_agn_discs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stanislav DeLaurentiis
In this paper, we study how gaseous dynamical friction (DF) affects the motion of fly-by stellar-mass black holes (sBHs) embedded in active galactic nucleus (AGN) discs. We perform 3-body integrations of the interaction of two co-planar sBHs in nearby, initially circular orbits around the supermassive black hole (SMBH). We find that DF can facilitate the formation of gravitationally bound near-Keplerian binaries in AGN discs, and we delineate the discrete ranges of impact parameters and AGN disc parameters for which such captures occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-phase metallicity break radii of star-forming galaxies in IllustrisTNG</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas-phase_metallicity_break_radii_of_star-forming_galaxies_in_illustristng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas-phase_metallicity_break_radii_of_star-forming_galaxies_in_illustristng/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex M. Garcia
We present radial gas-phase metallicity profiles, gradients, and break radii at redshift $z = 0 - 3$ from the TNG50-1 star-forming galaxy population. These metallicity profiles are characterized by an emphasis on identifying the steep inner gradient and flat outer gradient. From this, the break radius, $r_{\rm Break}$, is defined as the region where the transition occurs. We observe the break radius having a positive trend with mass that weakens with redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting ALMA non-detections of JWST super-early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpreting_alma_non-detections_of_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpreting_alma_non-detections_of_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Kohandel
Recent attempts to detect OIII 88$\mu$m emission from super-early ($z&amp;gt;10$) galaxy candidates observed by JWST have been unsuccessful. By using zoom-in simulations, we show that these galaxies are faint, and mostly fall below the local metal-poor $[OIII]-SFR$ relation as a result of their low ionization parameter, $U_{\rm ion}\lesssim 10^{-3}$. Such low $U_{\rm ion}$ values are found in galaxies that are in an early assembly stage, and whose stars are still embedded in high-density natal clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Narrow Line Region Dynamics in Nearby Active Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_narrow_line_region_dynamics_in_nearby_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_narrow_line_region_dynamics_in_nearby_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Beena Meena
We present dynamical models of the narrow line region (NLR) outflows in the nearby Seyfert galaxies Mrk 3, Mrk 78, NGC 1068, and NGC 4151 using observations from the Hubble Space Telescope and Apache Point Observatory. We employ long-slit spectroscopy to map the spatially-resolved outflow and rotational velocities of the ionized gas. We also perform surface brightness decompositions of host galaxy images to constrain the enclosed stellar mass distributions as functions of distance from the supermassive black holes (SMBHs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic-Chemical analysis and Time tagging for the Diagonal Ridge Structure of the Galactic Outer Disk with LAMOST Red Giant Branch Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.09227/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.09227/</guid>
      <description>Peng Yang
We investigate the kinematic-chemical distribution of Red Giant Branch (RGB)stars from the LAMOST survey crossed matched with Gaia DR2 proper motions, and present time tagging for the well-known ridge structures (diagonal distributions for $V_R$ in the $R$, $V_φ$ plane) in the range of Galactocentric distance $R$ = 8 to 15 kpc. We detect six ridge structures, including five ridges apparent in the radial velocity distribution and three ridges apparent in the vertical velocity, the sensitive time of which to the perturbations are from young population (0$-$3 Gyr) to old population (9$-$14 Gyr).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Deviations in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.02535/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.02535/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Cohen
Fluctuations play a critical role in cosmology. They are relevant across a range of phenomena from the dynamics of inflation to the formation of structure. In many cases, these fluctuations are coarse grained and follow a Gaussian distribution as a consequence of the Central Limit Theorem. Yet, some classes of observables are dominated by rare fluctuations and are sensitive to the details of the underlying microphysics. In this paper, we argue that the Large Deviation Principle can be used to diagnose when one must to appeal to the fundamental description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Deviations in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04476/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04476/</guid>
      <description>Xin Wang
Fluctuations play a critical role in cosmology. They are relevant across a range of phenomena from the dynamics of inflation to the formation of structure. In many cases, these fluctuations are coarse grained and follow a Gaussian distribution as a consequence of the Central Limit Theorem. Yet, some classes of observables are dominated by rare fluctuations and are sensitive to the details of the underlying microphysics. In this paper, we argue that the Large Deviation Principle can be used to diagnose when one must to appeal to the fundamental description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping dust attenuation and the 2175 Å bump at kpc scales in nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_dust_attenuation_and_the_2175_%C3%A5_bump_at_kpc_scales_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_dust_attenuation_and_the_2175_%C3%A5_bump_at_kpc_scales_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuang Zhou
We develop a novel approach to measure dust attenuation properties of galaxies,including the dust opacity and shape of the attenuation curve in both optical and NUV, as well as the strength of the 2175{\AA} absorption feature. From an observed spectrum the method uses a model-independent approach to derive a relative attenuation curve.The absolute amplitude is then calibrated with the NIR photometry. The dust-corrected spectrum is fitted with stellar population models to derive the dust-free model spectrum covering the whole wavelength range from NUV to NIR and is compared with the observed SED/spectrum to determine dust attenuation properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength studies of G298.6$-$0.0: An old GeV supernova remnant interacting with molecular clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_studies_of_g298.6_-_0.0_an_old_gev_supernova_remnant_interacting_with_molecular_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_studies_of_g298.6_-_0.0_an_old_gev_supernova_remnant_interacting_with_molecular_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paul K. H. Yeung
Hadronic $\gamma$-ray sources associated with supernova remnants (SNRs) can serve as stopwatches for the escape of cosmic rays from SNRs, which gradually develops from highest-energy particles to lowest-energy particles with time. In this work, we analyze the 13.7~yr \emph{Fermi}-LAT data to investigate the $\gamma$-ray feature in/around the SNR G298.6$-$0.0 region. With $\gamma$-ray spatial analyses, we detect three point-like components. Among them, Src-NE is at the eastern SNR shell, and Src-NW is adjacent to the western edge of this SNR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-local contribution from small scales in galaxy-galaxy lensing: Comparison of mitigation schemes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-local_contribution_from_small_scales_in_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_comparison_of_mitigation_schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-local_contribution_from_small_scales_in_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_comparison_of_mitigation_schemes/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Prat
Recent cosmological analyses with large-scale structure and weak lensing measurements, usually referred to as 3$\times$2pt, had to discard a lot of signal-to-noise from small scales due to our inability to precisely model non-linearities and baryonic effects. Galaxy-galaxy lensing, or the position-shear correlation between lens and source galaxies, is one of the three two-point correlation functions that are included in such analyses, usually estimated with the mean tangential shear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical analyses of M31 dark matter profiles</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03252/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03252/</guid>
      <description>Kuantay Boshkayev
We reproduce the rotation curve of the Andromeda galaxy (M31) by taking into account its bulge, disk, and halo components, considering the last one to contain the major part of dark matter mass. Hence, our prescription is to split the galactic bulge into two components, namely, the inner and main bulges, respectively. Both bulges are thus modeled by exponential density profiles since we underline that the widely accepted de Vaucouleurs law fails to reproduce the whole galactic bulge rotation curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the application of dimensionality reduction and clustering algorithms for the classification of kinematic morphologies of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_application_of_dimensionality_reduction_and_clustering_algorithms_for_the_classification_of_kinematic_morphologies_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_application_of_dimensionality_reduction_and_clustering_algorithms_for_the_classification_of_kinematic_morphologies_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. S. Rosito
The morphological classification of galaxies is considered a relevant issue and can be approached from different points of view. The increasing growth in the size and accuracy of astronomical data sets brings with it the need for the use of automatic methods to perform these classifications. The aim of this work is to propose and evaluate a method for automatic unsupervised classification of kinematic morphologies of galaxies that yields a meaningful clustering and captures the variations of the fundamental properties of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the bright-end of the UV luminosity functions of galaxies at $z \sim 0.6-1.2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_bright-end_of_the_uv_luminosity_functions_of_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.6-1.2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_bright-end_of_the_uv_luminosity_functions_of_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.6-1.2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Sharma
We derive the Ultra-Violet (UV) luminosity function (LF) of star forming galaxies falling in the redshift range $z = 0.6 - 1.2$, in the rest-frame far-UV (1500 {\AA}) wavelength. For this work we are in particular interested in the bright end of the UV LF in this redshift range. The data from \textit{XMM-Newton} Optical Monitor (XMM-OM), near-ultraviolet (1600-4000 {\AA}) observations over 1.5 deg\textsuperscript{2} of the COSMOS field are employed for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peekaboo: the extremely metal poor dwarf galaxy HIPASS J1131-31</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03478/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03478/</guid>
      <description>I. D. Karachentsev
The &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; irregular &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; HIPASS J1131-31 was discovered as a source of HI emission at low redshift in such close proximity of a bright star that we call it Peekaboo. The &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; resolves into stars in images with Hubble Space Telescope, leading to a distance estimate of 6.8+-0.7 Mpc. Spectral optical observations with the Southern African Large Telescope reveal HIPASS J1131-31 to be one of the most extremely metal-poor &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxies&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; known with the gas-phase oxygen abundance 12+log(O/H) = 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peekaboo: the extremely metal poor dwarf galaxy HIPASS J1131-31</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peekaboo_the_extremely_metal_poor_dwarf_galaxy_hipass_j1131-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peekaboo_the_extremely_metal_poor_dwarf_galaxy_hipass_j1131-31/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. D. Karachentsev
The dwarf irregular galaxy HIPASS J1131-31 was discovered as a source of HI emission at low redshift in such close proximity of a bright star that we call it Peekaboo. The galaxy resolves into stars in images with Hubble Space Telescope, leading to a distance estimate of 6.8+-0.7 Mpc. Spectral optical observations with the Southern African Large Telescope reveal HIPASS J1131-31 to be one of the most extremely metal-poor galaxies known with the gas-phase oxygen abundance 12+log(O/H) = 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric and Structural Parameters of Newly Discovered Nuclear Star Clusters in Local Volume Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04151/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04151/</guid>
      <description>Nils Hoyer
We use high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging data of &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxies&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; in the Local Volume ($\lesssim 11$ Mpc) to parameterise 19 newly discovered nuclear star clusters (NSCs). Most of the clusters have stellar masses of $M_{\star}^{nsc} \lesssim 10^6$ M$_{\odot}$ and compare to Galactic globular clusters in terms of ellipticity, effective radius, stellar mass, and surface density. The clusters are modelled with a Sérsic profile and their surface brightness evaluated at the effective radius reveals a tight positive correlation to the host &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric and Structural Parameters of Newly Discovered Nuclear Star Clusters in Local Volume Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_structural_parameters_of_newly_discovered_nuclear_star_clusters_in_local_volume_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_structural_parameters_of_newly_discovered_nuclear_star_clusters_in_local_volume_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nils Hoyer
We use high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging data of dwarf galaxies in the Local Volume ($\lesssim 11$ Mpc) to parameterise 19 newly discovered nuclear star clusters (NSCs). Most of the clusters have stellar masses of $M_{\star}^{nsc} \lesssim 10^6$ M${\odot}$ and compare to Galactic globular clusters in terms of ellipticity, effective radius, stellar mass, and surface density. The clusters are modelled with a S&#39;ersic profile and their surface brightness evaluated at the effective radius reveals a tight positive correlation to the host galaxy stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric Mass Estimation and the Stellar Mass-Halo Mass Relation for Low Mass Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_mass_estimation_and_the_stellar_mass-halo_mass_relation_for_low_mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_mass_estimation_and_the_stellar_mass-halo_mass_relation_for_low_mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dennis Zaritsky
We present a photometric halo mass estimation technique for local galaxies that enables us to establish the stellar mass-halo mass (SMHM) relation down to stellar masses of 10$^5$ M$\odot$. We find no detectable differences among the SMHM relations of four local galaxy clusters or between the cluster and field relations and we find agreement with extrapolations of previous SMHM relations derived using abundance matching approaches. We fit a power law to our empirical SMHM relation and find that for adopted NFW dark matter profiles and for M$* &amp;lt; 10^9$ M$\odot$, the halo mass is M$h = 10^{10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarized radio emission unveils the structure of the pre-supernova circumstellar magnetic field and the radio emission in SN1987A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. Petruk
The detected polarized radio emission from remnant of SN1987A opens the possibility to unveil the structure of the pre-supernova magnetic field in the circumstellar medium. Properties derived from direct measurements would be of importance for understanding the progenitor stars and their magnetic fields. As the first step to this goal, we adopted the hydrodynamic data from an elaborated three-dimensional (3-D) numerical model of SN1987A. We have developed an approximate method for reconstruction&#39; of 3-D magnetic field structure inside supernova remnant on the hydrodynamic background&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDSS-IV MaNGA: How Galaxy Interactions Influence Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss-iv_manga_how_galaxy_interactions_influence_active_galactic_nuclei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss-iv_manga_how_galaxy_interactions_influence_active_galactic_nuclei/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joshua L. Steffen
We present a comparative study of active galactic nuclei (AGN) between galaxy pairs and isolated galaxies with the final data release of the MaNGA integral field spectroscopic survey. We build a sample of 391 kinematic galaxy pairs within the footprint of the survey and select AGN using the survey&amp;rsquo;s spectra. We use the comoving volume densities of the AGN samples to quantify the effects that tidal interactions have on the triggering of nuclear accretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating the collapse of rotating primordial gas clouds to study the survival possibility of Pop III protostars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.10789/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.10789/</guid>
      <description>Shubham Raghuvanshi
It has been argued that the low-mass primordial stars ($m_{\rm Pop III}\,\leq 0.8\,M_\odot$) are likely to enter the main sequence and hence possibly be found in the present-day Galaxy. However, due to limitations in existing numerical capabilities, current three-dimensional (3D) &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;simulations&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; of disk fragmentation are capable of following only a few thousands of years of evolution after the formation of the first protostar. In this work we use a modified version of {\sc Gadget}-2 smoothed particle hydrodynamics(SPH) code to present the results of non-linear collapse of the gas clouds associated with various degrees of initial solid body rotation (parameterized by $β$) using a piecewise polytropic equation of state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of the structure and kinematics of the Galaxy according to VLBI astrometry of masers and radio stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_the_structure_and_kinematics_of_the_galaxy_according_to_vlbi_astrometry_of_masers_and_radio_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_the_structure_and_kinematics_of_the_galaxy_according_to_vlbi_astrometry_of_masers_and_radio_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. V. Bobylev
In recent years, radio interferometric observations have achieved high accuracy in determining the absolute values of trigonometric parallaxes and proper motions of maser radiation sources and radio stars. The error in determining the trigonometric parallaxes of these objects averages about 10 microarcseconds, which allows us to confidently study the geometric and kinematic properties of the distribution of stars located at great distances from the Sun, up to the center of the Galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synergy between CSST galaxy survey and gravitational-wave observation: Inferring the Hubble constant from dark standard sirens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synergy_between_csst_galaxy_survey_and_gravitational-wave_observation_inferring_the_hubble_constant_from_dark_standard_sirens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synergy_between_csst_galaxy_survey_and_gravitational-wave_observation_inferring_the_hubble_constant_from_dark_standard_sirens/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ji-Yu Song
Gravitational waves (GWs) from compact binary coalescences encode the absolute luminosity distances of GW sources. Once the redshifts of GW sources are known, one can use the distance-redshift relation to constrain cosmological parameters. One way to obtain the redshifts is to localize GW sources by GW observations and then use galaxy catalogs to determine redshifts from a statistical analysis of redshift information of the potential host galaxies, and such GW data are commonly referred to as dark sirens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Measuring Physical Parameters in Galaxies: A Critical Assessment of Spectral Energy Distribution Fitting Techniques</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_art_of_measuring_physical_parameters_in_galaxies_a_critical_assessment_of_spectral_energy_distribution_fitting_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_art_of_measuring_physical_parameters_in_galaxies_a_critical_assessment_of_spectral_energy_distribution_fitting_techniques/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camilla Pacifici
The study of galaxy evolution hinges on our ability to interpret multi-wavelength galaxy observations in terms of their physical properties. To do this, we rely on spectral energy distribution (SED) models which allow us to infer physical parameters from spectrophotometric data. In recent years, thanks to the wide and deep multi-waveband galaxy surveys, the volume of high quality data have significantly increased. Alongside the increased data, algorithms performing SED fitting have improved, including better modeling prescriptions, newer templates, and more extensive sampling in wavelength space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The formation of the brightest cluster galaxy and intracluster light in cosmological N-body simulations with the Galaxy Replacement Technique</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_formation_of_the_brightest_cluster_galaxy_and_intracluster_light_in_cosmological_n-body_simulations_with_the_galaxy_replacement_technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_formation_of_the_brightest_cluster_galaxy_and_intracluster_light_in_cosmological_n-body_simulations_with_the_galaxy_replacement_technique/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyungwon Chun
We investigate the formation channels of the intracluster light (ICL) and the brightest cluster galaxy (BCG) in clusters at $z=0$. For this, we perform multi-resolution cosmological N-body simulations using the &amp;ldquo;Galaxy Replacement Technique&amp;rdquo; (GRT). We study the formation channels of the ICL and BCG as a function of distance from the cluster center and the dynamical state of the clusters at $z=0$. To do this, we trace back the stars of the ICL and BCG, and identify the stellar components in which they existed when they first fell into the clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The molecular gas kinematics in the host galaxy of non-repeating FRB 180924B</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_molecular_gas_kinematics_in_the_host_galaxy_of_non-repeating_frb_180924b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_molecular_gas_kinematics_in_the_host_galaxy_of_non-repeating_frb_180924b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tzu-Yin Hsu
Fast radio bursts (FRBs) are millisecond-duration transients with large dispersion measures. The origin of FRBs is still mysterious. One of the methods to comprehend FRB origin is to probe the physical environments of FRB host galaxies. Mapping molecular-gas kinematics in FRB host galaxies is critical because it results in star formation that is likely connected to the birth of FRB progenitors. However, most previous works of FRB host galaxies have focused on its stellar component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The N5K Challenge: Non-Limber Integration for LSST Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_n5k_challenge_non-limber_integration_for_lsst_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_n5k_challenge_non-limber_integration_for_lsst_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. D. Leonard
The rapidly increasing statistical power of cosmological imaging surveys requires us to reassess the regime of validity for various approximations that accelerate the calculation of relevant theoretical predictions. In this paper, we present the results of the &amp;lsquo;N5K non-Limber integration challenge&amp;rsquo;, the goal of which was to quantify the performance of different approaches to calculating the angular power spectrum of galaxy number counts and cosmic shear data without invoking the so-called &amp;lsquo;Limber approximation&amp;rsquo;, in the context of the Rubin Observatory Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of double-peak emission-line galaxies: rotating discs, bars or galaxy mergers?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.02529/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.02529/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Maschmann
Emission lines with a double-peak (DP) shape, detected in the centre of &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxies&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;, have been extensively used in the past to identify peculiar kinematics such as dual active galactic nuclei, outflows or &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;mergers&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;. From a large DP &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; sample, a connection to minor &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;merger&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxies&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; with ongoing star formation was suggested. To gain a better understanding of different mechanisms creating a DP signature, we here explore synthetic SDSS spectroscopic observations computed from disc models and simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of double-peak emission-line galaxies: rotating discs, bars or galaxy mergers?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_double-peak_emission-line_galaxies_rotating_discs_bars_or_galaxy_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_double-peak_emission-line_galaxies_rotating_discs_bars_or_galaxy_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Maschmann
Emission lines with a double-peak (DP) shape, detected in the centre of galaxies, have been extensively used in the past to identify peculiar kinematics such as dual active galactic nuclei, outflows or mergers. From a large DP galaxy sample, a connection to minor merger galaxies with ongoing star formation was suggested. To gain a better understanding of different mechanisms creating a DP signature, we here explore synthetic SDSS spectroscopic observations computed from disc models and simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PHANGS-JWST Treasury Survey: Star Formation, Feedback, and Dust Physics at High Angular resolution in Nearby GalaxieS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_phangs-jwst_treasury_survey_star_formation_feedback_and_dust_physics_at_high_angular_resolution_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_phangs-jwst_treasury_survey_star_formation_feedback_and_dust_physics_at_high_angular_resolution_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Janice C. Lee
The PHANGS collaboration has been building a reference dataset for the multi-scale, multi-phase study of star formation and the interstellar medium in nearby galaxies. With the successful launch and commissioning of JWST, we can now obtain high-resolution infrared imaging to probe the youngest stellar populations and dust emission on the scales of star clusters and molecular clouds ($\sim$5-50 pc). In Cycle 1, PHANGS is conducting an 8-band imaging survey from 2-21$\mu$m of 19 nearby spiral galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prevalence and influence of circumstellar material around hydrogen-rich supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_prevalence_and_influence_of_circumstellar_material_around_hydrogen-rich_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_prevalence_and_influence_of_circumstellar_material_around_hydrogen-rich_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rachel J. Bruch
Spectroscopic detection of transient narrow emission lines (flash-ionisation features) traces the presence of circumstellar material (CSM) around massive stars exploding as core-collapse supernovae. Transient emission lines disappearing shortly after the SN explosion suggest that the spatial extent of this material is compact; hence implying that the progenitor star experienced episodes of enhanced mass loss shortly prior to explosion. The early light curves of Type II supernovae (SNe II) are assumed to be initially powered by shock-cooling emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure and composition of multiphase galactic winds in a Large Magellanic Cloud mass simulated galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_structure_and_composition_of_multiphase_galactic_winds_in_a_large_magellanic_cloud_mass_simulated_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_structure_and_composition_of_multiphase_galactic_winds_in_a_large_magellanic_cloud_mass_simulated_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ulrich P. Steinwandel
We present the first results from a high resolution simulation with a focus on galactic wind driving for an isolated galaxy with a halo mass of $\sim 10^{11}$ M${\odot}$ (similar to the Large Magellanic Cloud) and a total gas mass of $\sim 6 \times 10^{8}$ M${\odot}$, resulting in $\sim 10^{8}$ gas cells at $\sim 4$ M${\odot}$ mass resolution. We adopt a resolved stellar feedback model with non-equilibrium cooling and heating, including photoelectric heating and photo-ionizing radiation, as well as supernovae (SNe), coupled to the second order meshless finite mass (MFM) method for hydrodynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Type Ibn Supernova 2019kbj -- Indications for Diversity in Type Ibn Supernova Progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ibn_supernova_2019kbj_--_indications_for_diversity_in_type_ibn_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ibn_supernova_2019kbj_--_indications_for_diversity_in_type_ibn_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tom Ben-Ami
Type Ibn supernovae (SNe) are a rare class of stellar explosions whose progenitor systems are not yet well determined. We present and analyze observations of the Type Ibn SN 2019kbj, and model its light curve in order to constrain its progenitor and explosion parameters. SN 2019kbj shows roughly constant temperature during the first month after peak, indicating a power source (likely CSM interaction) that keeps the continuum emission hot at ~15000K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THESAN-HR: How does reionization impact early galaxy evolution?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thesan-hr_how_does_reionization_impact_early_galaxy_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thesan-hr_how_does_reionization_impact_early_galaxy_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Josh Borrow
Early galaxies were the radiation source for reionization, with the photoheating feedback from the reionization process expected to reduce the efficiency of star formation in low mass haloes. Hence, to fully understand reionization and galaxy formation, we must study their impact on each other. The THESAN project has so far aimed to study the impact of galaxy formation physics on reionization, but here we present the new THESAN simulations with a factor 50 higher resolution ($m_{\rm b} \approx 10^4$~M$\odot$) that aim to self-consistently study the back-reaction of reionization on galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three dimensional magnetorotational core-collapse supernova explosions of a 39 solar mass progenitor star</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jade Powell
We perform three-dimensional simulations of magnetorotational supernovae using a $39,M_{\odot}$ progenitor star with two different initial magnetic field strengths of $10^{10}$ G and $10^{12}$ G in the core. Both models rapidly undergo shock revival and their explosion energies asymptote within a few hundred milliseconds to values of $\gtrsim 2\times10^{51}$ erg after conservatively correcting for the binding energy of the envelope. Magnetically collimated, non-relativistic jets form in both models, though the jets are subject to non-axisymmetric instabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultraviolet imaging observations of three jellyfish galaxies: Star formation suppression in the centre and ongoing star formation in stripped tails</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ultraviolet_imaging_observations_of_three_jellyfish_galaxies_star_formation_suppression_in_the_centre_and_ongoing_star_formation_in_stripped_tails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ultraviolet_imaging_observations_of_three_jellyfish_galaxies_star_formation_suppression_in_the_centre_and_ongoing_star_formation_in_stripped_tails/</guid>
      <description>First author: Koshy George
Spiral galaxies undergo strong ram-pressure effects when they fall into the galaxy cluster potential. As a consequence, their gas is stripped to form extended tails within which star formation can happen, giving them the typical jellyfish appearance. The ultraviolet imaging observations of jellyfish galaxies provide an opportunity to understand ongoing star formation in the stripped tails. We report the ultraviolet observations of the jellyfish galaxies JW39, JO60, JO194 and compare with observations in optical continuum and $\mathrm{H}{\alpha}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding globular cluster abundances through nuclear reactions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03648/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03648/</guid>
      <description>P Adsley
Globular clusters contain multiple stellar populations, with some previous generation of stars polluting the current stars with heavier elements. Understanding the history of globular clusters is helpful in understanding how galaxies merged and evolved and therefore constraining the site or sites of this historic pollution is a priority. The acceptable temperature and density conditions of these polluting sites depend on critical &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;reaction&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; rates. In this paper, three experimental studies helping to constrain astrophysically important &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;reaction&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; rates are briefly discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What it takes to solve the Hubble tension through modifications of cosmological recombination</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/what_it_takes_to_solve_the_hubble_tension_through_modifications_of_cosmological_recombination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/what_it_takes_to_solve_the_hubble_tension_through_modifications_of_cosmological_recombination/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nanoom Lee
We develop a novel general formalism allowing us to obtain values of the Hubble constant in agreement with late-time observables without degrading the fit to Cosmic Microwave Background data, considering perturbative modifications around a fiducial $\Lambda$CDM cosmology. Taking as proof-of-principle the case of a time-varying electron mass and fine structure constant, we demonstrate that a modified recombination can solve the Hubble tension and lower $S_8$ to match weak lensing measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
