<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>most recent update (Mon Jan 16 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-mon-jan-16-2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in most recent update (Mon Jan 16 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-mon-jan-16-2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Globular Clusters in NGC 4839 Falling into Coma: Evidence for the Second Infall?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05269/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05269/</guid>
      <description>Seong-A Oh
NGC 4839 is the brightest galaxy (cD) of the NGC 4839 group at $R\approx 1$ Mpc in the south-west of the Coma cluster, which is known to be falling into Coma. However, it has been controversial whether it is in the first phase of infall or in the second phase of infall after passing the Coma center. We present a wide field study of globular clusters (GCs) in NGC 4839 and its environment based on Hyper Suprime-Cam $gr$ images in the Subaru archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Populations in Low-mass Globular Clusters: Eridanus</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05410/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05410/</guid>
      <description>Yue Wang
Multiple populations (MPs), characterized by variations in light elemental abundances, have been found in stellar clusters in the Milky Way, Magellanic Clouds, as well as several other dwarf galaxies. Based on a large amount of observations, mass has been suggested to be a key parameter affecting the presence and appearance of MPs in stellar clusters. To further investigate the existence of MPs in low-mass clusters and explore the mass threshold for MP formation, we carried out a project studying the stellar population composition in several low-mass Galactic globular clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength Analysis of a Nearby Heavily Obscured AGN in NGC 449</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_analysis_of_a_nearby_heavily_obscured_agn_in_ngc_449/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_analysis_of_a_nearby_heavily_obscured_agn_in_ngc_449/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaotong Guo
We presented the multiwavelength analysis of a heavily obscured active galactic nucleus (AGN) in NGC 449. We first constructed a broadband X-ray spectrum using the latest NuSTAR and XMM-Newton data. Its column density ($\simeq 10^{24} \rm{cm}^{-2}$) and photon index ($\Gamma\simeq 2.4$) were reliably obtained by analyzing the broadband X-ray spectrum. However, the scattering fraction and the intrinsic X-ray luminosity could not be well constrained. Combined with the information obtained from the mid-infrared (mid-IR) spectrum and spectral energy distribution (SED) fitting, we derived its intrinsic X-ray luminosity ($\simeq 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Gaussianity in the cosmic microwave background from loop quantum cosmology</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussianity_in_the_cosmic_microwave_background_from_loop_quantum_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-gaussianity_in_the_cosmic_microwave_background_from_loop_quantum_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>First author: Roshna K
Primordial non-Gaussianity has set strong constraints on models of the early universe. Studies have shown that Loop Quantum Cosmology (LQC), which is an attempt to extend inflationary scenario to planck scales, leads to a strongly scale dependent and oscillatory non-Gaussianity. In particular, the non-Gaussianity function $f_{_{\rm NL}}(k_1,, k_2,, k_3)$ generated in LQC, though similar to that generated during slow roll inflation at small scales, is highly scale dependent and oscillatory at large wavelengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pegasus W: An Ultra-Faint Dwarf Galaxy Outside the Halo of M31 Not Quenched by Reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04157/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04157/</guid>
      <description>Kristen. B. W. McQuinn
We report the discovery of an ultrafaint dwarf (UFD) galaxy, Pegasus W, located on the far side of the Milky Way-M31 system and outside the virial radius of M31. The distance to the galaxy is 915 (+60/-91) kpc, measured using the luminosity of horizontal branch (HB) stars identified in Hubble Space Telescope optical imaging. The galaxy has a half-light radius (r_h) of 100 (+11/-13) pc, M_V = -7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fornax3D project: Environmental effects on the assembly of dynamically cold disks in Fornax cluster galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fornax3d_project_environmental_effects_on_the_assembly_of_dynamically_cold_disks_in_fornax_cluster_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_fornax3d_project_environmental_effects_on_the_assembly_of_dynamically_cold_disks_in_fornax_cluster_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Ding
We apply a population-orbit superposition method to 16 galaxies in the Fornax cluster observed with MUSE/VLT in the context of the Fornax3D project. By fitting the luminosity distribution, stellar kinematics, and age and metallicity maps simultaneously, we obtained the internal stellar orbit distribution, as well as the age and metallicity distribution of stars on different orbits for each galaxy. Based on the model, we decompose each galaxy into a dynamically cold disk (orbital circularity $\lambda_z\ge0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rebrightening of a ROSAT-selected tidal disruption event: repeated weak partial disruption flares from a quiescent galaxy?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_rebrightening_of_a_rosat-selected_tidal_disruption_event_repeated_weak_partial_disruption_flares_from_a_quiescent_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_rebrightening_of_a_rosat-selected_tidal_disruption_event_repeated_weak_partial_disruption_flares_from_a_quiescent_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Malyali
The ROSAT-selected tidal disruption event (TDE) candidate RX J133157.6-324319.7 (J1331), was detected in 1993 as a bright (0.2-2 keV flux of $(1.0 \pm 0.1) \times 10^{-12}$ erg s$^{-1}$ cm$^{-2}$), ultra-soft ($kT=0.11 \pm 0.03$ keV) X-ray flare from a quiescent galaxy ($z=0.05189$). During its fifth All-Sky survey (eRASS5) in 2022, SRG/eROSITA detected the repeated flaring of J1331, where it had rebrightened to an observed 0.2-2 keV flux of $(6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The splashback radius of groups and clusters of galaxies at low redshifts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_splashback_radius_of_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies_at_low_redshifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_splashback_radius_of_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies_at_low_redshifts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Flera G. Kopylova
We present a study of the distribution of galaxies along the radius of 157 groups and clusters of galaxies (200~km~s$^{-1}$ &amp;lt; $\sigma$ &amp;lt; 1100~km~s$^{-1}$) of the local Universe (0.01 &amp;lt; $z$ &amp;lt; 0.1). We introduced a new boundary of galaxy systems and identified it with the splashback radius $R_{sp}$. We also identified the central region of galaxy systems with a radius of $R_c$. These radii are defined by the observed integrated distribution of the total number of galaxies depending on the squared distance from the center of the groups/clusters coinciding, as a rule, with the brightest galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tucana dwarf spheroidal: a distant backsplash galaxy of M31?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.02229/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.02229/</guid>
      <description>Isabel M. E. Santos-Santos,
We use the APOSTLE Local Group (LG) cosmological hydro-simulations to examine the properties of &amp;amp;#34;backsplash&amp;amp;#34; galaxies, i.e, dwarfs which were within the virial boundaries of the Milky Way (MW) or M31 in the past, but are today outside their virial radius ($r_{200}$). More than half of all dwarfs between $1-2\,r_{200}$ of each primary are backsplash. More distant backsplash systems, i.e., those reaching distances well beyond $2\,r_{200}$, are typically close to apocentre of nearly radial orbits, and, therefore, essentially at rest relative to their primary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward accurate measurement of property-dependent galaxy clustering: II. Tests of the smoothed density-corrected $V_{\rm max}$ method</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toward_accurate_measurement_of_property-dependent_galaxy_clustering_ii._tests_of_the_smoothed_density-corrected__v__rm_max__method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toward_accurate_measurement_of_property-dependent_galaxy_clustering_ii._tests_of_the_smoothed_density-corrected__v__rm_max__method/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lei Yang
We present a smoothed density-corrected $V_{\rm max}$ technique for building a random catalog for property-dependent galaxy clustering estimation. This approach is essentially based on the density-corrected $V_{\rm max}$ method of Cole(2011), with three improvements to the original method. To validate the improved method, we generate two sets of flux-limited samples from two independent mock catalogs with different $k+e$ corrections. By comparing the two-point correlation functions, our results demonstrate that the random catalog created by the smoothed density-corrected $V_{\rm max}$ approach provides a more accurate and precise measurement for both sets of mock samples than the commonly used $V_{\rm max}$ method and redshift shuffled method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black hole and galaxy co-evolution in radio-loud AGN at z ~ 0.3-4</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_and_galaxy_co-evolution_in_radio-loud_agn_at_z_~_0.3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/black_hole_and_galaxy_co-evolution_in_radio-loud_agn_at_z_~_0.3-4/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Poitevineau
There exists a well known relation between the mass of the supermassive black hole (SMBH) in the center of galaxies and their bulge mass or central velocity dispersion. This suggests a co-evolution between SMBH and their galaxy hosts. Our aim is to study this relation specifically for radio loud galaxies, and as a function of redshift $z$. We selected a sample of radio-galaxies and AGN by cross-matching the low radio frequency sources from VLA FIRST with spectroscopically confirmed sources from wide field surveys including SDSS DR14 ugriz and DES DR2 grzY in optical, WISE in infrared, and the Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) spectroscopic survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrono-chemodynamical analysis of the globular cluster NGC 6355: Looking for the fundamental bricks of the Bulge</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05227/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05227/</guid>
      <description>Stefano O. Souza
The information on Galactic assembly time is imprinted on the chemodynamics of globular clusters. This makes them important probes that help us to understand the formation and evolution of the Milky Way. Discerning between in-situ and ex-situ origin of these objects is difficult when we study the Galactic bulge, which is the most complex and mixed component of the Milky Way. To investigate the early evolution of the Galactic bulge, we analysed the globular cluster NGC 6355.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO Excitation in High-z Main Sequence Analogues: Resolved CO(4-3)/CO(3-2) Line Ratios in DYNAMO Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co_excitation_in_high-z_main_sequence_analogues_resolved_co4-3_co3-2_line_ratios_in_dynamo_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co_excitation_in_high-z_main_sequence_analogues_resolved_co4-3_co3-2_line_ratios_in_dynamo_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Lenkić
The spectral line energy distribution of carbon monoxide contains information about the physical conditions of the star forming molecular hydrogen gas; however, the relation to local radiation field properties is poorly constrained. Using ~ 1-2 kpc scale ALMA observations of CO(3-2) and CO(4-3), we characterize the CO(4-3)/CO(3-2) line ratios of local analogues of main sequence galaxies at z ~ 1-2, drawn from the DYNAMO sample. We measure CO(4-3)/CO(3-2) across the disk of each galaxy and find a median line ratio of $R_{43} = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-evolution of Dust and Chemistry in Galaxy Simulations with a Resolved Interstellar Medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co-evolution_of_dust_and_chemistry_in_galaxy_simulations_with_a_resolved_interstellar_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/co-evolution_of_dust_and_chemistry_in_galaxy_simulations_with_a_resolved_interstellar_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chia-Yu Hu
Nearby dwarf irregular galaxies are ideal laboratories for studying the interstellar medium (ISM) at low metallicity, which is expected to be common for galaxies at very high redshift that will be observed by the James Webb Space Telescope. We present the first high-resolution (~0.2 pc) hydrodynamical simulations of an isolated low-metallicity ($0.1~Z_\odot$) dwarf galaxy coupled with a time-dependent chemistry network and a dust evolution model where dust is locally produced and destroyed by various processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological-Scale HI Distribution Around Galaxies and AGN Probed with the HETDEX and SDSS Spectroscopic Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological-scale_hi_distribution_around_galaxies_and_agn_probed_with_the_hetdex_and_sdss_spectroscopic_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological-scale_hi_distribution_around_galaxies_and_agn_probed_with_the_hetdex_and_sdss_spectroscopic_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dongsheng Sun
We present cosmological-scale 3-dimensional (3D) neutral hydrogen ({\sc Hi}) tomographic maps at $z=2-3$ over a total of 837 deg$^2$ in two blank fields that are developed with Ly$\alpha$ forest absorptions of 14,736 background Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) quasars at $z$=2.08-3.67. Using the tomographic maps, we investigate the large-scale ($\gtrsim 10$ $h^{-1}$cMpc) average {\sc Hi} radial profiles and two-direction profiles of the line-of-sight (LoS) and transverse (TS) directions around galaxies and AGN at $z=2-3$ identified by the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy eXperiment (HETDEX) and SDSS surveys, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLARES IX: The Physical Mechanisms Driving Compact Galaxy Formation and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flares_ix_the_physical_mechanisms_driving_compact_galaxy_formation_and_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flares_ix_the_physical_mechanisms_driving_compact_galaxy_formation_and_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: William J. Roper
In the FLARES (First Light And Reionisation Epoch Simulations) suite of hydrodynamical simulations, we find the high redshift ($z&amp;gt;5$) intrinsic size-luminosity relation is, surprisingly, negatively sloped. However, after including the effects of dust attenuation we find a positively sloped UV observed size-luminosity relation in good agreement with other simulated and observational studies. In this work, we extend this analysis to probe the underlying physical mechanisms driving the formation and evolution of the compact galaxies driving the negative size-mass/size-luminosity relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the origin of stars in the Galaxy impacts the composition of planetary building blocks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_the_origin_of_stars_in_the_galaxy_impacts_the_composition_of_planetary_building_blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_the_origin_of_stars_in_the_galaxy_impacts_the_composition_of_planetary_building_blocks/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Cabral
Context. Our Galaxy is composed of different stellar populations with varying chemical abundances, which are thought to imprint the composition of planet building blocks (PBBs). As such, the properties of stars should affect the properties of planets and small bodies formed in their systems. In this context, high-resolution spectroscopic surveys open a window into the chemical links between and their host stars. Aims. We aim to determine the PBB composition trends for various stellar populations across the Galaxy by comparing the two large spectroscopic surveys APOGEE and GALAH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Dynamical Properties of Globular Clusters through a Family of Lowered Isothermal Models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04868/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04868/</guid>
      <description>Chia-Hsuan Cheng,
To investigate the dynamical properties of globular clusters, the surface brightness and kinematic data were collected and fitted to a family of lowered isothermal models called LIMEPY models. For 18 studied globular clusters, the amounts of concentration, truncation, and anisotropy were determined. In addition, the cluster mass, half-mass radius, distance, and mass-to-light ratio were also obtained. In general, LIMEPY models could describe these clusters well. Among these 18 clusters, NGC 5139, NGC 6388, and NGC 7078 were claimed to be candidates to host intermediate-mass black holes in literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematics and Origin of Gas in the Disk Galaxy NGC 2655</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kinematics_and_origin_of_gas_in_the_disk_galaxy_ngc_2655/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kinematics_and_origin_of_gas_in_the_disk_galaxy_ngc_2655/</guid>
      <description>First author: Olga K. Sil&amp;rsquo;chenko
The new observational data concerning distribution, excitation, and kinematics of the ionized gas in the giant early-type disk galaxy NGC 2655 obtained at the 6m telescope of the Special Astrophysical Observatory (SAO RAS) and at the 2.5m telescope of the Caucasian Mountain Observatory of the Sternberg Astronomical Institute (CMO SAI MSU) are presented in this work. The joint analysis of these and earlier spectral observations has allowed us to make a conclusion about multiple nature of the gas in NGC 2655.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic fields do not suppress global star formation in low metallicity dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.04922/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.04922/</guid>
      <description>David J. Whitworth
Many studies concluded that magnetic fields suppress star formation in molecular clouds and Milky Way like galaxies. However, most of these studies are based on fully developed fields that have reached the saturation level, with little work on investigating how an initial weak primordial field affects star formation in low metallicity environments. In this paper, we investigate the impact of a weak initial field on low metallicity dwarf galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical simulations of the random angular momentum in convection II: delayed explosions of red supergiants following &#34;failed&#39;&#39; supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_simulations_of_the_random_angular_momentum_in_convection_ii_delayed_explosions_of_red_supergiants_following_failed_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_simulations_of_the_random_angular_momentum_in_convection_ii_delayed_explosions_of_red_supergiants_following_failed_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrea Antoni
When collapse of the iron core in a massive red or yellow supergiant does not lead to a neutrino-driven explosion, a significant fraction of the convective hydrogen envelope will fall in towards the black hole formed from the collapsing core. The random velocity field in the convective envelope results in finite specific angular momentum in each infalling shell. Using 3D hydrodynamical simulations, we follow the infall of this material to small radii, resolving the circularization radii of the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of the Probability of Interaction of Globular Clusters with Each Other and with the Galactic Center on the Cosmological Time Scale According to Gaia DR2 Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04936/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04936/</guid>
      <description>Maryna Ishchenko,
This study is aimed at investigating the dynamic evolution of the orbits of stellar globular clusters (GCs). To integrate the orbits backward in time, the authors use models of the time-varying potentials derived from cosmological simulations, which are closest to the potential of the Galaxy. This allows for estimating the probability of close passages (collisions) of GCs with respect to each other and the Galactic center (GalC) in the Galaxy undergoing dynamic changes in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of the Probability of Interaction of Globular Clusters with Each Other and with the Galactic Center on the Cosmological Time Scale According to Gaia DR2 Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_analysis_of_the_probability_of_interaction_of_globular_clusters_with_each_other_and_with_the_galactic_center_on_the_cosmological_time_scale_according_to_gaia_dr2_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/statistical_analysis_of_the_probability_of_interaction_of_globular_clusters_with_each_other_and_with_the_galactic_center_on_the_cosmological_time_scale_according_to_gaia_dr2_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maryna Ishchenko
This study is aimed at investigating the dynamic evolution of the orbits of stellar globular clusters (GCs). To integrate the orbits backward in time, the authors use models of the time-varying potentials derived from cosmological simulations, which are closest to the potential of the Galaxy. This allows for estimating the probability of close passages (collisions) of GCs with respect to each other and the Galactic center (GalC) in the Galaxy undergoing dynamic changes in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Direct-Method Oxygen Abundance of Typical Dwarf Galaxies at Cosmic High-Noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.05976/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.05976/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Gburek,
We present a Keck/MOSFIRE, rest-optical, composite spectrum of 16 typical, gravitationally-lensed, star-forming, dwarf galaxies at $1.7 \lesssim z \lesssim 2.6$ ($z_{\rm{mean}}=2.30$), all chosen independent of emission-line strength. These galaxies have a median stellar mass of $\log(M_\ast/\rm{M_\odot})_{\rm{med}} = 8.29^{+0.51}_{-0.43}$ and a median star formation rate of $\rm{SFR_{Hα}^{med} = 2.25^{+2.15}_{-1.26}\ M_\odot\ yr^{-1}}$. We measure the faint, electron-temperature-sensitive, $[O III]$ $λ$4363 emission line at $2.5σ$ ($4.1σ$) significance when considering a bootstrapped (statistical-only) uncertainty spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The e-TidalGCs Project: Modeling the extra-tidal features generated by Galactic globular clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05166/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05166/</guid>
      <description>Salvatore Ferrone
We present the e-TidalGCs Project which aims at modeling and predicting the extra-tidal features surrounding all Galactic globular clusters for which 6D phase space information, masses and sizes are available (currently 159 globular clusters). We focus the analysis and presentation of the results on the distribution of extra-tidal material on the sky, and on the different structures found at different heliocentric distances. We emphasize the wide variety of morphologies found: beyond the canonical tidal tails, our models reveal that the extra-tidal features generated by globular clusters take a wide variety of shapes, from thin and elongated shapes, to thick, and complex halo-like structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hubble Space Telescope UV Legacy Survey of Galactic Globular Clusters. XXIV. Differences in internal kinematics of multiple stellar populations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04148/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04148/</guid>
      <description>M. Libralato
Our understanding of the kinematic properties of multiple stellar populations (mPOPs) in Galactic globular clusters (GCs) is still limited compared to what we know about their chemical and photometric characteristics. Such limitation arises from the lack of a comprehensive observational investigation of this topic. Here we present the first homogeneous kinematic analysis of mPOPs in 56 GCs based on high-precision proper motions computed with Hubble Space Telescope data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The implications of large binding energies of massive stripped core collapse supernova progenitors on the explosion mechanism</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_implications_of_large_binding_energies_of_massive_stripped_core_collapse_supernova_progenitors_on_the_explosion_mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_implications_of_large_binding_energies_of_massive_stripped_core_collapse_supernova_progenitors_on_the_explosion_mechanism/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dmitry Shishkin
We examine the binding energy of massive stripped-envelope core collapse supernova (SECCSN) progenitors with the stellar evolution code MESA, and find that only the jittering jets explosion mechanism can account for explosions where carbon-oxygen cores with masses of $&amp;gt;20M_\odot$ collapse to leave a neutron star (NS) remnant. We calculate the binding energy at core collapse under the assumption that the remnant is a NS. Namely, stellar gas above mass coordinate of $~1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The many reasons that the rotation curves of low-mass galaxies can fail as tracers of their matter distributions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_many_reasons_that_the_rotation_curves_of_low-mass_galaxies_can_fail_as_tracers_of_their_matter_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_many_reasons_that_the_rotation_curves_of_low-mass_galaxies_can_fail_as_tracers_of_their_matter_distributions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Eleanor R. Downing
It is routinely assumed that galaxy rotation curves are equal to their circular velocity curves (modulo some corrections) such that they are good dynamical mass tracers. We take a visualisation-driven approach to exploring the limits of the validity of this assumption for a sample of $33$ low-mass galaxies ($60&amp;lt;v_\mathrm{max}/\mathrm{km},\mathrm{s}^{-1}&amp;lt;120$) from the APOSTLE suite of cosmological hydrodynamical simulations. Only $3$ of these have rotation curves nearly equal to their circular velocity curves at $z=0$, the rest are undergoing a wide variety of dynamical perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path from the Chinese and Japanese Observations of Supernova 1181 AD, to a Type Iax Supernova, to the Merger of CO and ONe White Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_path_from_the_chinese_and_japanese_observations_of_supernova_1181_ad_to_a_type_iax_supernova_to_the_merger_of_co_and_one_white_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_path_from_the_chinese_and_japanese_observations_of_supernova_1181_ad_to_a_type_iax_supernova_to_the_merger_of_co_and_one_white_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bradley E. Schaefer
In 1181 AD, Chinese and Japanese observers reported a bright Guest Star&#39; in the constellation Chuanshe, unmoving and visible for 185 days. In 2013, D. Patchick discovered a unique nebula surrounding a unique star, with two groups attributing this structure, named Pa 30&amp;rsquo;, to be the supernova remnant of SN 1181, as a sub-subclass of supernova, the low-luminosity Type Iax. Here, I provide a wide range of new observational evidence: First, a detailed analysis of the original Chinese and Japanese reports places the `Guest Star&amp;rsquo; of 1181 into a small region with the only interesting source being Pa 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The satellite population around luminous red galaxies in the 25 square degree DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys Early Data Release</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_satellite_population_around_luminous_red_galaxies_in_the_25_square_degree_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys_early_data_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_satellite_population_around_luminous_red_galaxies_in_the_25_square_degree_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys_early_data_release/</guid>
      <description>First author: Melinda Townsend
Luminous Red Galaxies, or LRGs, are representative of the most massive galaxies and were originally selected in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey as good tracers of large scale structure. They are dominated by by uniformly old stellar populations, have low star formation rates, early type morphologies, and little cold gas. Despite having old stellar populations and little in situ star formation, studies have shown that they have grown their stellar mass since z=1, implying that they grow predominantly via the accretion of satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does a typical full-disc around a post-AGB binary look like? -- Radiative transfer models reproducing PIONIER, GRAVITY, and MATISSE data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02622/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.02622/</guid>
      <description>A. Corporaal
(abridged) Stable circumbinary discs around evolved post-Asymptotic Giant branch (post-AGB) binary systems show many similarities with protoplanetary discs around young stellar objects. These discs can provide constraints on both binary evolution and the formation of macrostructures within circumstellar discs. Here we focus on one post-AGB binary system: IRAS08544-4431. We aim to refine the physical model of IRAS08544-4431 with a radiative transfer treatment and continue the near-infrared and mid-infrared interferometric analysis covering the H-, K-, L-, and N-bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Study of Ia-CSM Supernovae from the ZTF Bright Transient Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_systematic_study_of_ia-csm_supernovae_from_the_ztf_bright_transient_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_systematic_study_of_ia-csm_supernovae_from_the_ztf_bright_transient_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yashvi Sharma
Among the supernovae (SNe) that show strong interaction with the circumstellar medium, there is a rare subclass of Type Ia supernovae, SNe Ia-CSM, that show strong narrow hydrogen emission lines much like SNe IIn but on top of a diluted over-luminous Type Ia spectrum. In the only previous systematic study of this class (Silverman et al. 2013), 16 objects were identified, 8 historic and 8 from the Palomar Transient Factory (PTF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended Corona Models of X-ray Reverberation in the AGN 1H~0707-495 and IRAS 13224-3809</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extended_corona_models_of_x-ray_reverberation_in_the_agn_1h~0707-495_and_iras_13224-3809/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extended_corona_models_of_x-ray_reverberation_in_the_agn_1h~0707-495_and_iras_13224-3809/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Hancock
We fit a new vertically extended corona model to previously measured reverberation time lags observed by \emph{XMM-Newton} in two extremely variable Narrow Line Seyfert 1 Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN), 1H~0707-495 and IRAS~13224-3809, in a variety of similarly observed flux groups and explore the model in all observations over a 16 year period. The model employs two X-ray sources located along the black hole rotational axis at height, $h_1$ and $h_2$ respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhomogeneous enrichment of radioactive nuclei in the Galaxy: Deposition of live Mn-53, Fe-60, Hf-182, and Pu-244 into deep-sea archives. Surfing the wave?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_enrichment_of_radioactive_nuclei_in_the_galaxy_deposition_of_live_mn-53_fe-60_hf-182_and_pu-244_into_deep-sea_archives._surfing_the_wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_enrichment_of_radioactive_nuclei_in_the_galaxy_deposition_of_live_mn-53_fe-60_hf-182_and_pu-244_into_deep-sea_archives._surfing_the_wave/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin Wehmeyer
While modelling the galactic chemical evolution (GCE) of stable elements provides insights to the formation history of the Galaxy and the relative contributions of nucleosynthesis sites, modelling the evolution of short-lived radioisotopes (SLRs) can provide supplementary timing information on recent nucleosynthesis. To study the evolution of SLRs, we need to understand their spatial distribution. Using a 3-dimensional GCE model, we investigated the evolution of four SLRs: Mn-53, Fe-60, Hf-182, and Pu-244 with the aim of explaining detections of recent (within the last $\approx$1-20 Myr) deposition of live Mn-53, Fe-60, and Pu-244 of extrasolar origin into deep-sea reservoirs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of Precessing Jets and the Formation of X-shaped Radio Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_precessing_jets_and_the_formation_of_x-shaped_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_precessing_jets_and_the_formation_of_x-shaped_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chris Nolting
Jet precession is sometimes invoked to explain asymmetries in radio galaxy (RG) jets and &amp;ldquo;X/S/Z-shape&amp;rdquo; radio galaxies, caused by the presence of a binary black hole companion to the source active galactic nucleus (AGN) or by accretion instabilities. We present a series of simulations of radio galaxy jet precession to examine how these sources would evolve over time, including a passive distribution of cosmic ray electrons (CRe) so we can model radio synchrotron emissions and create synthetic radio maps of the sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2020bio: A Double-peaked Type IIb Supernova with Evidence of Early-time Circumstellar Interaction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2020bio_a_double-peaked_type_iib_supernova_with_evidence_of_early-time_circumstellar_interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2020bio_a_double-peaked_type_iib_supernova_with_evidence_of_early-time_circumstellar_interaction/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Pellegrino
We present photometric and spectroscopic observations of SN 2020bio, a double-peaked Type IIb supernova (SN) discovered within a day of explosion, primarily obtained by Las Cumbres Observatory and Swift. SN 2020bio displays a rapid and long-lasting initial decline throughout the first week of its light curve, similar to other well-studied Type IIb SNe. This early-time emission is thought to originate from the cooling of the extended outer envelope of the progenitor star that is shock-heated by the SN explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar mass dependent galaxy size-dark matter halo radius relation unveiled by Subaru-HSC survey weak lensing measurements</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_mass_dependent_galaxy_size-dark_matter_halo_radius_relation_unveiled_by_subaru-hsc_survey_weak_lensing_measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/stellar_mass_dependent_galaxy_size-dark_matter_halo_radius_relation_unveiled_by_subaru-hsc_survey_weak_lensing_measurements/</guid>
      <description>First author: Preetish K. Mishra
We investigate the stellar mass-dependence of the galaxy size-dark matter halo radius relation for low redshift galaxies using weak gravitational lensing measurements. Our sample consists of $\sim$38,000 galaxies more massive than $10^{8} {\rm M}{\odot}h^{-2}$ and within $z&amp;lt;0.3$ drawn from the overlap of GAMA survey DR4 and HSC-SSP PDR2. We divide our sample into a number of stellar mass bins and measure stacked weak lensing signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong 21-cm fluctuations and anisotropy due to the line-of-sight effect of radio galaxies at cosmic dawn</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_21-cm_fluctuations_and_anisotropy_due_to_the_line-of-sight_effect_of_radio_galaxies_at_cosmic_dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_21-cm_fluctuations_and_anisotropy_due_to_the_line-of-sight_effect_of_radio_galaxies_at_cosmic_dawn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sudipta Sikder
The reported detection of the global 21-cm signal by the EDGES collaboration is significantly stronger than standard astrophysical predictions. One possible explanation is an early radio excess above the cosmic microwave background. Such a radio background could have been produced by high redshift galaxies, if they were especially efficient in producing low-frequency synchrotron radiation. We have previously studied the effects of such an inhomogeneous radio background on the 21-cm signal; however, we made a simplifying assumption of isotropy of the background seen by each hydrogen cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The alignment of galaxies at the Baryon Acoustic Oscillation scale</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alignment_of_galaxies_at_the_baryon_acoustic_oscillation_scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_alignment_of_galaxies_at_the_baryon_acoustic_oscillation_scale/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dennis van Dompseler
Massive elliptical galaxies align pointing towards each other in the structure of the Universe. Such alignments are well-described at large scales through a linear relation with respect to the tidal field of the large-scale structure. At such scales, galaxy alignments are sensitive to the presence of baryon acoustic oscillations (BAO). The shape of the BAO feature in galaxy alignment correlations differs from the traditional peak in the clustering correlation function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Core Normal Type Ia Supernova 2019np: An Overall Spherical Explosion with an Aspherical Surface Layer and an Aspherical 56Ni Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_core_normal_type_ia_supernova_2019np_an_overall_spherical_explosion_with_an_aspherical_surface_layer_and_an_aspherical_56ni_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_core_normal_type_ia_supernova_2019np_an_overall_spherical_explosion_with_an_aspherical_surface_layer_and_an_aspherical_56ni_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Hoeflich
Optical spectropolarimetry of the normal thermonuclear supernova SN2019np from -14.5 to +14.5 days relative to B-band maximum detected an intrinsic continuum polarization, p(cont), of 0.21+-0.09% at the first epoch. Between days -11.5 to +05, p(cont) remained about 0 and by day +14.5 was again significant at 0.19+-0.10%. Not considering the first epoch, the dominant axis of SiII(6355A) was roughly constant, staying close to the continuum until both rotated in opposite directions on day +14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gaia-ESO Survey: Preparing the ground for 4MOST &amp; WEAVE galactic surveys. Chemical evolution of lithium with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.08874/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.08874/</guid>
      <description>S. Nepal
With its origin coming from several sources (Big Bang, stars, cosmic rays) and given its strong depletion during its stellar lifetime, the lithium element is of great interest as its chemical evolution in the Milky Way is not well understood at present. To help constrain stellar and galactic chemical evolution models, numerous and precise lithium abundances are necessary for a large range of evolutionary stages, metallicities, and Galactic volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the mass spectrum of destroyed dwarf galaxies with the metallicity distribution function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04667/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04667/</guid>
      <description>Alis J. Deason
Accreted stellar populations are comprised of the remnants of destroyed galaxies, and often dominate the `stellar haloes&amp;amp;#39; of galaxies such as the Milky Way (MW). This ensemble of external contributors is a key indicator of the past assembly history of a galaxy. We introduce a novel statistical method that uses the unbinned metallicity distribution function (MDF) of a stellar population to estimate the mass spectrum of its progenitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the mass spectrum of destroyed dwarf galaxies with the metallicity distribution function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unravelling_the_mass_spectrum_of_destroyed_dwarf_galaxies_with_the_metallicity_distribution_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unravelling_the_mass_spectrum_of_destroyed_dwarf_galaxies_with_the_metallicity_distribution_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alis J. Deason
Accreted stellar populations are comprised of the remnants of destroyed galaxies, and often dominate the `stellar haloes&amp;rsquo; of galaxies such as the Milky Way (MW). This ensemble of external contributors is a key indicator of the past assembly history of a galaxy. We introduce a novel statistical method that uses the unbinned metallicity distribution function (MDF) of a stellar population to estimate the mass spectrum of its progenitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
