<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New_articles on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New_articles on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A non-repeating fast radio burst in a dwarf host galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_non-repeating_fast_radio_burst_in_a_dwarf_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_non-repeating_fast_radio_burst_in_a_dwarf_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shivani Bhandari
We present the discovery of as-of-yet non-repeating Fast Radio Burst (FRB) with the Australian Square Kilometer Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) as a part of the Commensal Real-time ASKAP Fast Transients (CRAFT) Survey. FRB 20210117A was detected at the center frequency of 1271.5 MHz with a dispersion measure (DM) of $728.95\pm 0.01$ pc cm$^{-3}$. The sub-arcsecond localization of the burst led to the identification of its host galaxy at a $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Mode Gas Accretion on Two Galaxy Groups at z$\sim$2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cold_mode_gas_accretion_on_two_galaxy_groups_at_z__sim_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/cold_mode_gas_accretion_on_two_galaxy_groups_at_z__sim_2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrey Vayner
We present Keck Cosmic Web Imager (KCWI) integral field spectroscopy (IFS) observations of rest-frame UV emission lines $\rm Ly\alpha$, C IV $\lambda \lambda$ 1548 \AA, 1550\AA and He II 1640 \AA observed in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) of two $z=2$ radio-loud quasar host galaxies. We detect extended emission on 80-90 kpc scale in $\rm Ly\alpha$ in both systems with C IV, and He II emission also detected out to 30-50 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of the Central Mass Concentration on Bar Formation in Disk Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/effects_of_the_central_mass_concentration_on_bar_formation_in_disk_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/effects_of_the_central_mass_concentration_on_bar_formation_in_disk_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dajeong Jang
While bars are common in disk galaxies, their formation conditions are not well understood. We use $N$-body simulations to study bar formation and evolution in isolated galaxies consisting of a stellar disk, a classical bulge, and a dark halo. We consider 24 galaxy models that are similar to the Milky Way but differ in the mass and compactness of the classical bulge and halo concentration. We find that the bar formation requires $(Q_{T,\text{min}}/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme nature of four blue-excess dust-obscured galaxies revealed by optical spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/extreme_nature_of_four_blue-excess_dust-obscured_galaxies_revealed_by_optical_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/extreme_nature_of_four_blue-excess_dust-obscured_galaxies_revealed_by_optical_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Akatoki Noboriguchi
We report optical spectroscopic observations of four blue-excess dust-obscured galaxies (BluDOGs) identified by Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam. BluDOGs are a sub-class of dust-obscured galaxies (DOGs, defined with the extremely red color $(i-[22]){\rm AB} \geq 7.0$; Toba et al. 2015), showing a significant flux excess in the optical $g$- and $r$-bands over the power-law fits to the fluxes at the longer wavelengths. Noboriguchi et al. (2019) has suggested that BluDOGs may correspond to the blowing-out phase involved in a gas-rich major merger scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Spectra of Supernova Remnants in M83</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Frank Winkler
In order to better characterize the rich supernova remnant (SNR) population of M83 (NGC 5236), we have obtained high-resolution (about 85 km/s) spectra of 119 of the SNRs and SNR candidates in M83 with Gemini/GMOS, as well as new spectra of the young SNRs B12-174a and SN1957D. Most of the SNRs and SNR candidates have [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios that exceed 0.4. Combining these results with earlier studies we have carried out with MUSE and at lower spectroscopic resolution with GMOS, we have confirmed a total of 238 emission nebulae to be SNRs on the basis of their [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios, about half of which have emission lines that show velocity broadening greater than 100 km/s, providing a kinematic confirmation that they are SNRs and not H II regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological Parameters and Associated Uncertainties for 8 Million Galaxies in the Hyper Suprime-Cam Wide Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/morphological_parameters_and_associated_uncertainties_for_8_million_galaxies_in_the_hyper_suprime-cam_wide_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/morphological_parameters_and_associated_uncertainties_for_8_million_galaxies_in_the_hyper_suprime-cam_wide_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aritra Ghosh
We use the Galaxy Morphology Posterior Estimation Network (GaMPEN) to estimate morphological parameters and associated uncertainties for $\sim 8$ million galaxies in the Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) Wide survey with $z \leq 0.75$ and $m \leq 23$. GaMPEN is a machine learning framework that estimates Bayesian posteriors for a galaxy&amp;rsquo;s bulge-to-total light ratio ($L_B/L_T$), effective radius ($R_e$), and flux ($F$). By first training on simulations of galaxies and then applying transfer learning using real data, we trained GaMPEN with $&amp;lt;1%$ of our dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuSTAR Observes Two Bulgeless Galaxies: No Hard X-ray AGN Detected in NGC 4178 or J0851&#43;3926</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/nustar_observes_two_bulgeless_galaxies_no_hard_x-ray_agn_detected_in_ngc_4178_or_j0851&#43;3926/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan W. Pfeifle
The discovery over the last several decades of moderate luminosity AGNs in disk-dominated galaxies - which show no &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; bulges - suggests that secular mechanisms represent an important growth pathway for supermassive black holes in these systems. We present new follow-up NuSTAR observations of the optically-elusive AGNs in two bulgeless galaxies, NGC 4178 and J0851+3926. NGC 4178 was originally reported as hosting an AGN based on the detection of [Ne V] mid-infrared emission detected by Spitzer, and based on Chandra X-ray imaging it has since been argued to host either a heavily obscured AGN or a supernova remnant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHANGS-JWST First Results: The Influence of Stellar Clusters on PAHs in Nearby Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/phangs-jwst_first_results_the_influence_of_stellar_clusters_on_pahs_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/phangs-jwst_first_results_the_influence_of_stellar_clusters_on_pahs_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel A. Dale
We present a comparison of theoretical predictions of dust continuum and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) emission with new JWST observations in three nearby galaxies: NGC 628, NGC 1365, and NGC 7496. Our analysis focuses on a total of 1063 compact stellar clusters and 2654 stellar associations previously characterized by HST in the three galaxies. We find that the distributions and trends in the observed PAH-focused infrared colors generally agree with theoretical expectations, and that the bulk of the observations is more aligned with models of larger, ionized PAHs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repeating periodic eruptions of the supernova impostor SN 2000ch</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mojgan Aghakhanloo
We analyse photometric observations of the supernova (SN) impostor SN 2000ch in NGC 3432 covering the time since its discovery. This source was previously observed to have four outbursts in 2000&amp;ndash;2010. Observations now reveal at least two additional outbursts in 2004-2006, and ten outbursts in 2013-2022. Outburst light curves are irregular and multipeaked, exhibiting a wide variety of peak magnitude, duration, and shape. The more recent outbursts (after 2010) repeat with a period of $198.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSD measurements from BOSS galaxy power spectrum using the halo perturbation theory model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/rsd_measurements_from_boss_galaxy_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_perturbation_theory_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/rsd_measurements_from_boss_galaxy_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_perturbation_theory_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Byeonghee Yu
We present growth of structure constraints from the cosmological analysis of the power spectrum multipoles of SDSS-III BOSS DR12 galaxies. We use the galaxy power spectrum model of Hand et al. (2017), which decomposes the galaxies into halo mass bins, each of which is modeled separately using the relations between halo biases and halo mass. The model combines Eulerian perturbation theory and halo model calibrated on $N$-body simulations to model the halo clustering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernova 2020wnt: An Atypical Superluminous Supernova with a Hidden Central Engine</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samaporn Tinyanont
We present observations of a peculiar hydrogen- and helium-poor stripped-envelope (SE) supernova (SN) 2020wnt, primarily in the optical and near-infrared (near-IR). Its peak absolute bolometric magnitude of -20.9 mag and a rise time of 69~days are reminiscent of hydrogen-poor superluminous SNe (SLSNe~I), luminous transients potentially powered by spinning-down magnetars. Before the main peak, there is a brief peak lasting &amp;lt;10 days post-explosion, likely caused by interaction with circumstellar medium (CSM) ejected ~years before the SN explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Cosmology with Double Source Lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/testing_cosmology_with_double_source_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/testing_cosmology_with_double_source_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: Divij Sharma
Double source lensing provides a dimensionless ratio of distance ratios, a &amp;ldquo;remote viewing&amp;rdquo; of cosmology through distances relative to the gravitational lens, beyond the observer. We use this to test the cosmological framework, particularly with respect to spatial curvature and the distance duality relation. We derive a consistency equation for constant spatial curvature, allowing not only the investigation of flat vs curved but of the Friedmann-Lema^itre-Robertson-Walker framework itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ALPINE-ALMA [CII] survey: double stellar population and AGN activity in a galaxy at $z\sim5.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_alpine-alma_cii_survey_double_stellar_population_and_agn_activity_in_a_galaxy_at__z_sim5.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Barchiesi
GDS J033218.92-275302.7 (here GS-14) is a $z\sim5.5$ galaxy detected in [CII] as part of the ALPINE survey with unusual UV spectral features that have been interpreted as signatures of either a double stellar population or of an active galactic nucleus (AGN). We exploited the multi-wavelength coverage of GS-14 to investigate the properties and the origin of its emission. We performed UV-to-NIR SED-fitting, with single/double stellar population and/or AGN component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The disappearances of six supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Schuyler D. Van Dyk
As part of a larger completed Hubble Space Telescope (HST) Snapshot program, we observed the sites of six nearby core-collapse supernovae (SNe) at high spatial resolution: SN 2012A, SN 2013ej, SN 2016gkg, SN 2017eaw, SN 2018zd, and SN 2018aoq. These observations were all conducted at sufficiently late times in each SN&amp;rsquo;s evolution to demonstrate that the massive-star progenitor candidate identified in each case in pre-explosion imaging data had indeed vanished and was therefore most likely the actual progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The galaxy mass-size relation in CARLA clusters and proto-clusters at 1.4 &lt; z &lt; 2.8: larger cluster galaxy sizes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_galaxy_mass-size_relation_in_carla_clusters_and_proto-clusters_at_1.4__z__2.8_larger_cluster_galaxy_sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_galaxy_mass-size_relation_in_carla_clusters_and_proto-clusters_at_1.4__z__2.8_larger_cluster_galaxy_sizes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anton V. Afanasiev
(Abridged) We study the galaxy mass-size relation in CARLA spectroscopically confirmed clusters at $1.4&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2.8$, which span a total stellar mass $11.3&amp;lt;\mathrm{log}(M^c_*/M_{\odot})&amp;lt;12.6$ (halo mass $13.5 \lesssim \mathrm{log}(M^c_h/M_{\odot}) \lesssim 14.5$). Our main finding is that cluster passive ETG at $z \gtrsim 1.5$ with ${\rm log}(M/M_{\odot})&amp;gt;10.5$ are systematically $\gtrsim 0.2-0.3~{\rm dex}$ larger than field ETGs. The passive ETG average size evolution is slower at $1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2$ when compared to the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The H$α$ and [O III] $λ5007$ Luminosity Functions of $1.2&lt;z&lt;1.9$ Emission-Line Galaxies from HST Grism Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_h_%CE%B1__and_o_iii__%CE%BB5007__luminosity_functions_of__1.2z1.9__emission-line_galaxies_from_hst_grism_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_h_%CE%B1__and_o_iii__%CE%BB5007__luminosity_functions_of__1.2z1.9__emission-line_galaxies_from_hst_grism_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gautam Nagaraj
Euclid and the Roman Space Telescope (Roman) will soon use grism spectroscopy to detect millions of galaxies via H$\alpha$ and [O III] $\lambda 5007$ emission. To better constrain the expected galaxy counts from these instruments, we use a vetted sample of 4,239 emission-line galaxies from the 3D-HST survey to measure the H$\alpha$ and [O III] $\lambda 5007$ luminosity functions between $1.16&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;1.90$; this sample is $\sim 4$ times larger than previous studies at this redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one-loop bispectrum of galaxies in redshift space from the Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_one-loop_bispectrum_of_galaxies_in_redshift_space_from_the_effective_field_theory_of_large-scale_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_one-loop_bispectrum_of_galaxies_in_redshift_space_from_the_effective_field_theory_of_large-scale_structure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guido D&amp;rsquo;Amico
We derive the kernels and the Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure counterterms for the one-loop bispectrum of dark matter and of biased tracers in real and redshift space. This requires the expansion of biased tracers up to fourth order in fluctuations. In the process, we encounter several subtleties related to renormalization. One is the fact that, in renormalizing the momentum, a local counterterm contributes non-locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The radio structure of the $γ$-ray narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy SDSS J211852.96$-$073227.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_radio_structure_of_the__%CE%B3_-ray_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_sdss_j211852.96_-_073227.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_radio_structure_of_the__%CE%B3_-ray_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_sdss_j211852.96_-_073227.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xi Shao
The $\gamma$-ray narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxies (NLS1s) can be considered to be the third class of $\gamma$-ray active galactic nuclei possessing relativistic jets. In this paper, we present multi-band high resolution Very Long Baseline Array (VLBA) images of the $\gamma$-ray NLS1, SDSS J211852.96$-$073227.5 (J2118$-$0732, $z=0.26$). We find a core-jet radio morphology and significant flux density variations in the radio core. The high brightness temperature estimated from VLBA images and core variability demonstrate that it exhibits substantial relativistic beaming effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibrating cosmological simulations with implicit likelihood inference using galaxy growth observables</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/calibrating_cosmological_simulations_with_implicit_likelihood_inference_using_galaxy_growth_observables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/calibrating_cosmological_simulations_with_implicit_likelihood_inference_using_galaxy_growth_observables/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yongseok Jo
In a novel approach employing implicit likelihood inference (ILI), also known as likelihood-free inference, we calibrate the parameters of cosmological hydrodynamic simulations against observations, which has previously been unfeasible due to the high computational cost of these simulations. For computational efficiency, we train neural networks as emulators on ~1000 cosmological simulations from the CAMELS project to estimate simulated observables, taking as input the cosmological and astrophysical parameters, and use these emulators as surrogates to the cosmological simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting the interstellar medium of a z=6.3 galaxy: X-shooter spectroscopy and HST imaging of the afterglow and environment of the Swift GRB 210905A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dissecting_the_interstellar_medium_of_a_z6.3_galaxy_x-shooter_spectroscopy_and_hst_imaging_of_the_afterglow_and_environment_of_the_swift_grb_210905a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dissecting_the_interstellar_medium_of_a_z6.3_galaxy_x-shooter_spectroscopy_and_hst_imaging_of_the_afterglow_and_environment_of_the_swift_grb_210905a/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Saccardi
The study of the properties of galaxies in the first billion years after the Big Bang is one of the major topic of current astrophysics. Optical/near-infrared spectroscopy of the afterglows of long Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) provide a powerful diagnostic tool to probe the interstellar medium (ISM) of their host galaxies and foreground absorbers, even up to the highest redshifts. We analyze the VLT/X-shooter afterglow spectrum of GRB 210905A, triggered by the Swift Neil Gehrels Observatory, and detect neutral-hydrogen, low-ionization, high-ionization, and fine-structure absorption lines from a complex system at z=6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for a Massive Andromeda Galaxy Using Satellite Galaxy Proper Motions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evidence_for_a_massive_andromeda_galaxy_using_satellite_galaxy_proper_motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evidence_for_a_massive_andromeda_galaxy_using_satellite_galaxy_proper_motions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ekta Patel
We present new mass estimates for Andromeda (M31) using the orbital angular momenta of four satellite galaxies (M33, NGC 185, NGC 147, IC 10) derived from existing proper motions, distances, and line-of-sight velocities. We infer two masses for M31: $M_{\rm vir}= 2.81^{+1.48}{-0.75}\times10^{12}, M{\odot}$ using satellite galaxy phase space information derived with HST-based M31 proper motions and $M_{\rm vir}=2.99^{+1.32}{-0.68}\times10^{12}, M{\odot}$ using phase space information derived with the weighted average of HST+Gaia-based M31 proper motions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for supernova feedback sustaining gas turbulence in nearby star-forming galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
HI and CO observations indicate that the cold gas in galaxies is very turbulent. However, the turbulent energy is expected to be quickly dissipated, implying that some energy source is needed to explain the observations. The nature of such turbulence was long unclear, as even the main candidate, supernova (SN) feedback, seemed insufficient. Other mechanisms have been proposed, but without reaching a general consensus. The key novelty of our work is considering that the gas disc thickness and flaring increase the dissipation timescale of turbulence, thus reducing the energy injection rate required to sustain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA): The Dependence of Star Formation on Surface Brightness in Low Redshift Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_the_dependence_of_star_formation_on_surface_brightness_in_low_redshift_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_the_dependence_of_star_formation_on_surface_brightness_in_low_redshift_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Phillipps
The star formation rate in galaxies is well known to correlate with stellar mass (the `star-forming main sequence&amp;rsquo;). Here we extend this further to explore any additional dependence on galaxy surface brightness, a proxy for stellar mass surface density. We use a large sample of low redshift ($z \leq 0.08$) galaxies from the GAMA survey which have both SED derived star formation rates and photometric bulge-disc decompositions, the latter providing measures of disc surface brightness and disc masses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lopsided Galaxies in a cosmological context: a new galaxy-halo connection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lopsided_galaxies_in_a_cosmological_context_a_new_galaxy-halo_connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/lopsided_galaxies_in_a_cosmological_context_a_new_galaxy-halo_connection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Silvio Varela-Lavin
Disc galaxies commonly show asymmetric features in their morphology, such as warps and lopsidedness. These features can provide key information regarding the recent evolution of a given disc galaxy. In the nearby Universe, up to ~30 percent of late-type galaxies display a global non-axisymmetric lopsided mass distribution, but little attention has been paid to the origin of this perturbation. In this work, we study the origin of lopsided perturbations in simulated disc galaxies extracted from the TNG50 simulation of the IllustrisTNG project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merger Signatures are Common, but not Universal, In Massive, Recently-Quenched Galaxies at z~0.7</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/merger_signatures_are_common_but_not_universal_in_massive_recently-quenched_galaxies_at_z~0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/merger_signatures_are_common_but_not_universal_in_massive_recently-quenched_galaxies_at_z~0.7/</guid>
      <description>First author: Margaret Verrico
We present visual classifications of merger-induced tidal disturbances in 143 $\rm{M}* \sim 10^{11}\rm{M}\odot$ post-starburst galaxies at z$\sim$0.7 identified in the SQuIGG$\vec{L}$E Sample. This sample spectroscopically selects galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey that have stopped their primary epoch of star formation within the past $\sim$500 Myrs. Visual classifications are performed on Hyper Suprime Cam (HSC) i-band imaging. We compare to a control sample of mass- and redshift-matched star-forming and quiescent galaxies from the Large Early Galaxy Census and find that post-starburst galaxies are more likely to be classified as disturbed than either category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Reconstructed Images of Jets Launched by SANE Super-Eddington Accretion Flows Around SMBHs with the ngEHT</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modeling_reconstructed_images_of_jets_launched_by_sane_super-eddington_accretion_flows_around_smbhs_with_the_ngeht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modeling_reconstructed_images_of_jets_launched_by_sane_super-eddington_accretion_flows_around_smbhs_with_the_ngeht/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brandon Curd
Tidal disruption events (TDEs) around super massive black holes (SMBHs) are a potential laboratory to study super-Eddington accretion disks and sometimes result in powerful jets or outflows which may shine in the radio and sub millimeter bands. In this work, we model the thermal synchrotron emission of jets from general relativistic radiation magneto-hydrodynamics (GRRMHD) simulations of a BH accretion disk/jet system which assumes the TDE resulted in a magnetized accretion disk around a BH accreting at $\sim 12-25$ times the Eddington accretion rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the sociology and hierarchy of voids: a study of seven CAVITY nearby galaxy voids and their dynamical CosmicFlows-3 environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_sociology_and_hierarchy_of_voids_a_study_of_seven_cavity_nearby_galaxy_voids_and_their_dynamical_cosmicflows-3_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_sociology_and_hierarchy_of_voids_a_study_of_seven_cavity_nearby_galaxy_voids_and_their_dynamical_cosmicflows-3_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. M. Courtois
Context. The present study addresses a key question for our understanding of the relation between void galaxies and their environment: the relationship between luminous and dark matter in and around voids. Aims. To explore how empty of matter local Universe voids are, we study the full (dark+luminous) matter content of seven nearby cosmic voids that are fully contained within the CosmicFlows-3 volume. Methods. The cosmic voids matter density profiles are independently obtained using two different methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientations of DM Halos in FIRE-2 Milky Way-mass Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orientations_of_dm_halos_in_fire-2_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orientations_of_dm_halos_in_fire-2_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jay Baptista
The shape and orientation of dark matter (DM) halos are sensitive to the micro-physics of the DM particle, yet in many mass models, the symmetry axes of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s DM halo are often assumed to be aligned with the symmetry axes of the stellar disk. This is well-motivated for the inner DM halo but not for the outer halo. We use zoomed cosmological-baryonic simulations from the Latte suite of FIRE-2 Milky Way-mass galaxies to explore the evolution of the DM halo&amp;rsquo;s orientation with radius and time, with or without a major merger with a Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) analog, and when varying the DM model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the extended structure of multiple sources strongly lensed by the ultra-massive elliptical galaxy SDSS J0100&#43;1818</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/reconstructing_the_extended_structure_of_multiple_sources_strongly_lensed_by_the_ultra-massive_elliptical_galaxy_sdss_j0100&#43;1818/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/reconstructing_the_extended_structure_of_multiple_sources_strongly_lensed_by_the_ultra-massive_elliptical_galaxy_sdss_j0100&#43;1818/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Bolamperti
We study the total and baryonic mass distributions of the deflector SDSS J0100+1818 through a full strong lensing analysis. The system is composed by an ultra-massive early-type galaxy at $z=0.581$, with total stellar mass of $(1.5 \pm 0.3) 10^{12}$ M$\odot$ and stellar velocity dispersion of ($450 \pm 40$) km s$^{-1}$, surrounded by ten multiple images of three background sources, two of which spectroscopically confirmed at $z=1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying cosmic ray sources using intergalactic electromagnetic cascades</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/studying_cosmic_ray_sources_using_intergalactic_electromagnetic_cascades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/studying_cosmic_ray_sources_using_intergalactic_electromagnetic_cascades/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Uryson
In this paper intergalatic electromagnetic cascades are used as a probe of cosmic ray sources. This is achieved as follows. In extragalactic space cosmic rays initiate electromagnetic cascades in which gamma-ray and neutrino emission arises. We used the joint analysis of cosmic ray data, along with extragalactic gamma-ray and neutrino emission, to study particle acceleration in the vicinity of supermassive black holes. Particle injection spectra depend on processes of particle acceleration, and here we discuss models with various injection spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of a Relativistic Jet Following the Disruption of a Star by a Cosmological Black Hole</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_birth_of_a_relativistic_jet_following_the_disruption_of_a_star_by_a_cosmological_black_hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_birth_of_a_relativistic_jet_following_the_disruption_of_a_star_by_a_cosmological_black_hole/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dheeraj R. Pasham
A black hole can launch a powerful relativistic jet after it tidally disrupts a star. If this jet fortuitously aligns with our line of sight, the overall brightness is Doppler boosted by several orders of magnitude. Consequently, such on-axis relativistic tidal disruption events (TDEs) have the potential to unveil cosmological (redshift $z&amp;gt;$1) quiescent black holes and are ideal test beds to understand the radiative mechanisms operating in super-Eddington jets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Energy Survey Year 3 high redshift sample: Selection, characterization and analysis of galaxy clustering</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_dark_energy_survey_year_3_high_redshift_sample_selection_characterization_and_analysis_of_galaxy_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_dark_energy_survey_year_3_high_redshift_sample_selection_characterization_and_analysis_of_galaxy_clustering/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Sánchez
The fiducial cosmological analyses of imaging galaxy surveys like the Dark Energy Survey (DES) typically probe the Universe at redshifts $z &amp;lt; 1$. This is mainly because of the limited depth of these surveys, and also because such analyses rely heavily on galaxy lensing, which is more efficient at low redshifts. In this work we present the selection and characterization of high-redshift galaxy samples using DES Year 3 data, and the analysis of their galaxy clustering measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The volumetric star formation law in nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
Star formation laws are empirical relations between the cold gas (HI+H$_2$) content of a galaxy and its star formation rate (SFR), being crucial for any model of galaxy formation and evolution. A well known example of such laws is the Schmidt-Kennicutt law, which is based on the projected surface densities. However, it has been long unclear whether a more fundamental relation exists between the intrinsic volume densities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward Accurate Modeling of Galaxy Clustering on Small Scales: Halo Model Extensions &amp; Lingering Tension</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/toward_accurate_modeling_of_galaxy_clustering_on_small_scales_halo_model_extensions__lingering_tension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/toward_accurate_modeling_of_galaxy_clustering_on_small_scales_halo_model_extensions__lingering_tension/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gillian D. Beltz-Mohrmann
This paper represents an effort to provide robust constraints on cosmology and the galaxy-halo connection using a fully numerical model of small-scale galaxy clustering. We explore two extensions to the standard Halo Occupation Distribution model: assembly bias, whereby halo occupation depends on both halo mass and the larger environment, and velocity bias, whereby galaxy velocities do not perfectly trace the velocity of the dark matter within the halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERTICO III: The Kennicutt-Schmidt relation in Virgo cluster galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/vertico_iii_the_kennicutt-schmidt_relation_in_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/vertico_iii_the_kennicutt-schmidt_relation_in_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. J. Jiménez-Donaire
In this VERTICO science paper we aim to study how the star formation process depends on galactic environment and gravitational interactions in the context of galaxy evolution. We explore the scaling relation between the star formation rate (SFR) surface density and the molecular gas surface density, also known as the Kennicutt-Schmidt (KS) relation, in a subsample of Virgo cluster spiral galaxies. We use new ACA and TP observations from the VERTICO-ALMA Large Program at 720pc resolution to resolve the molecular gas content, as traced by the 12CO(2-1) transition, across the disks of 37 spiral galaxies in the Virgo cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Optical, Ultraviolet and Soft X-ray excess Emissions in AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/association_of_optical_ultraviolet_and_soft_x-ray_excess_emissions_in_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Nour
Soft X-ray emission (0.5&amp;ndash;2.0 keV) plays a pivotal role in regulating the optical and UV emission in the AGNs. We collected a sample of 1811 AGNs from the SDSS database and obtained various parameters of Balmer lines, optical continuum, MgII line &amp;amp; UV continuum and studied their dependencies on soft X-ray luminosity. Based on the linear regression analysis, we found that FWHM${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ FWHM${\text{H}\beta}^{0.554}$ suggesting that UV emission is arising from a region relatively outside the broad line region (BLR) associated to the H$\beta$ emission and found a strong correlation between optical and UV luminosities (L${\text{MgII}}$ $\propto$ L${\text{H}\beta}^{0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical abundances in the dwarf galaxy NGC 4163 based on the nebular and auroral emission lines</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/chemical_abundances_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4163_based_on_the_nebular_and_auroral_emission_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/chemical_abundances_in_the_dwarf_galaxy_ngc_4163_based_on_the_nebular_and_auroral_emission_lines/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. A. Zinchenko
We constructed an oxygen abundance map and N/O ratio map of the unusually low excitation dwarf irregular galaxy NGC 4163 based on publicly available spectroscopy obtained by the MaNGA survey. We detected auroral emission line [OII]$\lambda\lambda$7320,7330 which allows us to measure chemical abundance by direct T$_e$ method. We found that the scatter of the oxygen abundance derived by the strong line method is large. The oxygen abundances 12 + log(O/H) derived by strong line method vary from ~7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-noising non-Gaussian fields in cosmology with normalizing flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/de-noising_non-gaussian_fields_in_cosmology_with_normalizing_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/de-noising_non-gaussian_fields_in_cosmology_with_normalizing_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Rouhiainen
Fields in cosmology, such as the matter distribution, are observed by experiments up to experimental noise. The first step in cosmological data analysis is usually to de-noise the observed field using an analytic or simulation driven prior. On large enough scales, such fields are Gaussian, and the de-noising step is known as Wiener filtering. However, on smaller scales probed by upcoming experiments, a Gaussian prior is substantially sub-optimal because the true field distribution is very non-Gaussian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of star clusters and enrichment by massive stars in simulations of low-metallicity galaxies with a fully sampled initial stellar mass function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/formation_of_star_clusters_and_enrichment_by_massive_stars_in_simulations_of_low-metallicity_galaxies_with_a_fully_sampled_initial_stellar_mass_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/formation_of_star_clusters_and_enrichment_by_massive_stars_in_simulations_of_low-metallicity_galaxies_with_a_fully_sampled_initial_stellar_mass_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalia Lahén
We present new GRIFFIN project hydrodynamical simulations that model the formation of galactic star cluster populations in low-metallicity ($Z=0.00021$) dwarf galaxies, including radiation, supernova and stellar wind feedback of individual massive stars. In the simulations, stars are sampled from the stellar initial mass function (IMF) down to the hydrogen burning limit of 0.08 M$_\odot$. Mass conservation is enforced within a radius of 1 pc for the formation massive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard X-ray Observations of the Hydrogen-poor Superluminous Supernova SN 2018hti with NuSTAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Igor Andreoni
Some Hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae are likely powered by a magnetar central engine, making their luminosity larger than common supernovae. Although a significant amount of X-ray flux is expected from the spin down of the magnetar, direct observational evidence is still to be found, giving rise to the &amp;ldquo;missing energy&amp;rdquo; problem. Here we present NuSTAR observations of nearby SN 2018hti 2.4y (rest frame) after its optical peak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferencing Progenitor and Explosion Properties of Evolving Core-collapse Supernovae from Zwicky Transient Facility Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bhagya M. Subrayan
We analyze a sample of 45 Type II supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) public survey using a grid of hydrodynamical models in order to assess whether theoretically-driven forecasts can intelligently guide follow up observations supporting all-sky survey alert streams. We estimate several progenitor properties and explosion physics parameters including zero-age-main-sequence (ZAMS) mass, mass-loss rate, kinetic energy, 56Ni mass synthesized, host extinction, and the time of explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOJAVE XX. Decade-long linear polarization variability in AGN jets at parsec scales</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mojave_xx._decade-long_linear_polarization_variability_in_agn_jets_at_parsec_scales/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. I. Zobnina
We studied the variability properties of the linear polarization of active galactic nucleus (AGN) jets on parsec-scales using stacking. Our sample is drawn from the MOJAVE program and consists of 436 AGNs manifesting core-jet morphology and having at least five VLBA observing epochs at 15 GHz from January 1996 through August 2019, with some additional archival VLBA data reduced by us. We employed a stacking procedure and constructed maps of (i) standard deviation of fractional polarization and electric vector position angle (EVPA) over epochs as the measure of variability, (ii) median polarization degree to quantify typical values in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential contributions of Pop III and intermediate-mass Pop II stars to cosmic chemical enrichment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/potential_contributions_of_pop_iii_and_intermediate-mass_pop_ii_stars_to_cosmic_chemical_enrichment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/potential_contributions_of_pop_iii_and_intermediate-mass_pop_ii_stars_to_cosmic_chemical_enrichment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lia C. Corazza
We propose a semi-analytic model that is developed to understand the cosmological evolution of the mean metallicity in the Universe. In particular, we study the contributions of Population III (Pop III) and Population II (Pop II) stars to the production of $\mathrm{Fe,~Si,~Zn, ~Ni,~P, ~Mg, ~Al, ~S, ~C, ~N}$, and $\mathrm{~O}$. We aim to quantify the roles of two different models in the chemical enrichment of the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pristine Inner Galaxy Survey (PIGS) VI: Different vertical distributions between two DIBs at 442.8 nm and 862.1 nm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_pristine_inner_galaxy_survey_pigs_vi_different_vertical_distributions_between_two_dibs_at_442.8_nm_and_862.1_nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_pristine_inner_galaxy_survey_pigs_vi_different_vertical_distributions_between_two_dibs_at_442.8_nm_and_862.1_nm/</guid>
      <description>First author: He Zhao
Although diffuse interstellar bands (DIBs) were discovered over 100 years ago, for most of them, their origins are still unknown. Investigation on the correlations between different DIBs is an important way to study the behavior and distributions of their carriers. Based on stacking thousands of spectra from the Pristine Inner Galaxy Survey, we study the correlations between two DIBs at 442.8 nm ($\lambda$442.8) and 862.1 nm ($\lambda$862.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VINTERGATAN-GM: The cosmological imprints of early mergers on Milky-Way-mass galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/vintergatan-gm_the_cosmological_imprints_of_early_mergers_on_milky-way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/vintergatan-gm_the_cosmological_imprints_of_early_mergers_on_milky-way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martin P. Rey
We present a new suite of cosmological zoom-in hydrodynamical ($\approx 20, \mathrm{pc}$) simulations of Milky-Way mass galaxies to study how a varying mass ratio for a Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) progenitor impacts the $z=0$ chemodynamics of halo stars. Using the genetic modification approach, we create five cosmological histories for a Milky-Way-mass dark matter halo ($M_{200} \approx 10^{12} , M_\mathrm{\odot}$), incrementally increasing the stellar mass ratio of a $z\approx2$ merger from 1:25 to 1:2, while fixing the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s final dynamical, stellar mass and large-scale environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: HI gas kinematics of galaxy pairs in cluster environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pilot_survey_hi_gas_kinematics_of_galaxy_pairs_in_cluster_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/wallaby_pilot_survey_hi_gas_kinematics_of_galaxy_pairs_in_cluster_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shin-Jeong Kim
We examine the HI gas kinematics of galaxy pairs in two clusters and a group using Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) WALLABY pilot survey observations. We compare the HI properties of galaxy pair candidates in the Hydra I and Norma clusters, and the NGC 4636 group, with those of non-paired control galaxies selected in the same fields. We perform HI profile decomposition of the sample galaxies using a tool, {\sc baygaud} which allows us to de-blend a line-of-sight velocity profile with an optimal number of Gaussian components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray Absorption Lines in the Warm-Hot Intergalactic Medium: Probing Chandra observations with the CAMEL simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/x-ray_absorption_lines_in_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_probing_chandra_observations_with_the_camel_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/x-ray_absorption_lines_in_the_warm-hot_intergalactic_medium_probing_chandra_observations_with_the_camel_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amanda Butler Contreras
Known as the &amp;ldquo;Missing Baryon Problem&amp;rdquo;, about one-third of baryons in the local universe remain unaccounted for. The missing baryons are thought to reside in the warm-hot intergalactic medium (WHIM) of the cosmic web filaments, which are challenging to detect. Recent Chandra X-ray observations from Kov&#39;acs et al. (2019) used a novel stacking analysis and detected an OVII absorption line toward the sightline of a luminous quasar, hinting that the missing baryons may reside in the WHIM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Properties of OGLE4 Mira variables in our Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/infrared_properties_of_ogle4_mira_variables_in_our_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/infrared_properties_of_ogle4_mira_variables_in_our_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyung-Won Suh
We investigate infrared properties of OGLE4 Mira variables in our Galaxy. For each object, we cross-identify the WISE, 2MASS, and IRAS counterparts. We present various IR two-color diagrams (2CDs) and period-magnitude and period-color relations for the Mira variables. Generally, the Miras variables with longer periods are brighter in the IR fluxes and redder in the IR colors. In this work, we also revise and update the previous catalog of AGB stars in our Galaxy using the new sample of OGLE4 Mira variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Fourier-Transformation Model for the Production of Hard and Soft X-Ray Time Lags in AGNs: Application to 1H 0707-495</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/an_analytical_fourier-transformation_model_for_the_production_of_hard_and_soft_x-ray_time_lags_in_agns_application_to_1h_0707-495/</guid>
      <description>First author: David C. Baughman
The variability of the X-ray emission from active galactic nuclei is often characterized using time lags observed between soft and hard energy bands in the detector. The time lags are usually computed using the complex cross spectrum, which is based on the Fourier transforms of the hard and soft time series data. It has been noted that some active galactic nuclei display soft X-ray time lags, in addition to the more ubiquitous hard lags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN Feedback in SDSS-IV MaNGA: AGNs Have Suppressed Central Star-Formation Rates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/agn_feedback_in_sdss-iv_manga_agns_have_suppressed_central_star-formation_rates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Caleb Lammers
Despite the importance of feedback from active galactic nuclei (AGN) in models of galaxy evolution, observational constraints on the influence of AGN feedback on star formation remain weak. To this end, we have compared the star formation trends of 279 low-redshift AGN galaxies with 558 non-active control galaxies using integral field unit spectroscopy from the SDSS-IV MaNGA survey. With a Gaussian process-based methodology, we reconstruct non-parametric star formation histories in spatially-resolved spaxels covering the face of each galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the bright-end of the UV luminosity functions of galaxies at $z \sim 0.6-1.2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_bright-end_of_the_uv_luminosity_functions_of_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.6-1.2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/on_the_bright-end_of_the_uv_luminosity_functions_of_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.6-1.2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Sharma
We derive the Ultra-Violet (UV) luminosity function (LF) of star forming galaxies falling in the redshift range $z = 0.6 - 1.2$, in the rest-frame far-UV (1500 {\AA}) wavelength. For this work we are in particular interested in the bright end of the UV LF in this redshift range. The data from \textit{XMM-Newton} Optical Monitor (XMM-OM), near-ultraviolet (1600-4000 {\AA}) observations over 1.5 deg\textsuperscript{2} of the COSMOS field are employed for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarized radio emission unveils the structure of the pre-supernova circumstellar magnetic field and the radio emission in SN1987A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. Petruk
The detected polarized radio emission from remnant of SN1987A opens the possibility to unveil the structure of the pre-supernova magnetic field in the circumstellar medium. Properties derived from direct measurements would be of importance for understanding the progenitor stars and their magnetic fields. As the first step to this goal, we adopted the hydrodynamic data from an elaborated three-dimensional (3-D) numerical model of SN1987A. We have developed an approximate method for reconstruction&#39; of 3-D magnetic field structure inside supernova remnant on the hydrodynamic background&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synergy between CSST galaxy survey and gravitational-wave observation: Inferring the Hubble constant from dark standard sirens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/synergy_between_csst_galaxy_survey_and_gravitational-wave_observation_inferring_the_hubble_constant_from_dark_standard_sirens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/synergy_between_csst_galaxy_survey_and_gravitational-wave_observation_inferring_the_hubble_constant_from_dark_standard_sirens/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ji-Yu Song
Gravitational waves (GWs) from compact binary coalescences encode the absolute luminosity distances of GW sources. Once the redshifts of GW sources are known, one can use the distance-redshift relation to constrain cosmological parameters. One way to obtain the redshifts is to localize GW sources by GW observations and then use galaxy catalogs to determine redshifts from a statistical analysis of redshift information of the potential host galaxies, and such GW data are commonly referred to as dark sirens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three dimensional magnetorotational core-collapse supernova explosions of a 39 solar mass progenitor star</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jade Powell
We perform three-dimensional simulations of magnetorotational supernovae using a $39,M_{\odot}$ progenitor star with two different initial magnetic field strengths of $10^{10}$ G and $10^{12}$ G in the core. Both models rapidly undergo shock revival and their explosion energies asymptote within a few hundred milliseconds to values of $\gtrsim 2\times10^{51}$ erg after conservatively correcting for the binding energy of the envelope. Magnetically collimated, non-relativistic jets form in both models, though the jets are subject to non-axisymmetric instabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
