<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The R-Process Alliance: Abundance Universality among Some Elements at and between the First and Second R-Process Peaks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_r-process_alliance_abundance_universality_among_some_elements_at_and_between_the_first_and_second_r-process_peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_r-process_alliance_abundance_universality_among_some_elements_at_and_between_the_first_and_second_r-process_peaks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ian U. Roederer
We present new observational benchmarks of rapid neutron-capture process (r-process) nucleosynthesis for elements at and between the first (A ~ 80) and second (A ~ 130) peaks. Our analysis is based on archival ultraviolet and optical spectroscopy of eight metal-poor stars with Se (Z = 34) or Te (Z = 52) detections, whose r-process enhancement varies by more than a factor of 30 (-0.22 &amp;lt;= [Eu/Fe] &amp;lt;= +1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for planetary transits on a set of 1.4 million multi-sector DIAmante lightcurves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_search_for_planetary_transits_on_a_set_of_1.4_million_multi-sector_diamante_lightcurves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_search_for_planetary_transits_on_a_set_of_1.4_million_multi-sector_diamante_lightcurves/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Montalto
I report the results of a new search for transiting planets on a set of 1.4 million lightcurves extracted from TESS Full Frame Images (FFIs) using the DIAmante pipeline. The data come from the first two years of observations of TESS (Sectors 1-26) and the study is focused on a sample of FGKM dwarf and subgiant stars optimized for the search of transiting planets. The search was performed on the detrended and stitched multi-sector lightcurves applying the Box-fitting Least Squares algorithm and a Random Forest classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbital parallax of binary systems compared to GAIA DR3 and the parallax zero-point offset at bright magnitudes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orbital_parallax_of_binary_systems_compared_to_gaia_dr3_and_the_parallax_zero-point_offset_at_bright_magnitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orbital_parallax_of_binary_systems_compared_to_gaia_dr3_and_the_parallax_zero-point_offset_at_bright_magnitudes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martin Groenewegen
(abridged)Multiple systems for which the astrometric and spectroscopic orbit are known offer the unique possibility of determining the distance to these systems directly without any assumptions. They are therefore ideal objects for a comparison of Gaia data release 3 (GDR3) parallax data, especially since GDR3 presents the results of the non-single star (NSS) analysis that potentially results in improved parallaxes. An sample of 192 orbital parallax determinations for 186 systems is compiled from the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relation of Observable Stellar Parameters to Mass-Loss Rate of AGB Stars in the LMC</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/relation_of_observable_stellar_parameters_to_mass-loss_rate_of_agb_stars_in_the_lmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/relation_of_observable_stellar_parameters_to_mass-loss_rate_of_agb_stars_in_the_lmc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Henry A. Prager
Using the Riebel et al. (2012) data set for 6,889 pulsating AGB stars in the LMC, we have derived formulae for mass-loss rate as a function of luminosity and pulsation period or luminosity and mass in three ways, for each of five subsets of data: fundamental mode oxygen rich stars, first overtone mode oxygen rich stars stars, fundamental mode carbon stars, first overtone mode carbon stars, and extreme carbon stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct Determination of the Activation Energy for Diffusion of OH Radicals on Water Ice</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/direct_determination_of_the_activation_energy_for_diffusion_of_oh_radicals_on_water_ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/direct_determination_of_the_activation_energy_for_diffusion_of_oh_radicals_on_water_ice/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Miyazaki
Using a combination of photostimulated desorption and resonance-enhanced multiphoton ionization methods, the behaviors of OH radicals on the surface of interstellar ice analog was monitored at temperatures between 54 and 80 K. The OH number density on the surface of ultraviolet (UV)-irradiated compact amorphous solid water gradually decreased at temperatures above 60 K. Analyzing the temperature dependence of OH intensities with the Arrhenius equation, the decrease can be explained by recombination of two OH radicals, which is rate-limited by thermal diffusion of OH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELVES III: Environmental Quenching by Milky Way-Mass Hosts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iii_environmental_quenching_by_milky_way-mass_hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iii_environmental_quenching_by_milky_way-mass_hosts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jenny E. Greene
Isolated dwarf galaxies nearly always exhibit robust star formation but satellite dwarf galaxies are often devoid of young stars, even in Milky Way-mass groups. Dwarf galaxies thus offer an important laboratory into the environmental processes that cease star formation. We explore the balance of quiescent and star-forming galaxies (quenched fractions) for a sample of ~400 satellite galaxies around 30 Local Volume hosts from the Exploration of Local VolumE Satellites (ELVES) Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three low-mass companions around aged stars discovered by TESS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/three_low-mass_companions_around_aged_stars_discovered_by_tess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/three_low-mass_companions_around_aged_stars_discovered_by_tess/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zitao Lin
We report the discovery of three transiting low-mass companions to aged stars: a brown dwarf (TOI-2336b) and two objects near the hydrogen burning mass limit (TOI-1608b and TOI-2521b). These three systems were first identified using data from the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS). TOI-2336b has a radius of $1.05\pm 0.04\ R_J$, a mass of $69.9\pm 2.3\ M_J$ and an orbital period of 7.71 days. TOI-1608b has a radius of $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virial theorem in clusters of galaxies with MOND</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/virial_theorem_in_clusters_of_galaxies_with_mond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/virial_theorem_in_clusters_of_galaxies_with_mond/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Lopez-Corredoira
A specific modification of Newtonian dynamics known as MOND has been shown to reproduce the dynamics of most astrophysical systems at different scales without invoking non-baryonic dark matter (DM). There is, however, a long-standing unsolved problem when MOND is applied to rich clusters of galaxies in the form of a deficit (by a factor around two) of predicted dynamical mass derived from the virial theorem with respect to observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A large (~1 pc) contracting envelope around the prestellar core L1544</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_large_~1_pc_contracting_envelope_around_the_prestellar_core_l1544/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_large_~1_pc_contracting_envelope_around_the_prestellar_core_l1544/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Redaelli
Prestellar cores, the birthplace of Sun-like stars, form from the fragmentation of the filamentary structure that composes molecular clouds, from which they must inherit at least partially the kinematics. Furthermore, when they are on the verge of gravitational collapse, they show signs of subsonic infall motions. How extended these motions are, which depends on how the collapse occurs, remains largely unknown. We want to investigate the kinematics of the envelope that surrounds the prototypical prestellar core L1544, studying the cloud-core connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Molecular Gas Ring Hidden in the Sombrero Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_molecular_gas_ring_hidden_in_the_sombrero_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_molecular_gas_ring_hidden_in_the_sombrero_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica Sutter
We present Herschel, ALMA, and MUSE observations of the molecular ring of Messier 104, also known as the Sombrero galaxy. These previously unpublished archival data shed new light on the content of the interstellar medium of M104. In particular, molecular hydrogen measured by CO emission and dust measured by far-infrared light are uniformly distributed along the ring. The ionized gas revealed by H$\alpha$ and [CII] emission is distributed in knots along the ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almanac: Weak Lensing power spectra and map inference on the masked sphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/almanac_weak_lensing_power_spectra_and_map_inference_on_the_masked_sphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/almanac_weak_lensing_power_spectra_and_map_inference_on_the_masked_sphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Loureiro
We present a field-based signal extraction of weak lensing from noisy observations on the curved and masked sky. We test the analysis on a simulated Euclid-like survey, using a Euclid-like mask and noise level. To make optimal use of the information available in such a galaxy survey, we present a Bayesian method for inferring the angular power spectra of the weak lensing fields, together with an inference of the noise-cleaned tomographic weak lensing shear and convergence (projected mass) maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetrical tidal tails of open star clusters: stars crossing their cluster&#39;s prah challenge Newtonian gravitation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/asymmetrical_tidal_tails_of_open_star_clusters_stars_crossing_their_clusters_prah_challenge_newtonian_gravitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/asymmetrical_tidal_tails_of_open_star_clusters_stars_crossing_their_clusters_prah_challenge_newtonian_gravitation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pavel Kroupa
After their birth a significant fraction of all stars pass through the tidal threshold (prah) of their cluster of origin into the classical tidal tails. The asymmetry between the number of stars in the leading and trailing tails tests gravitational theory. All five open clusters with tail data (Hyades, Praesepe, Coma Berenices, COIN-Gaia 13, NGC 752) have visibly more stars within dcl = 50 pc of their centre in their leading than their trailing tail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Type Ia supernovae through their heights in edge-on galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_type_ia_supernovae_through_their_heights_in_edge-on_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_type_ia_supernovae_through_their_heights_in_edge-on_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lilit V. Barkhudaryan
In this Letter, using classified 197 supernovae (SNe) Ia, we perform an analyses of their height distributions from the disc in edge-on spirals and investigate their light-curve (LC) decline rates $(\Delta m_{15})$. We demonstrate, for the first time, that 91T-, 91bg-like, and normal SNe Ia subclasses are distributed differently toward the plane of their host disc. The average height from the disc and its comparison with scales of thin/thick disc components gives a possibility to roughly estimate the SNe Ia progenitor ages: 91T-like events, being at the smallest heights, originate from relatively younger progenitors with ages of about several 100 Myr, 91bg-like SNe, having the highest distribution, arise from progenitors with significantly older ages $\sim 10$ Gyr, and normal SNe Ia, which distributed between those of the two others, are from progenitors of about one up to $\sim 10$ Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDSS-IV MaStar: Stellar Parameter Determination with Continuum-Supplemented Full-Spectrum Fitting</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/sdss-iv_mastar_stellar_parameter_determination_with_continuum-supplemented_full-spectrum_fitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/sdss-iv_mastar_stellar_parameter_determination_with_continuum-supplemented_full-spectrum_fitting/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Lazarz
We present a stellar parameter catalog built to accompany the MaStar Stellar Library, which is a comprehensive collection of empirical, medium-resolution stellar spectra. We constructed this parameter catalog by using a multicomponent $\chi^{2}$ fitting approach to match MaStar spectra to models generated by interpolating the ATLAS9-based BOSZ model spectra. The total $\chi^{2}$ for a given model is defined as the sum of components constructed to characterize narrow-band features of observed spectra (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spiral arms of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_spiral_arms_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_spiral_arms_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: George Contopoulos
The most important theory of the spiral arms of galaxies is the density wave theory based on the Lin-Shu dispersion relation. However, the density waves move with the group velocity towards the inner Lindblad resonance and tend to disappear. Various mechanisms to replenish the spiral waves have been proposed. Nonlinear effects play an important role near the inner and outer Lindblad resonances and corotation. The orbits supporting the spiral arms are precessing ellipses in normal galaxies that extend up to the 4/1 resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why weak lensing cluster shapes are insensitive to self-interacting dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/why_weak_lensing_cluster_shapes_are_insensitive_to_self-interacting_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/why_weak_lensing_cluster_shapes_are_insensitive_to_self-interacting_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew Robertson
We investigate whether the shapes of galaxy clusters inferred from weak gravitational lensing can be used as a test of the nature of dark matter. We analyse mock weak lensing data, with gravitational lenses extracted from cosmological simulations run with two different dark matter models (CDM and SIDM). We fit elliptical NFW profiles to the shear fields of the simulated clusters. Despite large differences in the distribution of 3D shapes between CDM and SIDM, we find that the distributions of weak-lensing-inferred cluster shapes are almost indistinguishable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Spectroscopic Survey of the Quiescent Medium of Nearby Clouds: II. Ice Formation and Grain Growth in Perseus and Serpens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/infrared_spectroscopic_survey_of_the_quiescent_medium_of_nearby_clouds_ii._ice_formation_and_grain_growth_in_perseus_and_serpens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/infrared_spectroscopic_survey_of_the_quiescent_medium_of_nearby_clouds_ii._ice_formation_and_grain_growth_in_perseus_and_serpens/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. C. L. Madden
The properties of dust change during the transition from diffuse to dense clouds as a result of ice formation and dust coagulation, but much is still unclear about this transformation. We present 2-20 micron spectra of 49 field stars behind the Perseus and Serpens Molecular Clouds and establish relationships between the near-infrared continuum extinction (AK) and the depths of the 9.7 micron silicate (tau97) and 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Infrared Polarization of the Diffuse Interstellar Medium toward CygOB2-12</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mid-infrared_polarization_of_the_diffuse_interstellar_medium_toward_cygob2-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mid-infrared_polarization_of_the_diffuse_interstellar_medium_toward_cygob2-12/</guid>
      <description>First author: Charles M. Telesco
We present the first mid-IR detection of the linear polarization toward the star CygOB2-12, a luminous blue hypergiant that, with Av of ~10 mag of foreground extinction, is a benchmark in the study of the properties of dust in the diffuse interstellar medium. The 8-13 micrometer spectropolarimetry, obtained with the CanariCam multi-mode camera at the Gran Telescopio Canarias (GTC), shows clear trends with wavelength characteristic of silicate grains aligned in the interstellar magnetic field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Stellar Populations of Globular Clusters From Homogeneous Ca-CN-CH-NH Photometry. VII. Metal-Poor Populations in 47 Tucanae (NGC 104)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/multiple_stellar_populations_of_globular_clusters_from_homogeneous_ca-cn-ch-nh_photometry._vii._metal-poor_populations_in_47_tucanae_ngc_104/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/multiple_stellar_populations_of_globular_clusters_from_homogeneous_ca-cn-ch-nh_photometry._vii._metal-poor_populations_in_47_tucanae_ngc_104/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jae-Woo Lee
We present new large field-of-view ($\sim$1\deg$\times$1\deg) Ca-CN photometry of the prototypical metal-rich globular cluster 47 Tucanae (NGC 104). Our results are the following. (1) The populational number ratios of the red giant branch (RGB) and red horizontal branch (RHB) are in excellent agreement: n(CN-w):n(CN-s) = 30:70 ($\pm$1&amp;ndash;2), where the CN-w and CN-s stand for the CN-weak and CN-strong populations, respectively. Both the CN-s RGB and RHB populations are more centrally concentrated than those of CN-w populations are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimisation of the SVOM satellite strategy for the follow-up of Gravitational wave events</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optimisation_of_the_svom_satellite_strategy_for_the_follow-up_of_gravitational_wave_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optimisation_of_the_svom_satellite_strategy_for_the_follow-up_of_gravitational_wave_events/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. -G. Ducoin
The SVOM satellite, to be launched at the end of 2023, is primarily devoted to the multi-wavelength observation of gamma-ray bursts and other higher-energy transients. Thanks to its onboard Microchannel X-ray Telescope and Visible-band Telescope, it is also very well adapted to the electromagnetic follow-up of gravitational wave events. We discuss the SVOM follow-up strategy for gravitational wave trigger candidates provided by LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA. In particular, we make use of recent developments of galaxy catalogs adapted to the horizon of gravitational wave detectors to optimise the chance of counterpart discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolved Molecular Gas Observations of MaNGA Post-starbursts Reveal a Tumultuous Past</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolved_molecular_gas_observations_of_manga_post-starbursts_reveal_a_tumultuous_past/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resolved_molecular_gas_observations_of_manga_post-starbursts_reveal_a_tumultuous_past/</guid>
      <description>First author: Justin Atsushi Otter
Post-starburst galaxies (PSBs) have recently and rapidly quenched their star-formation, thus they are an important way to understand how galaxies transition from star-forming late-types to quiescent early-types. The recent discovery of large cold gas reservoirs in PSBs calls into question the theory that galaxies must lose their gas to become quiescent. Optical Integral Field Spectroscopy (IFS) surveys have revealed two classes of PSBs: central PSBs with central quenching regions and ring PSBs with quenching in their outskirts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing for relics of past strong buckling events in edge-on galaxies: Simulation predictions and data from S$^{4}$G</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_for_relics_of_past_strong_buckling_events_in_edge-on_galaxies_simulation_predictions_and_data_from_s_4_g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_for_relics_of_past_strong_buckling_events_in_edge-on_galaxies_simulation_predictions_and_data_from_s_4_g/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. Cuomo
The short-lived buckling instability is responsible for the formation of at least some box/peanut (B/P) shaped bulges, which are observed in most massive, $z=0$, barred galaxies. Nevertheless, it has also been suggested that B/P bulges form via the slow trapping of stars onto vertically extended resonant orbits. The key difference between these two scenarios is that when the bar buckles, symmetry about the mid-plane is broken for a period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Galaxy Winds During the Big Bang of Starbursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accelerating_galaxy_winds_during_the_big_bang_of_starbursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accelerating_galaxy_winds_during_the_big_bang_of_starbursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew J. Hayes
We develop a new method to infer the temporal, geometric, and energetic properties of galaxy outflows, by combining stellar spectral modeling to infer starburst ages, and absorption lines to measure velocities. If winds are accelerated with time during a starburst event, then these two measurements enable us to solve for the wind radius, similarly to length scales and the Hubble parameter in Big Bang cosmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing three-dimensional magnetic field, turbulence, and self-gravity in the star-forming region L1688</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_three-dimensional_magnetic_field_turbulence_and_self-gravity_in_the_star-forming_region_l1688/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_three-dimensional_magnetic_field_turbulence_and_self-gravity_in_the_star-forming_region_l1688/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yue Hu
Interaction of three-dimensional magnetic fields, turbulence, and self-gravity in the molecular cloud is crucial in understanding star formation but has not been addressed so far. In this work, we target the low-mass star-forming region L1688 and use the spectral emissions of $^{12}$CO, $^{13}$CO, C$^{18}$O, and H I, as well as polarized dust emissions. To obtain the 3D direction of the magnetic field, we employ the polarization fraction analysis developed in Hu &amp;amp; Lazarian (2022).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiency of the top-down PAH-to-fullerene conversion in UV irradiated environments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/efficiency_of_the_top-down_pah-to-fullerene_conversion_in_uv_irradiated_environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/efficiency_of_the_top-down_pah-to-fullerene_conversion_in_uv_irradiated_environments/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. S. Murga
Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) and fullerenes play a major role in the physics and chemistry of the interstellar medium. Based on a number of recent experimental and theoretical investigations we developed a model in which PAHs are subject to photo-dissociation (carbon and hydrogen loss) and hydrogenation. We take into account that dehydrogenated PAHs may fold into closed structures &amp;ndash; fullerenes. Fullerenes, in their turn, can be also hydrogenated, becoming fulleranes, and photo-dissociated, losing carbon and hydrogen atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the Convective Turnover Time</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/estimating_the_convective_turnover_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/estimating_the_convective_turnover_time/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wei-Chun Jao
The introduction of the Rossby number (R$_0$), which incorporates the convective turnover time ($\tau$), in 1984 was a pioneering idea for understanding the correlation between stellar rotation and activity. The convective turnover time, which cannot be measured directly, is often inferred using existing $\tau$-mass or $\tau$-color relations, typically established based on an ensemble of different types of stars by assuming that $\tau$ is a function of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extragalactic neutrino emission induced by Supermassive and Stellar Mass Black Hole mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extragalactic_neutrino_emission_induced_by_supermassive_and_stellar_mass_black_hole_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extragalactic_neutrino_emission_induced_by_supermassive_and_stellar_mass_black_hole_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ilja Jaroschewski
The recent detections of binary stellar mass black hole mergers by the LIGO and Virgo Collaborations suggest that such mergers are common occurrences. Galaxy mergers further indicate that supermassive black holes in centers of galaxies also merge and are typically expected to have had at least one merger in their lifetime, possibly many. In the presence of a jet, these mergers are almost always accompanied by a change of the jet direction and a connected jet precession motion, leading to interactions of the jet with ambient matter and producing very high-energy particles, and consequently high-energy gamma-rays and neutrinos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Local Volume Dwarf Galaxy Candidates from the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_local_volume_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_from_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_local_volume_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_from_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. D. Karachentsev
We undertook a search for new dwarf galaxies in the vicinity of relatively isolated nearby galaxies with distances $D &amp;lt; 12$ Mpc and stellar masses in the $2\times10^{11}-3\times10^8~M_{\odot}$ interval, using the data from the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys. Around the 46 considered Local Volume galaxies, $67$ new candidates for satellites of these galaxies were found. About half of them are classified as spheroidal dwarfs of low surface brightness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDSS IV MaNGA: Bar pattern speed in Milky Way Analogue galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss_iv_manga_bar_pattern_speed_in_milky_way_analogue_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss_iv_manga_bar_pattern_speed_in_milky_way_analogue_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Luis Garma-Oehmichen
Most secular effects produced by stellar bars strongly depend on the pattern speed. Unfortunately, it is also the most difficult observational parameter to estimate. In this work, we measured the bar pattern speed of 97 Milky-Way Analogue galaxies from the MaNGA survey using the Tremaine-Weinberg method. The sample was selected by constraining the stellar mass and morphological type. We improve our measurements by weighting three independent estimates of the disc position angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The integrated perturbation theory for cosmological tensor fields II: Loop corrections</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_integrated_perturbation_theory_for_cosmological_tensor_fields_ii_loop_corrections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_integrated_perturbation_theory_for_cosmological_tensor_fields_ii_loop_corrections/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takahiko Matsubara
In the previous paper [arXiv:2210.10435], the nonlinear perturbation theory of cosmological density field is generalized to include the tensor-valued bias of astronomical objects, such as spins and shapes of galaxies and any other tensors of arbitrary ranks which are associated with objects that we can observe. We apply this newly developed method to explicitly calculate nonlinear power spectra and correlation functions both in real space and in redshift space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very metal-poor stars in the solar vicinity: age determination</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/very_metal-poor_stars_in_the_solar_vicinity_age_determination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/very_metal-poor_stars_in_the_solar_vicinity_age_determination/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anastasiia Plotnikova
The ages of the oldest and most metal-poor stars in the Milky Way bear important information on the age of the Universe and its standard model. We analyze a sample of 28 extremely metal-poor field stars in the solar vicinity culled from the literature and carefully determine their ages. To this aim, we critically make use of Gaia data to derive their distances and associated uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for kilonova radio flares in a sample of Swift/BAT short GRBs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_kilonova_radio_flares_in_a_sample_of_swift_bat_short_grbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_kilonova_radio_flares_in_a_sample_of_swift_bat_short_grbs/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Eddins
The multi-messenger detection of GW170817 showed that binary neutron star (BNS) mergers are progenitors of (at least some) short gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), and that short GRB jets (and their afterglows) can have structures (and observational properties) more complex than predicted by the standard top-hat jet scenario. Indeed, the emission from the structured jet launched in GW170817 peaked in the radio band (cm wavelengths) at about 100 d since merger - a timescale much longer than the typical time span of radio follow-up observations of short GRBs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Millimeter Flares Detected from Epsilon Eridani with ALMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_millimeter_flares_detected_from_epsilon_eridani_with_alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_millimeter_flares_detected_from_epsilon_eridani_with_alma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kiana Burton
We report the detection of three large millimeter flaring events from the nearby Sun-like, $\epsilon$ Eridani, found in archival ALMA 12m and ACA observations at 1.33 mm taken from 2015 January 17-18 and 2016 October 24-November 23, respectively. This is the first time that flares have been detected from a Sun-like star at millimeter wavelengths. The largest flare among our data was detected in the ALMA observations on 2015 January 17 from 20:09:10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRB 180325A: dust grain-size distribution and interstellar iron nanoparticles contribution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/grb_180325a_dust_grain-size_distribution_and_interstellar_iron_nanoparticles_contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/grb_180325a_dust_grain-size_distribution_and_interstellar_iron_nanoparticles_contribution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elizabeth Cappellazzo
We modelled dust grain-size distributions for carbonaceous and silicates dust, as well as for free-flying iron nanoparticles in the environment of a $\gamma$-ray burst (GRB) afterglow, GRB 180325A. This GRB, at $z=2.2486$, has an unambiguous detection of the 2175 \r{A} extinction feature with $R_V=4.58$ and $A_V=1.58$. In addition to silicates, polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH), and graphite, we used iron nanoparticles grain-size distributions for the first time to model the observed extinction curve of GRB 180325A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Tidal Disruption Events with an Expansion of the FLEET Machine Learning Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_tidal_disruption_events_with_an_expansion_of_the_fleet_machine_learning_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_tidal_disruption_events_with_an_expansion_of_the_fleet_machine_learning_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sebastian Gomez
We present an expansion of FLEET, a machine learning algorithm optimized to select transients that are most likely to be tidal disruption events (TDEs). FLEET is based on a random forest algorithm trained on the light curves and host galaxy information of 4,779 spectroscopically classified transients. For transients with a probability of being a TDE, \ptde$&amp;gt;0.5$, we can successfully recover TDEs with a $\approx40$% completeness and a $\approx30$% purity when using the first 20 days of photometry, or a similar completeness and $\approx50$% purity when including 40 days of photometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeMoN: Lens Modelling with Neural networks -- I. Automated modelling of strong gravitational lenses with Bayesian Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lemon_lens_modelling_with_neural_networks_--_i._automated_modelling_of_strong_gravitational_lenses_with_bayesian_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lemon_lens_modelling_with_neural_networks_--_i._automated_modelling_of_strong_gravitational_lenses_with_bayesian_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrizio Gentile
The unprecedented number of gravitational lenses expected from new-generation facilities such as the ESA Euclid telescope and the Vera Rubin Observatory makes it crucial to rethink our classical approach to lens-modelling. In this paper, we present LeMoN (Lens Modelling with Neural networks): a new machine-learning algorithm able to analyse hundreds of thousands of gravitational lenses in a reasonable amount of time. The algorithm is based on a Bayesian Neural Network: a new generation of neural networks able to associate a reliable confidence interval to each predicted parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-infrared imaging of Supernova 1987A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mid-infrared_imaging_of_supernova_1987a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mid-infrared_imaging_of_supernova_1987a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mikako Matsuura
At a distance of 50 kpc, Supernova 1987A is an ideal target to study how a young supernova (SN) evolves in time. Its equatorial ring, filled with material expelled from the progenitor star about 20,000 years ago, has been engulfed with SN blast waves. Shocks heat dust grains in the ring, emitting their energy at mid-infrared (IR) wavelengths We present ground-based 10&amp;ndash;18$\mu$m monitoring of the ring of SN 1987A from day 6067 to 12814 at a resolution of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconnection-Driven Energy Cascade in Magnetohydrodynamic Turbulence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconnection-driven_energy_cascade_in_magnetohydrodynamic_turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconnection-driven_energy_cascade_in_magnetohydrodynamic_turbulence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chuanfei Dong
Magnetohydrodynamic turbulence regulates the transfer of energy from large to small scales in many astrophysical systems, including the solar atmosphere. We perform three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic simulations with unprecedentedly large magnetic Reynolds number to reveal how rapid reconnection of magnetic field lines changes the classical paradigm of the turbulent energy cascade. By breaking elongated current sheets into chains of small magnetic flux ropes (or plasmoids), magnetic reconnection leads to a new range of turbulent energy cascade, where the rate of energy transfer is controlled by the growth rate of the plasmoids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red supergiant stars in IC 1613 and metallicity-dependent mixing length in the evolutionary model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/red_supergiant_stars_in_ic_1613_and_metallicity-dependent_mixing_length_in_the_evolutionary_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/red_supergiant_stars_in_ic_1613_and_metallicity-dependent_mixing_length_in_the_evolutionary_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sang-Hyun Chun
We report a spectroscopic study on red supergiant stars (RSGs) in the irregular dwarf galaxy IC 1613 in the Local Group. We derive the effective temperatures ($T_\mathrm{eff}$) and metallicities of 14 RSGs by synthetic spectral fitting to the spectra observed with the MMIRS instrument on the MMT telescope for a wavelength range from 1.16 $\mu$m to 1.23 $\mu$m. A weak bimodal distribution of the RSG metallicity centered on the [Fe/H]=$-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation level of turbulence in collapsing gas clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_level_of_turbulence_in_collapsing_gas_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_level_of_turbulence_in_collapsing_gas_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sho Higashi
We investigate the physical mechanism that decides the saturation level of turbulence in collapsing gas clouds. We perform a suite of high-resolution numerical simulations following the collapse of turbulent gas clouds with various effective polytropic exponents $\gamma_{\rm eff}$, initial Mach numbers $\mathcal{M}0$, and initial turbulent seeds. Equating the energy injection rate by gravitational contraction and the dissipation rate of turbulence, we obtain an analytic expression of the saturation level of turbulence, and compare it with the numerical results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMC-Last Mosaic Images</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/smc-last_mosaic_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/smc-last_mosaic_images/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. R. Mizuno
We present mosaic images of the Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC) observed with the Spitzer IRAC 3.6 $\mu$m and 4.5 $\mu$m bands over two epochs, 2017 August 25 to 2017 September 13, and 2017 November 24 to 2018 February 12. The survey region comprises $\sim$30 square degrees covering the SMC and the Bridge to the Large Magellanic Cloud. The region is covered by 52 $\sim$1$.!!^\circ$1$\times$1$.!!^\circ$1 tiles, with each tile including images in each band for both separate and combined epochs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nova KT Eri Is a Recurrent Nova With a Recurrence Time-Scale of 40-50 Years</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_nova_kt_eri_is_a_recurrent_nova_with_a_recurrence_time-scale_of_40-50_years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_nova_kt_eri_is_a_recurrent_nova_with_a_recurrence_time-scale_of_40-50_years/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bradley E. Schaefer
KT Eridani was a very fast nova in 2009 peaking at V=5.42 mag. We marshal large data sets of photometry to finally work out the nature of KT Eri. From the TESS light curve, as confirmed with our radial velocity curve, we find an orbital period of 2.61595 days. With our 272 spectral energy distributions from simultaneous BVRIJHK measures, the companion star has a temperature of 6200$\pm$500 K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-Delay Cosmography: Measuring the Hubble Constant and other cosmological parameters with strong gravitational lensing</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-delay_cosmography_measuring_the_hubble_constant_and_other_cosmological_parameters_with_strong_gravitational_lensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-delay_cosmography_measuring_the_hubble_constant_and_other_cosmological_parameters_with_strong_gravitational_lensing/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Birrer
Multiply lensed sources experience a relative time delay in the arrival of photons. This effect can be used to measure absolute distances and the Hubble constant ($H_0$) and is known as time-delay cosmography. The methodology is independent of the local distance ladder and early-universe physics and provides a precise and competitive measurement of $H_0$. With upcoming observatories, time-delay cosmography can provide a 1% precision measurement of $H_0$ and can decisively shed light on the current reported &amp;lsquo;Hubble tension&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOI-3884 b: A rare 6-R$_{\oplus}$ planet that transits a low-mass star with a giant and likely polar spot</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-3884_b_a_rare_6-r___oplus__planet_that_transits_a_low-mass_star_with_a_giant_and_likely_polar_spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toi-3884_b_a_rare_6-r___oplus__planet_that_transits_a_low-mass_star_with_a_giant_and_likely_polar_spot/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. Almenara
The Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite mission identified a deep and asymmetric transit-like signal with a periodicity of 4.5 days orbiting the M4 dwarf star TOI-3884. The signal has been confirmed by follow-up observations collected by the ExTrA facility and Las Cumbres Observatory Global Telescope, which reveal that the transit is chromatic. The light curves are well modelled by a host star having a large polar spot transited by a 6-R${\oplus}$ planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray galaxies selected from HyperLEDA database</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_galaxies_selected_from_hyperleda_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_galaxies_selected_from_hyperleda_database/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Pulatova
We cross-matched the 4XMM-DR10 catalog with the HyperLEDA database and obtained the new sample of galaxies that contain X-ray sources. Excluding duplicate observations and false matches, we present a total of 7759 galaxies with X-ray sources. In the current work, we present general properties of the sample: namely the distribution in equatorial coordinates, radial velocity distribution, morphological type, and X-ray fluxes. The sample includes morphological classification for 5241 galaxies with X-ray emission, almost half of which, 42%, are elliptical (E, E-S0).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An intergalactic medium temperature from a giant radio galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_intergalactic_medium_temperature_from_a_giant_radio_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_intergalactic_medium_temperature_from_a_giant_radio_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martijn S. S. L. Oei
The warm-hot intergalactic medium (warm-hot IGM, or WHIM) pervades the filaments of the Cosmic Web and harbours half of the Universe&amp;rsquo;s baryons. The WHIM&amp;rsquo;s thermodynamic properties are notoriously hard to measure. Here we estimate a galaxy group - WHIM boundary temperature using a new method. In particular, we use a radio image of the giant radio galaxy (giant RG, or GRG) created by NGC 6185, a massive nearby spiral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of flares on giant stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characteristics_of_flares_on_giant_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characteristics_of_flares_on_giant_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Katalin Oláh
Although late-type dwarfs and giant stars are substantially different, their flares are thought to originate in similar physical processes and differ only by a scale factor in the energy levels. We study the validity of this approach. We search for characteristics of flares on active giants, which might be statistically different from those on main-sequence stars. We used nearly 4000 flares of 61 giants and 20 stars of other types that were observed with Kepler in long-cadence mode, which is the only suitable database for this comparative study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Investigation of Neutral Gas Origins (DINGO): HI stacking experiments with early science data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_investigation_of_neutral_gas_origins_dingo_hi_stacking_experiments_with_early_science_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_investigation_of_neutral_gas_origins_dingo_hi_stacking_experiments_with_early_science_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jonghwan Rhee
We present early science results from Deep Investigation of Neutral Gas Origins (DINGO), an HI survey using the Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP). Using ASKAP sub-arrays available during its commissioning phase, DINGO early science data were taken over $\sim$ 60 deg$^{2}$ of the Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) 23 h region with 35.5 hr integration time. We make direct detections of six known and one new sources at $z &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the lockstep growth between black holes and bulges create their mass relation?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_lockstep_growth_between_black_holes_and_bulges_create_their_mass_relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/does_the_lockstep_growth_between_black_holes_and_bulges_create_their_mass_relation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guang Yang
Recent studies have revealed a strong relation between sample-averaged black-hole (BH) accretion rate (BHAR) and star formation rate (SFR) among bulge-dominated galaxies, i.e., &amp;ldquo;lockstep&amp;rdquo; BH-bulge growth, in the distant universe. This relation might be closely related to the BH-bulge mass correlation observed in the local universe. To understand further BH-bulge coevolution, we present ALMA CO(2-1) or CO(3-2) observations of 7 star-forming bulge-dominated galaxies at z=0.5-2.5. Using the ALMA data, we detect significant ($&amp;gt;3\sigma$) CO emission from 4 objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episodic accretion and mergers during growth of massive protostars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/episodic_accretion_and_mergers_during_growth_of_massive_protostars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/episodic_accretion_and_mergers_during_growth_of_massive_protostars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vardan G. Elbakyan
3D simulations of high mass young stellar object (HMYSO) growth show that their circumstellar discs fragment onto multiple self-gravitating objects. Accretion of these by HMYSO may explain episodic accretion bursts discovered recently. We post-process results of a previous 3D simulation of a HMYSO disc with a 1D code that resolves the disc and object dynamics down to the stellar surface. We find that burst-like deposition of material into the inner disc seen in 3D simulations by itself does not always signify powerful accretion bursts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding high-redshift gamma-ray bursts in tandem near-infrared and optical surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/finding_high-redshift_gamma-ray_bursts_in_tandem_near-infrared_and_optical_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/finding_high-redshift_gamma-ray_bursts_in_tandem_near-infrared_and_optical_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Campana
The race for the most distant object in the Universe has been played by long-duration gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), star-forming galaxies and quasars. GRBs took a temporary lead with the discovery of GRB 090423 at a redshift z=8.2, but now the record-holder is the galaxy GN-z11 at z=11.0. Despite this record, galaxies and quasars are very faint (GN-z11 has a magnitude H=26), hampering the study of the physical properties of the primordial Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First detection of silicon-bearing molecules in $η$ Car</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_detection_of_silicon-bearing_molecules_in__%CE%B7__car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/first_detection_of_silicon-bearing_molecules_in__%CE%B7__car/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bordiu
We present ALMA band 6 observations of the luminous blue variable Eta Car, obtained within the ALMAGAL program. We report SiO J=5-4, SiS J=12-11 and SiN N=5-4 emission in the equatorial region of the Homunculus nebula, constituting the first detection of silicon- and sulphur-bearing molecules in the outskirts of a highly evolved, early-type massive star. SiO, SiS and SiN trace a clumpy equatorial ring that surrounds the central binary at a projected distance of 2 arcsec, delineating the inner rims of the butterfly-shaped dusty region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HI-shielding of ${\rm H_2}$ in UV-irradiated protogalaxies: suppression of the photodissociation rate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hi-shielding_of___rm_h_2__in_uv-irradiated_protogalaxies_suppression_of_the_photodissociation_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hi-shielding_of___rm_h_2__in_uv-irradiated_protogalaxies_suppression_of_the_photodissociation_rate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Meredith Neyer
We study the impact of neutral hydrogen absorption on ${\rm H_2}$ photodissociation in protogalactic haloes exposed to soft-UV radiation. Lyman-series absorption can significantly deplete dissociating photons as line overlap with the ${\rm H_2}$ Lyman-Werner bands occurs for neutral column densities exceeding $10^{22}$ ${\rm cm^{-2}}$, but this effect has not been previously included in studies of protogalactic haloes. We use high-resolution three-dimensional hydrodynamic simulations to investigate this &amp;ldquo;HI-shielding&amp;rdquo; in three metal-free atomic cooling haloes collapsing at redshift $z \sim 10-20$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving gravitational wave sources at cosmological distances: Impact on the measurement of the Hubble constant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/moving_gravitational_wave_sources_at_cosmological_distances_impact_on_the_measurement_of_the_hubble_constant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/moving_gravitational_wave_sources_at_cosmological_distances_impact_on_the_measurement_of_the_hubble_constant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alejandro Torres-Orjuela
Standard sirens &amp;ndash; gravitational wave (GW) sources with an electromagnetic (EM) counterpart &amp;ndash; can be used to measure the Hubble constant directly which should help to ease the existing Hubble tension. However, if the source is moving, a relativistic redshift affects the redshift of the EM counterpart and the apparent distance of the GW source, and thus it needs to be corrected to obtain accurate measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Epoch of Reionization using synergies of line intensity mapping</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_epoch_of_reionization_using_synergies_of_line_intensity_mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_epoch_of_reionization_using_synergies_of_line_intensity_mapping/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chandra Shekhar Murmu
The Epoch of Reionization (EoR) remains a poorly understood cosmic era for the most part. Yet, efforts are still going on to probe and understand this epoch. We present a review of the latest developments in the techniques (especially line-intensity mapping) to study the EoR and try to highlight the contribution of the Indian community in this field. Line-emissions like [H I]${\rm 21cm}$, Lyman-$\alpha$, [C II]${\text{158}\mu\text{m}}$ and their role as tracers in probing the EoR are discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The burst mode of accretion in massive star formation with stellar inertia</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_burst_mode_of_accretion_in_massive_star_formation_with_stellar_inertia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_burst_mode_of_accretion_in_massive_star_formation_with_stellar_inertia/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. M. -A. Meyer
The burst mode of accretion in massive star formation is a scenario linking the initial gravitational collapse of parent pre-stellar cores to the properties of their gravitationally unstable discs and of their accretion-driven bursts. In this study, we present a series of high-resolution 3D radiation-hydrodynamics numerical simulations for young massive stars formed out of collapsing 100 Mo molecular cores spinning with several values of the ratio of rotational-to-gravitational energies beta=5%-9%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MillenniumTNG Project: The galaxy population at $z\geq 8$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_galaxy_population_at__z_geq_8_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_millenniumtng_project_the_galaxy_population_at__z_geq_8_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rahul Kannan
The early release science results from the $\textit{James Webb Space Telescope (JWST)}$ have yielded an unexpected abundance of high-redshift luminous galaxies that seems to be in tension with current theories of galaxy formation. However, it is currently difficult to draw definitive conclusions form these results as the sources have not yet been spectroscopically confirmed. It is in any case important to establish baseline predictions from current state-of-the-art galaxy formation models that can be compared and contrasted with these new measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new look at the infrared properties of z $\sim$ 5 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_look_at_the_infrared_properties_of_z___sim__5_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_look_at_the_infrared_properties_of_z___sim__5_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Sommovigo
Recent ALMA large surveys unveiled the presence of significant dust continuum emission in star-forming galaxies at $z&amp;gt;4$. Unfortunately, such large programs &amp;ndash; i.e. ALPINE ($z\sim 5$) and REBELS ($z \sim 7$) &amp;ndash; only provide us with a single Far-Infrared (FIR) continuum data point for their individual targets. Therefore, high-$z$ galaxies FIR spectral energy densities (SEDs) remain mostly unconstrained, hinging on an assumption for their dust temperature ($T_{\rm d}$) in the SED fitting procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of Population III Stars with Stellar Atmosphere and Evolutionary Modeling and Predictions of their Observability with the James Webb Space Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_population_iii_stars_with_stellar_atmosphere_and_evolutionary_modeling_and_predictions_of_their_observability_with_the_james_webb_space_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_population_iii_stars_with_stellar_atmosphere_and_evolutionary_modeling_and_predictions_of_their_observability_with_the_james_webb_space_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mikaela M. Larkin
Population III stars were the first stars to form after the Big Bang, and are believed to have made the earliest contribution to the metal content of the universe beyond the products of the Big Bang Nucleosynthesis. These stars are theorized to have had extremely short lifespans, and therefore would only be observable at high redshifts ($z \geq 3-17$) and faint apparent magnitudes ($m_{AB} \gtrsim 40$).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HALOGAS: Strong Constraints on the Neutral Gas Reservoir and Accretion Rate in Nearby Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/halogas_strong_constraints_on_the_neutral_gas_reservoir_and_accretion_rate_in_nearby_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/halogas_strong_constraints_on_the_neutral_gas_reservoir_and_accretion_rate_in_nearby_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Kamphuis
Galaxies in the local Universe are thought to require ongoing replenishment of their gas reservoir in order to maintain the observed star formation rates. Cosmological simulations predict that such accretion can occur in both a dynamically hot and cold mode. However, until now observational evidence of the accretion required to match the observed star formation histories is lacking. This paper attempts to determine whether galaxies in the local Universe possess a significant reservoir of HI and what would be the accretion rates derived from such reservoirs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling lens potentials with continuous neural fields in galaxy-scale strong lenses</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_lens_potentials_with_continuous_neural_fields_in_galaxy-scale_strong_lenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_lens_potentials_with_continuous_neural_fields_in_galaxy-scale_strong_lenses/</guid>
      <description>First author: Luca Biggio
Strong gravitational lensing is a unique observational tool for studying the dark and luminous mass distribution both within and between galaxies. Given the presence of substructures, current strong lensing observations demand more complex mass models than smooth analytical profiles, such as power-law ellipsoids. In this work, we introduce a continuous neural field to predict the lensing potential at any position throughout the image plane, allowing for a nearly model-independent description of the lensing mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planetary nebulae with Wolf-Rayet-type central stars -- IV. NGC 1501 and its mixing layer</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planetary_nebulae_with_wolf-rayet-type_central_stars_--_iv._ngc_1501_and_its_mixing_layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/planetary_nebulae_with_wolf-rayet-type_central_stars_--_iv._ngc_1501_and_its_mixing_layer/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Rubio
Theory predicts that the temperature of the X-ray-emitting gas ($\sim$10$^{6}$ K) detected from planetary nebulae (PNe) is a consequence of mixing or thermal conduction when in contact with the ionized outer rim ($\sim$10$^{4}$ K). Gas at intermediate temperatures ($\sim$10$^{5}$ K) can be used to study the physics of the production of X-ray-emitting gas, via C IV, N V and O VI ions. Here we model the stellar atmosphere of the CSPN of NGC 1501 to demonstrate that even this hot H-deficient [WO4]-type star cannot produce these emission lines by photoionization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Study of the Hardening in the AMS-02 Nuclei Spectra at a Few Hundred GV</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantitative_study_of_the_hardening_in_the_ams-02_nuclei_spectra_at_a_few_hundred_gv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quantitative_study_of_the_hardening_in_the_ams-02_nuclei_spectra_at_a_few_hundred_gv/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jia-Shu Niu
The most significant feature in the cosmic-ray (CR) nuclei spectra is the spectral hardening at a few hundred GV. Whether the hardening of the different nuclei species are same or not is important for constructing CR source and propagation models. In this work, we collect the latest released AMS-02 CR nuclei spectra of primary species (proton, helium, carbon, oxygen, neon, magnesium, silicon, and iron), secondary species (lithium, beryllium, boron, and fluorine), and hybrid species (nitrogen, sodium, and aluminum), and study the break positions and the spectral index differences (less and greater than the break rigidity) of the spectral hardening quantitatively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Modes of LyC Escape From Bursty Star Formation: Implications for [C II] Deficits and the Sources of Reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/two_modes_of_lyc_escape_from_bursty_star_formation_implications_for_c_ii_deficits_and_the_sources_of_reionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/two_modes_of_lyc_escape_from_bursty_star_formation_implications_for_c_ii_deficits_and_the_sources_of_reionization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Harley Katz
We use the SPHINX$^{20}$ cosmological radiation hydrodynamics simulation to study how Lyman Continuum (LyC) photons escape from galaxies and the observational signatures of this escape. We define two classes of LyC leaker: Bursty Leakers and Remnant Leakers, based on their star formation rates (SFRs) that are averaged over 10 Myr (SFR${10}$) or 100 Myr (SFR${100}$). Both have $f_{\rm esc}&amp;gt;20%$ and experienced an extreme burst of star formation, but Bursty Leakers have ${\rm SFR_{10}&amp;gt;SFR_{100}}$, while Remnant Leakers have ${\rm SFR_{10}&amp;lt;SFR_{100}}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak lensing in the blue: a counter-intuitive strategy for stratospheric observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/weak_lensing_in_the_blue_a_counter-intuitive_strategy_for_stratospheric_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/weak_lensing_in_the_blue_a_counter-intuitive_strategy_for_stratospheric_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mohamed M. Shaaban
The statistical power of weak lensing measurements is principally driven by the number of high redshift galaxies whose shapes are resolved. Conventional wisdom and physical intuition suggest this is optimised by deep imaging at long (red or near IR) wavelengths, to avoid losing redshifted Balmer break and Lyman break galaxies. We use the synthetic Emission Line EL-COSMOS catalogue to simulate lensing observations using different filters, from various altitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALMA Observation of a $z\gtrsim10$ Galaxy Candidate Discovered with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/alma_observation_of_a__z_gtrsim10__galaxy_candidate_discovered_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/alma_observation_of_a__z_gtrsim10__galaxy_candidate_discovered_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ilsang Yoon
We report ALMA observation of a $z\gtrsim10$ galaxy candidate (GHZ1) discovered from the GLASS-JWST Early Release Science Program. Our ALMA program aims to detect the [OIII] emission line at the rest-frame 3393.0062 GHz ($88.36\mu$m) and far-IR continuum emission with the spectral window setup seamlessly covering 26.125 GHz frequency range ($10.10&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;11.14$). A total of 7 hours of on-source integration was employed, using four frequency settings to cover the full range (1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping gas around massive galaxies: cross-correlation of DES Y3 galaxies and Compton-$y$-maps from SPT and Planck</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_gas_around_massive_galaxies_cross-correlation_of_des_y3_galaxies_and_compton-_y_-maps_from_spt_and_planck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_gas_around_massive_galaxies_cross-correlation_of_des_y3_galaxies_and_compton-_y_-maps_from_spt_and_planck/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Sánchez
We cross-correlate positions of galaxies measured in data from the first three years of the Dark Energy Survey with Compton-$y$-maps generated using data from the South Pole Telescope (SPT) and the {\it Planck} mission. We model this cross-correlation measurement together with the galaxy auto-correlation to constrain the distribution of gas in the Universe. We measure the hydrostatic mass bias or, equivalently, the mean halo bias-weighted electron pressure $\langle b_{h}P_{e}\rangle$, using large-scale information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occurrence rate of hot Jupiters around early-type M dwarfs based on TESS data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/occurrence_rate_of_hot_jupiters_around_early-type_m_dwarfs_based_on_tess_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/occurrence_rate_of_hot_jupiters_around_early-type_m_dwarfs_based_on_tess_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tianjun Gan
We present an estimate of the occurrence rate of hot Jupiters ($7
R_{\oplus}\leq R_{p}\leq 2\ R_{J}$, $0.8 \leq P_{b}\leq 10$ days) around early-type M dwarfs based on stars observed by TESS during its Primary Mission. We adopt stellar parameters from the TESS Input Catalog, and construct a sample of 60,819 M dwarfs with $10.5 \leq T_{\rm mag}\leq 13.5$, effective temperature $2900 \leq T_{\rm eff}\leq 4000\ K$ and stellar mass $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Escape Velocity Profile and Virial Mass Estimate of The Milky Way Galaxy from Gaia Observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_global_escape_velocity_profile_and_virial_mass_estimate_of_the_milky_way_galaxy_from_gaia_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_global_escape_velocity_profile_and_virial_mass_estimate_of_the_milky_way_galaxy_from_gaia_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeffrey M. La Fortune
Gaia HyperVelocity Star (HVS) kinematic observations favor a local escape velocity of ~700 km/s, nearly forty-percent greater than conventional estimates. Combining HVS and dwarf galaxy satellite data reveal the global escape velocity profile for the Galaxy smoothly traces an unbroken Keplerian decline from the central bar to the most remote satellite galaxy. We reveal a robust upper bound in baryonic mass discrepancy (maximal relative accelerations) linked to the virial theorem and obtain a fundamental and universal mass discrepancy-acceleration relation for virialized compact cosmic objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A radio-detected thermonuclear supernova from a single-degenerate progenitor with a helium star donor</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_radio-detected_thermonuclear_supernova_from_a_single-degenerate_progenitor_with_a_helium_star_donor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_radio-detected_thermonuclear_supernova_from_a_single-degenerate_progenitor_with_a_helium_star_donor/</guid>
      <description>First author: Erik C. Kool
Type Ia supernovae are thought to be carbon-oxygen white dwarf stars that explode after accreting material from a companion star, but despite extensive studies the nature of the companion star is still poorly understood, as is the explosion mechanism. In the single degenerate scenario, the companion is a non-degenerate star that loses material through winds and/or binary interaction, and a few Type Ia supernovae have shown evidence for hydrogen-rich circumstellar material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of one neutron star candidate from radial velocity monitoring</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_one_neutron_star_candidate_from_radial_velocity_monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_one_neutron_star_candidate_from_radial_velocity_monitoring/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hailong Yuan
We report the discovery of one possible neutron star binary ($P_{\rm orb} =$ 0.8666 day) by using the LAMOST low-resolution spectroscopic data. The visible companion is a late A-type dwarf ($T_{\rm eff} = 7900 \pm 200$ K; log$g$ $=$ 4.3$\pm$0.2; $M =$ 1.7$\pm$0.1 M${\odot}$; $R\ =\ 1.7\pm0.2$ R${\odot}$), at a distance of 1.11$\pm0.03$ kpc. No double-lined feature can be seen from the GTC/HORuS high-resolution spectra, thus the radial velocity variation indicates an invisible object hiding in the binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It takes two to know one: Computing accurate one-point PDF covariances from effective two-point PDF models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/it_takes_two_to_know_one_computing_accurate_one-point_pdf_covariances_from_effective_two-point_pdf_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/it_takes_two_to_know_one_computing_accurate_one-point_pdf_covariances_from_effective_two-point_pdf_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Cora Uhlemann
One-point probability distribution functions (PDFs) of the cosmic matter density are powerful cosmological probes that extract non-Gaussian properties of the matter distribution and complement two-point statistics. Computing the covariance of one-point PDFs is key for building a robust galaxy survey analysis for upcoming surveys like Euclid and the Rubin Observatory LSST and requires good models for the two-point PDFs characterising spatial correlations. In this work, we obtain accurate PDF covariances using effective shifted lognormal two-point PDF models for the mildly non-Gaussian weak lensing convergence and validate our predictions against large sets of Gaussian and non-Gaussian maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar Dust Emission in Quasar IR SEDs and Its Correlation with Narrow Line Regions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polar_dust_emission_in_quasar_ir_seds_and_its_correlation_with_narrow_line_regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polar_dust_emission_in_quasar_ir_seds_and_its_correlation_with_narrow_line_regions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jianwei Lyu
Polar dust has been found to play an important role in the mid-infrared emission of nearby Seyfert nuclei. If and how often polar dust exists among the quasar population is unknown due to the lack of spatially-resolved observations. In this Letter, we report correlations between the prominence of AGN forbidden line emission (commonly associated with the narrow line region) and the dust mid-IR energy output among the archetypal Palomar-Green quasar sample and other bright type-1 AGNs drawn from the SDSS, Spitzer and WISE archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Supermassive Black Hole Spin Mass-Energy Characteristics: A New Method and Results</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robust_supermassive_black_hole_spin_mass-energy_characteristics_a_new_method_and_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/robust_supermassive_black_hole_spin_mass-energy_characteristics_a_new_method_and_results/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ruth A. Daly
The rotational properties of astrophysical black holes are fundamental quantities that characterization the black holes. A new method to empirically determine the spin mass-energy characteristics of astrophysical black holes is presented and applied here. Results are obtained for a sample of 100 supermassive black holes with collimated dual outflows and redshifts between about zero and two. An analysis indicates that about two-thirds of the black holes are maximally spinning, while one-third have a broad distribution of spin values; it is shown that the same distributions describe the quantity $\rm{(M_{rot}/M_{irr})}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature Fluctuations in Quasar Accretion Discs from Spectroscopic Monitoring Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temperature_fluctuations_in_quasar_accretion_discs_from_spectroscopic_monitoring_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temperature_fluctuations_in_quasar_accretion_discs_from_spectroscopic_monitoring_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zachary Stone
Neustadt &amp;amp; Kochanek (2022, hereafter NK22) proposed a new method to reconstruct the temperature perturbation map (as functions of time and disc radius) of AGN accretion discs using multi-wavelength photometric light curves. We apply their technique to 100 quasars at $z=0.5-2$ from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Reverberation Mapping project, using multi-epoch spectroscopy that covers rest-frame UV-optical continuum emission from the quasar and probes days to months timescales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MASSIVE Survey. XVIII. Deep Wide-Field $K$-band Photometry and Local Scaling Relations for Massive Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_massive_survey._xviii._deep_wide-field__k_-band_photometry_and_local_scaling_relations_for_massive_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_massive_survey._xviii._deep_wide-field__k_-band_photometry_and_local_scaling_relations_for_massive_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew E. Quenneville
We present wide-field, deep $K$-band photometry of 98 luminous early-type galaxies (ETGs) from the MASSIVE survey based on observations taken with the WIRCam instrument on the Canada-France-Hawaii Telescope. Using these images, we extract accurate total $K$-band luminosities ($L_K$) and half-light radii ($R_e$) for this sample of galaxies. We use these new values to explore the size-luminosity and Faber-Jackson relations for massive ETGs. Within this volume-limited sample, we find clear evidence for curvature in both relations, indicating that the most luminous galaxies tend to have larger sizes and smaller velocity dispersions than expected from a simple power-law fit to less luminous galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Host Galaxy Photometric Redshifts to Improve Cosmological Constraints with Type Ia Supernova in the LSST Era</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_host_galaxy_photometric_redshifts_to_improve_cosmological_constraints_with_type_ia_supernova_in_the_lsst_era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/using_host_galaxy_photometric_redshifts_to_improve_cosmological_constraints_with_type_ia_supernova_in_the_lsst_era/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ayan Mitra
We perform a rigorous cosmology analysis on simulated type Ia supernovae (SN~Ia) and evaluate the improvement from including photometric host-galaxy redshifts compared to using only the &amp;ldquo;zspec&amp;rdquo; subset with spectroscopic redshifts from the host or SN. We use the Deep Drilling Fields (~50 deg^2) from the Photometric LSST Astronomical Time-Series Classification Challenge (PLaSTiCC), in combination with a low-z sample based on Data Challenge2 (DC2). The analysis includes light curve fitting to standardize the SN brightness, a high-statistics simulation to obtain a bias-corrected Hubble diagram, a statistical+systematics covariance matrix including calibration and photo-z uncertainties, and cosmology fitting with a prior from the cosmic microwave background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHTZ 1: A high excitation Planetary Nebula not a gaseous cocoon from runaway star HD 185806</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/whtz_1_a_high_excitation_planetary_nebula_not_a_gaseous_cocoon_from_runaway_star_hd_185806/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/whtz_1_a_high_excitation_planetary_nebula_not_a_gaseous_cocoon_from_runaway_star_hd_185806/</guid>
      <description>First author: Quentin A. Parker
We present evidence that the nebular cocoon and bow-shock emission nebula putatively and recently reported as deriving from the 9th magnitude &amp;ldquo;runaway&amp;rdquo; star HD 185806 is the previously discovered but obscure planetary nebula WHTZ 1 (Ra 7). It has a Gaia DR3 G~16 blue ionizing star at its geometric centre. We present imagery, spectroscopy, other data and arguments to support that this emission source is a high excitation Planetary Nebula not a stellar wind bow shock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wide Binaries as a Modified Gravity test: prospects for detecting triple-system contamination</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wide_binaries_as_a_modified_gravity_test_prospects_for_detecting_triple-system_contamination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wide_binaries_as_a_modified_gravity_test_prospects_for_detecting_triple-system_contamination/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dhruv Manchanda
Several recent studies have shown that velocity differences of very wide binary stars, measured to high precision with GAIA, can potentially provide an interesting test for modified-gravity theories which attempt to emulate dark matter; in essence, MOND-like theories (with external field effect included) predict that wide binaries (wider than $\sim 7$ kAU) should orbit $\sim 15%$ faster than Newtonian for similar orbit parameters; such a shift is readily detectable in principle in the sample of 9,000 candidate systems selected from GAIA EDR3 by Pittordis and Sutherland (2022).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Star-Forming Complexes in the Ring of the S0 galaxy NGC 4324</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/young_star-forming_complexes_in_the_ring_of_the_s0_galaxy_ngc_4324/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/young_star-forming_complexes_in_the_ring_of_the_s0_galaxy_ngc_4324/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. S. Proshina
We present the results of our study of starforming regions in the lenticular galaxy NGC 4324. During a complex analysis of multiwavelength observational data &amp;ndash; the narrow-band emission-line images obtained with the 2.5-m telescope at the Caucasus Mountain Observatory of the Sternberg Astronomical Institute of the Moscow State University and the archival images in the broad bands of the SDSS, GALEX and WISE surveys &amp;ndash; we have detected young starforming complexes (clumps) located in the inner ring of the lenticular galaxy NGC 4324, and we have established a regular pattern of their distribution along the ring, which, nevertheless, changes with time (with age of starforming regions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Lensed Lyman-Alpha Emitters within the Early HETDEX Data Set</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_lensed_lyman-alpha_emitters_within_the_early_hetdex_data_set/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_lensed_lyman-alpha_emitters_within_the_early_hetdex_data_set/</guid>
      <description>First author: Isaac H. Laseter
The Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy Experiment (HETDEX) is a large-volume spectroscopic survey without pre-selection of sources, searching ~ 540 deg^2 for Lyman-alpha emitting galaxies (LAEs) at 1.9 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 3.5. Taking advantage of such a wide-volume survey, we perform a pilot study using early HETDEX data to search for lensed Lyman-alpha emitters. After performing a proof-of-concept using a previously known lensed LAE covered by HETDEX, we perform a search for previously unknown lensed LAEs in the HETDEX spectroscopic sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust survival rates in clumps passing through the Cas~A reverse shock -- II. The impact of magnetic fields</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_survival_rates_in_clumps_passing_through_the_cas~a_reverse_shock_--_ii._the_impact_of_magnetic_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_survival_rates_in_clumps_passing_through_the_cas~a_reverse_shock_--_ii._the_impact_of_magnetic_fields/</guid>
      <description>First author: Florian Kirchschlager
Dust grains form in the clumpy ejecta of core-collapse supernovae where they are subject to the reverse shock, which is able to disrupt the clumps and destroy the grains. Important dust destruction processes include thermal and kinetic sputtering as well as fragmentation and grain vaporization. In the present study, we focus on the effect of magnetic fields on the destruction processes. We have performed magneto-hydrodynamical simulations using AstroBEAR to model a shock wave interacting with an ejecta clump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational focusing effects on streaming dark matter as a new detection concept</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_focusing_effects_on_streaming_dark_matter_as_a_new_detection_concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_focusing_effects_on_streaming_dark_matter_as_a_new_detection_concept/</guid>
      <description>First author: Abaz Kryemadhi
This work suggests how to search for streaming constituents from the dark sector. Following cosmological reasoning, a very large number of dark fine grained streams are expected in the Galaxy. Within the solar system, planetary gravitational focusing is effective for the slow DM particles, with possible strong flux enhancements only for streaming dark constituents. The present simulation incorporates gravitational effects preceding their encounter with Earth bound detectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the finite life-time of UHECR sources</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_the_finite_life-time_of_uhecr_sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_the_finite_life-time_of_uhecr_sources/</guid>
      <description>First author: Björn Eichmann
The observational data on ultrahigh energy cosmic rays (UHECR), in particular their mass composition, show strong indications for extremely hard spectra of individual mass groups of CR nuclei at Earth. In this work, we show that such hard spectra can be the result of the finite life-time of UHECR sources, if a few individual sources dominate the UHECR flux at the highest energies. In this case, time delays induced by deflections in the turbulent extragalactic magnetic field as well as from the diffusive or advective escape from the source environment can suppress low-energy CRs, leading to a steepening of the observed spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KiDS-Legacy calibration: unifying shear and redshift calibration with the SKiLLS multi-band image simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kids-legacy_calibration_unifying_shear_and_redshift_calibration_with_the_skills_multi-band_image_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kids-legacy_calibration_unifying_shear_and_redshift_calibration_with_the_skills_multi-band_image_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shun-Sheng Li
We present SKiLLS, a suite of multi-band image simulations for the KiDS-Legacy analysis, the weak lensing analysis of the complete Kilo-Degree Survey. The resulting catalogues enable joint shear and redshift calibration, enhancing the realism and hence accuracy over previous efforts. To create a large volume of simulated galaxies with faithful properties and to a sufficient depth, we integrate cosmological simulations with high-quality imaging observations. We also improve the realism of simulated images by allowing the point spread function (PSF) to differ between CCD images, including stellar density variations and varying noise levels between pointings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimising the H$α$ index for the identification of activity signals in FGK stars. Improvement of the correlation between H$α$ and CaII H&amp;K</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optimising_the_h_%CE%B1__index_for_the_identification_of_activity_signals_in_fgk_stars._improvement_of_the_correlation_between_h_%CE%B1__and_caii_hk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optimising_the_h_%CE%B1__index_for_the_identification_of_activity_signals_in_fgk_stars._improvement_of_the_correlation_between_h_%CE%B1__and_caii_hk/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Gomes da Silva
In this work we investigate the effect of the H$\alpha$ bandpass width in the correlation between the CaII H&amp;amp;K and H$\alpha$ indices with the aim of improving the H$\alpha$ index to better identify and model the signals coming from activity variability. We used a sample of 152 FGK dwarfs observed with HARPS for more than 13 years with enough cadence to be able to detect rotational modulations and cycles in activity proxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probable low-frequency quasi-periodic oscillations in blazars from the ZTF survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probable_low-frequency_quasi-periodic_oscillations_in_blazars_from_the_ztf_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probable_low-frequency_quasi-periodic_oscillations_in_blazars_from_the_ztf_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anuvab Banerjee
We investigate the possible presence of quasi-periodic oscillation (QPO) signals in 2103 blazars from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) time-domain survey. We detect a low frequency QPO signal in five blazars observed over these 3.8 year long optical r-band ZTF light curves. These periods range from 144 days to 196 days detected at $\gtrsim4\sigma$ significance levels in both the Lomb-Scargle periodogram and Weighted Wavelet Z-transform analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relativistic Signatures of Flux Eruption Events Near Black Holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/relativistic_signatures_of_flux_eruption_events_near_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/relativistic_signatures_of_flux_eruption_events_near_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zachary Gelles
Images of supermassive black holes produced using very long baseline interferometry provide a pathway to directly observing effects of a highly curved spacetime, such as a bright photon ring&#39;&#39; that arises from strongly lensed emission. In addition, the emission near supermassive black holes is highly variable, with bright high-energy flares regularly observed. We demonstrate that intrinsic variability can introduce prominent associated changes in the relative brightness of the photon ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The information on halo properties contained in spectroscopic observations of late-type galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_information_on_halo_properties_contained_in_spectroscopic_observations_of_late-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_information_on_halo_properties_contained_in_spectroscopic_observations_of_late-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tariq Yasin
Rotation curves are the key observational manifestation of the dark matter distribution around late-type galaxies. In a halo model context, the precision of constraints on halo parameters is a complex function of the properties of the measurements as well as properties of the galaxy itself. Forthcoming surveys will resolve rotation curves to varying degrees of precision, or measure their integrated effect in the HI linewidth. To ascertain the relative significance of the relevant quantities for constraining halo properties, we study the information on halo mass and concentration as quantified by the Kullback-Leibler divergence of the kinematics-informed posterior from the uninformative prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Local Group&#39;s mass: probably no more than the sum of its parts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_local_groups_mass_probably_no_more_than_the_sum_of_its_parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_local_groups_mass_probably_no_more_than_the_sum_of_its_parts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Till Sawala
The total mass of the Local Group (LG) and the masses of its primary constituents, the Milky Way and M31, are important anchors for several cosmological questions. In recent years, independent measurements have consistently yielded halo masses close to $10^{12} \mathrm{M_\odot}$ for the MW, and $1-2 \times 10^{12} \mathrm{M_\odot}$ for M31, while estimates derived from the pair&amp;rsquo;s kinematics via the `timing argument&amp;rsquo; have yielded a combined mass of around $5 \times 10^{12} \mathrm{M_\odot}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The REACH radiometer for detecting the 21-cm hydrogen signal from redshift 7.5 to 28</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_reach_radiometer_for_detecting_the_21-cm_hydrogen_signal_from_redshift_7.5_to_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_reach_radiometer_for_detecting_the_21-cm_hydrogen_signal_from_redshift_7.5_to_28/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. de Lera Acedo
Observations of the 21-cm line from primordial hydrogen promise to be one of the best tools to study the early epochs of the Universe: the Dark Ages, the Cosmic Dawn, and the subsequent Epoch of Reionization. In 2018, the EDGES experiment caught the attention of the cosmology community with a potential detection of an absorption feature in the sky-averaged radio spectrum centred at 78 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the gap -- the disappearance of the intermediate period gap for fully convective stars, uncovered by new ZTF rotation periods</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bridging_the_gap_--_the_disappearance_of_the_intermediate_period_gap_for_fully_convective_stars_uncovered_by_new_ztf_rotation_periods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bridging_the_gap_--_the_disappearance_of_the_intermediate_period_gap_for_fully_convective_stars_uncovered_by_new_ztf_rotation_periods/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuxi Lu
The intermediate period gap, discovered by Kepler, is an observed dearth of stellar rotation periods in the temperature-period diagram at $\sim$ 20 days for G dwarfs and up to $\sim$ 30 days for early-M dwarfs. However, because Kepler mainly targeted solar-like stars, there is a lack of measured periods for M dwarfs, especially those at the fully convective limit. Therefore it is unclear if the intermediate period gap exists for mid- to late-M dwarfs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Post-Starburst Galaxies Host Compact Molecular Gas Reservoirs?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/do_post-starburst_galaxies_host_compact_molecular_gas_reservoirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/do_post-starburst_galaxies_host_compact_molecular_gas_reservoirs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fengwu Sun
We analysed the high-resolution (up to $\sim$0.2&amp;quot;) ALMA CO (2-1) and 1.3 mm dust continuum data of eight gas-rich post-starburst galaxies (PSBs) in the local Universe, six of which had been studied by Smercina et al. (2022). In contrast to this study reporting the detections of extraordinarily compact (i.e., unresolved) reservoirs of molecular gas in the six PSBs, our visibility-plane analysis resolves the CO (2-1) emission in all eight PSBs with effective radii ($R_\mathrm{e,CO}$) of $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental effective temperature measurements for eclipsing binary stars -- II. The detached F-type eclipsing binary CPD-54 810</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fundamental_effective_temperature_measurements_for_eclipsing_binary_stars_--_ii._the_detached_f-type_eclipsing_binary_cpd-54_810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fundamental_effective_temperature_measurements_for_eclipsing_binary_stars_--_ii._the_detached_f-type_eclipsing_binary_cpd-54_810/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. J. Miller
CPD-54 810 is a double-lined detached eclipsing binary containing two mid-F type dwarfs on an eccentric 26-day orbit. We perform a combined analysis of the extensive photometry obtained by the TESS space mission along with previously published observations to obtain a full orbital and physical solution for the system. We measure the following model-independent masses and radii: M1 = 1.3094+/-0.0051 Msun, M2 = 1.0896+/-0.0034 Msun, R1 = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST Imaging of the Cartwheel Galaxy Reveals Dust Formation in SN 2021afdx</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_imaging_of_the_cartwheel_galaxy_reveals_dust_formation_in_sn_2021afdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_imaging_of_the_cartwheel_galaxy_reveals_dust_formation_in_sn_2021afdx/</guid>
      <description>First author: Griffin Hosseinzadeh
We present near- and mid-infrared (0.9-18 $\mu$m) photometry of supernova (SN) 2021afdx, which was imaged serendipitously with the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) as part of its Early Release Observations of the Cartwheel Galaxy. Our ground-based optical observations show it is likely to be a Type IIb SN, the explosion of a yellow supergiant, and its infrared spectral energy distribution (SED) $\approx$200 days after explosion shows two distinct components, which we attribute to hot gas and warm dust in the SN ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman-alpha Emitters in Ionized Bubbles: Constraining the Environment and Ionized Fraction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lyman-alpha_emitters_in_ionized_bubbles_constraining_the_environment_and_ionized_fraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lyman-alpha_emitters_in_ionized_bubbles_constraining_the_environment_and_ionized_fraction/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. C. Trapp
Lyman-alpha emitters (LAEs) are excellent probes of the reionization process, as they must be surrounded by large ionized bubbles in order to be visible during the reionization era. Large ionized regions are thought to correspond to over-dense regions and may be protoclusters, making them interesting test-beds for early massive structures. Close associations containing several LAEs are often assumed to mark over-dense, ionized bubbles. Here, we develop the first framework to quantify the ionization and density fields of high-z galaxy associations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-wavelength observations of the obscuring wind in the radio-quiet quasar MR 2251-178</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-wavelength_observations_of_the_obscuring_wind_in_the_radio-quiet_quasar_mr_2251-178/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-wavelength_observations_of_the_obscuring_wind_in_the_radio-quiet_quasar_mr_2251-178/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junjie Mao
Obscuring winds driven away from active supermassive black holes are rarely seen due to their transient nature. They have been observed with multi-wavelength observations in a few Seyfert 1 galaxies and one broad absorption line radio-quiet quasar so far. An X-ray obscuration event in MR 2251-178 was caught in late 2020, which triggered multi-wavelength (NIR to X-ray) observations targeting this radio-quiet quasar. In the X-ray band, the obscurer leads to a flux drop in the soft X-ray band from late 2020 to early 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of testing late-time cosmology with weak lensing of gravitational waves and galaxy surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_of_testing_late-time_cosmology_with_weak_lensing_of_gravitational_waves_and_galaxy_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_of_testing_late-time_cosmology_with_weak_lensing_of_gravitational_waves_and_galaxy_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna Balaudo
We investigate the synergy of upcoming galaxy surveys and gravitational wave (GW) experiments in constraining late-time cosmology, examining the cross-correlations between the weak lensing of gravitational waves (GW-WL) and the galaxy fields. Without focusing on any specific GW detector configuration, we benchmark the requirements for the high-precision measurement of cosmological parameters by considering several scenarios, varying the number of detected GW events and the uncertainty on the inference of the source luminosity distance and redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation-driven acceleration in the expanding WR140 dust shell</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation-driven_acceleration_in_the_expanding_wr140_dust_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiation-driven_acceleration_in_the_expanding_wr140_dust_shell/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yinuo Han
The Wolf-Rayet (WR) binary system WR140 is a close (0.9-16.7 mas) binary star consisting of an O5 primary and WC7 companion and is known as the archetype of episodic dust-producing WRs. Dust in WR binaries is known to form in a confined stream originating from the collision of the two stellar winds, with orbital motion of the binary sculpting the large-scale dust structure into arcs as dust is swept radially outwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral cube extraction for the VLT/SPHERE IFS: Open-source pipeline with full forward modeling and improved sensitivity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectral_cube_extraction_for_the_vlt_sphere_ifs_open-source_pipeline_with_full_forward_modeling_and_improved_sensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectral_cube_extraction_for_the_vlt_sphere_ifs_open-source_pipeline_with_full_forward_modeling_and_improved_sensitivity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthias Samland
We present a new open-source data-reduction pipeline to reconstruct spectral data cubes from raw SPHERE integral-field spectrograph (IFS) data. The pipeline is written in Python and based on the pipeline that was developed for the CHARIS IFS. It introduces several improvements to SPHERE data analysis that ultimately produce significant improvements in postprocessing sensitivity. We first used new data to measure SPHERE lenslet point spread functions (PSFs) at the four laser calibration wavelengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ASAS-SN Bright Supernova Catalog -- V. 2018-2020</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_asas-sn_bright_supernova_catalog_--_v._2018-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_asas-sn_bright_supernova_catalog_--_v._2018-2020/</guid>
      <description>First author: K. D. Neumann
We catalog the 443 bright supernovae discovered by the All-Sky Automated Survey for Supernovae (ASAS-SN) in $2018-2020$ along with the 519 supernovae recovered by ASAS-SN and 516 additional $m_{peak}\leq18$ mag supernovae missed by ASAS-SN. Our statistical analysis focuses primarily on the 984 supernovae discovered or recovered in ASAS-SN $g$-band observations. The complete sample of 2427 ASAS-SN supernovae includes earlier $V$-band samples and unrecovered supernovae. For each supernova, we identify the host galaxy, its UV to mid-IR photometry, and the offset of the supernova from the center of the host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eccentricity Distribution of Wide Binaries</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_eccentricity_distribution_of_wide_binaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_eccentricity_distribution_of_wide_binaries/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Benisty
Future Gaia and Legacy Survey of Space and Time data releases, together with wide area spectroscopic surveys, will deliver large samples of resolved binary stars with phase space coordinates, albeit with low-cadence. Given an eccentricity law $f(\epsilon)$, we derive properties of (i) the velocity distribution $v/\sqrt{G M/r}$ normalised by the value for a circular orbit at the measured separation $r$; (ii) the astrometric acceleration distributions $a/\left(G M/r^2\right)$ again normalised to the circular orbit value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JCMT BISTRO Survey: A Spiral Magnetic Field in a Hub-Filament Structure, Monoceros R2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jcmt_bistro_survey_a_spiral_magnetic_field_in_a_hub-filament_structure_monoceros_r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jcmt_bistro_survey_a_spiral_magnetic_field_in_a_hub-filament_structure_monoceros_r2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jihye Hwang
We present and analyze observations of polarized dust emission at 850 $\mu$m towards the central 1 pc $\times$ 1 pc hub-filament structure of Monoceros R2 (Mon R2). The data are obtained with SCUBA-2/POL-2 on the James Clerk Maxwell Telescope (JCMT) as part of the BISTRO (B-fields in Star-forming Region Observations) survey. The orientations of the magnetic field follow the spiral structure of Mon R2, which are well-described by an axisymmetric magnetic field model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The local dark matter distribution in self-interacting dark matter halos</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_local_dark_matter_distribution_in_self-interacting_dark_matter_halos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_local_dark_matter_distribution_in_self-interacting_dark_matter_halos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elham Rahimi
We study the effects of dark matter self-interactions on the local dark matter distribution in selected Milky Way-like galaxies in the EAGLE hydrodynamical simulations. The simulations were run with two different self-interacting dark matter models, a constant and velocity-dependent self-interaction cross-section. We find that the local dark matter velocity distribution of the Milky Way-like halos in the simulations with dark matter self-interactions and baryons are generally similar to those extracted from cold collisionless dark matter simulations with baryons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A census of compact sources at 162MHz: first data release from the MWA Phase II IPS Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_census_of_compact_sources_at_162mhz_first_data_release_from_the_mwa_phase_ii_ips_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_census_of_compact_sources_at_162mhz_first_data_release_from_the_mwa_phase_ii_ips_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: John Morgan
We present a catalogue of over 7000 sources from the GLEAM survey which have significant structure on sub-arcsecond scales at 162MHz. The compact nature of these sources was detected and quantified via their Interplanetary Scintillation (IPS) signature, measured in interferometric images from the Murchison Widefield Array. The advantage of this approach is that all sufficiently compact sources across the survey area are included down to a well-defined flux density limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrometric and photometric standard candidates for the upcoming 4-m ILMT survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/astrometric_and_photometric_standard_candidates_for_the_upcoming_4-m_ilmt_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/astrometric_and_photometric_standard_candidates_for_the_upcoming_4-m_ilmt_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Naveen Dukiya
The International Liquid Mirror Telescope (ILMT) is a 4-meter class survey telescope that has recently achieved first light and is expected to swing into full operations by 1st January 2023. It scans the sky in a fixed 22&amp;rsquo; wide strip centered at the declination of $+29^o21&#39;41&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;$ and works in Time Delay Integration (TDI) mode. We present a full catalog of sources in the ILMT strip that can serve as astrometric calibrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy-halo size relation from SDSS DR7 and the ELUCID simulation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy-halo_size_relation_from_sdss_dr7_and_the_elucid_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy-halo_size_relation_from_sdss_dr7_and_the_elucid_simulation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Youcai Zhang
Based on galaxies in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Data Release 7 (SDSS DR7) and dark matter haloes in the dark matter only, cosmological and constrained ELUCID simulation, we investigate the relation between the observed radii of central galaxies with stellar mass $\gtrsim 10^{8} h^{-2}{\rm M}\odot$ and the virial radii of their host dark matter haloes with virial mass $\gtrsim 10^{10.5} h^{-1}{\rm M}\odot$, and the dependence of galaxy-halo size relation on the halo spin and concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas accretion and Ram Pressure Stripping of Haloes in Void Walls</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_accretion_and_ram_pressure_stripping_of_haloes_in_void_walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_accretion_and_ram_pressure_stripping_of_haloes_in_void_walls/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. B. Thompson
We conduct hydrodynamical cosmological zoom simulations of fourteen voids to study the ability of haloes to accrete gas at different locations throughout the voids at z = 0. Measuring the relative velocity of haloes with respect to their ambient gas, we find that a tenth of the haloes are expected to be unable to accrete external gas due to its fast flow passed them (so called &amp;lsquo;fast flow haloes&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GWSim: A python package to create GW mock samples for different astrophysical populations and cosmological models of binary black holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gwsim_a_python_package_to_create_gw_mock_samples_for_different_astrophysical_populations_and_cosmological_models_of_binary_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gwsim_a_python_package_to_create_gw_mock_samples_for_different_astrophysical_populations_and_cosmological_models_of_binary_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christos Karathanasis
Precision cosmology with gravitational wave (GW) sources requires understanding the interplay between GW source population and cosmological parameters governing the dynamics of the Universe. With the fast increase of GW detections, for exploring many aspects of cosmology and fundamental physics it is necessary to develop a tool which can simulate GW mock samples for several population and cosmological models with and without a galaxy catalog. We have developed a new code called GWSim, allowing to make GW mock events from a large range of configurations, varying the cosmology, the merger rate, and the GW source parameters (mass and spin distributions in particular), for a given network of GW detectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ironing the folds: The phase space chevrons of a GSE-like merger as a dark matter subhalo detector</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ironing_the_folds_the_phase_space_chevrons_of_a_gse-like_merger_as_a_dark_matter_subhalo_detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ironing_the_folds_the_phase_space_chevrons_of_a_gse-like_merger_as_a_dark_matter_subhalo_detector/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elliot Y. Davies
Recent work uncovered features in the phase space of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s stellar halo which may be attributed to the last major merger. When stellar material from a satellite is accreted onto its host, it phase mixes and appears finely substructured in phase space. For a high-eccentricity merger, this substructure most clearly manifests as numerous wrapping chevrons in $(v_r, r)$ space, corresponding to stripes in $(E, \theta_r)$ space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling photometric variations due to a global inhomogeneity on an obliquely rotating star: application to lightcurves of white dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_photometric_variations_due_to_a_global_inhomogeneity_on_an_obliquely_rotating_star_application_to_lightcurves_of_white_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_photometric_variations_due_to_a_global_inhomogeneity_on_an_obliquely_rotating_star_application_to_lightcurves_of_white_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yasushi Suto
We develop a general framework to compute photometric variations induced by the oblique rotation of a star with an axisymmetric inhomogeneous surface. We apply the framework to compute lightcurves of white dwarfs adopting two simple models of their surface inhomogeneity. Depending on the surface model and the location of the observer, the resulting lightcurve exhibits a departure from a purely sinusoidal curve that are observed for a fraction of white dwarfs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ASKAP Radio Supernova Remnants and Candidates in the Large Magellanic Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_askap_radio_supernova_remnants_and_candidates_in_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_askap_radio_supernova_remnants_and_candidates_in_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</guid>
      <description>First author: Luke M. Bozzetto
We present a new Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) sample of 14 radio Supernova Remnant (SNR) candidates in the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC). This new sample is a significant increase to the known number of older, larger and low surface brightness LMC SNRs. We employ a multi-frequency search for each object and found possible traces of optical and occasionally X-ray emission in several of these 14 SNR candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulsating H-deficient WDs and pre-WDs observed with TESS: V. Discovery of two new DBV pulsators, WD J152738.4-450207.4 and WD 1708-871, and asteroseismology of the already known DBV stars PG 1351&#43;489, EC 20058-5234, and EC 04207-4748</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pulsating_h-deficient_wds_and_pre-wds_observed_with_tess_v._discovery_of_two_new_dbv_pulsators_wd_j152738.4-450207.4_and_wd_1708-871_and_asteroseismology_of_the_already_known_dbv_stars_pg_1351&#43;489_ec_20058-5234_and_ec_04207-4748/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pulsating_h-deficient_wds_and_pre-wds_observed_with_tess_v._discovery_of_two_new_dbv_pulsators_wd_j152738.4-450207.4_and_wd_1708-871_and_asteroseismology_of_the_already_known_dbv_stars_pg_1351&#43;489_ec_20058-5234_and_ec_04207-4748/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alejandro H. Córsico
The {\sl TESS} space mission has recently demonstrated its great potential to discover new pulsating white dwarf and pre-white dwarf stars, and to detect periodicities with high precision in already known white-dwarf pulsators. We report the discovery of two new pulsating He-rich atmosphere white dwarfs (DBVs) and present a detailed asteroseismological analysis of three already known DBV stars employing observations collected by the {\sl TESS} mission along with ground-based data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio Variability and Broad-Band Spectra of Infrared Galaxies with and without OH Megamaser Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_variability_and_broad-band_spectra_of_infrared_galaxies_with_and_without_oh_megamaser_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_variability_and_broad-band_spectra_of_infrared_galaxies_with_and_without_oh_megamaser_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yu. V. Sotnikova
We study the radio variability of galaxies with and without sources of hydroxyl (OH) megamaser radiation based on the continuum radio measurements conducted in 2019-2022 with the radio telescope RATAN-600 at frequencies of 2.3, 4.7, 8.2, and 11.2 GHz. Presumably, radio continuum emission significantly affects the megamaser radiation brightness, therefore, such a characteristic as the variability of radio emission is important for determining the OHM galaxies parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic follow-up of statistically selected extremely metal-poor star candidates from GALAH DR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopic_follow-up_of_statistically_selected_extremely_metal-poor_star_candidates_from_galah_dr3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopic_follow-up_of_statistically_selected_extremely_metal-poor_star_candidates_from_galah_dr3/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. S. Da Costa
The advent of large-scale stellar spectroscopic surveys naturally leads to the implementation of machine learning techniques to isolate, for example, small sub-samples of potentially interesting stars from the full data set. A recent example is the application of the t-SNE statistical method to $\sim$600,000 stellar spectra from the GALAH survey in order to identify a sample of candidate extremely metal-poor (EMP, [Fe/H] $\leq$ -3) stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starburst Nuclei as Light Dark Matter Laboratories</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/starburst_nuclei_as_light_dark_matter_laboratories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/starburst_nuclei_as_light_dark_matter_laboratories/</guid>
      <description>First author: Antonio Ambrosone
Starburst galaxies are well-motivated astrophysical emitters of high-energy gamma-rays. They are well-known cosmic-ray &amp;ldquo;reservoirs&amp;rdquo;, thanks to their large magnetic fields which confine high-energy protons for $\sim 10^5$ years. Over such long times, cosmic-ray transport can be significantly affected by scatterings with sub-GeV dark matter. Here we point out that this scattering distorts the cosmic-ray spectrum, and the distortion can be indirectly observed by measuring the gamma-rays produced by cosmic-rays via hadronic collisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Analysis Routines for Single and Double Peaked Type 2 AGN Spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/efficient_analysis_routines_for_single_and_double_peaked_type_2_agn_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/efficient_analysis_routines_for_single_and_double_peaked_type_2_agn_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew Selwood
Driven by the imminent need to rapidly process and classify millions of AGN spectra drawn from next generation astronomical facilities, we present a spectral fitting routine for Type 2 AGN spectra optimised for high volume processing, using the Quasar Spectral Fitting library (QSFit). We analyse an optically selected sample of 813 luminous Type 2 AGN spectra at $z &amp;lt; 0.83$ from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) to qualify its performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far-ultraviolet Dust Extinction and Molecular Hydrogen in the Diffuse Milky Way Interstellar Medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/far-ultraviolet_dust_extinction_and_molecular_hydrogen_in_the_diffuse_milky_way_interstellar_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/far-ultraviolet_dust_extinction_and_molecular_hydrogen_in_the_diffuse_milky_way_interstellar_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dries Van De Putte
We aim to compare variations in the full-UV dust extinction curve (912-3000 Angstrom), with the HI/H$_2$/total H content along diffuse Milky Way sightlines, to investigate possible connections between ISM conditions and dust properties. We combine an existing sample of 75 UV extinction curves based on IUE and FUSE data, with atomic and molecular column densities measured through UV absorption. The H$_2$ column density data are based on existing Lyman-Werner absorption band models from earlier work on the extinction curves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Constraints on the 21 cm EoR Power Spectrum and the X-Ray Heating of the IGM with HERA Phase I Observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improved_constraints_on_the_21_cm_eor_power_spectrum_and_the_x-ray_heating_of_the_igm_with_hera_phase_i_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/improved_constraints_on_the_21_cm_eor_power_spectrum_and_the_x-ray_heating_of_the_igm_with_hera_phase_i_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: The HERA Collaboration
We report the most sensitive upper limits to date on the 21 cm epoch of reionization power spectrum using 94 nights of observing with Phase I of the Hydrogen Epoch of Reionization Array (HERA). Using similar analysis techniques as in previously reported limits (HERA Collaboration 2022a), we find at 95% confidence that $\Delta^2(k = 0.34$ $h$ Mpc$^{-1}$) $\leq 457$ mK$^2$ at $z = 7.9$ and that $\Delta^2 (k = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the time variable spectral energy distribution of the blazar CTA 102 from 2008 to 2022</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_time_variable_spectral_energy_distribution_of_the_blazar_cta_102_from_2008_to_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_the_time_variable_spectral_energy_distribution_of_the_blazar_cta_102_from_2008_to_2022/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Sahakyan
We present long-term multiwavelength observations of blazar CTA 102 ($z=1.037$). Detailed temporal and spectral analyses of $\gamma$-ray, X-ray and UV/optical data observed by {\it Fermi}-LAT, Swift XRT, NuSTAR and Swift-UVOT over a period of 14 years, between August 2008 and March 2022, was performed. We found strong variability of source emission in all the considered bands, especially in the $\gamma$-ray band it exhibited extreme outbursts when the flux crossed the level of $10^{-5}:{\rm photon:cm^{-2}:s^{-1}}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUSE crowded field 3D spectroscopy in NGC 300 III. Characterizing extremely faint HII regions and diffuse ionized gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/muse_crowded_field_3d_spectroscopy_in_ngc_300_iii._characterizing_extremely_faint_hii_regions_and_diffuse_ionized_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/muse_crowded_field_3d_spectroscopy_in_ngc_300_iii._characterizing_extremely_faint_hii_regions_and_diffuse_ionized_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Genoveva Micheva
There are known differences between the physical properties of HII and diffuse ionized gas (DIG), but most of the studied regions in the literature are relatively bright. We compiled a faint sample of 390 HII regions with median $\log_{10}H\alpha$=34.7 in the spiral galaxy NGC300, derived their physical properties in terms of metallicity, density, extinction, and kinematics, and performed a comparative analysis of the properties of the DIG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the typical width of Herschel filaments</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_typical_width_of_herschel_filaments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_typical_width_of_herschel_filaments/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ph. André
Herschel studies suggest that nearby (d &amp;lt; 500 pc) molecular filaments have a typical half-power width ~0.1pc, but this finding has been questioned on the ground that the measured widths tend to increase with distance. Here we revisit the dependence of measured filament widths on distance or equivalently spatial resolution, in an effort to determine whether nearby molecular filaments have a characteristic half-power width or whether this is an artifact of the finite resolution of the Herschel data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the distant universe with a very luminous fast radio burst at redshift 1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_distant_universe_with_a_very_luminous_fast_radio_burst_at_redshift_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_distant_universe_with_a_very_luminous_fast_radio_burst_at_redshift_1/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stuart D. Ryder
Fast radio bursts are millisecond-duration pulses of radio emission that have been found to originate at extragalactic distances. The bursts show dispersion imparted by intervening plasma, with the bulk attributed to the intergalactic medium. Here we report the discovery of a burst, FRB20220610A, in a complex host galaxy system at a redshift of $z=1.016 \pm 0.002$. The relationship between its redshift and dispersion confirm that the bulk of the baryonic matter was ionized and in the intergalactic medium when the universe was almost half its present age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting GeV-scale annihilating dark matter with the AMS-02 positron fraction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revisiting_gev-scale_annihilating_dark_matter_with_the_ams-02_positron_fraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revisiting_gev-scale_annihilating_dark_matter_with_the_ams-02_positron_fraction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iason Krommydas
Antimatter cosmic-rays are used to probe new phenomena in physics, including dark matter annihilation. We use the cosmic-ray positron fraction spectrum by the Alpha Magnetic Spectrometer, to search for such an annihilation signal in the Galaxy. We focus on dark matter with mass between 5 and 120 GeV, producing high-energy electrons and positrons. In these cosmic-ray energies the interplay of multiple astrophysical sources and phenomena, makes this search highly sensitive to the underlying astrophysical background assumptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semi-analytic forecasts for Roman -- the beginning of a new era of deep-wide galaxy surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/semi-analytic_forecasts_for_roman_--_the_beginning_of_a_new_era_of_deep-wide_galaxy_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/semi-analytic_forecasts_for_roman_--_the_beginning_of_a_new_era_of_deep-wide_galaxy_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Y. Aaron Yung
The Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope, NASA&amp;rsquo;s next flagship observatory, will redefine deep-field galaxy survey with a field of view two orders of magnitude larger than Hubble and an angular resolution of matching quality. These future deep-wide galaxy surveys necessitate new simulations to forecast their scientific output and to optimise survey strategies. In this work, we present five realizations of 2-deg^2 lightcones, containing a total of &amp;gt;25 million simulated galaxies with -16 &amp;lt; MUV &amp;lt; -25 spanning z ~ 0 to 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JWST High Redshift Observations and Primordial Non-Gaussianity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jwst_high_redshift_observations_and_primordial_non-gaussianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_jwst_high_redshift_observations_and_primordial_non-gaussianity/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Biagetti
Several bright and massive galaxy candidates at high redshifts have been recently observed by the James Webb Space Telescope. Such early massive galaxies seem difficult to reconcile with standard $\Lambda$ Cold Dark Matter model predictions. We discuss under which circumstances such observed massive galaxy candidates can be explained by introducing primordial non-Gaussianity in the initial conditions of the cosmological perturbations.
arxiv link
pdf link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obscured Nucleus and Shocked Environment of VV 114E Revealed by JWST/MIRI Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_obscured_nucleus_and_shocked_environment_of_vv_114e_revealed_by_jwst_miri_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_obscured_nucleus_and_shocked_environment_of_vv_114e_revealed_by_jwst_miri_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. R. Donnan
We present a spectroscopic analysis of the heavily obscured nucleus and the surrounding environment of the eastern region of the nearby ($z = 0.02007$) interacting galaxy VV 114 with the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) Mid-InfraRed Instrument (MIRI). We model the spectrum from 4.9 - 28 $\mu$m to extract Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbon (PAH) emission and the underlying obscured continuum. We find that the NE nucleus (A) is highly obscured where the low PAH equivalent width (EW) ratio, EW(12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perkins INfrared Exosatellite Survey (PINES) II. Transit Candidates and Implications for Planet Occurrence around L and T Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_perkins_infrared_exosatellite_survey_pines_ii._transit_candidates_and_implications_for_planet_occurrence_around_l_and_t_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_perkins_infrared_exosatellite_survey_pines_ii._transit_candidates_and_implications_for_planet_occurrence_around_l_and_t_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Patrick Tamburo
We describe a new transit detection algorithm designed to detect single transit events in discontinuous Perkins INfrared Exosatellite Survey (PINES) observations of L and T dwarfs. We use this algorithm to search for transits in 131 PINES light curves and identify two transit candidates: 2MASS J18212815+1414010 (2MASS J1821+1414) and 2MASS J08350622+1953050 (2MASS J0835+1953). We disfavor 2MASS J1821+1414 as a genuine transit candidate due to the known variability properties of the source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The small-scale dynamo in a multiphase supernova-driven medium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_small-scale_dynamo_in_a_multiphase_supernova-driven_medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_small-scale_dynamo_in_a_multiphase_supernova-driven_medium/</guid>
      <description>First author: Frederick A. Gent
Magnetic fields grow quickly, even at early cosmological times, suggesting the action of a small-scale dynamo (SSD) in the interstellar medium (ISM) of galaxies. Many studies have focused on idealized, isotropic, homogeneous, turbulent driving of the SSD. Here we analyze more realistic simulations of supernova-driven turbulence to understand how it drives an SSD. We find that SSD growth rates are intermittently variable as a result of the evolving multiphase ISM structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$\textit{Gaia}$ white dwarfs within 40 pc III: spectroscopic observations of new candidates in the southern hemisphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/__textitgaia__white_dwarfs_within_40_pc_iii_spectroscopic_observations_of_new_candidates_in_the_southern_hemisphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/__textitgaia__white_dwarfs_within_40_pc_iii_spectroscopic_observations_of_new_candidates_in_the_southern_hemisphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mairi W. O&amp;rsquo;Brien
We present a spectroscopic survey of 248 white dwarf candidates within 40 pc of the Sun; of these 244 are in the southern hemisphere. Observations were performed mostly with the Very Large Telescope (X-Shooter) and Southern Astrophysical Research Telescope. Almost all candidates were selected from $\textit{Gaia}$ Data Release 3 (DR3). We find a total of 246 confirmed white dwarfs, 209 of which had no previously published spectra, and two main-sequence star contaminants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A catalog of candidate double and lensed quasars from Gaia and WISE data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_catalog_of_candidate_double_and_lensed_quasars_from_gaia_and_wise_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_catalog_of_candidate_double_and_lensed_quasars_from_gaia_and_wise_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Valeri V. Makarov
Making use of strong correlations between closely separated multiple or double sources and photometric and astrometric metadata in Gaia EDR3, we generate a catalog of candidate double and multiply imaged lensed quasars and AGNs, comprising 3140 systems. It includes two partially overlapping parts, a sample of distant (redshifts mostly greater than 1) sources with perturbed data, and systems resolved into separate components by Gaia at separations less than $2\arcsec$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A HARPS radial velocity search for planets in the Scorpius-Centaurus association. And its combination with the HARPS and SOPHIE young nearby stars (YNS) surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_harps_radial_velocity_search_for_planets_in_the_scorpius-centaurus_association._and_its_combination_with_the_harps_and_sophie_young_nearby_stars_yns_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_harps_radial_velocity_search_for_planets_in_the_scorpius-centaurus_association._and_its_combination_with_the_harps_and_sophie_young_nearby_stars_yns_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Antoine Grandjean
The Scorpius-Centaurus (Sco-Cen) young and nearby massive star-forming region is particularly well suited for extrasolar planet searches with both direct imaging and radial velocity (RV) techniques. The RV search, however, is challenging, as the stars are faster rotators on average than their older stellar counterparts of similar spectral types. Moreover, the RV time series show strong signatures of stellar variability (spots and faculae) and/or stellar pulsations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Milliarcsecond Accurate Position for Sagittarius A*</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_milliarcsecond_accurate_position_for_sagittarius_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_milliarcsecond_accurate_position_for_sagittarius_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuangjing Xu
The absolute position of Sgr A*, the compact radio source at the center of the Milky Way, had been uncertain by several tens of milliarcseconds. Here we report improved astrometric measurements of the absolute position and proper motion of Sgr A*. Three epochs of phase-referencing observations were conducted with the VLBA for Sgr A* at 22 and 43 GHz in 2019 and 2020. Using extragalactic radio sources with sub-milliarcsecond accurate positions as reference, we determined the absolute position of Sgr A* at a reference epoch 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pilot Survey of an M Dwarf Flare Star with Swift&#39;s UV Grism</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_pilot_survey_of_an_m_dwarf_flare_star_with_swifts_uv_grism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_pilot_survey_of_an_m_dwarf_flare_star_with_swifts_uv_grism/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shashank Chavali
The near-ultraviolet (NUV) spectral region is a useful diagnostic for stellar flare physics and assessing the energy environment of young exoplanets, especially as relates to prebiotic chemistry. We conducted a pilot NUV spectroscopic flare survey of the young M dwarf AU Mic with the Neil Gehrels Swift Observatory&amp;rsquo;s UltraViolet and Optical Telescope. We detected four flares and three other epochs of significantly elevated count rates during the 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A unified theory for dark matter halo mass function and density profile</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unified_theory_for_dark_matter_halo_mass_function_and_density_profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unified_theory_for_dark_matter_halo_mass_function_and_density_profile/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhijie Xu
Halo abundance and structures are critical to understand the small scale challenges for $\Lambda$CDM cosmology. We present a unified theory and analytical models for both halo mass function and halo density profile based on a random walk of halos and dark matter particles. The position dependent waiting time in random walk leads to a stretched Gaussian for mass function and density with a power-law on small scale and an exponential decay on large scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy and precision of triaxial orbit models II: Viewing angles, shape and orbital structure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accuracy_and_precision_of_triaxial_orbit_models_ii_viewing_angles_shape_and_orbital_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accuracy_and_precision_of_triaxial_orbit_models_ii_viewing_angles_shape_and_orbital_structure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stefano de Nicola
We explore the potential of our novel triaxial modeling machinery in recovering the viewing angles, the shape and the orbit distribution of galaxies by using a high-resolution $N$-body merger simulation. Our modelling technique includes several recent advancements. (i) Our new triaxial deprojection algorithm SHAPE3D is able to significantly shrink the range of possible orientations of a triaxial galaxy and therefore to constrain its shape relying only on photometric information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An environmental analysis of the fast transient AT2018cow and implications for its progenitor and late-time brightness</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_environmental_analysis_of_the_fast_transient_at2018cow_and_implications_for_its_progenitor_and_late-time_brightness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_environmental_analysis_of_the_fast_transient_at2018cow_and_implications_for_its_progenitor_and_late-time_brightness/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ning-Chen Sun
The nature of the newly discovered fast blue optical transients (FBOTs) is still puzzling astronomers. In this paper we carry out a comprehensive analysis of the molecular gas, ionized gas and stellar populations in the environment of the nearby FBOT AT2018cow based on ALMA, VLT/MUSE and HST/WFC3 observations. A prominent molecular concentration of 6 ($\pm$ 1) $\times$ 10$^6$ $M_\odot$ is found in the vicinity of AT2018cow, which has given rise to two active star-forming complexes with ages of 4 $\pm$ 1 Myr and $\lesssim$2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CASA on the fringe -- Development of VLBI processing capabilities for CASA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/casa_on_the_fringe_--_development_of_vlbi_processing_capabilities_for_casa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/casa_on_the_fringe_--_development_of_vlbi_processing_capabilities_for_casa/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ilse M. van Bemmel
New functionality to process Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) data has been implemented in the CASA package. This includes two new tasks to handle fringe fitting and VLBI-specific amplitude calibration steps. Existing tasks have been adjusted to handle VLBI visibility data and calibration meta-data properly. With these updates, it is now possible to process VLBI continuum and spectral line observations in CASA. This article describes the development and implementation, and presents an outline for the workflow when calibrating European VLBI Network or Very Long Baseline Array data in CASA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CASA, the Common Astronomy Software Applications for Radio Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/casa_the_common_astronomy_software_applications_for_radio_astronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/casa_the_common_astronomy_software_applications_for_radio_astronomy/</guid>
      <description>First author: THE CASA TEAM
CASA, the Common Astronomy Software Applications, is the primary data processing software for the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) and the Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array (VLA), and is frequently used also for other radio telescopes. The CASA software can handle data from single-dish, aperture-synthesis, and Very Long Baseline Interferometery (VLBI) telescopes. One of its core functionalities is to support the calibration and imaging pipelines for ALMA, VLA, VLA Sky Survey (VLASS), and the Nobeyama 45m telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CN 2-1 and CS 5-4 observations toward Arp 299 with the SMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cn_2-1_and_cs_5-4_observations_toward_arp_299_with_the_sma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cn_2-1_and_cs_5-4_observations_toward_arp_299_with_the_sma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junzhi Wang
Dense gas is the key for understanding star formation in galaxies. We present high resolution ($\sim3&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;$) observations of CN 2-1 and CS 5-4 as dense gas tracers toward Arp 299, a mid stage major merger of galaxies, with the Submillimeter Array (SMA). The spatial distribution of CN 2-1 and CS 5-4 are generally consistent with each other, as well as HCN 1-0 in literature. However, different line ratios of CS 5-4 and CN 2-1 are found in A, B, and C regions, with highest value in B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collisional growth efficiency of dust aggregates and its independence of the strength of interparticle rolling friction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collisional_growth_efficiency_of_dust_aggregates_and_its_independence_of_the_strength_of_interparticle_rolling_friction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collisional_growth_efficiency_of_dust_aggregates_and_its_independence_of_the_strength_of_interparticle_rolling_friction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sota Arakawa
The pairwise collisional growth of dust aggregates consisting submicron-sized grains is the first step of the planet formation, and understanding the collisional behavior of dust aggregates is therefore essential. It is known that the main energy dissipation mechanisms are the tangential frictions between particles in contact, namely, rolling, sliding, and twisting. However, there is a large uncertainty for the strength of rolling friction, and the dependence of the collisional growth condition on the strength of rolling friction was poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent infall of satellites: Collective effects changing the overall picture</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/concurrent_infall_of_satellites_collective_effects_changing_the_overall_picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/concurrent_infall_of_satellites_collective_effects_changing_the_overall_picture/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Trelles
A variety of new physical processes have proven to play an important role in orbital decay of a satellite galaxy embedded inside a dark matter halo but this is not fully understood. Our goal is to assess if the orbital history of a satellite remains unchanged during a concurrent sinking. For this purpose we analyze the impact that the internal structure of the satellites and their spatial distribution inside the host halo may have on the concurrent sinking process due to both mass loss and the combined effect of self-friction, which have not been studied before for concurrent sinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the nature of the 18-min periodic radio transient GLEAM-X J162759.5-523504.3 via multi-wavelength observations and magneto-thermal simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_nature_of_the_18-min_periodic_radio_transient_gleam-x_j162759.5-523504.3_via_multi-wavelength_observations_and_magneto-thermal_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_nature_of_the_18-min_periodic_radio_transient_gleam-x_j162759.5-523504.3_via_multi-wavelength_observations_and_magneto-thermal_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Rea
We observed the periodic radio transient GLEAM-X J162759.5-523504.3 (GLEAM-X J1627) using the Chandra X-ray Observatory for about 30-ks on January 22-23, 2022, simultaneously with radio observations from MWA, MeerKAT and ATCA. Its radio emission and 18-min periodicity led the source to be tentatively interpreted as an extreme magnetar or a peculiar highly magnetic white dwarf. The source was not detected in the 0.3-8 keV energy range with a 3-sigma upper-limit on the count rate of 3x10^{-4} counts/s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographics of z ~ 6 Quasars in the Black Hole Mass-Luminosity Plane</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/demographics_of_z_~_6_quasars_in_the_black_hole_mass-luminosity_plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/demographics_of_z_~_6_quasars_in_the_black_hole_mass-luminosity_plane/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jin Wu
We study the demographics of z ~ 6 broad-line quasars in the black hole (BH) mass-luminosity plane using a sample of more than 100 quasars at 5.7 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 6.5. These quasars have well quantified selection functions and nearly one third of them also have virial BH masses estimated from near-IR spectroscopy. We use forward modeling of parameterized intrinsic distributions of BH masses and Eddington ratios, and account for the sample flux limits and measurement uncertainties of the BH masses and luminosities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of 24 radio-bright quasars at $4.9 \leq z \leq6.6$ using low-frequency radio observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_24_radio-bright_quasars_at__4.9__leq_z__leq6.6__using_low-frequency_radio_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_24_radio-bright_quasars_at__4.9__leq_z__leq6.6__using_low-frequency_radio_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Gloudemans
High redshift quasars ($z&amp;gt;5$) that also shine brightly at radio wavelengths are unique signposts of supermassive black hole activity in the early universe. However, bright radio sources at $z\ge5$ are extremely rare and therefore we have started a campaign to search for new high-$z$ quasars by combining an optical dropout selection driven by the $g$, $r$, and $z$ bands from the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI) Legacy Imaging Surveys with low-frequency radio observations from the LOFAR Two-metre Sky Survey (LoTSS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust grains cannot grow to millimeter sizes in protostellar envelopes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_grains_cannot_grow_to_millimeter_sizes_in_protostellar_envelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust_grains_cannot_grow_to_millimeter_sizes_in_protostellar_envelopes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kedron Silsbee
A big question in the field of star and planet formation is the time at which substantial dust grain growth occurs. The observed properties of dust emission across different wavelength ranges have been used as an indication that millimeter-sized grains are already present in the envelopes of young protostars. However, this interpretation is in tension with results from coagulation simulations, which are not able to produce such large grains in these conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of dwarf galaxies in $f(R)$ gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_of_dwarf_galaxies_in__fr__gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_of_dwarf_galaxies_in__fr__gravity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ivan de Martino
We use the kinematic data of the stars in eight dwarf spheroidal galaxies to assess whether $f(R)$ gravity can fit the observed profiles of the line-of-sight velocity dispersion of these systems without resorting to dark matter. Our model assumes that each galaxy is spherically symmetric and has a constant velocity anisotropy parameter $\beta$ and constant mass-to-light ratio consistent with stellar population synthesis models. We solve the spherical Jeans equation that includes the Yukawa-like gravitational potential appearing in the weak field limit of $f(R)$ gravity, and a Plummer density profile for the stellar distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Plausible Range of N2O Biosignatures on Exo-Earths: An Integrated Biogeochemical, Photochemical, and Spectral Modeling Approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evaluating_the_plausible_range_of_n2o_biosignatures_on_exo-earths_an_integrated_biogeochemical_photochemical_and_spectral_modeling_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evaluating_the_plausible_range_of_n2o_biosignatures_on_exo-earths_an_integrated_biogeochemical_photochemical_and_spectral_modeling_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: Edward W. Schwieterman
Nitrous oxide (N2O) &amp;ndash; a product of microbial nitrogen metabolism &amp;ndash; is a compelling exoplanet biosignature gas with distinctive spectral features in the near- and mid-infrared, and only minor abiotic sources on Earth. Previous investigations of N2O as a biosignature have examined scenarios using Earthlike N2O mixing ratios or surface fluxes, or those inferred from Earth&amp;rsquo;s geologic record. However, biological fluxes of N2O could be substantially higher, due to a lack of metal catalysts or if the last step of the denitrification metabolism that yields N2 from N2O had never evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Fundamental Mechanism in Driving Highest-velocity Ionized Outflows in Radio AGNs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_fundamental_mechanism_in_driving_highest-velocity_ionized_outflows_in_radio_agns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_fundamental_mechanism_in_driving_highest-velocity_ionized_outflows_in_radio_agns/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ashraf Ayubinia
We investigate the ionized gas kinematics relationship with X-ray, radio and accreting properties using a sample of 348 nearby ($z &amp;lt; 0.4$) SDSS-FIRST-X-ray detected AGNs. X-ray properties of our sample are obtained from XMM-$Newton$, $Swift$ and $Chandra$ observations. We unveil the ionized gas outflows in our sample manifested by the non-gravitational broad component in [OIII] $\lambda$5007$\overset{\circ}{A}$. emission line profiles. From the comparison of the correlation of non-parametric outflow velocities (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finite shock model of density in supersonic turbulence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/finite_shock_model_of_density_in_supersonic_turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/finite_shock_model_of_density_in_supersonic_turbulence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Branislav Rabatin
The probability distribution of density in isothermal, supersonic, turbulent gas is approximately lognormal. This behaviour can be traced back to the shock waves travelling through the medium, which randomly adjust the density by a random factor of the local sonic Mach number squared. Provided a certain parcel of gas experiences a large number of shocks, due to the central limit theorem, the resulting distribution for density is lognormal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of c-C6H5CN ice using the SPACE TIGER experimental setup</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_c-c6h5cn_ice_using_the_space_tiger_experimental_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_c-c6h5cn_ice_using_the_space_tiger_experimental_setup/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pavlo Maksyutenko
Benzonitrile (c-C6H5CN) has been recently detected in cold and dense regions of the interstellar medium (ISM), where it has been used as a signpost of a rich aromatic organic chemistry that might lead to the production of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs). One possible origin of this benzonitrile is interstellar ice chemistry involving benzene (c-C6H6) and nitrile molecules (organic molecules containing the -CN group). We have addressed the plausibility of this c-C6H5CN formation pathway through laboratory experiments using our new setup SPACE TIGER.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy kinematics and mass estimates at z~1 from ionised gas and stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_kinematics_and_mass_estimates_at_z~1_from_ionised_gas_and_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_kinematics_and_mass_estimates_at_z~1_from_ionised_gas_and_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hannah Übler
We compare ionised gas and stellar kinematics of 16 star-forming galaxies ($\log(M_\star/M_\odot)=9.7-11.2$, SFR=6-86 $M_\odot/yr$) at $z\sim1$ using near-infrared integral field spectroscopy (IFS) of H$\alpha$ emission from the KMOS$^{\rm 3D}$ survey and optical slit spectroscopy of stellar absorption and gas emission from the LEGA-C survey. H$\alpha$ is dynamically colder than stars, with higher disc rotation velocities (by ~45 per cent) and lower disc velocity dispersions (by a factor ~2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Spin Classification I: Z-wise vs S-wise Spirals With Chirality Equivariant Residual Network</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_spin_classification_i_z-wise_vs_s-wise_spirals_with_chirality_equivariant_residual_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_spin_classification_i_z-wise_vs_s-wise_spirals_with_chirality_equivariant_residual_network/</guid>
      <description>First author: He Jia
The angular momentum of galaxies (galaxy spin) contains rich information about the initial condition of the Universe, yet it is challenging to efficiently measure the spin direction for the tremendous amount of galaxies that are being mapped by the ongoing and forthcoming cosmological surveys. We present a machine learning based classifier for the Z-wise vs S-wise spirals, which can help to break the degeneracy in the galaxy spin direction measurement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Zoo: Clump Scout -- Design and first application of a two-dimensional aggregation tool for citizen science</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_zoo_clump_scout_--_design_and_first_application_of_a_two-dimensional_aggregation_tool_for_citizen_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_zoo_clump_scout_--_design_and_first_application_of_a_two-dimensional_aggregation_tool_for_citizen_science/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hugh Dickinson
Galaxy Zoo: Clump Scout is a web-based citizen science project designed to identify and spatially locate giant star forming clumps in galaxies that were imaged by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Legacy Survey. We present a statistically driven software framework that is designed to aggregate two-dimensional annotations of clump locations provided by multiple independent Galaxy Zoo: Clump Scout volunteers and generate a consensus label that identifies the locations of probable clumps within each galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas Morphology of Milky Way-like Galaxies in the TNG50: Signals of Twisting and Stretching</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_morphology_of_milky_way-like_galaxies_in_the_tng50_signals_of_twisting_and_stretching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas_morphology_of_milky_way-like_galaxies_in_the_tng50_signals_of_twisting_and_stretching/</guid>
      <description>First author: Thomas K. Waters
We present an in-depth analysis of gas morphologies for a sample of 25 Milky Way-like galaxies from the Illustris TNG50 simulation. We constrain the morphology of cold, warm, hot gas, and gas particles as a whole using a Local Shell Iterative Method (LSIM) and explore its observational implications by computing the hard-to-soft X-ray ratio, which ranges between $10^{-3}$-$10^{-2}$ in the inner $\sim 50 \rm kpc$ of the distribution and $10^{-5}$-$10^{-4}$ at the outer portion of the hot gas distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravothermal collapse of Self-Interacting Dark Matter halos as the Origin of Intermediate Mass Black Holes in Milky Way satellites</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravothermal_collapse_of_self-interacting_dark_matter_halos_as_the_origin_of_intermediate_mass_black_holes_in_milky_way_satellites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravothermal_collapse_of_self-interacting_dark_matter_halos_as_the_origin_of_intermediate_mass_black_holes_in_milky_way_satellites/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tamar Meshveliani
Milky Way (MW) satellites exhibit a diverse range of internal kinematics, reflecting in turn a diverse set of subhalo density profiles. These profiles include large cores and dense cusps, which any successful dark matter model must explain simultaneously. A plausible driver of such diversity is self-interactions between dark matter particles (SIDM) if the cross section passes the threshold for the gravothermal collapse phase at the characteristic velocities of the MW satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informed systematic method to identify variable mid and late-T dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/informed_systematic_method_to_identify_variable_mid_and_late-t_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/informed_systematic_method_to_identify_variable_mid_and_late-t_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalia Oliveros-Gómez
The majority of brown dwarfs show some level of photometric or spectro-photometric variability in different wavelength ranges. This variability allow us to trace the 3D atmospheric structures of variable brown dwarfs and directly-imaged exoplanets with radiative-transfer models and mapping codes. Nevertheless, to date, we do not have an informed method to pre-select the brown dwarfs that might show a higher variability amplitude for a thorough variability study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the [C$\,{\rm \scriptsize II}$]-to-H$\,{\rm \scriptsize I}$ conversion factor and the H$\,{\rm \scriptsize I}$ gas budget of galaxies at $z\approx 6$ with hydrodynamical simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_c___rm__scriptsize_ii_-to-h___rm__scriptsize_i__conversion_factor_and_the_h___rm__scriptsize_i__gas_budget_of_galaxies_at__z_approx_6__with_hydrodynamical_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_c___rm__scriptsize_ii_-to-h___rm__scriptsize_i__conversion_factor_and_the_h___rm__scriptsize_i__gas_budget_of_galaxies_at__z_approx_6__with_hydrodynamical_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Vizgan
One of the most fundamental baryonic matter components of galaxies is the neutral atomic hydrogen (H$,{\rm \scriptsize I}$). At low redshifts, this component can be traced directly through the 21-cm transition, but to infer H$,{\rm \scriptsize I}$ gas content of the most distant galaxies, a viable tracer is needed. We here investigate the fidelity of the fine structure transition of the ($^2P_{3/2} - ^2P_{1/3}$) transition of singly-ionized carbon [C$,{\rm \scriptsize II}$] at $158,\mu$m as a proxy for H$,{\rm \scriptsize I}$ in a set simulated galaxies at $z\approx 6$, following the work by Heintz et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic analysis of the Large Magellanic Cloud using Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kinematic_analysis_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud_using_gaia_dr3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kinematic_analysis_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud_using_gaia_dr3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ó. Jiménez-Arranz
Context: The high quality of the Gaia mission data is allowing to study the internal kinematics of the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) in unprecedented detail, providing insights on the non-axisymmetric structure of its disc. Aims: To define and validate an improved selection strategy to distinguish the LMC stars from the Milky Way foreground. To check the possible biases that assumed parameters or sample contamination from the Milky Way can introduce in the analysis of the internal kinematics of the LMC using Gaia data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Interferometer For Exoplanets (LIFE): VI. Detecting rocky exoplanets in the habitable zones of Sun-like stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/large_interferometer_for_exoplanets_life_vi._detecting_rocky_exoplanets_in_the_habitable_zones_of_sun-like_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/large_interferometer_for_exoplanets_life_vi._detecting_rocky_exoplanets_in_the_habitable_zones_of_sun-like_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jens Kammerer
While previous studies have shown a strong preference for a future mid-infrared nulling interferometer space mission to detect planets within the HZ around M dwarfs, we here focus on a more conservative approach toward the concept of habitability and present yield estimates for two stellar samples consisting of nearby (d&amp;lt;20 pc) Sun-like stars (4800-6300 K) and nearby FGK-type stars (3940-7220 K) accessible to such a mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late-time H/He-poor circumstellar interaction in the normal-looking type-Ic supernova SN 2021ocs: an exposed oxygen-magnesium layer and extreme stripping of the progenitor</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/late-time_h_he-poor_circumstellar_interaction_in_the_normal-looking_type-ic_supernova_sn_2021ocs_an_exposed_oxygen-magnesium_layer_and_extreme_stripping_of_the_progenitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/late-time_h_he-poor_circumstellar_interaction_in_the_normal-looking_type-ic_supernova_sn_2021ocs_an_exposed_oxygen-magnesium_layer_and_extreme_stripping_of_the_progenitor/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. Kuncarayakti
Supernova (SN) 2021ocs was discovered in the galaxy NGC 7828 within the interacting system Arp 144, and subsequently classified as a normal type-Ic SN around peak brightness. VLT/FORS2 observations in the nebular phase at 150 d reveal that the spectrum is dominated by oxygen and magnesium emission lines of different transitions and ionization states: O I, [O I], [O II], [O III], Mg I, and Mg II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Variations of Redshift Distributions with Probability Integral Transforms</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_variations_of_redshift_distributions_with_probability_integral_transforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_variations_of_redshift_distributions_with_probability_integral_transforms/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Myles
We present a method for mapping variations between probability distribution functions and apply this method within the context of measuring galaxy redshift distributions from imaging survey data. This method, which we name PITPZ for the probability integral transformations it relies on, uses a difference in curves between distribution functions in an ensemble as a transformation to apply to another distribution function, thus transferring the variation in the ensemble to the latter distribution function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive stars in metal-poor dwarf galaxies are often extreme rotators</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/massive_stars_in_metal-poor_dwarf_galaxies_are_often_extreme_rotators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/massive_stars_in_metal-poor_dwarf_galaxies_are_often_extreme_rotators/</guid>
      <description>First author: Abel Schootemeijer
We probe how common extremely rapid rotation is among massive stars in the early universe by measuring the OBe star fraction in nearby metal-poor dwarf galaxies. We apply a new method that uses broad-band photometry to measure the galaxy-wide OBe star fractions in the Magellanic Clouds and three more distant, more metal-poor dwarf galaxies. We find OBe star fractions of ~20% in the Large Magellanic Cloud (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOA-2020-BLG-208: Cool Sub-Saturn Planet Within Predicted Desert</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/moa-2020-blg-208_cool_sub-saturn_planet_within_predicted_desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/moa-2020-blg-208_cool_sub-saturn_planet_within_predicted_desert/</guid>
      <description>First author: Greg Olmschenk
We analyze the MOA-2020-BLG-208 gravitational microlensing event and present the discovery and characterization of a new planet with an estimated sub-Saturn mass. With a mass ratio $q = 3.17^{+0.28}{-0.26} \times 10^{-4}$ and a separation $s = 1.3807^{+0.0018}{-0.0018}$, the planet lies near the peak of the mass-ratio function derived by the MOA collaboration (Suzuki et al. 2016), near the edge of expected sample sensitivity. For these estimates we provide results using two mass law priors: one assuming that all stars have an equal planet-hosting probability, and the other assuming that planets are more likely to orbit around more massive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Gas Reservoirs in Massive Quiescent Galaxies at $\mathrm{z\sim0.7}$ Linked to Late Time Star Formation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/molecular_gas_reservoirs_in_massive_quiescent_galaxies_at___mathrmz_sim0.7__linked_to_late_time_star_formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/molecular_gas_reservoirs_in_massive_quiescent_galaxies_at___mathrmz_sim0.7__linked_to_late_time_star_formation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Charity Woodrum
We explore how the presence of detectable molecular gas depends on the inferred star formation histories (SFHs) in 8 massive, quiescent galaxies at $\mathrm{z\sim0.7}$. Half of the sample have clear detections of molecular gas, traced by CO(2-1). We find that the molecular gas content is unrelated to the rate of star formation decline prior to the most recent 1 Gyr, suggesting that the gas reservoirs are not leftover from their primary star formation epoch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurino Cadence of TXS~0506&#43;056 Consistent with Supermassive Binary Origin</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/neurino_cadence_of_txs~0506&#43;056_consistent_with_supermassive_binary_origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/neurino_cadence_of_txs~0506&#43;056_consistent_with_supermassive_binary_origin/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Becker Tjus
On September 18, 2022, an alert by ceCube indicated that a ~170TeV neutrino arrived in directional coincidence with the blazar TXS 0506+056. This event adds to two previous ones: a neutrino alert from its direction on September 22, 2017, and a 3sigma signature of a dozen neutrinos in 2014/2015. deBruijn 2020 showed that these two previous neutrino emission episodes could be due to a supermassive binary black hole (SMBBH) where jet precession close to final coalescence results in periodic emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OGLE-BLG504.12.201843: A possible extreme dwarf nova</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ogle-blg504.12.201843_a_possible_extreme_dwarf_nova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ogle-blg504.12.201843_a_possible_extreme_dwarf_nova/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camille Landri
We present the analysis of existing optical photometry and new optical spectroscopy of the candidate cataclysmic variable star OGLE-BLG504.12.201843. As was shown previously, this object has an orbital period of 0.523419 days and exhibits year-long outbursts with a mean period of 973 days. Using digitized photographic archives, we show that the earliest recorded outburst occurred in 1910. We propose that this object is a U Gem-type dwarf nova with extreme properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the triggering of extreme starburst events in low-metallicity galaxies: a deep search for companions of Green Peas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_triggering_of_extreme_starburst_events_in_low-metallicity_galaxies_a_deep_search_for_companions_of_green_peas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_triggering_of_extreme_starburst_events_in_low-metallicity_galaxies_a_deep_search_for_companions_of_green_peas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lauren Laufman
Green pea galaxies are starbursting, low-mass galaxies that are good analogues to star-forming galaxies in the early universe. We perform a survey of 23 Green Peas using the MUSE Integral Field Unit spectrograph on the VLT to search for companion galaxies. The survey reaches an average point-source depth of $\sim 10^{-18}$ erg cm$^{-2}$ s$^{-1}$ for emission lines. The MUSE field of view allows us to probe a 1$\times$1 arcmin$^2$ field around these galaxies and to search their surroundings for faint companions that could have interacted with them and induced their starburst episodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Photometric Redshifts for the Cosmic Assembly Near-Infrared Deep Extragalactic Legacy Survey (CANDELS)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optimized_photometric_redshifts_for_the_cosmic_assembly_near-infrared_deep_extragalactic_legacy_survey_candels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optimized_photometric_redshifts_for_the_cosmic_assembly_near-infrared_deep_extragalactic_legacy_survey_candels/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dritan Kodra
We present the first comprehensive release of photometric redshifts (photo-z&amp;rsquo;s) from the Cosmic Assembly Near-Infrared Deep Extragalactic Legacy Survey (CANDELS) team. We use statistics based upon the Quantile-Quantile (Q&amp;ndash;Q) plot to identify biases and signatures of underestimated or overestimated errors in photo-z probability density functions (PDFs) produced by six groups in the collaboration; correcting for these effects makes the resulting PDFs better match the statistical definition of a PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perturbed precessing ellipses as the building blocks of spiral arms in a barred galaxy with two pattern speeds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbed_precessing_ellipses_as_the_building_blocks_of_spiral_arms_in_a_barred_galaxy_with_two_pattern_speeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/perturbed_precessing_ellipses_as_the_building_blocks_of_spiral_arms_in_a_barred_galaxy_with_two_pattern_speeds/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Harsoula
Observations and simulations of barred spiral galaxies have shown that, in general, the spiral arms rotate at a different pattern speed to that of the bar. The main conclusion from the bibliography is that the bar rotates faster than the spiral arms with a double or even a triple value of angular velocity. The theory that prevails in explaining the formation of the spiral arms in the case of a barred spiral galaxy with two pattern speeds is the manifold theory, where the orbits that support the spiral density wave are chaotic, and are related to the manifolds emanating from the Lagrangian points L_1 and L_2 at the end of the bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Modeling of Dust Polarization from Magnetically Enhanced Radiative Torque (MRAT) Alignment in Protostellar Cores with POLARIS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/physical_modeling_of_dust_polarization_from_magnetically_enhanced_radiative_torque_mrat_alignment_in_protostellar_cores_with_polaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/physical_modeling_of_dust_polarization_from_magnetically_enhanced_radiative_torque_mrat_alignment_in_protostellar_cores_with_polaris/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nguyen Chau Giang
Magnetic fields ($\textbf{B}$) are an important factor that controls the star formation process. The leading method to observe $\textbf{B}$ is using polarized thermal emission from dust grains aligned with $\textbf{B}$. However, in dense environments such as protostellar cores, dust grains may have inefficient alignment due to strong gas randomizations, so that using dust polarization to trace $\textbf{B}$ is uncertain. Hoang $&amp;amp;$ Lazarian (2016) demonstrated that the grain alignment by RAdiative Torques is enhanced if dust grains contain embedded iron inclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quashing a suspected selection bias in galaxy samples having dynamically-measured supermassive black holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quashing_a_suspected_selection_bias_in_galaxy_samples_having_dynamically-measured_supermassive_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quashing_a_suspected_selection_bias_in_galaxy_samples_having_dynamically-measured_supermassive_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nandini Sahu
Local early-type galaxies with directly-measured black hole masses, $M_{\rm bh}$, have been reported to represent a biased sample relative to the population at large. Such galaxies with Spitzer Space Telescope imaging have been purported to possess velocity dispersions, $\sigma$, at least $\sim$0.1 dex larger for a given galaxy stellar mass, $M_{\rm ,gal}$, than is typically observed among thousands of early-type galaxies imaged by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Quenching of Galaxies at Cosmic Noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_quenching_of_galaxies_at_cosmic_noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_quenching_of_galaxies_at_cosmic_noon/</guid>
      <description>First author: Minjung Park
The existence of massive quiescent galaxies at high redshift seems to require rapid quenching, but it is unclear whether all quiescent galaxies have gone through this phase and what physical mechanisms are involved. To study rapid quenching, we use rest-frame colors to select 12 young quiescent galaxies at $z \sim 1.5$. From spectral energy distribution fitting, we find that they all experienced intense starbursts prior to rapid quenching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relativistic effects in a mildly recycled pulsar binary: PSR J1952&#43;2630</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/relativistic_effects_in_a_mildly_recycled_pulsar_binary_psr_j1952&#43;2630/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/relativistic_effects_in_a_mildly_recycled_pulsar_binary_psr_j1952&#43;2630/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Gautam
We report the results of timing observations of PSR J1952+2630, a 20.7 ms pulsar in orbit with a massive white dwarf companion. With the increased timing baseline, we obtain improved estimates for astrometric, spin, and binary parameters for this system. We get an improvement of an order of magnitude on the proper motion, and, for the first time, we detect three post-Keplerian parameters in this system: the advance of periastron, the orbital decay, and the Shapiro delay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying the prestellar core L1517B in Taurus molecular cloud using ammonia (NH_{3}) observation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/studying_the_prestellar_core_l1517b_in_taurus_molecular_cloud_using_ammonia_nh_3_observation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/studying_the_prestellar_core_l1517b_in_taurus_molecular_cloud_using_ammonia_nh_3_observation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Atanu Koley
Temperature measurement is essential in prestellar cores for understanding the initial conditions prior to the star formation. Here, in this work, we study the ammonia lines (J,K=1,1 and 2,2) in the prestellar core L1517B with the Very Large Array Radio Telescope (VLA). Our analysis indicates that the core is close to round in shape with a constant internal kinetic temperature of ~ 9K, suggesting the core seems to be an isothermal sphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival of Terrestrial N2-O2 Atmospheres in Violent XUV Environments through Efficient Atomic Line Radiative Cooling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/survival_of_terrestrial_n2-o2_atmospheres_in_violent_xuv_environments_through_efficient_atomic_line_radiative_cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/survival_of_terrestrial_n2-o2_atmospheres_in_violent_xuv_environments_through_efficient_atomic_line_radiative_cooling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Akifumi Nakayama
Atmospheres play a crucial role in planetary habitability. Around M dwarfs and young Sun-like stars, planets receiving the same insolation as the present-day Earth are exposed to intense stellar X-rays and extreme-ultraviolet (XUV) radiation. This study explores the fundamental question of whether the atmosphere of present-day Earth could survive in such harsh XUV environments. Previous theoretical studies suggest that stellar XUV irradiation is sufficiently intense to remove such atmospheres completely on short timescales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustained FU Orionis-type outbursts from colliding discs in stellar flybys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sustained_fu_orionis-type_outbursts_from_colliding_discs_in_stellar_flybys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sustained_fu_orionis-type_outbursts_from_colliding_discs_in_stellar_flybys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Elisabeth M. A. Borchert
We perform 3D hydrodynamics simulations of disc-disc stellar flybys with on-the-fly Monte Carlo radiative transfer. We show that pre-existing circumstellar discs around both stars result in fast rising ($\sim$yrs) outbursts lasting 2-5 times longer than for a star-disc flyby. The perturber always goes into outburst ($\dot{M}&amp;gt;10^{-5}~{\rm M_{\odot}~ yr^{-1}}$). Whereas we find that the primary goes into a decades long outburst only when the flyby is retrograde to the circumprimary disc rotation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Astrometric Animation of Water Masers towards the Mira Variable BX Cam</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_astrometric_animation_of_water_masers_towards_the_mira_variable_bx_cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_astrometric_animation_of_water_masers_towards_the_mira_variable_bx_cam/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuangjing Xu
We report VLBI monitoring observations of the 22 GHz water (H${2}$O) masers around the Mira variable BX Cam, which were carried out as a part of the EAVN Synthesis of Stellar Maser Animations (ESTEMA) project. Data of 37 epochs in total were obtained from 2018 May to 2021 June with a time interval of 3-4 weeks, spanning approximately three stellar pulsation periods ($P= \sim$440 d). In particular, the dual-beam system equipped on the VERA stations was used to measure the kinematics and parallaxes of the H${2}$O maser features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circumgalactic Medium of Extreme Emission Line Galaxies at z ~ 2: Resolved Spectroscopy and Radiative Transfer Modeling of Spatially Extended Lyman-alpha Emission in the KBSS-KCWI Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_circumgalactic_medium_of_extreme_emission_line_galaxies_at_z_~_2_resolved_spectroscopy_and_radiative_transfer_modeling_of_spatially_extended_lyman-alpha_emission_in_the_kbss-kcwi_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_circumgalactic_medium_of_extreme_emission_line_galaxies_at_z_~_2_resolved_spectroscopy_and_radiative_transfer_modeling_of_spatially_extended_lyman-alpha_emission_in_the_kbss-kcwi_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dawn K. Erb
The resonantly scattered Lyman-$\alpha$ line illuminates the extended halos of neutral hydrogen in the circumgalactic medium of galaxies. We present integral field Keck Cosmic Web Imager observations of double-peaked, spatially extended Ly$\alpha$ emission in 12 relatively low-mass ($M_{\star} \sim10^9 , M_{\odot}$) $z\sim2$ galaxies characterized by extreme nebular emission lines. Using individual spaxels and small bins as well as radially binned profiles of larger regions, we find that for most objects in the sample the Ly$\alpha$ blue-to-red peak ratio increases, the peak separation decreases, and the fraction of flux emerging at line center increases with radius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The correlation between WISE 12 $μ$m emission and molecular gas tracers on sub-kpc scales in nearby star-forming galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_correlation_between_wise_12__%CE%BC_m_emission_and_molecular_gas_tracers_on_sub-kpc_scales_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_correlation_between_wise_12__%CE%BC_m_emission_and_molecular_gas_tracers_on_sub-kpc_scales_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yang Gao
We complement the MALATANG sample of dense gas in nearby galaxies with archival observations of $^{12}\rm CO$ and its isotopologues to determine scaling relations between Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer (WISE) 12 $\mu$m emission and molecular gas tracers at sub-kiloparsec scales. We find that 12 $\mu$m luminosity is more tightly correlated with $^{12}\rm CO$ than it is with $^{13}\rm CO$ or dense gas tracers. Residuals between predicted and observed $^{12}\rm CO$ are only weakly correlated with molecular gas mass surface density ($\Sigma_{\rm mol}$) in regions where $\Sigma_{\rm mol}$ is very low ($\sim 10~{\rm M_{\odot}~pc^{-2}}$).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DAWES review 10: The impact of deep learning for the analysis of galaxy surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dawes_review_10_the_impact_of_deep_learning_for_the_analysis_of_galaxy_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dawes_review_10_the_impact_of_deep_learning_for_the_analysis_of_galaxy_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marc Huertas-Company
The amount and complexity of data delivered by modern galaxy surveys has been steadily increasing over the past years. Extracting coherent scientific information from these large and multi-modal data sets remains an open issue and data driven approaches such as deep learning have rapidly emerged as a potentially powerful solution to some long lasting challenges. This enthusiasm is reflected in an unprecedented exponential growth of publications using neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hidden side of cosmic star formation at z &gt; 3: Bridging optically-dark and Lyman break galaxies with GOODS-ALMA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_hidden_side_of_cosmic_star_formation_at_z__3_bridging_optically-dark_and_lyman_break_galaxies_with_goods-alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_hidden_side_of_cosmic_star_formation_at_z__3_bridging_optically-dark_and_lyman_break_galaxies_with_goods-alma/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mengyuan Xiao
Our current understanding of the cosmic star formation history at z&amp;gt;3 is primarily based on UV-selected galaxies (i.e., LBGs). Recent studies of H-dropouts revealed that we may be missing a large amount of star formation taking place in massive galaxies at z&amp;gt;3. In this work, we extend the H-dropout criterion to lower masses to select optically-dark/faint galaxies (OFGs), in order to complete the census between LBGs and H-dropouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nearest Neutron Star Candidate in a Binary Revealed by Optical Time-domain Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_nearest_neutron_star_candidate_in_a_binary_revealed_by_optical_time-domain_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_nearest_neutron_star_candidate_in_a_binary_revealed_by_optical_time-domain_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ling-Lin Zheng
Recent studies have revealed the global deposition on Earth of radioactive elements (e.g., $^{60}$Fe) resulting from the metal-enriched ejecta of nearby (within $\sim 100$ pc) supernova explosions. The majority of neutron stars in our Solar neighborhood remain to be discovered. Here we report the discovery of the nearest ($127.7 \pm 0.3$ pc) neutron star candidate in the single-lined spectroscopic binary LAMOST J235456.76+335625.7 (hereafter J2354). Utilizing the multi-epoch spectra and high-cadence periodic light curves, we measure the mass of the visible star ($M_{\rm vis}=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pattern speeds of vertical breathing waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pattern_speeds_of_vertical_breathing_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pattern_speeds_of_vertical_breathing_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tigran Khachaturyants
We measure and compare the pattern speeds of vertical breathing, vertical bending, and spiral density waves in two isolated N-body+SPH simulations, using windowed Fourier transforms over 1 Gyr time intervals. We show that the pattern speeds of the breathing waves match those of the spirals but are different from those of the bending waves. We also observe matching pattern speeds between the bar and breathing waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Solar Neighborhood L: Spectroscopic Discovery of K Dwarfs Younger Than 1 Gyr and New Binaries within 30 pc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_solar_neighborhood_l_spectroscopic_discovery_of_k_dwarfs_younger_than_1_gyr_and_new_binaries_within_30_pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_solar_neighborhood_l_spectroscopic_discovery_of_k_dwarfs_younger_than_1_gyr_and_new_binaries_within_30_pc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hodari-Sadiki Hubbard-James
As part of a comprehensive effort to characterize the nearest stars, the CHIRON echelle spectrograph on the CTIO/SMARTS 1.5m telescope is being used to acquire high resolution (R = 80000) spectra of K dwarfs within 50 parsecs. This paper provides spectral details about 35 K dwarfs from five benchmark sets with estimated ages spanning 20 Myr &amp;ndash; 5.7 Gyr. Four spectral age and activity indicators are tested, three of which aligned with the estimated ages of the benchmark groups &amp;ndash; the Na I doublet (5889.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To See or Not to See a $z\sim13$ Galaxy? That is the Question</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/to_see_or_not_to_see_a__z_sim13__galaxy_that_is_the_question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/to_see_or_not_to_see_a__z_sim13__galaxy_that_is_the_question/</guid>
      <description>First author: Melanie Kaasinen
When did the first galaxies form?&#39;&#39; is still one of the greatest unanswered questions in astronomy. Theory and current stellar population models imply that the first galaxies formed at least at z=14-15. Yet, the highest redshift galaxy to have been securely confirmed remains GN-z11, at z$\sim$11. The galaxy HD1&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; was recently proposed to be a z=13.27 galaxy based on its potential Lyman break and tentative [O III] 88 {\mu}m detection with ALMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Twisty Linear Polarization Morphologies in Black Hole Images</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unraveling_twisty_linear_polarization_morphologies_in_black_hole_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unraveling_twisty_linear_polarization_morphologies_in_black_hole_images/</guid>
      <description>First author: Razieh Emami
We investigate general relativistic magnetohydrodynamic simulations (GRMHD) to determine the physical origin of the twisty patterns of linear polarization seen in spatially resolved black hole images and explain their morphological dependence on black hole spin. By characterising the observed emission with a simple analytic ring model, we find that the twisty morphology is determined by the magnetic field structure in the emitting region. Moreover, the dependence of this twisty pattern on spin can be attributed to changes in the magnetic field geometry that occur due to the frame dragging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untangling the Sources of Abundance Dispersion in Low-Metallicity Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untangling_the_sources_of_abundance_dispersion_in_low-metallicity_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untangling_the_sources_of_abundance_dispersion_in_low-metallicity_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emily J. Griffith
We measure abundances of 12 elements (Na, Mg, Si, Ca, Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni) in a sample of 86 metal-poor ($-2 \lesssim \text{[Fe/H]} \lesssim -1$) subgiant stars in the solar neighborhood. Abundances are derived from high-resolution spectra taken with the Potsdam Echelle Polarimetric and Spectroscopic Instrument on the Large Binocular Telescope, modeled using iSpec and MOOG. By carefully quantifying the impact of photon-noise ($&amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variability of eclipse timing:the case of V471 Tauri</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/variability_of_eclipse_timingthe_case_of_v471_tauri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/variability_of_eclipse_timingthe_case_of_v471_tauri/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emil Kundra
The post-common envelope binary V471 Tauri has been an object of interest for decades. V471 Tau shows various phenomena due to its evolutionary state and unique properties, e.g. its magnetic accretion and eclipse timing variation (ETV). Previous authors explained the ETVs by different, sometimes contradictory theories. In this paper, we present and analyse the variability of the eclipse timing of this star. We observed V471 Tauri over the last ten years and covered the second cycle of its period variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray Reverberation Mapping of Ark 564 using Gaussian Process Regression</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_reverberation_mapping_of_ark_564_using_gaussian_process_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_reverberation_mapping_of_ark_564_using_gaussian_process_regression/</guid>
      <description>First author: Collin D. Lewin
Ark 564 is an extreme high-Eddington Narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy, known for being one of the brightest, most rapidly variable soft X-ray AGN, and for having one of the lowest temperature coronae. Here we present a 410-ks NuSTAR observation and two 115-ks XMM-Newton observations of this unique source, which reveal a very strong, relativistically broadened iron line. We compute the Fourier-resolved time lags by first using Gaussian processes to interpolate the NuSTAR gaps, implementing the first employment of multi-task learning for application in AGN timing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
