<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The R-Process Alliance: Abundance Universality among Some Elements at and between the First and Second R-Process Peaks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_r-process_alliance_abundance_universality_among_some_elements_at_and_between_the_first_and_second_r-process_peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_r-process_alliance_abundance_universality_among_some_elements_at_and_between_the_first_and_second_r-process_peaks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ian U. Roederer
We present new observational benchmarks of rapid neutron-capture process (r-process) nucleosynthesis for elements at and between the first (A ~ 80) and second (A ~ 130) peaks. Our analysis is based on archival ultraviolet and optical spectroscopy of eight metal-poor stars with Se (Z = 34) or Te (Z = 52) detections, whose r-process enhancement varies by more than a factor of 30 (-0.22 &amp;lt;= [Eu/Fe] &amp;lt;= +1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for planetary transits on a set of 1.4 million multi-sector DIAmante lightcurves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_search_for_planetary_transits_on_a_set_of_1.4_million_multi-sector_diamante_lightcurves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_search_for_planetary_transits_on_a_set_of_1.4_million_multi-sector_diamante_lightcurves/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Montalto
I report the results of a new search for transiting planets on a set of 1.4 million lightcurves extracted from TESS Full Frame Images (FFIs) using the DIAmante pipeline. The data come from the first two years of observations of TESS (Sectors 1-26) and the study is focused on a sample of FGKM dwarf and subgiant stars optimized for the search of transiting planets. The search was performed on the detrended and stitched multi-sector lightcurves applying the Box-fitting Least Squares algorithm and a Random Forest classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbital parallax of binary systems compared to GAIA DR3 and the parallax zero-point offset at bright magnitudes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orbital_parallax_of_binary_systems_compared_to_gaia_dr3_and_the_parallax_zero-point_offset_at_bright_magnitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/orbital_parallax_of_binary_systems_compared_to_gaia_dr3_and_the_parallax_zero-point_offset_at_bright_magnitudes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martin Groenewegen
(abridged)Multiple systems for which the astrometric and spectroscopic orbit are known offer the unique possibility of determining the distance to these systems directly without any assumptions. They are therefore ideal objects for a comparison of Gaia data release 3 (GDR3) parallax data, especially since GDR3 presents the results of the non-single star (NSS) analysis that potentially results in improved parallaxes. An sample of 192 orbital parallax determinations for 186 systems is compiled from the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relation of Observable Stellar Parameters to Mass-Loss Rate of AGB Stars in the LMC</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/relation_of_observable_stellar_parameters_to_mass-loss_rate_of_agb_stars_in_the_lmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/relation_of_observable_stellar_parameters_to_mass-loss_rate_of_agb_stars_in_the_lmc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Henry A. Prager
Using the Riebel et al. (2012) data set for 6,889 pulsating AGB stars in the LMC, we have derived formulae for mass-loss rate as a function of luminosity and pulsation period or luminosity and mass in three ways, for each of five subsets of data: fundamental mode oxygen rich stars, first overtone mode oxygen rich stars stars, fundamental mode carbon stars, first overtone mode carbon stars, and extreme carbon stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct Determination of the Activation Energy for Diffusion of OH Radicals on Water Ice</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/direct_determination_of_the_activation_energy_for_diffusion_of_oh_radicals_on_water_ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/direct_determination_of_the_activation_energy_for_diffusion_of_oh_radicals_on_water_ice/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Miyazaki
Using a combination of photostimulated desorption and resonance-enhanced multiphoton ionization methods, the behaviors of OH radicals on the surface of interstellar ice analog was monitored at temperatures between 54 and 80 K. The OH number density on the surface of ultraviolet (UV)-irradiated compact amorphous solid water gradually decreased at temperatures above 60 K. Analyzing the temperature dependence of OH intensities with the Arrhenius equation, the decrease can be explained by recombination of two OH radicals, which is rate-limited by thermal diffusion of OH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELVES III: Environmental Quenching by Milky Way-Mass Hosts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iii_environmental_quenching_by_milky_way-mass_hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/elves_iii_environmental_quenching_by_milky_way-mass_hosts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jenny E. Greene
Isolated dwarf galaxies nearly always exhibit robust star formation but satellite dwarf galaxies are often devoid of young stars, even in Milky Way-mass groups. Dwarf galaxies thus offer an important laboratory into the environmental processes that cease star formation. We explore the balance of quiescent and star-forming galaxies (quenched fractions) for a sample of ~400 satellite galaxies around 30 Local Volume hosts from the Exploration of Local VolumE Satellites (ELVES) Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three low-mass companions around aged stars discovered by TESS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/three_low-mass_companions_around_aged_stars_discovered_by_tess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/three_low-mass_companions_around_aged_stars_discovered_by_tess/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zitao Lin
We report the discovery of three transiting low-mass companions to aged stars: a brown dwarf (TOI-2336b) and two objects near the hydrogen burning mass limit (TOI-1608b and TOI-2521b). These three systems were first identified using data from the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS). TOI-2336b has a radius of $1.05\pm 0.04\ R_J$, a mass of $69.9\pm 2.3\ M_J$ and an orbital period of 7.71 days. TOI-1608b has a radius of $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virial theorem in clusters of galaxies with MOND</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/virial_theorem_in_clusters_of_galaxies_with_mond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/virial_theorem_in_clusters_of_galaxies_with_mond/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Lopez-Corredoira
A specific modification of Newtonian dynamics known as MOND has been shown to reproduce the dynamics of most astrophysical systems at different scales without invoking non-baryonic dark matter (DM). There is, however, a long-standing unsolved problem when MOND is applied to rich clusters of galaxies in the form of a deficit (by a factor around two) of predicted dynamical mass derived from the virial theorem with respect to observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A large (~1 pc) contracting envelope around the prestellar core L1544</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_large_~1_pc_contracting_envelope_around_the_prestellar_core_l1544/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_large_~1_pc_contracting_envelope_around_the_prestellar_core_l1544/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Redaelli
Prestellar cores, the birthplace of Sun-like stars, form from the fragmentation of the filamentary structure that composes molecular clouds, from which they must inherit at least partially the kinematics. Furthermore, when they are on the verge of gravitational collapse, they show signs of subsonic infall motions. How extended these motions are, which depends on how the collapse occurs, remains largely unknown. We want to investigate the kinematics of the envelope that surrounds the prototypical prestellar core L1544, studying the cloud-core connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Molecular Gas Ring Hidden in the Sombrero Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_molecular_gas_ring_hidden_in_the_sombrero_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_molecular_gas_ring_hidden_in_the_sombrero_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica Sutter
We present Herschel, ALMA, and MUSE observations of the molecular ring of Messier 104, also known as the Sombrero galaxy. These previously unpublished archival data shed new light on the content of the interstellar medium of M104. In particular, molecular hydrogen measured by CO emission and dust measured by far-infrared light are uniformly distributed along the ring. The ionized gas revealed by H$\alpha$ and [CII] emission is distributed in knots along the ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almanac: Weak Lensing power spectra and map inference on the masked sphere</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/almanac_weak_lensing_power_spectra_and_map_inference_on_the_masked_sphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/almanac_weak_lensing_power_spectra_and_map_inference_on_the_masked_sphere/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Loureiro
We present a field-based signal extraction of weak lensing from noisy observations on the curved and masked sky. We test the analysis on a simulated Euclid-like survey, using a Euclid-like mask and noise level. To make optimal use of the information available in such a galaxy survey, we present a Bayesian method for inferring the angular power spectra of the weak lensing fields, together with an inference of the noise-cleaned tomographic weak lensing shear and convergence (projected mass) maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetrical tidal tails of open star clusters: stars crossing their cluster&#39;s prah challenge Newtonian gravitation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/asymmetrical_tidal_tails_of_open_star_clusters_stars_crossing_their_clusters_prah_challenge_newtonian_gravitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/asymmetrical_tidal_tails_of_open_star_clusters_stars_crossing_their_clusters_prah_challenge_newtonian_gravitation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pavel Kroupa
After their birth a significant fraction of all stars pass through the tidal threshold (prah) of their cluster of origin into the classical tidal tails. The asymmetry between the number of stars in the leading and trailing tails tests gravitational theory. All five open clusters with tail data (Hyades, Praesepe, Coma Berenices, COIN-Gaia 13, NGC 752) have visibly more stars within dcl = 50 pc of their centre in their leading than their trailing tail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Type Ia supernovae through their heights in edge-on galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_type_ia_supernovae_through_their_heights_in_edge-on_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/constraining_type_ia_supernovae_through_their_heights_in_edge-on_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lilit V. Barkhudaryan
In this Letter, using classified 197 supernovae (SNe) Ia, we perform an analyses of their height distributions from the disc in edge-on spirals and investigate their light-curve (LC) decline rates $(\Delta m_{15})$. We demonstrate, for the first time, that 91T-, 91bg-like, and normal SNe Ia subclasses are distributed differently toward the plane of their host disc. The average height from the disc and its comparison with scales of thin/thick disc components gives a possibility to roughly estimate the SNe Ia progenitor ages: 91T-like events, being at the smallest heights, originate from relatively younger progenitors with ages of about several 100 Myr, 91bg-like SNe, having the highest distribution, arise from progenitors with significantly older ages $\sim 10$ Gyr, and normal SNe Ia, which distributed between those of the two others, are from progenitors of about one up to $\sim 10$ Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDSS-IV MaStar: Stellar Parameter Determination with Continuum-Supplemented Full-Spectrum Fitting</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/sdss-iv_mastar_stellar_parameter_determination_with_continuum-supplemented_full-spectrum_fitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/sdss-iv_mastar_stellar_parameter_determination_with_continuum-supplemented_full-spectrum_fitting/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Lazarz
We present a stellar parameter catalog built to accompany the MaStar Stellar Library, which is a comprehensive collection of empirical, medium-resolution stellar spectra. We constructed this parameter catalog by using a multicomponent $\chi^{2}$ fitting approach to match MaStar spectra to models generated by interpolating the ATLAS9-based BOSZ model spectra. The total $\chi^{2}$ for a given model is defined as the sum of components constructed to characterize narrow-band features of observed spectra (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spiral arms of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_spiral_arms_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_spiral_arms_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: George Contopoulos
The most important theory of the spiral arms of galaxies is the density wave theory based on the Lin-Shu dispersion relation. However, the density waves move with the group velocity towards the inner Lindblad resonance and tend to disappear. Various mechanisms to replenish the spiral waves have been proposed. Nonlinear effects play an important role near the inner and outer Lindblad resonances and corotation. The orbits supporting the spiral arms are precessing ellipses in normal galaxies that extend up to the 4/1 resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why weak lensing cluster shapes are insensitive to self-interacting dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/why_weak_lensing_cluster_shapes_are_insensitive_to_self-interacting_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/why_weak_lensing_cluster_shapes_are_insensitive_to_self-interacting_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew Robertson
We investigate whether the shapes of galaxy clusters inferred from weak gravitational lensing can be used as a test of the nature of dark matter. We analyse mock weak lensing data, with gravitational lenses extracted from cosmological simulations run with two different dark matter models (CDM and SIDM). We fit elliptical NFW profiles to the shear fields of the simulated clusters. Despite large differences in the distribution of 3D shapes between CDM and SIDM, we find that the distributions of weak-lensing-inferred cluster shapes are almost indistinguishable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Spectroscopic Survey of the Quiescent Medium of Nearby Clouds: II. Ice Formation and Grain Growth in Perseus and Serpens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/infrared_spectroscopic_survey_of_the_quiescent_medium_of_nearby_clouds_ii._ice_formation_and_grain_growth_in_perseus_and_serpens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/infrared_spectroscopic_survey_of_the_quiescent_medium_of_nearby_clouds_ii._ice_formation_and_grain_growth_in_perseus_and_serpens/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. C. L. Madden
The properties of dust change during the transition from diffuse to dense clouds as a result of ice formation and dust coagulation, but much is still unclear about this transformation. We present 2-20 micron spectra of 49 field stars behind the Perseus and Serpens Molecular Clouds and establish relationships between the near-infrared continuum extinction (AK) and the depths of the 9.7 micron silicate (tau97) and 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Infrared Polarization of the Diffuse Interstellar Medium toward CygOB2-12</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mid-infrared_polarization_of_the_diffuse_interstellar_medium_toward_cygob2-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/mid-infrared_polarization_of_the_diffuse_interstellar_medium_toward_cygob2-12/</guid>
      <description>First author: Charles M. Telesco
We present the first mid-IR detection of the linear polarization toward the star CygOB2-12, a luminous blue hypergiant that, with Av of ~10 mag of foreground extinction, is a benchmark in the study of the properties of dust in the diffuse interstellar medium. The 8-13 micrometer spectropolarimetry, obtained with the CanariCam multi-mode camera at the Gran Telescopio Canarias (GTC), shows clear trends with wavelength characteristic of silicate grains aligned in the interstellar magnetic field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Stellar Populations of Globular Clusters From Homogeneous Ca-CN-CH-NH Photometry. VII. Metal-Poor Populations in 47 Tucanae (NGC 104)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/multiple_stellar_populations_of_globular_clusters_from_homogeneous_ca-cn-ch-nh_photometry._vii._metal-poor_populations_in_47_tucanae_ngc_104/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/multiple_stellar_populations_of_globular_clusters_from_homogeneous_ca-cn-ch-nh_photometry._vii._metal-poor_populations_in_47_tucanae_ngc_104/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jae-Woo Lee
We present new large field-of-view ($\sim$1\deg$\times$1\deg) Ca-CN photometry of the prototypical metal-rich globular cluster 47 Tucanae (NGC 104). Our results are the following. (1) The populational number ratios of the red giant branch (RGB) and red horizontal branch (RHB) are in excellent agreement: n(CN-w):n(CN-s) = 30:70 ($\pm$1&amp;ndash;2), where the CN-w and CN-s stand for the CN-weak and CN-strong populations, respectively. Both the CN-s RGB and RHB populations are more centrally concentrated than those of CN-w populations are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
