<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accretion from Winds of Red Giant Branch Stars May Reveal the Supermassive Black Hole in Leo I</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article2/dwarf-galaxy/accretion_from_winds_of_red_giant_branch_stars_may_reveal_the_supermassive_black_hole_in_leo_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article2/dwarf-galaxy/accretion_from_winds_of_red_giant_branch_stars_may_reveal_the_supermassive_black_hole_in_leo_i/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabio Pacucci
A supermassive black hole (SMBH) of $\sim 3\times 10^6 , \rm M_\odot$ was recently detected via dynamical measurements at the center of the dwarf galaxy Leo I. Standing $\sim 2$ orders of magnitude above standard scaling relations, this SMBH is hosted by a galaxy devoid of gas and with no significant star formation in the last $\sim 1$ Gyr. This detection can profoundly impact the formation models for black holes and their hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio observations of four active galactic nuclei hosting intermediate-mass black hole candidates: studying the outflow activity and evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article2/dwarf-galaxy/radio_observations_of_four_active_galactic_nuclei_hosting_intermediate-mass_black_hole_candidates_studying_the_outflow_activity_and_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article2/dwarf-galaxy/radio_observations_of_four_active_galactic_nuclei_hosting_intermediate-mass_black_hole_candidates_studying_the_outflow_activity_and_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaolong Yang
Observational searches for intermediate-mass black holes (IMBHs; $10^2 - 10^6$ $M_\odot$) include relatively isolated dwarf galaxies. For those that host active galactic nuclei (AGNs), the IMBH nature may be discerned through the accretion - jet activity. We present radio observations of four AGN-hosting dwarf galaxies (which potentially harbor IMBHs). Very large array (VLA) observations indicate steep spectra (indices of $-$0.63 to $-$1.05) between 1.4 and 9 GHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Outflows and Inefficient Star Formation in the Reionization-era Ultra-faint Dwarf Galaxy Eridanus II</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article2/dwarf-galaxy/strong_outflows_and_inefficient_star_formation_in_the_reionization-era_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxy_eridanus_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article2/dwarf-galaxy/strong_outflows_and_inefficient_star_formation_in_the_reionization-era_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxy_eridanus_ii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nathan R. Sandford
We present novel constraints on the underlying galaxy formation physics (e.g., mass loading factor, star formation history, metal retention) at $z \gtrsim 7$ for the low-mass ($M_*\sim10^5$ M$\odot$) Local Group ultra-faint dwarf galaxy (UFD) Eridanus II (Eri II) Using a hierarchical Bayesian framework, we apply a one-zone chemical evolution model to Eri II&amp;rsquo;s CaHK-based photometric metallicity distribution function (MDF; [Fe/H]) and find that the evolution of Eri II is well-characterized by a short, exponentially declining star-formation history ($\tau\text{SFH} = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endothermic self-interacting dark matter in Milky Way-like dark matter haloes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/endothermic_self-interacting_dark_matter_in_milky_way-like_dark_matter_haloes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/endothermic_self-interacting_dark_matter_in_milky_way-like_dark_matter_haloes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stephanie O&amp;rsquo;Neil
Self-interacting dark matter (SIDM) offers the potential to mitigate some of the discrepancies between simulated cold dark matter (CDM) and observed galactic properties. We introduce a physically motivated SIDM model to understand the effects of self interactions on the properties of Milky Way and dwarf galaxy sized haloes. This model consists of dark matter with a nearly degenerate excited state, which allows for both elastic and inelastic scattering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the Tilt of the Milky Way&#39;s Dark Matter Halo with the Sagittarius Stream</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/constraining_the_tilt_of_the_milky_ways_dark_matter_halo_with_the_sagittarius_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/constraining_the_tilt_of_the_milky_ways_dark_matter_halo_with_the_sagittarius_stream/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nondh Panithanpaisal
Recent studies have suggested that the Milky Way (MW)&amp;rsquo;s Dark Matter (DM) halo may be significantly tilted with respect to its central stellar disk, a feature that might be linked to its formation history. In this work, we demonstrate a method of constraining the orientation of the minor axis of the DM halo using the angle and frequency variables. This method is complementary to other traditional techniques, such as orbit fitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf galaxy formation with and without dark matter-baryon streaming velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/dwarf_galaxy_formation_with_and_without_dark_matter-baryon_streaming_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/dwarf_galaxy_formation_with_and_without_dark_matter-baryon_streaming_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna T. P. Schauer
We study how supersonic streaming velocities of baryons relative to dark matter &amp;ndash; a large-scale effect imprinted at recombination and coherent over $\sim 3$ Mpc scales &amp;ndash; affects the formation of dwarf galaxies at $z \gtrsim 5$. We perform cosmological hydrodynamic simulations, including and excluding streaming velocities, in regions centered on halos with $M_{\rm vir}(z=0) \approx 10^{10}$ M${\odot}$; the simulations are part of the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project and run with FIRE-3 physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying globular clusters and applying them to estimate the mass of the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/dwarf-galaxy/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: GuangChen Sun
We combine the kinematics of 159 globular clusters (GCs) provided by the Gaia Early Data Release 3 (EDR 3) with other observational data to classify the GCs, and to estimate the mass of Milky Way (MW). We use the age-metallicity relation, integrals of motion, action space and the GC orbits to identify the GCs as either formed in-situ (Bulge and Disk) or ex-situ (via accretion). We find that $45.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
