<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dwarf galaxy on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/dwarf-galaxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A LOFAR sample of luminous compact sources coincident with nearby dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lofar_sample_of_luminous_compact_sources_coincident_with_nearby_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_lofar_sample_of_luminous_compact_sources_coincident_with_nearby_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Vohl
The vast majority of extragalactic, compact continuum radio sources are associated with star formation or jets from (super)massive black holes and, as such, are more likely to be found in association with starburst galaxies or early type galaxies. Recently, two new populations of radio sources have been identified: (a) compact and persistent sources (PRS) associated with fast radio bursts (FRB) in dwarf galaxies and (b) compact sources in dwarf galaxies that could belong to the long-sought population of intermediate-mass black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of binary stars in the early evolutionary phases of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_binary_stars_in_the_early_evolutionary_phases_of_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_binary_stars_in_the_early_evolutionary_phases_of_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexander R. Livernois
The dynamics of binary stars provides a unique avenue to gather insight into the study of the structure and dynamics of star clusters and galaxies. In this paper, we present the results of a set of $N$-body simulations aimed at exploring the evolution of binary stars during the early evolutionary phases of ultra-faint dwarf galaxies (UFD). In our simulations, we assume that the stellar component of the UFD is initially dynamically cold and evolves towards its final equilibrium after undergoing the violent relaxation phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhomogeneous Galactic Chemical Evolution: Modelling Ultra-Faint Dwarf Galaxies of the Large Magellanic Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_galactic_chemical_evolution_modelling_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inhomogeneous_galactic_chemical_evolution_modelling_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxies_of_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryan K. Alexander
Ultra-faint dwarf galaxies are among the oldest and most metal-poor galaxies in the cosmos, observed to contain no traces of gas at the present time and a high dark matter mass fraction. Understanding the chemical abundance dispersion in such extreme environments could shed light on the properties of the first generations of stars in the cosmos. We present a novel inhomogeneous chemical evolution model, i-GEtool, that we apply to two ultra-faint dwarf galaxies, Carina II (Car II) and Reticulum II (Ret II), which are satellites of the Large Magellanic Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for FRB persistent radio source counterparts in dwarf galaxies using LOFAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_frb_persistent_radio_source_counterparts_in_dwarf_galaxies_using_lofar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_frb_persistent_radio_source_counterparts_in_dwarf_galaxies_using_lofar/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Vohl
The repeating FRB 20121102A was localized to a star-forming region in a dwarf galaxy and found to be co-located with a persistent radio source (PRS). FRB 20190520B is only the second known source sharing phenomenology akin to FRB 20121102A&amp;rsquo;s, with similar burst activity, host galaxy properties, as well as being associated with a PRS. PRS emission is potentially a calorimeter, allowing us to estimate the energy output of the central FRB engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIMP cross-section limits from LOFAR observations of dwarf spheroidal galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wimp_cross-section_limits_from_lofar_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wimp_cross-section_limits_from_lofar_observations_of_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Gajović
Weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs) can self-annihilate and thus provide us with the possibility for an indirect detection of Dark Matter (DM). Dwarf spheroidal (dSph) galaxies are excellent places to search for annihilation signals because they are rich in DM and background emission is low. If magnetic fields in dSph exist, the particles produced in DM annihilation emit synchrotron radiation. We use the non-detection of 150 MHz radio continuum emission from dSph galaxies with the LOw Frequency ARray (LOFAR) to derive constraints on the annihilation cross-section of WIMPs into electron-positron pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Dynamical Heating of Dwarf Galaxies in a Fuzzy Dark Matter Halo</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_dynamical_heating_of_dwarf_galaxies_in_a_fuzzy_dark_matter_halo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_dynamical_heating_of_dwarf_galaxies_in_a_fuzzy_dark_matter_halo/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dhruba Dutta Chowdhury
Fuzzy Dark Matter (FDM), consisting of ultralight bosons, is an intriguing alternative to Cold Dark Matter. Numerical simulations solving the Schr&amp;quot;odinger-Poisson (SP) equation, which governs FDM dynamics, show that FDM halos consist of a central solitonic core (representing the ground state of the SP equation), surrounded by a large envelope of excited states. Wave interference gives rise to order unity density fluctuations throughout the envelope and causes the soliton to undergo density oscillations and execute a confined random walk in the central region of the halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New dwarf galaxy candidates in the sphere of influence of the Local Volume spiral galaxy NGC2683</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_in_the_sphere_of_influence_of_the_local_volume_spiral_galaxy_ngc2683/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_dwarf_galaxy_candidates_in_the_sphere_of_influence_of_the_local_volume_spiral_galaxy_ngc2683/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Crosby
We present initial results of a survey of host $L_{*}$ galaxies environments in the Local Volume ($D&amp;lt;10,$Mpc) searching for satellite dwarf galaxy candidates using the wide-field Hyper Suprime-Cam imager on the 8m Subaru Telescope. The current paper presents complete results on NGC2683 ($M_{B_T,0}=-19.62$, $D=9.36,Mpc$, $v_{\odot}=411,km,s^{-1}$), an isolated Sc spiral galaxy in the Leo Spur. At the distance of NGC2683, we image the complete volume out to projected radii of $380,kpc$ using a hexagonal arrangement of 7 pointings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a dwarf galaxy satellite-of-satellite problem in $Λ$CDM?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_there_a_dwarf_galaxy_satellite-of-satellite_problem_in__%CE%BB_cdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_there_a_dwarf_galaxy_satellite-of-satellite_problem_in__%CE%BB_cdm/</guid>
      <description>First author: Oliver Müller
Dark matter clusters on all scales, therefore it is expected that even substructure should host its own substructure. Using the Extragalactic Distance Database, we searched for dwarf galaxy satellites of dwarf galaxies, i.e. satellite-of-satellite galaxies, corresponding to these substructures-of-substructure. Going through HST data of 117 dwarf galaxies, we report the discovery of a dwarf galaxy around the ultra-diffuse M96 companion M96-DF6 at 10 Mpc. Modelling its structural parameters, we find that it is an ultra-faint dwarf galaxy which is 135 times fainter than its host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the diversity and similarity of radially anisotropic Milky Way-like stellar haloes: implications for dwarf galaxy searches</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_diversity_and_similarity_of_radially_anisotropic_milky_way-like_stellar_haloes_implications_for_dwarf_galaxy_searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/exploring_the_diversity_and_similarity_of_radially_anisotropic_milky_way-like_stellar_haloes_implications_for_dwarf_galaxy_searches/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matthew D. A. Orkney
We investigate the properties of mergers that are comparable to the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) using cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of Milky Way-like galaxies. It was previously shown that these mergers occur over a wide range of times ($6-10,$Gyr ago). We find that the merger progenitors span an order of magnitude in their peak stellar mass ($3\times10^8&amp;lt;M_{\star}/\rm{M}{\odot}&amp;lt;4\times10^9$) and include both rotation and pressure-supported galaxies ($0.10&amp;lt;D/T&amp;lt;0.77$). In a minority of cases, the GSE-like debris is comprised of stars from more than one merger progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observations of R-Process Stars in the Milky Way and Dwarf Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.09188/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.09188/</guid>
      <description>Anna Frebel
This chapter presents an overview of the recent progress on spectroscopic observations of metal-poor stars with r-process element signatures found in the Milky Way&amp;amp;#39;s stellar halo and satellite dwarf galaxies. Major empirical lessons related to the origins of the r-process are discussed, including the universality of the observed r-process pattern and deviations from universality among the light r-process elements and actinides. Different astrophysical sites of the r-process based on theoretical expectations are presented, including common and rare supernovae and neutron star mergers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Ultraheavy Dark Matter from Observations of Dwarf Spheroidal Galaxies with VERITAS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08784/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.08784/</guid>
      <description>VERITAS collaboration
Dark matter is a key piece of the current cosmological scenario, with weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs) a leading dark matter candidate. WIMPs have not been detected in their conventional parameter space (100 GeV $\lesssim M_χ \lesssim$ 100 TeV), a mass range accessible with current Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes. As ultraheavy dark matter (UHDM; $M_χ \gtrsim$ 100 TeV) has been suggested as an under-explored alternative to the WIMP paradigm, we search for an indirect dark matter annihilation signal in a higher mass range (up to 30 PeV) with the VERITAS gamma-ray observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Isaac Newton Telescope Monitoring Survey of Local Group Dwarf Galaxies. VI. The Star Formation History and Dust Production in Andromeda IX</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07674/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07674/</guid>
      <description>Hedieh Abdollahi
We present a photometric study of the resolved stellar populations in And IX, the closest satellite to the M31, a metal-poor and low-mass dwarf spheroidal galaxy. We estimate a distance modulus of $24.56_{-0.15}^{+0.05}$ mag based on the tip of the red giant branch (TRGB). By probing the variability of asymptotic giant branch stars (AGB), we study the star formation history of And IX. We identified 50 long period variables (LPVs) in And IX using the Isaac Newton Telescope (INT) in two filters, Sloan $i&amp;amp;#39;$ and Harris $V$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging Black Holes in Dwarf Galaxies: Calculating Binary Black Hole Coalescence Timescales from Simulations for LISA Detection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.15035/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2111.15035/</guid>
      <description>Victoria I. De Cun
Supermassive black holes (SMBHs) merging in dwarf galaxies will be detectable by the Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA) in the mid-2030s. Previous cosmological hydrodynamic simulations have shown the prediction of massive black holes merging in dwarf galaxies, but these simulations are limited by their resolution and cannot follow black hole pairs all the way to coalescence. We calculate the delay time between black hole pairing and merger based on the properties of the black holes and their host galaxies, and use these properties to calculate gravitational wave strains for eleven different binary black holes that merge inside dwarf galaxies from eight cosmological simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate-mass black holes: finding of episodic, large-scale and powerful jet activity in a dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06214/</guid>
      <description>Jun Yang
Dwarf galaxies are characterised by a very low luminosity and low mass. Because of significant accretion and ejection activity of massive black holes, some dwarf galaxies also host low-luminosity active galactic nuclei (AGNs). In a few dwarf AGNs, very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) observations have found faint non-thermal radio emission. SDSS J090613.77+561015.2 is a dwarf AGN owning an intermediate-mass black hole (IMBH) with a mass of $M_{BH} = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of structural parameters and systemic proper motion of Sextans dwarf spheroidal galaxy with Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06071/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.06071/</guid>
      <description>Akira Tokiwa
We use the Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) data to study structural parameters and systemic proper motion of the Sextans dwarf spheroidal galaxy at the heliocentric distance of 86 kpc, which is one of the most important targets for studies of dark matter nature and galaxy formation physics. Thanks to the superb image quality and wide area coverage of the Sextans field, the HSC data enables a secure selection of member star candidates based on the colour-magnitude cut, yielding about 10,000 member candidates at magnitudes down to $i\sim 24$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dwarf Galaxy Debris Stream Associated with Palomar 1 and the Anticenter Stream</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05232/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.05232/</guid>
      <description>Yong Yang
We report the discovery of a new stream (dubbed as Yangtze) detected in $Gaia$ Data Release 3. The stream is at a heliocentric distance of $\sim$ 9.12 kpc and spans nearly 27$°$ by 1.9$°$ on sky. The colour-magnitude diagram of Yangtze indicates a stellar population of Age $\sim$ 11 Gyr and $[M/H]$ $\sim$ -0.7 dex. It has a number density of about 5.5 stars degree$^{-2}$ along with a surface brightness of $Σ_G \simeq$ 34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf Galaxies United by Dark Bosons</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.00181/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.00181/</guid>
      <description>Alvaro Pozo,
Low mass galaxies in the Local Group are dominated by dark matter and comprise the well studied ``dwarf Spheroidal&amp;amp;#34; (dSph) class, with typical masses of $10^{9-10}M_\odot$ and also the equally numerous ``ultra faint dwarfs&amp;amp;#34; (UFD), discovered recently, that are distinctly smaller and denser with masses of only $10^{7-8}M_\odot$. This bimodality amongst low mass galaxies contrasts with the scale free continuity expected for galaxies formed under gravity, as in the standard Cold Dark Matter (CDM) model for heavy particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The extended &#34;stellar halo&#34; of the Ursa Minor dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.13214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.13214/</guid>
      <description>Federico Sestito
Five stars in the extreme outskirts (from $\sim5$ to $\sim12$ elliptical half-light radii, r$_h$) of the Ursa Minor (UMi) dwarf galaxy have been identified as potential new members using a Bayesian algorithm applied to \textit{Gaia} EDR3 data. These targets were observed with the GRACES spectrograph, resulting in precise radial velocities and metallicities that confirm their association with UMi. For the brightest and outermost star (Target~1, at $\sim12$ r$_h$), the chemical abundances of $α$- (Mg, Ca, Ti), odd-Z (Na, K, Sc), Fe-peak (Fe, Ni, Cr), and neutron-capture process (Ba) elements have also been determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The viability of ultralight bosonic dark matter in dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2206.05244/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2206.05244/</guid>
      <description>Isabelle S. Goldstein
The dark matter distribution in dwarf galaxies holds a wealth of information on the fundamental properties and interactions of the dark matter particle. In this paper, we study whether ultralight bosonic dark matter is consistent with the gravitational potential extracted from stellar kinematics. We use velocity dispersion measurements to constrain models for halo mass and particle mass. The posterior likelihood is multimodal. Particle masses of order $m\sim 10^{-22} {\rm{eV}}$ require halos of mass in excess of $\sim 10^{10} M_\odot$, while particle mass of order $m \gtrsim 10^{-20}{\rm{eV}}$ are favored by halos of mass $\sim [10^{8} - 10^{9}] M_\odot$, with a similar behavior to cold dark matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular cluster metallicity distributions in the E-MOSAICS simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.00398/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.00398/</guid>
      <description>Joel Pfeffer
The metallicity distributions of globular cluster (GC) systems in galaxies are a critical test of any GC formation scenario. In this work, we investigate the predicted GC metallicity distributions of galaxies in the MOdelling Star cluster population Assembly In Cosmological Simulations within EAGLE (E-MOSAICS) simulation of a representative cosmological volume ($L = 34.4$ comoving Mpc). We find that the predicted GC metallicity distributions and median metallicities from the fiducial E-MOSAICS GC formation model agree well the observed distributions, except for galaxies with masses $M_\ast \sim 2 \times 10^{10}$ M$_\odot$, which contain an overabundance of metal-rich GCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pegasus W: An Ultra-Faint Dwarf Galaxy Outside the Halo of M31 Not Quenched by Reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04157/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04157/</guid>
      <description>Kristen. B. W. McQuinn
We report the discovery of an ultrafaint dwarf (UFD) galaxy, Pegasus W, located on the far side of the Milky Way-M31 system and outside the virial radius of M31. The distance to the galaxy is 915 (+60/-91) kpc, measured using the luminosity of horizontal branch (HB) stars identified in Hubble Space Telescope optical imaging. The galaxy has a half-light radius (r_h) of 100 (+11/-13) pc, M_V = -7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Formation Histories of Dwarf Spheroidal and Dwarf Elliptical Galaxies in the Local Universe </title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.10386/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.10386/</guid>
      <description>Mira Seo
We present the star formation histories (SFHs) of early-type dwarf galaxies, dSphs and dEs, in the local universe within z=0.01. The SFHs of early-type dwarf galaxies are characterized by pre-enriched, metal-poor old stellar populations, absence of moderately old stars that have ages of a few Gyr. There are some differences in the SFHs of dSphs and dEs. In particular, dSphs formed old ($\gtrsim10$ Gyr old) metal-poor stars $\sim2$ times more than dEs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A burst storm from the repeating FRB 20200120E in an M81 globular cluster</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2206.03759/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2206.03759/</guid>
      <description>K. Nimmo
The repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20200120E is exceptional because of its proximity and association with a globular cluster. Here we report $60$ bursts detected with the Effelsberg telescope at 1.4 GHz. We observe large variations in the burst rate, and report the first FRB 20200120E `burst storm&amp;amp;#39;, where the source suddenly became active and 53 bursts (fluence $\geq 0.04$ Jy ms) occurred within only 40 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular clusters as indicators of Galactic evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.08535/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.08535/</guid>
      <description>N. R. Arakelyan
We have studied the system of globular clusters (GCs) that formed in other galaxies and eventually accreted onto the Milky Way. Thus, the samples of GCs belonging to different tidal streams, obtained on the basis of the latest data from the Gaia observatory, were taken from the literature. We measured the anisotropy of the distribution of these GCs using the gyration tensor and found that the distribution of GCs in the streams is isotropic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of globular clusters in dwarf galaxies of the Local Group</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.08218/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.08218/</guid>
      <description>Yingtian Chen
The existence of globular clusters (GCs) in a few satellite galaxies, and their absence in majority of dwarf galaxies, present a challenge for models attempting to understand the origins of GCs. In addition to GC presence appearing stochastic and difficult to describe with average trends, in the smallest satellite galaxies GCs contribute a substantial fraction of total stellar mass. We investigate the stochasticity and number of GCs in dwarf galaxies using an updated version of our model that links the formation of GCs to the growth of the host galaxy mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrono-chemodynamical analysis of the globular cluster NGC 6355: Looking for the fundamental bricks of the Bulge</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05227/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.05227/</guid>
      <description>Stefano O. Souza
The information on Galactic assembly time is imprinted on the chemodynamics of globular clusters. This makes them important probes that help us to understand the formation and evolution of the Milky Way. Discerning between in-situ and ex-situ origin of these objects is difficult when we study the Galactic bulge, which is the most complex and mixed component of the Milky Way. To investigate the early evolution of the Galactic bulge, we analysed the globular cluster NGC 6355.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Neon Gap: Probing Ionization with Dwarf Galaxies at z~1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07444/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07444/</guid>
      <description>John Pharo,
We present measurements of $[NeIII]$ λ3869 emission in z~1 low-mass galaxies taken from the Keck/DEIMOS spectroscopic surveys HALO7D and DEEPWinds. We identify 167 individual galaxies with significant $[NeIII]$ emission lines, including 112 &amp;amp;#34;dwarf&amp;amp;#34; galaxies with log(M_{\star}/M_{\odot}) &amp;amp;lt; 9.5, with 0.3 &amp;amp;lt; z &amp;amp;lt; 1.4. We also measure $[NeIII]$ emission from composite spectra derived from all $[OII]$λλ3727,3729 line emitters in this range. This provides a unique sample of $[NeIII]$-emitters in the gap between well-studied emitters at z = 0 and 2 &amp;amp;lt; z &amp;amp;lt; 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying the satellite plane membership of Centaurus A&#39;s dwarf galaxies using orbital alignment constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07113/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07113/</guid>
      <description>Kristen. B. W. McQuinn
The flattened, possibly co-rotating plane of satellite galaxies around Centaurus A, if more than a fortuitous alignment, adds to the pre-existing tension between the well-studied Milky Way and M31 planes and the $Λ$CDM model of structure formation. It was recently reported that the Centaurus A satellite plane (CASP) may be rotationally supported, but a further understanding of the system&amp;amp;#39;s kinematics is elusive in the absence of full three-dimensional velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detailed chemical abundances of stars in the outskirts of the Tucana II ultra-faint dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.01740/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.01740/</guid>
      <description>Anirudh Chiti
We present chemical abundances and velocities of five stars between 0.3 kpc to 1.1 kpc from the center of the Tucana II ultra-faint dwarf galaxy (UFD) from high-resolution Magellan/MIKE spectroscopy. We find that every star is deficient in metals (-3.6 &amp;amp;lt; $[Fe/H]$ &amp;amp;lt; -1.9) and in neutron-capture elements as is characteristic of UFD stars, unambiguously confirming their association with Tucana II. Other chemical abundances (e.g., C, iron-peak) largely follow UFD trends and suggest that faint core-collapse supernovae (SNe) dominated the early evolution of Tucana II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic characteristics of the Milky Way globular clusters based on Gaia DR2 data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2201.07221/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2201.07221/</guid>
      <description>I. V. Chemerynska
Using the data from Gaia (ESA) Data Release 2 we performed the orbital calculations of globular clusters (GCs) of the Milky Way. To explore possible close encounters (or collisions) between the GCs, using our own developed high-order phi-GRAPE code, we integrated backward and forward the orbits of 119 objects with reliable positions and proper motions. In calculations, we adopted a realistic axisymmetric Galactic potential (bulge + disk + halo).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tucana dwarf spheroidal: a distant backsplash galaxy of M31?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.02229/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.02229/</guid>
      <description>Isabel M. E. Santos-Santos,
We use the APOSTLE Local Group (LG) cosmological hydro-simulations to examine the properties of &amp;amp;#34;backsplash&amp;amp;#34; galaxies, i.e, dwarfs which were within the virial boundaries of the Milky Way (MW) or M31 in the past, but are today outside their virial radius ($r_{200}$). More than half of all dwarfs between $1-2\,r_{200}$ of each primary are backsplash. More distant backsplash systems, i.e., those reaching distances well beyond $2\,r_{200}$, are typically close to apocentre of nearly radial orbits, and, therefore, essentially at rest relative to their primary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic fields do not suppress global star formation in low metallicity dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.04922/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.04922/</guid>
      <description>David J. Whitworth
Many studies concluded that magnetic fields suppress star formation in molecular clouds and Milky Way like galaxies. However, most of these studies are based on fully developed fields that have reached the saturation level, with little work on investigating how an initial weak primordial field affects star formation in low metallicity environments. In this paper, we investigate the impact of a weak initial field on low metallicity dwarf galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Direct-Method Oxygen Abundance of Typical Dwarf Galaxies at Cosmic High-Noon</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.05976/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.05976/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Gburek,
We present a Keck/MOSFIRE, rest-optical, composite spectrum of 16 typical, gravitationally-lensed, star-forming, dwarf galaxies at $1.7 \lesssim z \lesssim 2.6$ ($z_{\rm{mean}}=2.30$), all chosen independent of emission-line strength. These galaxies have a median stellar mass of $\log(M_\ast/\rm{M_\odot})_{\rm{med}} = 8.29^{+0.51}_{-0.43}$ and a median star formation rate of $\rm{SFR_{Hα}^{med} = 2.25^{+2.15}_{-1.26}\ M_\odot\ yr^{-1}}$. We measure the faint, electron-temperature-sensitive, $[O III]$ $λ$4363 emission line at $2.5σ$ ($4.1σ$) significance when considering a bootstrapped (statistical-only) uncertainty spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the mass spectrum of destroyed dwarf galaxies with the metallicity distribution function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04667/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.04667/</guid>
      <description>Alis J. Deason
Accreted stellar populations are comprised of the remnants of destroyed galaxies, and often dominate the `stellar haloes&amp;amp;#39; of galaxies such as the Milky Way (MW). This ensemble of external contributors is a key indicator of the past assembly history of a galaxy. We introduce a novel statistical method that uses the unbinned metallicity distribution function (MDF) of a stellar population to estimate the mass spectrum of its progenitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The accretion history of the Milky Way. I. How it shapes globular clusters and dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.07441/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.07441/</guid>
      <description>Francois Hammer
Halo inhabitants are individual stars, stellar streams, star and globular clusters, and dwarf galaxies. Here we compare the two last categories that include objects of similar stellar mass, which are often studied as self-dynamical equilibrium systems. We discover that the half-light radius of globular clusters depends on their orbital pericenter and total energy, and that Milky Way (MW) tides may explain the observed correlation. We also suggest that the accretion epoch of stellar systems in the MW halo can be calibrated by the total orbital energy, and that such a relation is due to both the mass growth of the MW and dynamical friction affecting mostly satellites with numerous orbits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stellar Kinematics of Void Dwarf Galaxies Using KCWI</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.03721/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.03721/</guid>
      <description>Mithi A. C. de los Reyes
Dwarf galaxies located in extremely under-dense cosmic voids are excellent test-beds for disentangling the effects of large-scale environment on galaxy formation and evolution. We present integral field spectroscopy for low-mass galaxies ($M_{\star}=10^{7}-10^{9}~M_{\odot}$) located inside (N=21) and outside (N=9) cosmic voids using the Keck Cosmic Web Imager (KCWI). Using measurements of stellar line-of-sight rotational velocity $v_{\mathrm{rot}}$ and velocity dispersion $σ_{\star}$, we test the tidal stirring hypothesis, which posits that dwarf spheroidal galaxies are formed through tidal interactions with more massive host galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength Scrutiny of X-ray Sources in Dwarf Galaxies: ULXs versus AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.01317/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.01317/</guid>
      <description>Erica Thygesen
Owing to their quiet evolutionary histories, nearby dwarf galaxies (stellar masses $M_\star \lesssim 3 \times 10^9 M_\odot$) have the potential to teach us about the mechanism(s) that &amp;amp;#39;seeded&amp;amp;#39; the growth of supermassive black holes, and also how the first stellar mass black holes formed and interacted with their environments. Here, we present high spatial-resolution observations of three dwarf galaxies in the X-ray (Chandra), the optical/near-infrared (Hubble Space Telescope), and the radio (Karl G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of dwarf galaxies in f(R) gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.02306/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.02306/</guid>
      <description>Ivan de Martino
We use the kinematic data of the stars in eight dwarf spheroidal galaxies to assess whether $f(R)$ gravity can fit the observed profiles of the line-of-sight velocity dispersion of these systems without resorting to dark matter. Our model assumes that each galaxy is spherically symmetric and has a constant velocity anisotropy parameter $β$ and constant mass-to-light ratio consistent with stellar population synthesis models. We solve the spherical Jeans equation that includes the Yukawa-like gravitational potential appearing in the weak field limit of $f(R)$ gravity, and a Plummer density profile for the stellar distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Panchromatic Study of Massive Stars in the Extremely Metal-Poor Local Group Dwarf Galaxy Leo A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.14349/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.14349/</guid>
      <description>Maude Gull
We characterize massive stars (M&amp;amp;gt;8 M_sun) in the nearby (D~0.8 Mpc) extremely metal-poor (Z~5% Z_sun) galaxy Leo A using Hubble Space Telescope ultra-violet (UV), optical, and near-infrared (NIR) imaging along with Keck/LRIS and MMT/Binospec optical spectroscopy for 18 main sequence OB stars. We find that: (a) 12 of our 18 stars show emission lines, despite not being associated with an H II region, suggestive of stellar activity (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overmassive black holes in dwarf galaxies out to z∼0.9 in the VIPERS survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.14057/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.14057/</guid>
      <description>M. Mezcua,
Supermassive black holes (SMBHs) are thought to originate from early Universe seed black holes of mass $M_\mathrm{BH} \sim 10^2$-10$^5$ M$_{\odot}$ and grown through cosmic time. Such seeds could be powering the active galactic nuclei (AGN) found in today&amp;amp;#39;s dwarf galaxies. However, probing a connection between the early seeds and local SMBHs has not yet been observationally possible. Massive black holes hosted in dwarf galaxies at intermediate redshifts, on the other hand, may represent the evolved counterparts of the seeds formed at very early times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaken, not blown: the gentle baryonic feedback of nearby starburst dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.02726/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.02726/</guid>
      <description>A. Marasco,
Baryonic feedback is expected to play a key role in regulating the star formation of low-mass galaxies by producing galaxy-scale winds associated with mass-loading factors $β\!\sim\!1\!-\!50$. We have tested this prediction using a sample of 19 nearby systems with stellar masses $10^7\!&amp;amp;lt;\!M_\star/{\rm M}_{\odot}\!&amp;amp;lt;\!10^{10}$, mostly lying above the main sequence of star-forming galaxies. We used MUSE@VLT optical integral field spectroscopy to study the warm ionised gas kinematics of these galaxies via a detailed modelling of their H$α$ emission line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pandora project. I: the impact of radiation and cosmic rays on baryonic and dark matter properties of dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.09139/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.09139/</guid>
      <description>Sergio Martin-Alvarez
Enshrouded in several well-known controversies, dwarf galaxies have been extensively studied to learn about the underlying cosmology, notwithstanding that physical processes regulating their properties are poorly understood. To shed light on these processes, we introduce the Pandora suite of 17 high-resolution (3.5 parsec half-cell side) dwarf galaxy formation cosmological simulations. Commencing with thermo-turbulent star formation and mechanical supernova feedback, we gradually increase the complexity of physics incorporated leading to full-physics models combining magnetism, on-the-fly radiative transfer and the corresponding stellar photoheating, and SN-accelerated cosmic rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined search in dwarf spheroidal galaxies for branon dark matter annihilation signatures with the MAGIC Telescopes </title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.07979/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.07979/</guid>
      <description>T. Miener,
One of the most pressing questions for modern physics is the nature of dark matter (DM). Several efforts have been made to model this elusive kind of matter. The largest fraction of DM cannot be made of any of the known particles of the Standard Model (SM). We focus on brane world theory as a prospective framework for DM candidates beyond the SM of particle physics. The new degrees of freedom that appear in flexible brane world models, corresponding to brane fluctuations, are called branons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2022ann: A type Icn supernova from a dwarf galaxy that reveals helium in its circumstellar environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05134/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05134/</guid>
      <description>K. W. Davis
We present optical and near-infrared (NIR) observations of the Type Icn supernova (SN Icn) 2022ann, the fifth member of its newly identified class of SNe. Its early optical spectra are dominated by narrow carbon and oxygen P-Cygni features with absorption velocities of 800 km/s; slower than other SNe Icn and indicative of interaction with a dense, H/He-poor circumstellar medium (CSM) that is outflowing slower than a typical Wolf-Rayet wind velocity of $&amp;gt;$1000 km/s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion from Winds of Red Giant Branch Stars May Reveal the Supermassive Black Hole in Leo I</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion_from_winds_of_red_giant_branch_stars_may_reveal_the_supermassive_black_hole_in_leo_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion_from_winds_of_red_giant_branch_stars_may_reveal_the_supermassive_black_hole_in_leo_i/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabio Pacucci
A supermassive black hole (SMBH) of $\sim 3\times 10^6 , \rm M_\odot$ was recently detected via dynamical measurements at the center of the dwarf galaxy Leo I. Standing $\sim 2$ orders of magnitude above standard scaling relations, this SMBH is hosted by a galaxy devoid of gas and with no significant star formation in the last $\sim 1$ Gyr. This detection can profoundly impact the formation models for black holes and their hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Outflows and Inefficient Star Formation in the Reionization-era Ultra-faint Dwarf Galaxy Eridanus II</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_outflows_and_inefficient_star_formation_in_the_reionization-era_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxy_eridanus_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_outflows_and_inefficient_star_formation_in_the_reionization-era_ultra-faint_dwarf_galaxy_eridanus_ii/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nathan R. Sandford
We present novel constraints on the underlying galaxy formation physics (e.g., mass loading factor, star formation history, metal retention) at $z \gtrsim 7$ for the low-mass ($M_*\sim10^5$ M$\odot$) Local Group ultra-faint dwarf galaxy (UFD) Eridanus II (Eri II) Using a hierarchical Bayesian framework, we apply a one-zone chemical evolution model to Eri II&amp;rsquo;s CaHK-based photometric metallicity distribution function (MDF; [Fe/H]) and find that the evolution of Eri II is well-characterized by a short, exponentially declining star-formation history ($\tau\text{SFH} = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endothermic self-interacting dark matter in Milky Way-like dark matter haloes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/endothermic_self-interacting_dark_matter_in_milky_way-like_dark_matter_haloes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/endothermic_self-interacting_dark_matter_in_milky_way-like_dark_matter_haloes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stephanie O&amp;rsquo;Neil
Self-interacting dark matter (SIDM) offers the potential to mitigate some of the discrepancies between simulated cold dark matter (CDM) and observed galactic properties. We introduce a physically motivated SIDM model to understand the effects of self interactions on the properties of Milky Way and dwarf galaxy sized haloes. This model consists of dark matter with a nearly degenerate excited state, which allows for both elastic and inelastic scattering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining the Tilt of the Milky Way&#39;s Dark Matter Halo with the Sagittarius Stream</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_tilt_of_the_milky_ways_dark_matter_halo_with_the_sagittarius_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_the_tilt_of_the_milky_ways_dark_matter_halo_with_the_sagittarius_stream/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nondh Panithanpaisal
Recent studies have suggested that the Milky Way (MW)&amp;rsquo;s Dark Matter (DM) halo may be significantly tilted with respect to its central stellar disk, a feature that might be linked to its formation history. In this work, we demonstrate a method of constraining the orientation of the minor axis of the DM halo using the angle and frequency variables. This method is complementary to other traditional techniques, such as orbit fitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarf galaxy formation with and without dark matter-baryon streaming velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxy_formation_with_and_without_dark_matter-baryon_streaming_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dwarf_galaxy_formation_with_and_without_dark_matter-baryon_streaming_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anna T. P. Schauer
We study how supersonic streaming velocities of baryons relative to dark matter &amp;ndash; a large-scale effect imprinted at recombination and coherent over $\sim 3$ Mpc scales &amp;ndash; affects the formation of dwarf galaxies at $z \gtrsim 5$. We perform cosmological hydrodynamic simulations, including and excluding streaming velocities, in regions centered on halos with $M_{\rm vir}(z=0) \approx 10^{10}$ M${\odot}$; the simulations are part of the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project and run with FIRE-3 physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying globular clusters and applying them to estimate the mass of the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classifying_globular_clusters_and_applying_them_to_estimate_the_mass_of_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: GuangChen Sun
We combine the kinematics of 159 globular clusters (GCs) provided by the Gaia Early Data Release 3 (EDR 3) with other observational data to classify the GCs, and to estimate the mass of Milky Way (MW). We use the age-metallicity relation, integrals of motion, action space and the GC orbits to identify the GCs as either formed in-situ (Bulge and Disk) or ex-situ (via accretion). We find that $45.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN quenching in simulated dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.05275/</guid>
      <description>Ray S. Sharma
We examine the quenching characteristics of $328$ isolated dwarf galaxies $\left(10^{8} &amp;lt; M_{\rm star}/M_\odot &amp;lt; 10^{10} \right)$ within the \Rom{} cosmological hydrodynamic simulation. Using mock observation methods, we identify isolated dwarf galaxies with quenched star formation and make direct comparisons to the quenched fraction in the NASA Sloan Atlas (NSA). Similar to other cosmological simulations, we find a population of quenched, isolated dwarf galaxies below $M_{\rm star} &amp;lt; 10^{9} M_\odot$ not detected within the NSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and dynamics of the peculiar stream Jhelum, A tentative role for the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2202.02132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2202.02132/</guid>
      <description>Hanneke C. Woudenberg
Stellar streams are a promising tool to study the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s dark matter subhalo population, as interactions with subhalos could produce substructure in streams. However, other possible causes for substructure first need to be well understood. Here we study the kinematics and the unusual morphology of the stellar stream Jhelum. Using a combination of ground-based photometry and Gaia EDR3 astrometry we characterize the morphology of Jhelum. We combine this new data with radial velocities from the literature to perform orbit integrations of the stream in static Galactic potentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a new Local Group Dwarf Galaxy Candidate in UNIONS: Boötes V</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.08242/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.08242/</guid>
      <description>Simon E. T. Smith
We present the discovery of Boötes V, a new ultra-faint dwarf galaxy candidate. This satellite is detected as a resolved overdensity of stars during an ongoing search for new Local Group dwarf galaxy candidates in the UNIONS photometric dataset. It has a physical half-light radius of 26.9$^{+7.5}_{-5.4}$ pc, a $V$-band magnitude of $-$4.5 $\pm$ 0.4 mag, and resides at a heliocentric distance of approximately 100 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early-type Dwarf Galaxies in the Local Universe. Evidence of Ex-situ Growth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03430/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03430/</guid>
      <description>Sanjaya Paudel
We report the discovery of a rare early-type &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; (dE), SDSS J125651.47+163024.2 (hereafter dE1256), possessing a tidal feature that was likely built up by accretion of an even smaller &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;. dE1256 is located in a nearly isolated environment, at the outskirt of the Virgo cluster. A detailed morphological examination reveals that the accreted stellar population is mainly deposited in the outer part of dE1256, where the tidal tail is most prominent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic signatures of impulsive supernova feedback in dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03795/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03795/</guid>
      <description>Jan D. Burger
Impulsive supernova feedback and non-standard dark matter models, such as self-interacting dark matter (SIDM), are the two main contenders for the role of the dominant core formation mechanism at the dwarf galaxy scale. Here we show that the impulsive supernova cycles that follow episodes of bursty star formation leave distinct features in the distribution function of stars: groups of stars with similar ages and metallicities develop overdense shells in phase space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peekaboo: the extremely metal poor dwarf galaxy HIPASS J1131-31</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03478/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03478/</guid>
      <description>I. D. Karachentsev
The &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; irregular &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; HIPASS J1131-31 was discovered as a source of HI emission at low redshift in such close proximity of a bright star that we call it Peekaboo. The &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; resolves into stars in images with Hubble Space Telescope, leading to a distance estimate of 6.8+-0.7 Mpc. Spectral optical observations with the Southern African Large Telescope reveal HIPASS J1131-31 to be one of the most extremely metal-poor &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxies&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; known with the gas-phase oxygen abundance 12+log(O/H) = 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric and Structural Parameters of Newly Discovered Nuclear Star Clusters in Local Volume Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04151/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04151/</guid>
      <description>Nils Hoyer
We use high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging data of &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dwarf&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxies&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; in the Local Volume ($\lesssim 11$ Mpc) to parameterise 19 newly discovered nuclear star clusters (NSCs). Most of the clusters have stellar masses of $M_{\star}^{nsc} \lesssim 10^6$ M$_{\odot}$ and compare to Galactic globular clusters in terms of ellipticity, effective radius, stellar mass, and surface density. The clusters are modelled with a Sérsic profile and their surface brightness evaluated at the effective radius reveals a tight positive correlation to the host &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;galaxy&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mass-Metallicity Relation of Dwarf Galaxies at the Cosmic Noon in the JWST Era</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01382/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.01382/</guid>
      <description>Mingyu Li, Zheng Cai
We present the mass-metallicity relation (MZR) at $z=2-3$ in the stellar mass range of $M_\star\approx 10^{6.5}-10^{9.5}M_\odot$ using 55 dwarf galaxies in the Abell 2744 and SMACS J0723-3732 galaxy cluster fields. These dwarf galaxies are identified and confirmed by deep JWST/NIRISS imaging and slitless grism spectroscopic observations. Taking advantage of the gravitational lensing effect, we extend the previous MZR relation at $z=2-3$ to a much lower mass regime by more than 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present-day gas content of simulated field dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.11782/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2209.11782/</guid>
      <description>Georg Herzog
We examine the gas content of field dwarf galaxies in a high-resolution cosmological simulation. In agreement with previous work, we find that galaxies inhabiting dark matter haloes with mass below a critical value, $M_{200} \lesssim M_{\rm crit} \approx 5\times 10^{9} \ M_{\odot}$, are quiescent at the present day. The gas content of these galaxies is thus insensitive to feedback from evolving stars. Almost half of these quiescent systems today have gas masses much smaller than that expected for their mass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
