<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arecibo Pulsar Beam Geometry at Lower Frequencies Radio Pulsar Beam Geometry Down to the 100-MHz Band: 76 Additional Sources Within the Arecibo Sky</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arecibo_pulsar_beam_geometry_at_lower_frequencies_radio_pulsar_beam_geometry_down_to_the_100-mhz_band_76_additional_sources_within_the_arecibo_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/arecibo_pulsar_beam_geometry_at_lower_frequencies_radio_pulsar_beam_geometry_down_to_the_100-mhz_band_76_additional_sources_within_the_arecibo_sky/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joanna Rankin
This paper provides analyses of the emission beam structure of 76 B&#39;&#39;-named pulsars within the Arecibo sky. Most of these objects are included in both the Gould &amp;amp; Lyne and LOFAR High Band surveys and thus complement our other works treating various parts of these populations. These comprise a further group of mostly well studied pulsars within the Arecibo sky that we here treat similarly to those in Olszanski et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects for detecting transient quasi-monochromatic gravitational waves from glitching pulsars with current and future detectors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prospects_for_detecting_transient_quasi-monochromatic_gravitational_waves_from_glitching_pulsars_with_current_and_future_detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/prospects_for_detecting_transient_quasi-monochromatic_gravitational_waves_from_glitching_pulsars_with_current_and_future_detectors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joan Moragues
Pulsars are rotating neutron stars that emit periodic electromagnetic radiation. While pulsars generally slow down as they lose energy, some also experience glitches: spontaneous increases of their rotational frequency. According to several models, these glitches can also lead to the emission of long-duration transient gravitational waves (GWs). We present detection prospects for such signals by comparing indirect energy upper limits on GW strain for known glitches with the sensitivity of current and future ground-based GW detectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for continuous gravitational waves from HESS~J1427-608 with a hidden Markov model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/search_for_continuous_gravitational_waves_from_hess~j1427-608_with_a_hidden_markov_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/search_for_continuous_gravitational_waves_from_hess~j1427-608_with_a_hidden_markov_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Deeksha Beniwal
We present a search for continuous gravitational wave signals from an unidentified pulsar potentially powering HESS J1427-608, a spatially-unresolved TeV point source detected by the High Energy Stereoscopic System (H.E.S.S). The search uses a semi-coherent algorithm, which combines the maximum likelihood $\mathcal{F}-$statistic with a hidden Markov Model to efficiently detect and track quasi-monochromatic signals that wander randomly in frequency. It uses data from the second observing run of the Advanced Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Catalogue of Solar-Like Oscillators Observed by TESS in 120-second and 20-second Cadence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_catalogue_of_solar-like_oscillators_observed_by_tess_in_120-second_and_20-second_cadence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_catalogue_of_solar-like_oscillators_observed_by_tess_in_120-second_and_20-second_cadence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emily Hatt
The Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission has provided photometric light curves for stars across nearly the entire sky. This allows for the application of asteroseismology to a pool of potential solar-like oscillators that is unprecedented in size. We aim to produce a catalogue of solar-like oscillators observed by TESS in the 120-second and 20-second cadence modes. The catalogue is intended to highlight stars oscillating at frequencies above the TESS 30-minute cadence Nyquist frequency with the purpose of encompassing the main sequence and subgiant evolutionary phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet Science With Ground Based and Space Based Surveys in the New Millennium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/comet_science_with_ground_based_and_space_based_surveys_in_the_new_millennium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/comet_science_with_ground_based_and_space_based_surveys_in_the_new_millennium/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. Bauer
We summarize the comet science provided by surveys. This includes surveys where the detections of comets are an advantageous benefit but were not part of the survey&#39;s original intent, as well as some pointed surveys where comet science was the goal. Many of the surveys are made using astrophysical and heliophysics assets. The surveys in our scope include those using ground-based as well as space-based telescope facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Mach Numbers for Magnetohydrodynamic Shocks with Accelerated Particles and Waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/critical_mach_numbers_for_magnetohydrodynamic_shocks_with_accelerated_particles_and_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/critical_mach_numbers_for_magnetohydrodynamic_shocks_with_accelerated_particles_and_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Martin Laming
The first critical fast Mach number is defined for a magnetohydrodynamic shock as the Mach number where the shock transitions from subcritical, laminar, behavior to supercritical behavior, characterized by incident ion reflection from the shock front. The ensuing upstream waves and turbulence are convected downstream leading to a turbulent shock structure. Formally this is the Mach number where plasma resistivity can no longer provide sufficient dissipation to establish a stable shock, and is characterized by the downstream flow speed becoming subsonic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation of the filamentation instability and dispersion measure of Fast Radio Bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/saturation_of_the_filamentation_instability_and_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/saturation_of_the_filamentation_instability_and_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emanuele Sobacchi
Nonlinear effects are crucial for the propagation of Fast Radio Bursts (FRBs) near the source. We study the filamentation of FRBs in the relativistic winds of magnetars, which are commonly invoked as the most natural FRB progenitors. As a result of filamentation, the particle number density and the radiation intensity develop strong gradients along the direction of the wind magnetic field. A steady state is reached when the plasma pressure balances the ponderomotive force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quenched Satellite Population Around Milky Way Analogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_quenched_satellite_population_around_milky_way_analogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_quenched_satellite_population_around_milky_way_analogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ananthan Karunakaran
We study the relative fractions of quenched and star-forming satellite galaxies in the Satellites Around Galactic Analogs (SAGA) survey and Exploration of Local VolumE Satellites (ELVES) program, two nearby and complementary samples of Milky Way-like galaxies that take different approaches to identify faint satellite galaxy populations. We cross-check and validate sample cuts and selection criteria, as well as explore the effects of different star-formation definitions when determining the quenched satellite fraction of Milky Way analogs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
