<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modelling shock-like injections of solar energetic particles with 3D test particle simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modelling_shock-like_injections_of_solar_energetic_particles_with_3d_test_particle_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modelling_shock-like_injections_of_solar_energetic_particles_with_3d_test_particle_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Hutchinson
Solar Energetic Particle (SEP) acceleration and injection into interplanetary space during gradual SEP events is thought to take place at Coronal Mass Ejection (CME)-driven shocks. Features of measured intensity profiles at 1 au have been attributed to properties of the radial and longitudinal/latitudinal injections at the shock. Focussed transport models are typically used to model acceleration at a CME-shock and subsequent propagation. Test particle simulations are an alternative approach but so far they have been carried out only with instantaneous injection near the Sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The TESS Grand Unified Hot Jupiter Survey. II. Twenty New Giant Planets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_tess_grand_unified_hot_jupiter_survey._ii._twenty_new_giant_planets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_tess_grand_unified_hot_jupiter_survey._ii._twenty_new_giant_planets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samuel W. Yee
NASA&amp;rsquo;s Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission promises to improve our understanding of hot Jupiters by providing an all-sky, magnitude-limited sample of transiting hot Jupiters suitable for population studies. Assembling such a sample requires confirming hundreds of planet candidates with additional follow-up observations. Here, we present twenty hot Jupiters that were detected using TESS data and confirmed to be planets through photometric, spectroscopic, and imaging observations coordinated by the TESS Follow-up Observing Program (TFOP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arecibo Pulsar Beam Geometry at Lower Frequencies Radio Pulsar Beam Geometry Down to the 100-MHz Band: 76 Additional Sources Within the Arecibo Sky</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arecibo_pulsar_beam_geometry_at_lower_frequencies_radio_pulsar_beam_geometry_down_to_the_100-mhz_band_76_additional_sources_within_the_arecibo_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arecibo_pulsar_beam_geometry_at_lower_frequencies_radio_pulsar_beam_geometry_down_to_the_100-mhz_band_76_additional_sources_within_the_arecibo_sky/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joanna Rankin
This paper provides analyses of the emission beam structure of 76 B&#39;&#39;-named pulsars within the Arecibo sky. Most of these objects are included in both the Gould &amp;amp; Lyne and LOFAR High Band surveys and thus complement our other works treating various parts of these populations. These comprise a further group of mostly well studied pulsars within the Arecibo sky that we here treat similarly to those in Olszanski et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects for detecting transient quasi-monochromatic gravitational waves from glitching pulsars with current and future detectors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_for_detecting_transient_quasi-monochromatic_gravitational_waves_from_glitching_pulsars_with_current_and_future_detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_for_detecting_transient_quasi-monochromatic_gravitational_waves_from_glitching_pulsars_with_current_and_future_detectors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joan Moragues
Pulsars are rotating neutron stars that emit periodic electromagnetic radiation. While pulsars generally slow down as they lose energy, some also experience glitches: spontaneous increases of their rotational frequency. According to several models, these glitches can also lead to the emission of long-duration transient gravitational waves (GWs). We present detection prospects for such signals by comparing indirect energy upper limits on GW strain for known glitches with the sensitivity of current and future ground-based GW detectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for continuous gravitational waves from HESS~J1427-608 with a hidden Markov model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_continuous_gravitational_waves_from_hess~j1427-608_with_a_hidden_markov_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/search_for_continuous_gravitational_waves_from_hess~j1427-608_with_a_hidden_markov_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Deeksha Beniwal
We present a search for continuous gravitational wave signals from an unidentified pulsar potentially powering HESS J1427-608, a spatially-unresolved TeV point source detected by the High Energy Stereoscopic System (H.E.S.S). The search uses a semi-coherent algorithm, which combines the maximum likelihood $\mathcal{F}-$statistic with a hidden Markov Model to efficiently detect and track quasi-monochromatic signals that wander randomly in frequency. It uses data from the second observing run of the Advanced Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Catalogue of Solar-Like Oscillators Observed by TESS in 120-second and 20-second Cadence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_catalogue_of_solar-like_oscillators_observed_by_tess_in_120-second_and_20-second_cadence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_catalogue_of_solar-like_oscillators_observed_by_tess_in_120-second_and_20-second_cadence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emily Hatt
The Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission has provided photometric light curves for stars across nearly the entire sky. This allows for the application of asteroseismology to a pool of potential solar-like oscillators that is unprecedented in size. We aim to produce a catalogue of solar-like oscillators observed by TESS in the 120-second and 20-second cadence modes. The catalogue is intended to highlight stars oscillating at frequencies above the TESS 30-minute cadence Nyquist frequency with the purpose of encompassing the main sequence and subgiant evolutionary phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet Science With Ground Based and Space Based Surveys in the New Millennium</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_science_with_ground_based_and_space_based_surveys_in_the_new_millennium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/comet_science_with_ground_based_and_space_based_surveys_in_the_new_millennium/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. Bauer
We summarize the comet science provided by surveys. This includes surveys where the detections of comets are an advantageous benefit but were not part of the survey&#39;s original intent, as well as some pointed surveys where comet science was the goal. Many of the surveys are made using astrophysical and heliophysics assets. The surveys in our scope include those using ground-based as well as space-based telescope facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Mach Numbers for Magnetohydrodynamic Shocks with Accelerated Particles and Waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/critical_mach_numbers_for_magnetohydrodynamic_shocks_with_accelerated_particles_and_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/critical_mach_numbers_for_magnetohydrodynamic_shocks_with_accelerated_particles_and_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Martin Laming
The first critical fast Mach number is defined for a magnetohydrodynamic shock as the Mach number where the shock transitions from subcritical, laminar, behavior to supercritical behavior, characterized by incident ion reflection from the shock front. The ensuing upstream waves and turbulence are convected downstream leading to a turbulent shock structure. Formally this is the Mach number where plasma resistivity can no longer provide sufficient dissipation to establish a stable shock, and is characterized by the downstream flow speed becoming subsonic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of updated Multipole Love and f-Love Universal Relations in context of Binary Neutron Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_updated_multipole_love_and_f-love_universal_relations_in_context_of_binary_neutron_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_updated_multipole_love_and_f-love_universal_relations_in_context_of_binary_neutron_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bikram Keshari Pradhan
Neutron star (NS) equation of state (EoS) insensitive relations or universal relations (UR) involving neutron star bulk properties play a crucial role in gravitational-wave astronomy. Considering a wide range of equations of state originating from (i) phenomenological relativistic mean field models, (ii) realistic EoS models based on different physical motivations, and (iii) polytropic EoSs described by spectral decomposition method, we update the EoS-insensitive relations involving NS tidal deformability (Multipole Love relation) and the UR between f-mode frequency and tidal deformability (f-Love relation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inconspicuous Solar Polar Coronal X-ray Jets as the Source of Conspicuous Hinode/EUV Imaging Spectrometer (EIS) Doppler Outflows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inconspicuous_solar_polar_coronal_x-ray_jets_as_the_source_of_conspicuous_hinode_euv_imaging_spectrometer_eis_doppler_outflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inconspicuous_solar_polar_coronal_x-ray_jets_as_the_source_of_conspicuous_hinode_euv_imaging_spectrometer_eis_doppler_outflows/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alphonse C. Sterling
We examine in greater detail five events previously identified as being sources of strong transient coronal outflows in a solar polar region in Hinode/EUV Imaging Spectrometer (EIS) Doppler data. Although relatively compact or faint and inconspicuous in Hinode/Soft X-ray Telescope (XRT) soft-X-ray (SXR) images and in Solar Dynamics Observatory (SDO)/Atmospheric Imaging Assembly (AIA) EUV images, we find that all of these events are consistent with being faint coronal X-ray jets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation of the filamentation instability and dispersion measure of Fast Radio Bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_of_the_filamentation_instability_and_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/saturation_of_the_filamentation_instability_and_dispersion_measure_of_fast_radio_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Emanuele Sobacchi
Nonlinear effects are crucial for the propagation of Fast Radio Bursts (FRBs) near the source. We study the filamentation of FRBs in the relativistic winds of magnetars, which are commonly invoked as the most natural FRB progenitors. As a result of filamentation, the particle number density and the radiation intensity develop strong gradients along the direction of the wind magnetic field. A steady state is reached when the plasma pressure balances the ponderomotive force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light curves of transneptunian objects from the K2 mission of the Kepler Space Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_transneptunian_objects_from_the_k2_mission_of_the_kepler_space_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_transneptunian_objects_from_the_k2_mission_of_the_kepler_space_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Viktória Kecskeméthy
The K2 mission of the Kepler Space Telescope allowed the observations of light curves of small solar system bodies throughout the whole Solar system. In this paper we present the results of a collection of K2 transneptunian object observations, between Campaigns C03 (November 2014 &amp;ndash; February 2015) to C19 (August &amp;ndash; September, 2018), which includes 66 targets. Due to the faintness of our targets the detectability rate of a light curve period is $\sim$56%, notably lower than in the case of other small body populations, like Hildas or Jovian trojans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of LEO Satellites With All-Sky Photometric Signatures</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_leo_satellites_with_all-sky_photometric_signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_leo_satellites_with_all-sky_photometric_signatures/</guid>
      <description>First author: Harrison Krantz
We present novel techniques and methodology for unresolved photometric characterization of low-Earth Orbit (LEO) satellites. With the Pomenis LEO Satellite Photometric Survey our team has made over 14,000 observations of Starlink and OneWeb satellites to measure their apparent brightness. From the apparent brightness of each satellite, we calculate a new metric: the effective albedo, which quantifies the specularity of the reflecting satellite. Unlike stellar magnitude units, the effective albedo accounts for apparent range and phase angle and enables direct comparison of different satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Link Between Black Holes in High-Mass X-ray Binaries and Gravitational-Wave Sources: Observational Selection Effects</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_missing_link_between_black_holes_in_high-mass_x-ray_binaries_and_gravitational-wave_sources_observational_selection_effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_missing_link_between_black_holes_in_high-mass_x-ray_binaries_and_gravitational-wave_sources_observational_selection_effects/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camille Liotine
There are few observed high-mass X-ray binaries (HMXBs) that harbor massive black holes, and none are likely to result in a binary black hole (BBH) that merges within a Hubble time; however, we know that massive merging BBHs exist from gravitational-wave observations. We investigate the role that X-ray and gravitational-wave observational selection effects play in determining the properties of their respective detected binary populations. We confirm that, as a result of selection effects, observable HMXBs and observable BBHs form at different redshifts and metallicities, with observable HMXBs forming at much lower redshifts and higher metallicities than observable BBHs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The POLARBEAR-2 and Simons Array Focal Plane Fabrication Status</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_polarbear-2_and_simons_array_focal_plane_fabrication_status/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_polarbear-2_and_simons_array_focal_plane_fabrication_status/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Westbrook
We present on the status of POLARBEAR-2 A (PB2-A) focal plane fabrication. The PB2-A is the first of three telescopes in the Simon Array (SA), which is an array of three cosmic microwave background (CMB) polarization sensitive telescopes located at the POLARBEAR (PB) site in Northern Chile. As the successor to the PB experiment, each telescope and receiver combination is named as PB2-A, PB2-B, and PB2-C.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
