<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Rotating 25 M⊙ Population III star: Physical Properties and Resulting Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/untitled/</guid>
      <description>Amar Aryan
In this Letter, we report the outcomes of 1-D modelling of a rotating 25 M$_{\odot}$ zero-age main-sequence Population III star up to the stage of the onset of core collapse. Rapidly rotating models display violent and sporadic mass losses after the Main-Sequence stage. In comparison to the solar metallicity model, Pop III models show very small pre-supernova radii. Further, with models at the stage of the onset of core collapse, we simulate the hydrodynamic simulations of resulting supernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The JWST Resolved Stellar Populations Early Release Science Program III: Photometric Star-Galaxy Separations for NIRCam</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07218/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07218/</guid>
      <description>Jack T. Warfield
We present criteria for separately classifying stars and unresolved background galaxies in photometric catalogs generated with the point spread function (PSF) fitting photometry software DOLPHOT from images taken of Draco II, WLM, and M92 with the Near Infrared Camera (NIRCam) on JWST. Photometric quality metrics from DOLPHOT in one or two filters can recover a pure sample of stars. Conversely, colors formed between short-wavelength (SW) and long-wavelength (LW) filters can be used to effectively identify pure samples of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the population III binary black hole mergers with intermediate mass black holes: dependence on common envelope parameter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.07496/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.07496/</guid>
      <description>Kotaro Hijikawa
The current gravitational wave (GW) detectors have successfully observed many binary compact objects, and the third generation ground-based GW detectors such as Einstein telescope and space-borne detectors such as LISA will start their GW observation in a decade. Ahead of the arrival of this new era, we perform a binary population synthesis calculation for very massive (&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;MathJax_Preview&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;display: none;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;MathJax&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;MathJax-Element-1-Frame&amp;quot; tabindex=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;nobr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;math&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;MathJax-Span-1&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;width: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Population III homogeneous stellar evolution on early cosmic reionisation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.15125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2205.15125/</guid>
      <description>Yves Sibony
Context: Population III (Pop III) stars may be fast rotating. An expected consequence of fast rotation is strong internal mixing that deeply affects their evolutionary tracks in the Hertzsprung-Russell diagram and hence their ionising power. aims: We investigate the impact on the ionising power of Pop III stars in an extreme case of internal mixing, the one leading to chemically homogeneous evolution (CHE). In that situation, during the main sequence phase, the star keeps the same chemical composition from its center to its surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Deviations in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04476/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.04476/</guid>
      <description>Xin Wang
Fluctuations play a critical role in cosmology. They are relevant across a range of phenomena from the dynamics of inflation to the formation of structure. In many cases, these fluctuations are coarse grained and follow a Gaussian distribution as a consequence of the Central Limit Theorem. Yet, some classes of observables are dominated by rare fluctuations and are sensitive to the details of the underlying microphysics. In this paper, we argue that the Large Deviation Principle can be used to diagnose when one must to appeal to the fundamental description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the observability and identification of Population III galaxies with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.02038/</guid>
      <description>James A. A. Trussler
We utilise theoretical models of Population III stellar+nebular spectra to investigate the prospects of observing and accurately identifying Population III galaxies with JWST using both deep imaging and spectroscopy. We investigate a series of different colour cuts, finding that a combination of NIRCam and MIRI photometry through the F444W-F560W, F560W-F770W colours offers the most robust identifier of potential $z=8$ Pop III candidates. We calculate that NIRCam will have to reach $\sim$ 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating the collapse of rotating primordial gas clouds to study the survival possibility of Pop III protostars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.10789/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.10789/</guid>
      <description>Shubham Raghuvanshi
It has been argued that the low-mass primordial stars ($m_{\rm Pop III}\,\leq 0.8\,M_\odot$) are likely to enter the main sequence and hence possibly be found in the present-day Galaxy. However, due to limitations in existing numerical capabilities, current three-dimensional (3D) &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;search-hit mathjax&amp;quot;&amp;gt;simulations&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; of disk fragmentation are capable of following only a few thousands of years of evolution after the formation of the first protostar. In this work we use a modified version of {\sc Gadget}-2 smoothed particle hydrodynamics(SPH) code to present the results of non-linear collapse of the gas clouds associated with various degrees of initial solid body rotation (parameterized by $β$) using a piecewise polytropic equation of state.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
