<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Population III on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/population-iii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modelling shock-like injections of solar energetic particles with 3D test particle simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modelling_shock-like_injections_of_solar_energetic_particles_with_3d_test_particle_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/modelling_shock-like_injections_of_solar_energetic_particles_with_3d_test_particle_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Hutchinson
Solar Energetic Particle (SEP) acceleration and injection into interplanetary space during gradual SEP events is thought to take place at Coronal Mass Ejection (CME)-driven shocks. Features of measured intensity profiles at 1 au have been attributed to properties of the radial and longitudinal/latitudinal injections at the shock. Focussed transport models are typically used to model acceleration at a CME-shock and subsequent propagation. Test particle simulations are an alternative approach but so far they have been carried out only with instantaneous injection near the Sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The TESS Grand Unified Hot Jupiter Survey. II. Twenty New Giant Planets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_tess_grand_unified_hot_jupiter_survey._ii._twenty_new_giant_planets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/the_tess_grand_unified_hot_jupiter_survey._ii._twenty_new_giant_planets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samuel W. Yee
NASA&amp;rsquo;s Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission promises to improve our understanding of hot Jupiters by providing an all-sky, magnitude-limited sample of transiting hot Jupiters suitable for population studies. Assembling such a sample requires confirming hundreds of planet candidates with additional follow-up observations. Here, we present twenty hot Jupiters that were detected using TESS data and confirmed to be planets through photometric, spectroscopic, and imaging observations coordinated by the TESS Follow-up Observing Program (TFOP).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
