<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>early universe on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/early-universe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in early universe on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/early-universe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>$	exttt{KOBEsim}$: a Bayesian observing strategy algorithm for planet detection in radial velocity blind-search surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/%5Ctextttkobesim_a_bayesian_observing_strategy_algorithm_for_planet_detection_in_radial_velocity_blind-search_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/%5Ctextttkobesim_a_bayesian_observing_strategy_algorithm_for_planet_detection_in_radial_velocity_blind-search_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. Balsalobre-Ruza
Ground-based observing time is precious in the era of exoplanet follow-up and characterization, especially in high-precision radial velocity instruments. Blind-search radial velocity surveys thus require a dedicated observational strategy in order to optimize the observing time, which is particularly crucial for the detection of small rocky worlds at large orbital periods. We develop an algorithm with the purpose of improving the efficiency of radial velocity observations in the context of exoplanet searches, and we apply it to the K-dwarfs Orbited By habitable Exoplanets (KOBE) experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The multipole expansion of the local expansion rate</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_multipole_expansion_of_the_local_expansion_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_multipole_expansion_of_the_local_expansion_rate/</guid>
      <description>First author: Basheer Kalbouneh
We design a new observable, the expansion rate fluctuation $\eta$, to characterize deviations from the linear relation between redshift and distance in the local universe. We also show how to compress the resulting signal into spherical harmonic coefficients in order to better decipher the structure and symmetries of the anisotropies in the local expansion rate. We apply this analysis scheme to several public catalogs of redshift-independent distances, the Cosmicflows-3 and Pantheon data sets, covering the redshift range $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Further Improving Distances to Binary Millisecond Pulsars with Gaia EDR3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/further_improving_distances_to_binary_millisecond_pulsars_with_gaia_edr3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/further_improving_distances_to_binary_millisecond_pulsars_with_gaia_edr3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Abigail Moran
We have identified 7 objects in Gaia Early DR3 associated with 6 International Pulsar Timing Array (PTA) pulsars. We combine both pulsar timing based parallax distance measurements with Gaia parallaxes to their companions, in an effort to improve distance measurements. We confirm previous cross-match findings for pulsars J0437-4715, J1012+5307, J1024-0719, J1732-5049, and J1843-1113. We no longer find the companion to J1949+3106 even though it was detected with a $&amp;gt; 3\sigma$ confidence in Gaia DR2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A crack in the track of the Hubble Constant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_crack_in_the_track_of_the_hubble_constant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_crack_in_the_track_of_the_hubble_constant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Marie Gueguen
Measuring the rate at which the universe expands at a given time &amp;ndash; the &amp;lsquo;Hubble constant&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; has been a topic of controversy since the first measure of its expansion by Edwin Hubble in the 1920&amp;rsquo;s. As early as the 1970&amp;rsquo;s, Sandage et de Vaucouleurs have been arguing about the adequate methodology for such a measurement. Should astronomers focus only on their best indicators, e.g., the Cepheids, and improve the precision of this measurement based on a unique object to the best possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Gravitational Lensing on Fast Transient Event Rates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_gravitational_lensing_on_fast_transient_event_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effect_of_gravitational_lensing_on_fast_transient_event_rates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mawson W. Sammons
Fast cosmological transients such as fast radio bursts (FRBs) and gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) represent a class of sources more compact than any other cosmological object. As such they are sensitive to significant magnification via gravitational lensing from a class of lenses which are not well-constrained by observations today. Low-mass primordial black holes are one such candidate which may constitute a significant fraction of the Universe&amp;rsquo;s dark matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A billion or more years of possible periglacial/glacial cycling in Protonilus Mensae, Mars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_billion_or_more_years_of_possible_periglacial_glacial_cycling_in_protonilus_mensae_mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_billion_or_more_years_of_possible_periglacial_glacial_cycling_in_protonilus_mensae_mars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Richard J. Soare
The long-term cyclicity and temporal succession of glacial-periglacial (or deglacial) periods or epochs are keynotes of Quaternary geology on Earth. Relatively recent work has begun to explore the histories of the mid- to higher-latitudinal terrain of Mars, especially in the northern hemisphere, for evidence of similar cyclicity and succession in the Mid to Late Amazonian Epoch. Here, we carry on with this work by focusing on Protonilus Mensae [PM] (43-490 N, 37-590 E).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BICEP / Keck XVII: Line of Sight Distortion Analysis: Estimates of Gravitational Lensing, Anisotropic Cosmic Birefringence, Patchy Reionization, and Systematic Errors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bicep___keck_xvii_line_of_sight_distortion_analysis_estimates_of_gravitational_lensing_anisotropic_cosmic_birefringence_patchy_reionization_and_systematic_errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/bicep___keck_xvii_line_of_sight_distortion_analysis_estimates_of_gravitational_lensing_anisotropic_cosmic_birefringence_patchy_reionization_and_systematic_errors/</guid>
      <description>First author: BICEP/Keck Collaboration
We present estimates of line-of-sight distortion fields derived from the 95 GHz and 150 GHz data taken by BICEP2, BICEP3, and Keck Array up to the 2018 observing season, leading to cosmological constraints and a study of instrumental and astrophysical systematics. Cosmological constraints are derived from three of the distortion fields concerning gravitational lensing from large-scale structure, polarization rotation from magnetic fields or an axion-like field, and the screening effect of patchy reionization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing afterglow models of FRB 200428 with early post-burst observations of SGR 1935&#43;2154</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_afterglow_models_of_frb_200428_with_early_post-burst_observations_of_sgr_1935&#43;2154/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/testing_afterglow_models_of_frb_200428_with_early_post-burst_observations_of_sgr_1935&#43;2154/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. J. Cooper
We present LOFAR imaging observations from the April/May 2020 active episode of magnetar SGR 1935+2154. We place the earliest radio limits on persistent emission following the low-luminosity fast radio burst FRB 200428 from the magnetar. We also perform an image-plane search for transient emission and find no radio flares during our observations. We examine post-FRB radio upper limits in the literature and find that all are consistent with the multi-wavelength afterglow predicted by the synchrotron maser shock model interpretation of FRB 200428.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the distant universe with a very luminous fast radio burst at redshift 1</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_distant_universe_with_a_very_luminous_fast_radio_burst_at_redshift_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_distant_universe_with_a_very_luminous_fast_radio_burst_at_redshift_1/</guid>
      <description>First author: Stuart D. Ryder
Fast radio bursts are millisecond-duration pulses of radio emission that have been found to originate at extragalactic distances. The bursts show dispersion imparted by intervening plasma, with the bulk attributed to the intergalactic medium. Here we report the discovery of a burst, FRB20220610A, in a complex host galaxy system at a redshift of $z=1.016 \pm 0.002$. The relationship between its redshift and dispersion confirm that the bulk of the baryonic matter was ionized and in the intergalactic medium when the universe was almost half its present age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMM-Newton view of the shock heating in an early merging cluster, CIZA J1358.9$-$4750</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/xmm-newton_view_of_the_shock_heating_in_an_early_merging_cluster_ciza_j1358.9-4750/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/xmm-newton_view_of_the_shock_heating_in_an_early_merging_cluster_ciza_j1358.9-4750/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Omiya
CIZA J1358.9-4750 is a nearby galaxy cluster in the early phase of a major merger. The two-dimensional temperature map using XMM-Newton EPIC-PN observation confirms the existence of a high temperature region, which we call the &amp;ldquo;hot region&amp;rdquo;, in the &amp;ldquo;bridge region&amp;rdquo; connecting the two clusters. The ~ 500 kpc wide region between the southeast and northwest boundaries also has higher pseudo pressure compared to the unshocked regions, suggesting the existence of two shocks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
