<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>early universe on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/early-universe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in early universe on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/early-universe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Early results from GLASS-JWST XVI: Discovering a bluer z~4-7 Universe through UV slopes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.13860/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2207.13860/</guid>
      <description>Themiya Nanayakkara
We use the GLASS-JWST Early Release Science NIRCam parallel observations to provide a first view of the UV continuum properties of NIRCam/F444W selected galaxies at 4&amp;amp;lt;z&amp;amp;lt;7. By combining multiwavelength NIRCam observations, we constrain the UV continuum slope for a sample of 401 galaxies with stringent quality controls. We find that &amp;amp;gt;99% of the galaxies are blue star-forming galaxies with very low levels of dust (Avbeta~0.01+/-0.33). We find no statistically significant correlation for UV slope with redshift or UV magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exotic energy injection in the early universe I: a novel treatment for low-energy electrons and photons</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07366/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07366/</guid>
      <description>Hongwan Liu,
Decaying or annihilating dark matter and other exotic energy injections can modify the spectrum of the universe&amp;amp;#39;s photon bath, resulting in e.g. new contributions to spectral distortions of the cosmic microwave background blackbody spectrum and modifications to the temperature and ionization history of the universe. Here, we present an improved version of the $\texttt{DarkHistory}$ code, which is now capable of consistently calculating the spectrum of low-energy photons by properly treating the interactions of these photons with the levels of hydrogen atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exotic energy injection in the early universe II: CMB spectral distortions and constraints on light dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07370/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07370/</guid>
      <description>Hongwan Liu
We calculate the post-recombination contribution to the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) spectral distortion due to general exotic energy injections, including dark matter (DM) decaying or annihilating to Standard Model particles. Upon subtracting the background distortion that would be present even without such energy injections, we find residual distortions that are still potentially large enough to be detectable by future experiments such as PIXIE. The distortions also have a high-energy spectral feature that is a unique signature of the injection of high-energy particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First emergence of cold accretion and supermassive star formation in the early universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.10263/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.10263/</guid>
      <description>Masaki Kiyuna
We investigate the first emergence of the so-called cold accretion, the accretion flows deeply penetrating a halo, in the early universe with cosmological N-body/SPH simulations. We study the structure of the accretion flow and its evolution within small halos with $\lesssim 10^8~{\rm M}_\odot$ with sufficiently high spatial resolutions down to $\sim 1 \ {\rm pc}$ scale. While previous studies only follow the evolution for a short period after the primordial cloud collapse, we follow the long-term evolution until the cold accretion first appears, employing the sink particle method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal Factories in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07376/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.07376/</guid>
      <description>Stephen Eales
We have measured the mass of metals in 13 submillimetre galaxies at z~4 in which the gas, based on previous observations, lies in a cold rotating disk. We measured the metal masses using either the submillimetre line or continuum emission from three tracers of the overall metal content - carbon atoms, carbon monoxide molecules and dust grains - using the first calibration of this technique that treats all three tracers simultaneously (Dunne et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational capture of magnetic monopoles by primordial black holes in the early universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07002/</guid>
      <description>Chen Zhang
It is intriguing to ask whether the existence of primordial black holes (PBHs) in the early universe could significantly reduce the abundance of certain stable massive particles (SMP) via gravitational capture, after which the PBHs evaporate before BBN to avoid conflict with stringent bounds. For example, this mechanism is relevant to an alternative solution of the monopole problem proposed by Stojkovic and Freese, in which magnetic monopoles produced in the early universe are captured by PBHs, thus freeing inflation from having to occur during or after the corresponding phase transitions that produced the monopoles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General-relativistic radiation transport scheme in Gmunu I: Implementation of two-moment based multi-frequency radiative transfer and code tests</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03261/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03261/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Chi-Kit Cheong
We present the implementation of two-moment based general-relativistic multi-group radiation transport module in the $\texttt{G}$eneral-relativistic $\texttt{mu}$ltigrid $\texttt{nu}$merical ($\texttt{Gmunu}$) code. On top of solving the general-relativistic magnetohydrodynamics and the Einstein equations with conformally flat approximations, the code solves the evolution equations of the zeroth- and first-order moments of the radiations. Analytic closure relation is used to obtain the higher order moments and close the system. The finite-volume discretisation has been adopted for the radiation moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population III X-ray Binaries and their Impact on the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03435/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2303.03435/</guid>
      <description>Nina S. Sartorio
The first population of X-ray binaries (XRBs) is expected to affect the thermal and ionization states of the gas in the early Universe. Although these X-ray sources are predicted to have important implications for high-redshift observable signals, such as the hydrogen 21-cm signal from cosmic dawn and the cosmic X-ray background, their properties are poorly explored, leaving theoretical models largely uninformed. In this paper we model a population of X-ray binaries arising from zero metallicity stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reoriented Memory of Galaxy Spins for the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reoriented_memory_of_galaxy_spins_for_the_early_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reoriented_memory_of_galaxy_spins_for_the_early_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jun-Sung Moon
Galaxy spins are believed to retain initially acquired tendency of being aligned with the intermediate principal axes of the linear tidal field, which disseminates a prospect of using them as a probe of the early universe physics. This roseate prospect, however, is contingent upon the key assumption that the observable stellar spins of the present galaxies measured at inner radii have the same alignment tendency toward the initial tidal field as their dark matter counterparts measured at virial limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistive Heating Induced by Streaming Cosmic Rays Around a Galaxy in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07028/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2302.07028/</guid>
      <description>Shota L. Yokoyama
It is expected that cosmic rays (CRs) escape from high-redshift galaxies at redshift $z\sim 10 \, - \, 20$ because CRs are accelerated by supernova remnants of the first stars. Although ultraviolet and X-ray photons are widely considered the main source of heating of the intergalactic medium, CRs can also contribute to it. When the CRs propagate in the intergalactic medium, in addition to the heating process due to CR ionization, resistive heating occurs due to the electron return current induced by the streaming CRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark matter and dark radiation from the early universe with a modulus coupled to the PQMSSM</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.12546/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.12546/</guid>
      <description>Howard Baer,
The supersymmetrized DFSZ axion model is especially compelling in that it contains 1. the SUSY solution to the gauge hierarchy problem, 2. the Peccei-Quinn (PQ) solution to the strong CP problem and 3. the Kim-Nilles solution to the SUSY mu problem. In a string setting, where a discrete R-symmetry ({\bf Z}_{24}^R for example) may emerge from the compactification process, a high-quality accidental axion (accion) can emerge from the accidental, approximate remnant global U(1)_{PQ} symmetry where the decay constant f_a is linked to the SUSY breaking scale, and is within the cosmological sweet zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the cosmological Lyman-Werner background radiation field in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.08242/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.08242/</guid>
      <description>Andrea Incatasciato
The Lyman-Werner (LW) radiation field is a key ingredient in the chemo-thermal evolution of gas in the Early Universe, as it dissociates H2 molecules, the primary cooling channel in an environment devoid of metals and dust. Despite its important role, it is still not implemented in cosmological simulations on a regular basis, in contrast to the general UV background. This is in part due to uncertainty in the source modelling, their spectra and abundance, as well as the detailed physics involved in the propagation of the photons and their interactions with the molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2102&#43;6015: an Intriguing Radio-loud Active Galactic Nucleus in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07355/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.07355/</guid>
      <description>S. Frey
The powerful high-redshift quasar J2102+6015 (at z=4.575) may provide useful information for studying supermassive black hole growth, galaxy evolution and feedback in the early Universe. The source has so far been imaged with very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) at 2/8 GHz (S/X) bands only, showing complex compact structure. Its total radio spectrum peaks at ~6 GHz in the rest frame. There is no sign of Doppler-boosted jet emission, and the separation of the two major features in its east-west oriented structure spanning ~10 milliarcsec does not change significantly on a timescale longer than a decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble tension as a guide for refining the early Universe: Cosmologies with explicit local Lorentz and diffeomorphism violation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.03883/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.03883/</guid>
      <description>Mohsen Khodadi
This paper is dedicated to assessing modified cosmological settings based on the gravitational Standard-Model Extension (SME). Our analysis rests upon the Hubble tension (HT), which is a discrepancy between the observational determination of the Hubble parameter via data from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Type Ia supernovae, respectively. While the latter approach is model-independent, the former highly depends on the model used to describe the physics of the early Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLARES VIII. The Emergence of Passive Galaxies in the Early Universe (z&gt;5)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.07540/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.07540/</guid>
      <description>Christopher C. Lovell
Passive galaxies are ubiquitous in the local universe, and various physical channels have been proposed that lead to this passivity. To date, robust passive galaxy candidates have been detected up to $z \leqslant 5$, but it is still unknown if they exist at higher redshifts, what their relative abundances are, and what causes them to stop forming stars. We present predictions from the First Light And Reionisation Epoch Simulations (FLARES), a series of zoom simulations of a range of overdensities using the EAGLE code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early or phantom dark energy, self-interacting, extra, or massive neutrinos, primordial magnetic fields, or a curved universe: An exploration of possible solutions to the $H_0$ and $σ_8$ problems</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.14435/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2208.14435/</guid>
      <description>Helena García Escudero
In this paper we explore the existing tensions in the local cosmological expansion rate, $H_0$, and amplitude of the clustering of large-scale structure at $8\, h^{-1}\mathrm{Mpc}$, $σ_8$, as well as models that claim to alleviate these tensions. We consider seven models: evolving dark energy ($w$CDM), extra radiation ($N_\mathrm{eff}$), massive neutrinos, curvature, primordial magnetic fields (PMF), self-interacting neutrino models, and early dark energy (EDE). We test these models against three data sets that span the full range of measurable cosmological epochs, have significant precision, and are well-tested against systematic effects: the Planck 2018 cosmic microwave background data, the Sloan Digital Sky Survey baryon acoustic oscillation scale measurements, and the Pantheon catalog of Type Ia supernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing early universe through redshifted 21-cm signal: Modelling and observational challenges</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_early_universe_through_redshifted_21-cm_signal_modelling_and_observational_challenges/</guid>
      <description>Abinash Kumar Shaw
The redshifted 21-cm radiation from the atomic hydrogen (HI) provides an excellent direct probe to study the evolution of HI in IGM and thus reveal the nature of the first luminous objects, their evolution and role during Cosmic Dawn (CD) and Epoch of Reionization (EoR), and formation and evolution of the structures thereafter. Direct mapping of the HI density during the CD-EoR is rather difficult with the current and future instruments due to large foreground and other observational contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic reconnection in the wakes of cosmic strings</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_reconnection_in_the_wakes_of_cosmic_strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magnetic_reconnection_in_the_wakes_of_cosmic_strings/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dilip Kumar
The motion of cosmic strings in the universe leads to the generation of wakes behind them. We study magnetized wakes of cosmic strings moving in the post recombination plasma. We show that magnetic reconnection can occur in the post shock region. Since the width of the cosmic string wake is very small, the reconnection occurs over a very short lengthscale. The reconnection leads to a large amount of kinetic energy being released in the post shock region of the cosmic string wake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio observations of four active galactic nuclei hosting intermediate-mass black hole candidates: studying the outflow activity and evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_observations_of_four_active_galactic_nuclei_hosting_intermediate-mass_black_hole_candidates_studying_the_outflow_activity_and_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_observations_of_four_active_galactic_nuclei_hosting_intermediate-mass_black_hole_candidates_studying_the_outflow_activity_and_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaolong Yang
Observational searches for intermediate-mass black holes (IMBHs; $10^2 - 10^6$ $M_\odot$) include relatively isolated dwarf galaxies. For those that host active galactic nuclei (AGNs), the IMBH nature may be discerned through the accretion - jet activity. We present radio observations of four AGN-hosting dwarf galaxies (which potentially harbor IMBHs). Very large array (VLA) observations indicate steep spectra (indices of $-$0.63 to $-$1.05) between 1.4 and 9 GHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The HI mass function of star-forming galaxies at $\mathbf{z \sim 0.35}$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_hi_mass_function_of_star-forming_galaxies_at___mathbfz__sim_0.35_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_hi_mass_function_of_star-forming_galaxies_at___mathbfz__sim_0.35_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Apurba Bera
The neutral atomic hydrogen (HI) mass function (HIMF) describes the distribution of the HI content of galaxies at any epoch; its evolution provides an important probe of models of galaxy formation and evolution. Here, we report Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope HI 21cm spectroscopy of blue star-forming galaxies at $z\approx0.20-0.42$ in the Extended Groth Strip, which has allowed us to determine the scaling relation between the average HI mass ($\rm{M_{HI}}$) and the absolute B-band magnitude ($\rm{M_B}$) of such galaxies at $z \approx 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The miniJPAS survey: stellar atmospheric parameters from 56 optical filters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_minijpas_survey_stellar_atmospheric_parameters_from_56_optical_filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_minijpas_survey_stellar_atmospheric_parameters_from_56_optical_filters/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. -B. Yuan
With a unique set of 54 overlapping narrow-band and two broader filters covering the entire optical range, the incoming Javalambre-Physics of the Accelerating Universe Astrophysical Survey (J-PAS) will provide a great opportunity for stellar physics and near-field cosmology. In this work, we use the miniJPAS data in 56 J-PAS filters and 4 complementary SDSS-like filters to explore and prove the potential of the J-PAS filter system in characterizing stars and deriving their atmospheric parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new method of reconstructing Galactic three-dimensional structures using ultralong-wavelength radio observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_of_reconstructing_galactic_three-dimensional_structures_using_ultralong-wavelength_radio_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_of_reconstructing_galactic_three-dimensional_structures_using_ultralong-wavelength_radio_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yanping Cong
The free-free absorption of low frequency radio waves by thermal electrons in the warm ionized medium of our Galaxy becomes very significant at $\lesssim 10$ MHz (ultralong-wavelength), and the absorption strength depends on the radio frequency. Upcoming space experiments such as the Discovering Sky at the Longest wavelength (DSL) and Farside Array for Radio Science Investigations of the Dark ages and Exoplanets (FARSIDE) will produce high-resolution multi-frequency sky maps at the ultralong-wavelength, providing a new window to observe the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a Dusty, Chemically Mature Companion to a z$\sim$4 Starburst Galaxy in JWST ERS Data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_dusty_chemically_mature_companion_to_a_z__sim_4_starburst_galaxy_in_jwst_ers_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_a_dusty_chemically_mature_companion_to_a_z__sim_4_starburst_galaxy_in_jwst_ers_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bo Peng
We report the discovery of two companion sources to a strongly lensed galaxy SPT0418-47 (&amp;ldquo;ring&amp;rdquo;) at redshift 4.225, targeted by the JWST Early Release Science program. We confirm that these sources are at a similar redshift as the ring based on H$\alpha$ detected in the NIRSpec spectrum, and $[C II]$ 158 $\mu$m line from ALMA. Using multiple spectral lines detected in JWST/NIRSpec, the rest-frame optical to infrared images from NIRCam and MIRI, and far-infrared (FIR) dust continuum detected by ALMA, we argue that the newly discovered sources are actually lensed images of the same companion galaxy, hereafter referred to as SPT0418-SE (&amp;ldquo;SE&amp;rdquo;), located within 5 kpc in the source plane of the ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Description and performance results of the trigger logic of TUS and Mini-EUSO to search for Ultra-High Energy Cosmic Rays from space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/description_and_performance_results_of_the_trigger_logic_of_tus_and_mini-euso_to_search_for_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays_from_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/description_and_performance_results_of_the_trigger_logic_of_tus_and_mini-euso_to_search_for_ultra-high_energy_cosmic_rays_from_space/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Bertaina
The trigger logic of the Tracking Ultraviolet Setup (TUS) and Multiwavelength Imaging New Instrument for the Extreme Universe Space Observatory (Mini-EUSO) space-based projects of the Joint Experiment Missions - EUSO (JEM-EUSO) program is summarized. The performance results on the search for ultra-high energy cosmic rays are presented.
arxiv link
pdf link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electron density variations in the interstellar medium and the average frequency profile of a scintle from pulsar scintillation spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/electron_density_variations_in_the_interstellar_medium_and_the_average_frequency_profile_of_a_scintle_from_pulsar_scintillation_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/electron_density_variations_in_the_interstellar_medium_and_the_average_frequency_profile_of_a_scintle_from_pulsar_scintillation_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Bartel
We observed the scintillation pattern of nine bright pulsars at 324 MHz and three at 1.68 GHz and analyzed the wavenumber spectrum which is related to electron density variations of the plasma turbulence of the interstellar medium. For all pulsars the frequency section of the autocorrelation function of the dynamic spectra to at least 45% of the maximum corresponds to predictions of scattering theories with a range of power-law exponents of the wavenumber spectrum of $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late-Forming PBH: Beyond the CMB era</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/late-forming_pbh_beyond_the_cmb_era/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/late-forming_pbh_beyond_the_cmb_era/</guid>
      <description>First author: Philip Lu
The intermediate mass black hole range, $10\lesssim M_{\rm BH}^{}/M_\odot^{}\lesssim 10^{5} $, has long offered enticing possibilities for primordial black holes (PBH), with populations in this range postulated to be responsible for some of the LIGO binary merger detected events as well as the existence of supermassive black holes embedded at galactic centers. However, a prominent bound derived from PBH accretion during recombination severely restricts the mass fraction of intermediate mass PBH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark matter freeze-in produces large post-inflationary isocurvature</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_matter_freeze-in_produces_large_post-inflationary_isocurvature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dark_matter_freeze-in_produces_large_post-inflationary_isocurvature/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicola Bellomo
In this Letter, we show that the nonthermal nature of dark matter freeze-in production leads to large, totally correlated dark matter-photon isocurvature perturbations, which are imprinted in anisotropies of the cosmic microwave background (CMB). Isocurvature is typically expected from inflationary physics, but the isocurvature from freeze-in arises post inflation. We compute the freeze-in of millicharged dark matter, generated from electron-positron annihilations in the early Universe. We find that current CMB observations from \textit{Planck} exclude this scenario for dark matter masses between 1 MeV and 10 GeV at more than $2\sigma$, whereas upcoming CMB experiments will have the sensitivity to reach at least the $4\sigma$ level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectro-spatial evolution of the CMB II: generalised Boltzmann hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_ii_generalised_boltzmann_hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectro-spatial_evolution_of_the_cmb_ii_generalised_boltzmann_hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jens Chluba
In this paper, we formulate a generalised photon Boltzmann hierarchy that allows us to model the evolution and creation of spectral distortion anisotropies in the early Universe. We directly build on our first paper in this series, extending the thermalisation Green&amp;rsquo;s function treatment to the anisotropic case. We show that the problem can be described with the common Boltzmann hierarchy for the photon field extended by new spectral parameters &amp;ndash; a step that reduces the complexity of the calculation by at least two orders of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The R-Process Alliance: Abundance Universality among Some Elements at and between the First and Second R-Process Peaks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_r-process_alliance_abundance_universality_among_some_elements_at_and_between_the_first_and_second_r-process_peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_r-process_alliance_abundance_universality_among_some_elements_at_and_between_the_first_and_second_r-process_peaks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ian U. Roederer
We present new observational benchmarks of rapid neutron-capture process (r-process) nucleosynthesis for elements at and between the first (A ~ 80) and second (A ~ 130) peaks. Our analysis is based on archival ultraviolet and optical spectroscopy of eight metal-poor stars with Se (Z = 34) or Te (Z = 52) detections, whose r-process enhancement varies by more than a factor of 30 (-0.22 &amp;lt;= [Eu/Fe] &amp;lt;= +1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A powerful (and likely young) radio-loud quasar at z=5.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_powerful_and_likely_young_radio-loud_quasar_at_z5.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_powerful_and_likely_young_radio-loud_quasar_at_z5.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Belladitta
We present the discovery of PSO J191.05696$+$86.43172 (hereafter PSO J191$+$86), a new powerful radio-loud quasar (QSO) in the early Universe (z = 5.32). We discovered it by cross-matching the NRAO VLA Sky Survey (NVSS) radio catalog at 1.4 GHz with the first data release of the Panoramic Survey Telescope and Rapid Response System (Pan-STARRS PS1) in the optical. With a NVSS flux density of 74.2 mJy, PSO J191$+$86 is one of the brightest radio QSO discovered at z$\sim$5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has JWST already falsified dark-matter-driven galaxy formation?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/has_jwst_already_falsified_dark-matter-driven_galaxy_formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/has_jwst_already_falsified_dark-matter-driven_galaxy_formation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Moritz Haslbauer
The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) discovered several luminous high-redshift galaxy candidates with stellar masses of $M_{} \gtrsim 10^{9} , \rm{M_{\odot}}$ at photometric redshifts $z_{\mathrm{phot}} \gtrsim 10$ which allows to constrain galaxy and structure formation models. For example, Adams et al. identified the candidate ID 1514 with $\log_{10}(M_{}/M_{\odot}) = {9.8}{-0.2}^{+0.2}$ located at $z{\mathrm{phot}} = 9.85_{-0.12}^{+0.18}$ and Naidu et al. found even more distant candidates labeled as GL-z11 and GL-z13 with $\log_{10}(M_{}/M_{\odot}) = 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a reliable calculation of relic radiation from primordial gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/towards_a_reliable_calculation_of_relic_radiation_from_primordial_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/towards_a_reliable_calculation_of_relic_radiation_from_primordial_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Giarè
Inflationary gravitational waves, behaving as additional radiation in the Early Universe, can increase the effective number of relativistic species ($N_{\rm eff}$) by a further correction that depends on the integrated energy-density in gravitational waves over all scales. This effect is typically used to constrain (blue-tilted) models of inflation in light of the bounds resulting from the Big Bang Nucleosynthesis. In this paper, we recompute this contribution, discussing some caveats of the state-of-the-art analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of neutrino decoupling from the early universe to the current universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.10307/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.10307/</guid>
      <description>Kensuke Akita
We review the distortions of spectra of relic neutrinos due to the interactions with electrons, positrons, and neutrinos in the early universe. We solve integro-differential kinetic equations for the neutrino density matrix, including vacuum three-flavor neutrino oscillations, oscillations in electron and positron background, a collision term and finite temperature corrections to electron mass and electromagnetic plasma up to the next-to-leading order $\mathcal{O}(e^3)$. After that, we estimate the effects of the spectral distortions in neutrino decoupling on the number density and energy density of the Cosmic Neutrino Background (C$ν$B) in the current universe, and discuss the implications of these effects on the capture rates in direct detection of the C$ν$B on tritium, with emphasis on the PTOLEMY-type experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic inhomogeneities in the early Universe: A numerical relativity approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03534/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.03534/</guid>
      <description>Cristian Joana
Cosmic inflation is arguably the most favoured paradigm of the very early Universe. It postulates an early phase of fast, nearly exponential, and accelerated expansion. Inflationary models are capable of explaining the overall flatness and homogeneity of today&amp;rsquo;s Universe at large scales. Despite being widely accepted by the physics community, these models are not absent from criticism. In scalar field inflation, a necessary condition to begin inflation is the requirement of a Universe dominated by the field&amp;rsquo;s potential, which implies a subdominant contribution from the scalar field dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaporation of Primordial Black Holes in the Early Universe: Mass and Spin Distributions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03878/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.03878/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Cheek
Many cosmological phenomena lead to the production of primordial black holes in the early Universe. These phenomena often create a population of black holes with extended mass and spin distributions. As these black holes evaporate via Hawking radiation, they can modify various cosmological observables, lead to the production of dark matter, modify the number of effective relativistic degrees of freedom, $N_{\rm eff}$, source a stochastic gravitational wave background and alter the dynamics of baryogenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Deviations in the Early Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.02535/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.02535/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Cohen
Fluctuations play a critical role in cosmology. They are relevant across a range of phenomena from the dynamics of inflation to the formation of structure. In many cases, these fluctuations are coarse grained and follow a Gaussian distribution as a consequence of the Central Limit Theorem. Yet, some classes of observables are dominated by rare fluctuations and are sensitive to the details of the underlying microphysics. In this paper, we argue that the Large Deviation Principle can be used to diagnose when one must to appeal to the fundamental description.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
