<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Data-constrained Magnetohydrodynamic Simulation of the X1.0 Solar Flare of 2021 October 28</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_data-constrained_magnetohydrodynamic_simulation_of_the_x1.0_solar_flare_of_2021_october_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_data-constrained_magnetohydrodynamic_simulation_of_the_x1.0_solar_flare_of_2021_october_28/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daiki Yamasaki
The solar active region NOAA 12887 produced a strong X1.0 flare on 2021 October 28, which exhibits X-shaped flare ribbons and a circle-shaped erupting filament. To understand the eruption process with these characteristics, we conducted a data-constrained magnetohydrodynamics simulation using a nonlinear force-free field of the active region about an hour before the flare as the initial condition. Our simulation reproduces the filament eruption observed in the Ha images of GONG and the 304 angstrom images of SDO/AIA and suggests that two mechanisms can possibly contribute to the magnetic eruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Simulation of Solar Magnetic Flux Emergence Using the AMR--CESE--MHD Code</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulation_of_solar_magnetic_flux_emergence_using_the_amr--cese--mhd_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulation_of_solar_magnetic_flux_emergence_using_the_amr--cese--mhd_code/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhipeng Liu
Magnetic flux emergence from the solar interior to the atmosphere is believed to be a key process of formation of solar active regions and driving solar eruptions. Due to the limited capability of observation, the flux emergence process is commonly studied using numerical simulations. In this paper, we developed a numerical model to simulate the emergence of a twisted magnetic flux tube from the convection zone to the corona using the AMR&amp;ndash;CESE&amp;ndash;MHD code, which is based on the conservation-element solution-element method with adaptive mesh refinement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for thermal gyro-synchrotron emission from hot stellar coronae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_thermal_gyro-synchrotron_emission_from_hot_stellar_coronae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_thermal_gyro-synchrotron_emission_from_hot_stellar_coronae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Walter Golay
We have searched for thermal gyro-synchrotron radio emission from a sample of five radio-loud stars whose X-ray coronae contain a hot ($T&amp;gt;10^7$ K) thermal component. We used the JVLA to measure Stokes I and V/I spectral energy distributions (SEDs) over the frequency range 15&amp;ndash;45 GHz, determining the best-fitting model parameters using power-law and thermal gyro-synchrotron emission models. The SEDs of the three chromospherically active binaries (Algol, UX Arietis, HR 1099) were well-fit by a power-law gyro-synchrotron model, with no evidence for a thermal component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of LBT atmospheric and turbulence conditions in the context of ALTA project</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_lbt_atmospheric_and_turbulence_conditions_in_the_context_of_alta_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_lbt_atmospheric_and_turbulence_conditions_in_the_context_of_alta_project/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Turchi
ALTA project has been active since 2016, providing, at LBT observatory site, forecasts of atmospheric parameters, such as temperature, wind speed and direction, relative humidity and precipitable water vapor, and optical turbulence parameters, such as seeing, wavefront coherence time and isoplanatic angle with the final goal to support nightly the science operation of the LBT. Besides to the forecasts, during the years ALTA has been collecting statistics on the atmospheric conditions which can be used to draw a very accurate characterization of the climatology of the telescope site located on top of Mount Graham, Arizona.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Two Years of FLEET: an Active Search for Superluminous Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_first_two_years_of_fleet_an_active_search_for_superluminous_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_first_two_years_of_fleet_an_active_search_for_superluminous_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sebastian Gomez
In November 2019 we began operating FLEET (Finding Luminous and Exotic Extragalactic Transients), a machine learning algorithm designed to photometrically identify Type I superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) in transient alert streams. Using FLEET, we spectroscopically classified 21 of the 50 SLSNe identified worldwide between November 2019 and January 2022. Based on our original algorithm, we anticipated that FLEET would achieve a purity of about 50% for transients with a probability of being a SLSN, \pslsn$&amp;gt;0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-Variable Jet Ejections from RW Aur A, RY Tau and DG Tau</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-variable_jet_ejections_from_rw_aur_a_ry_tau_and_dg_tau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/time-variable_jet_ejections_from_rw_aur_a_ry_tau_and_dg_tau/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michihiro Takami
We present Gemini-NIFS, VLT-SINFONI and Keck-OSIRIS observations of near-infrared [Fe II] emission associated with the well-studied jets from three active T Tauri stars; RW Aur A, RY Tau and DG Tau taken from 2012-2021. We primarily covered the redshifted jet from RW Aur A, and the blueshifted jets from RY Tau and DG Tau, to investigate long-term time variabilities potentially related to the activities of mass accretion and/or the stellar magnetic fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flare Duty Cycle of Gamma-Ray Blazars and Implications for High-Energy Neutrino Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flare_duty_cycle_of_gamma-ray_blazars_and_implications_for_high-energy_neutrino_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flare_duty_cycle_of_gamma-ray_blazars_and_implications_for_high-energy_neutrino_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kenji Yoshida
Gamma-ray flares of blazars may be accompanied by high-energy neutrinos due to interactions of high-energy cosmic rays in the jet with photons, as suggested by the detection of the high-energy neutrino IceCube-170922A during a major gamma-ray flare from blazar TXS 0506+056 at the $\sim3\sigma$ significance level. In this work, we present a statistical study of gamma-ray emission from blazars to constrain the contribution of gamma-ray flares to their neutrino output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric and spectroscopic studies of the long period low mass ratio deep contact binary KN Per</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_spectroscopic_studies_of_the_long_period_low_mass_ratio_deep_contact_binary_kn_per/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_spectroscopic_studies_of_the_long_period_low_mass_ratio_deep_contact_binary_kn_per/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xin-Yi Gao
The photometric analysis and spectroscopic study of the long period low mass ratio deep contact binary KN Per were executed. The light curves of BV(RI)$c$-band were from the Ningbo Bureau of Education and Xinjiang Observatory Telescope (NEXT) at the Xingming Observatory. Through the analysis of Wilson-Devinney (W-D) program, KN Per was found as an A-type low mass ratio deep contact binary (q=0.236, f=53.4%). A cool spot applied on the primary component was introduced to explain the unequal maxima of the light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-surface Plasma Flows and the Flare Productivity of Solar Active Regions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-surface_plasma_flows_and_the_flare_productivity_of_solar_active_regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-surface_plasma_flows_and_the_flare_productivity_of_solar_active_regions/</guid>
      <description>First author: B Lekshmi
The extreme space weather conditions resulting from high energetic events likes solar flares and Coronal Mass Ejections (CMEs) demand for reliable space weather forecasting. The magnetic flux tubes while rising through the convection zone gets twisted by the turbulent plasma flows, energizing the system and resulting in flares. We investigate the relationship between the subsurface plasma flows associated with flaring active regions and their surface magnetic flux and current helicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The astorb database at Lowell Observatory</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_astorb_database_at_lowell_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_astorb_database_at_lowell_observatory/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicholas A. Moskovitz
The astorb database at Lowell Observatory is an actively curated catalog of all known asteroids in the Solar System. astorb has heritage dating back to the 1970&amp;rsquo;s and has been publicly accessible since the 1990&amp;rsquo;s. Beginning in 2015 work began to modernize the underlying database infrastructure, operational software, and associated web applications. That effort has involved the expansion of astorb to incorporate new data such as physical properties (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plasma composition measurements in an active region from Solar Orbiter/SPICE and Hinode/EIS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/plasma_composition_measurements_in_an_active_region_from_solar_orbiter_spice_and_hinode_eis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/plasma_composition_measurements_in_an_active_region_from_solar_orbiter_spice_and_hinode_eis/</guid>
      <description>First author: David H. Brooks
A key goal of the Solar Orbiter mission is to connect elemental abundance measurements of the solar wind enveloping the spacecraft with EUV spectroscopic observations of their solar sources, but this is not an easy exercise. Observations from previous missions have revealed a highly complex picture of spatial and temporal variations of elemental abundances in the solar corona. We have used coordinated observations from Hinode and Solar Orbiter to attempt new abundance measurements with the SPICE (Spectral Imaging of the Coronal Environment) instrument, and benchmark them against standard analyses from EIS (EUV Imaging Spectrometer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Outbursts in the Ground-Based Photometry of 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_outbursts_in_the_ground-based_photometry_of_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_outbursts_in_the_ground-based_photometry_of_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Gardener
67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko is a Jupiter-family comet that was the target of the Rosetta mission, the first mission to successfully orbit and land a probe on a comet. This mission was accompanied by a large ground-based observing campaign. We have developed a pipeline to calibrate and measure photometry of comet 67P during its 2016 perihelion passage, making use of all visible wavelength broadband imaging collected across a wide range of facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The thermonuclear X-ray bursts of 4U 1730-22</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_thermonuclear_x-ray_bursts_of_4u_1730-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_thermonuclear_x-ray_bursts_of_4u_1730-22/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Bult
We present observations of the historic transient 4U 1730-22 as observed with the Neutron Star Interior Composition Explorer (NICER). After remaining in quiescence since its 1972 discovery, this X-ray binary showed renewed outburst activity in 2021 and 2022. We observed 4U 1730-22 extensively with NICER, detecting a total of 17 thermonuclear X-ray bursts. From a spectroscopic analysis, we find that these X-ray bursts can be divided into a group of bright and weak bursts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Testing of a 3U CubeSat to Test the In-situ Vetoing for the $ν$SOL Solar Neutrino Detector</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/design_and_testing_of_a_3u_cubesat_to_test_the_in-situ_vetoing_for_the__%CE%BD_sol_solar_neutrino_detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/design_and_testing_of_a_3u_cubesat_to_test_the_in-situ_vetoing_for_the__%CE%BD_sol_solar_neutrino_detector/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jonathan Folkerts
For years, earth-based neutrino detectors have been run and operated to detect the elusive neutrino. These have historically been enormous underground detectors. The neutrino Solar Orbiting Laboratory ($\nu$SOL) project is working to design a technical demonstration to show that a much smaller neutrino detector can be operated in near-solar environments for a future spaceflight mission. At a closest approach of 3 solar radii, there is a ten thousand-fold increase in the neutrino flux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toroidal flux loss due to flux emergence explains why solar cycles rise differently but decay in a similar way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toroidal_flux_loss_due_to_flux_emergence_explains_why_solar_cycles_rise_differently_but_decay_in_a_similar_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toroidal_flux_loss_due_to_flux_emergence_explains_why_solar_cycles_rise_differently_but_decay_in_a_similar_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: Akash Biswas
A striking feature of the solar cycle is that at the beginning, sunspots appear around mid-latitudes, and over time the latitudes of emergences migrate towards the equator.The maximum level of activity (e.g., sunspot number) varies from cycle to cycle.For strong cycles, the activity begins early and at higher latitudes with wider sunspot distributions than for weak cycles. The activity and the width of sunspot belts increase rapidly and begin to decline when the belts are still at high latitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COCONUT, a novel fast-converging MHD model for solar corona simulations: II. Assessing the impact of the input magnetic map on space-weather forecasting at minimum of activity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/coconut_a_novel_fast-converging_mhd_model_for_solar_corona_simulations_ii._assessing_the_impact_of_the_input_magnetic_map_on_space-weather_forecasting_at_minimum_of_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/coconut_a_novel_fast-converging_mhd_model_for_solar_corona_simulations_ii._assessing_the_impact_of_the_input_magnetic_map_on_space-weather_forecasting_at_minimum_of_activity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Barbara Perri
This paper is dedicated to the new implicit unstructured coronal code COCONUT, which aims at providing fast and accurate inputs for space weather forecast as an alternative to empirical models. We use all 20 available magnetic maps of the solar photosphere covering the date of the 2nd of July 2019 which corresponds to a solar eclipse on Earth. We use the same standard pre-processing on all maps, then perform coronal MHD simulations with the same numerical and physical parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Low $ΔV$ Spacecraft Missions to Oort Cloud Comet C/2014 UN$_{271}$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/analysis_of_low__%CE%B4v__spacecraft_missions_to_oort_cloud_comet_c_2014_un__271_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/analysis_of_low__%CE%B4v__spacecraft_missions_to_oort_cloud_comet_c_2014_un__271_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Adam Hibberd
Comet C/2014 UN${271}$, alternative designation &amp;lsquo;BB&amp;rsquo; after its discoverers &amp;lsquo;Bernardinelli/Bernstein&amp;rsquo;, and commonly referred to as UN${271}$, is an extreme case on two fronts, firstly its solar distance on discovery ($&amp;gt;$ 29 au) and secondly the size of its nucleus (137$\pm$ 15 km). With an aphelion distance of $\sim$33,000 au (w.r.t. the solar system barycentre) and an orbital period $\sim$2 million years, it is definitely an object from the solar system&amp;rsquo;s Oort cloud, and also by a good measure the largest Oort cloud object ever observed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The characteristics of flare- and CME-productive solar active regions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_characteristics_of_flare-_and_cme-productive_solar_active_regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_characteristics_of_flare-_and_cme-productive_solar_active_regions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ioannis Kontogiannis
Solar flares and coronal mass ejections (CMEs) cause immediate and adverse effects on the interplanetary space and geospace. The deeper understanding of the mechanisms that produce them and the construction of efficient prediction schemes are of paramount importance. The source regions of flares and CMEs exhibit some common morphological characteristics associated with strongly sheared magnetic polarity inversion lines, indicative of the complex magnetic configurations that store huge amounts of free magnetic energy and helicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional core-collapse supernovae with complex magnetic structures: II. Rotational instabilities and multimessenger signatures</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three-dimensional_core-collapse_supernovae_with_complex_magnetic_structures_ii._rotational_instabilities_and_multimessenger_signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three-dimensional_core-collapse_supernovae_with_complex_magnetic_structures_ii._rotational_instabilities_and_multimessenger_signatures/</guid>
      <description>First author: Matteo Bugli
The gravitational collapse of rapidly rotating massive stars can lead to the onset of the low $T/|W|$ instability within the central proto-neutron star (PNS), which leaves strong signatures in both the gravitational wave (GW) and neutrino emission. Strong large-scale magnetic fields are usually invoked to explain outstanding stellar explosions of rapidly rotating progenitors, but their impact on the growth of such instability has not yet been cleared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Catalog of Habitable Zone Exoplanets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_catalog_of_habitable_zone_exoplanets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_catalog_of_habitable_zone_exoplanets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michelle L. Hill
The search for habitable planets has revealed many planets that can vary greatly from an Earth analog environment. These include highly eccentric orbits, giant planets, different bulk densities, relatively active stars, and evolved stars. This work catalogs all planets found to reside in the HZ and provides HZ boundaries, orbit characterization, and the potential for spectroscopic follow-up observations. Demographics of the HZ planets are compared with a full catalog of exoplanets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAST observations of an extremely active episode of FRB 20201124A: II. Energy Distribution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_ii._energy_distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_ii._energy_distribution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yong-Kun Zhang
We report the properties of more than 800 bursts detected from the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20201124A with the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope (FAST) during an extremely active episode on UTC September 25-28, 2021 in a series of four papers. In this second paper of the series, we mainly focus on the energy distribution of the detected bursts. The event rate initially increased exponentially but the source activity stopped within 24 hours after the 4th day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAST observations of an extremely active episode of FRB 20201124A: IV. Spin Period Search</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_iv._spin_period_search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fast_observations_of_an_extremely_active_episode_of_frb_20201124a_iv._spin_period_search/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jia-Rui Niu
We report the properties of more than 800 bursts detected from the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20201124A with the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio telescope (FAST) during an extremely active episode on UTC September 25th-28th, 2021 in a series of four papers. In this fourth paper of the series, we present a systematic search of the spin period and linear acceleration of the source object from both 996 individual pulse peaks and the dedispersed time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferring Line-of-Sight Velocities and Doppler Widths from Stokes Profiles of GST/NIRIS Using Stacked Deep Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_line-of-sight_velocities_and_doppler_widths_from_stokes_profiles_of_gst_niris_using_stacked_deep_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_line-of-sight_velocities_and_doppler_widths_from_stokes_profiles_of_gst_niris_using_stacked_deep_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Haodi Jiang
Obtaining high-quality magnetic and velocity fields through Stokes inversion is crucial in solar physics. In this paper, we present a new deep learning method, named Stacked Deep Neural Networks (SDNN), for inferring line-of-sight (LOS) velocities and Doppler widths from Stokes profiles collected by the Near InfraRed Imaging Spectropolarimeter (NIRIS) on the 1.6 m Goode Solar Telescope (GST) at the Big Bear Solar Observatory (BBSO). The training data of SDNN is prepared by a Milne-Eddington (ME) inversion code used by BBSO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microwave response to sunspot oscillations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/microwave_response_to_sunspot_oscillations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/microwave_response_to_sunspot_oscillations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Robert Sych
We present the first observations of spatially resolved oscillation sources obtained with the Siberian Radioheliograph (SRH) at 3-6 GHz. We have found significant flux oscillations with periods of about 3, 5 and 13 minutes emitted from AR12833. The 3-minute periodicity dominates at higher frequencies. It was found that the apparent level of oscillations depends on the active region location on the disc, and scales down towards the limbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Parameter Measurements for the Ultra-Short-Period Planet TOI-1807b</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_parameter_measurements_for_the_ultra-short-period_planet_toi-1807b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_parameter_measurements_for_the_ultra-short-period_planet_toi-1807b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peifeng Peng
The ultra-short-period (USP) planets are exoplanets with very short orbital periods ($\textit{P} &amp;lt; 1$ day), and TOI-1807b is one such planet recently discovered by the TESS mission where it orbits in the TOI-1807 system that is still little known nowadays. In this paper, we re-analyzed the transit light curves of TOI-1807 using the latest TESS data from Sector 49, combined with previous data from Sector 22 and 23.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proton Irradiation of SiPM arrays for POLAR-2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/proton_irradiation_of_sipm_arrays_for_polar-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/proton_irradiation_of_sipm_arrays_for_polar-2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Slawomir Mianowski
POLAR-2 is a space-borne polarimeter, built to investigate the polarization of Gamma-Ray Bursts and help elucidate their mechanisms. The instrument is targeted for launch in 2024 or 2025 aboard the China Space Station and is being developed by a collaboration between institutes from Switzerland, Germany, Poland and China. The instrument will orbit at altitudes between 340km and 450km with an inclination of 42$^{\circ}$ and will be subjected to background radiation from cosmic rays and solar events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seismic Monitoring of the Sun&#39;s Far Hemisphere: A Crucial Component in Future Space Weather Forecasting (A White Paper Submitted to the Decadal Survey for Solar and Space Physics (Heliophysics) -- SSPH 2024-2033)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/seismic_monitoring_of_the_suns_far_hemisphere_a_crucial_component_in_future_space_weather_forecasting_a_white_paper_submitted_to_the_decadal_survey_for_solar_and_space_physics_heliophysics_--_ssph_2024-2033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/seismic_monitoring_of_the_suns_far_hemisphere_a_crucial_component_in_future_space_weather_forecasting_a_white_paper_submitted_to_the_decadal_survey_for_solar_and_space_physics_heliophysics_--_ssph_2024-2033/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kiran Jain
The purpose of this white paper is to put together a coherent vision for the role of helioseismic monitoring of magnetic activity in the Sun&amp;rsquo;s far hemisphere that will contribute to improving space weather forecasting as well as fundamental research in the coming decade. Our goal fits into the broader context of helioseismology in solar research for any number of endeavors when helioseismic monitors may be the sole synoptic view of the Sun&amp;rsquo;s far hemisphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and Differential Emission Measure Profiles in Turbulent Solar Active Region Loops</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temperature_and_differential_emission_measure_profiles_in_turbulent_solar_active_region_loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temperature_and_differential_emission_measure_profiles_in_turbulent_solar_active_region_loops/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Gordon Emslie
We examine the temperature structure of static coronal active region loops in regimes where thermal conductive transport is driven by Coulomb collisions, by turbulent scattering, or by a combination of the two. (In the last case collisional scattering dominates the heat transport at lower levels in the loop where temperatures are low and densities are high, while turbulent scattering dominates the heat transport at higher temperatures/lower densities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scintillating Tail of Comet C/2020 F3 (Neowise)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_scintillating_tail_of_comet_c_2020_f3_neowise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_scintillating_tail_of_comet_c_2020_f3_neowise/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. A. Fallows
Context. The occultation of a radio source by the plasma tail of a comet can be used to probe structure and dynamics in the tail. Such occultations are rare, and the occurrence of scintillation, due to small-scale density variations in the tail, remains somewhat controversial. Aims. A detailed observation taken with the Low-Frequency Array (LOFAR) of a serendipitous occultation of the compact radio source 3C196 by the plasma tail of comet C/2020 F3 (Neowise) is presented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
