<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>http://explosion.org/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://explosion.org/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pre-emergence Signatures Of Horizontal Divergent Flows In Solar Active Regions</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/pre-emergence_signatures_of_horizontal_divergent_flows_in_solar_active_regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/pre-emergence_signatures_of_horizontal_divergent_flows_in_solar_active_regions/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Rees-Crockford
Solar active regions (ARs) play a fundamental role in driving many of the geo-effective eruptions which propagate into the Solar System. However, we are still unable to consistently predict where and when ARs will occur across the solar disk by identifying pre-emergence signatures in observables such as the Doppler velocity (without using Helioseismic methods). Here we aim to determine the earliest time at which pre-emergence signatures, specifically the Horizontal Divergent Flow (HDF), can be confidently detected using data from the Solar Dynamics Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Helioseismic and Magnetic Imager (SDO/HMI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intranight optical variability of low-mass Active Galactic Nuclei: A Pointer to blazar-like activity</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/intranight_optical_variability_of_low-mass_active_galactic_nuclei_a_pointer_to_blazar-like_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/intranight_optical_variability_of_low-mass_active_galactic_nuclei_a_pointer_to_blazar-like_activity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gopal-Krishna
This study aims to characterise, for the first time, intranight optical variability (INOV) of low-mass active galactic nuclei (LMAGN) which host a black hole (BH) of mass $M_{BH} \sim 10^6 M_{\odot}$, i.e., even less massive than the Galactic centre black hole Sgr A* and 2-3 orders of magnitude below the supermassive black holes (SMBH, $M_{BH}$ $\sim$ $10^8 - 10^9 M_{\odot}$) which are believed to power quasars. Thus, LMAGN are a crucial subclass of AGN filling the wide gap between SMBH and stellar-mass BHs of Galactic X-ray binaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion and Host-Galaxy Properties of 14 New &#34;Changing-Look&#34; Active Galactic Nuclei Identified from the SDSS-V Survey</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/accretion_and_host-galaxy_properties_of_14_new_changing-look_active_galactic_nuclei_identified_from_the_sdss-v_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/accretion_and_host-galaxy_properties_of_14_new_changing-look_active_galactic_nuclei_identified_from_the_sdss-v_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Wang
The widely accepted active galactic nucleus (AGN) paradigm has been recently challenged by the discovery of the so-called changing-look&#39;&#39; (CL) phenomenon characterized by spectral-type transitions. By comparing the SDSS-V and SDSS DR16 spectroscopic datasets, here we report the identification of 14 new CL-AGNs (redshift $z&amp;lt;0.5$) exhibiting spectral-type changes on a timescale of $\sim 10$yr. Follow-up spectroscopy was conducted with the Lick Shane 3m and Keck 10m telescopes for three of the objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragment Dynamics in Active Asteroid 331P/Gibbs</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/fragment_dynamics_in_active_asteroid_331p_gibbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/fragment_dynamics_in_active_asteroid_331p_gibbs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Man-To Hui
We present a dynamical analysis of the fragmented active asteroid 331P/Gibbs. Using archival images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope from 2015 to 2018, we measured the astrometry of the primary and the three brightest (presumably the largest) components. Conventional orbit determination revealed a high-degree of orbital similarity between the components. We then applied a fragmentation model to fit the astrometry, obtaining key parameters including the fragmentation epochs and separation velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun-as-a-star Analyses of Various Solar Active Events Using H$α$ Spectral Images Taken by SMART/SDDI</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/sun-as-a-star_analyses_of_various_solar_active_events_using_h%CE%B1_spectral_images_taken_by_smart_sddi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/sun-as-a-star_analyses_of_various_solar_active_events_using_h%CE%B1_spectral_images_taken_by_smart_sddi/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takato Otsu
Sun-as-a-star analyses, in which observational data is spatially integrated, are useful for interpreting stellar data. For future applications to stellar observations, we performed Sun-as-a-star analyses of H$\alpha$ spectra for various active events on the Sun, not only for flares and filament eruptions/surges on the solar disk, but also for eruptions of off limb prominences using H$\alpha$ spectral images taken by the Solar Magnetic Activity Research Telescope / Solar Dynamics Doppler Imager (SMART/SDDI) at Hida Observatory, Kyoto University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and Differential Emission Measure Profiles in Turbulent Solar Active Region Loops</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/temperature_and_differential_emission_measure_profiles_in_turbulent_solar_active_region_loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/temperature_and_differential_emission_measure_profiles_in_turbulent_solar_active_region_loops/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Gordon Emslie
We examine the temperature structure of static coronal active region loops in regimes where thermal conductive transport is driven by Coulomb collisions, by turbulent scattering, or by a combination of the two. (In the last case collisional scattering dominates the heat transport at lower levels in the loop where temperatures are low and densities are high, while turbulent scattering dominates the heat transport at higher temperatures/lower densities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relation between the Optical eii Emission and the Dimensionless Accretion Rate for Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>http://explosion.org/article/the_relation_between_the_optical_%5Cfeii_emission_and_the_dimensionless_accretion_rate_for_active_galactic_nuclei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://explosion.org/article/the_relation_between_the_optical_%5Cfeii_emission_and_the_dimensionless_accretion_rate_for_active_galactic_nuclei/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liu Y. S.
It was suggested that the prominent feature of the optical Fe II emission has a connection with the accretion process in active galactic nuclei (AGN). For a large sample of 4037 quasars ($z &amp;lt; 0.8$) with measured $\rm H\beta$ line dispersion ($\sigma_{\rm H\beta}$) selected from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) and 120 compiled reverberation-mapped (RM) AGN, we use $\sigma_{\rm H\beta}$ and the extended $R_{\rm BLR}-L_{\rm 5100}$ relation to calculate supermassive black holes masses ($M_{\rm BH}$) from the single-epoch spectra for the SDSS subsample, and $\sigma_{\rm H\beta}$ from the mean spectra for the RM subsample.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
