<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Data-constrained Magnetohydrodynamic Simulation of the X1.0 Solar Flare of 2021 October 28</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_data-constrained_magnetohydrodynamic_simulation_of_the_x1.0_solar_flare_of_2021_october_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_data-constrained_magnetohydrodynamic_simulation_of_the_x1.0_solar_flare_of_2021_october_28/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daiki Yamasaki
The solar active region NOAA 12887 produced a strong X1.0 flare on 2021 October 28, which exhibits X-shaped flare ribbons and a circle-shaped erupting filament. To understand the eruption process with these characteristics, we conducted a data-constrained magnetohydrodynamics simulation using a nonlinear force-free field of the active region about an hour before the flare as the initial condition. Our simulation reproduces the filament eruption observed in the Ha images of GONG and the 304 angstrom images of SDO/AIA and suggests that two mechanisms can possibly contribute to the magnetic eruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Simulation of Solar Magnetic Flux Emergence Using the AMR--CESE--MHD Code</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulation_of_solar_magnetic_flux_emergence_using_the_amr--cese--mhd_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulation_of_solar_magnetic_flux_emergence_using_the_amr--cese--mhd_code/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhipeng Liu
Magnetic flux emergence from the solar interior to the atmosphere is believed to be a key process of formation of solar active regions and driving solar eruptions. Due to the limited capability of observation, the flux emergence process is commonly studied using numerical simulations. In this paper, we developed a numerical model to simulate the emergence of a twisted magnetic flux tube from the convection zone to the corona using the AMR&amp;ndash;CESE&amp;ndash;MHD code, which is based on the conservation-element solution-element method with adaptive mesh refinement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of LBT atmospheric and turbulence conditions in the context of ALTA project</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_lbt_atmospheric_and_turbulence_conditions_in_the_context_of_alta_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterization_of_lbt_atmospheric_and_turbulence_conditions_in_the_context_of_alta_project/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Turchi
ALTA project has been active since 2016, providing, at LBT observatory site, forecasts of atmospheric parameters, such as temperature, wind speed and direction, relative humidity and precipitable water vapor, and optical turbulence parameters, such as seeing, wavefront coherence time and isoplanatic angle with the final goal to support nightly the science operation of the LBT. Besides to the forecasts, during the years ALTA has been collecting statistics on the atmospheric conditions which can be used to draw a very accurate characterization of the climatology of the telescope site located on top of Mount Graham, Arizona.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flare Duty Cycle of Gamma-Ray Blazars and Implications for High-Energy Neutrino Emission</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flare_duty_cycle_of_gamma-ray_blazars_and_implications_for_high-energy_neutrino_emission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flare_duty_cycle_of_gamma-ray_blazars_and_implications_for_high-energy_neutrino_emission/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kenji Yoshida
Gamma-ray flares of blazars may be accompanied by high-energy neutrinos due to interactions of high-energy cosmic rays in the jet with photons, as suggested by the detection of the high-energy neutrino IceCube-170922A during a major gamma-ray flare from blazar TXS 0506+056 at the $\sim3\sigma$ significance level. In this work, we present a statistical study of gamma-ray emission from blazars to constrain the contribution of gamma-ray flares to their neutrino output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-surface Plasma Flows and the Flare Productivity of Solar Active Regions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-surface_plasma_flows_and_the_flare_productivity_of_solar_active_regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sub-surface_plasma_flows_and_the_flare_productivity_of_solar_active_regions/</guid>
      <description>First author: B Lekshmi
The extreme space weather conditions resulting from high energetic events likes solar flares and Coronal Mass Ejections (CMEs) demand for reliable space weather forecasting. The magnetic flux tubes while rising through the convection zone gets twisted by the turbulent plasma flows, energizing the system and resulting in flares. We investigate the relationship between the subsurface plasma flows associated with flaring active regions and their surface magnetic flux and current helicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Outbursts in the Ground-Based Photometry of 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_outbursts_in_the_ground-based_photometry_of_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_outbursts_in_the_ground-based_photometry_of_67p_churyumov-gerasimenko/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Gardener
67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko is a Jupiter-family comet that was the target of the Rosetta mission, the first mission to successfully orbit and land a probe on a comet. This mission was accompanied by a large ground-based observing campaign. We have developed a pipeline to calibrate and measure photometry of comet 67P during its 2016 perihelion passage, making use of all visible wavelength broadband imaging collected across a wide range of facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The thermonuclear X-ray bursts of 4U 1730-22</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_thermonuclear_x-ray_bursts_of_4u_1730-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_thermonuclear_x-ray_bursts_of_4u_1730-22/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Bult
We present observations of the historic transient 4U 1730-22 as observed with the Neutron Star Interior Composition Explorer (NICER). After remaining in quiescence since its 1972 discovery, this X-ray binary showed renewed outburst activity in 2021 and 2022. We observed 4U 1730-22 extensively with NICER, detecting a total of 17 thermonuclear X-ray bursts. From a spectroscopic analysis, we find that these X-ray bursts can be divided into a group of bright and weak bursts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Testing of a 3U CubeSat to Test the In-situ Vetoing for the $ν$SOL Solar Neutrino Detector</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/design_and_testing_of_a_3u_cubesat_to_test_the_in-situ_vetoing_for_the_%CE%BDsol_solar_neutrino_detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/design_and_testing_of_a_3u_cubesat_to_test_the_in-situ_vetoing_for_the_%CE%BDsol_solar_neutrino_detector/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jonathan Folkerts
For years, earth-based neutrino detectors have been run and operated to detect the elusive neutrino. These have historically been enormous underground detectors. The neutrino Solar Orbiting Laboratory ($\nu$SOL) project is working to design a technical demonstration to show that a much smaller neutrino detector can be operated in near-solar environments for a future spaceflight mission. At a closest approach of 3 solar radii, there is a ten thousand-fold increase in the neutrino flux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-emergence Signatures Of Horizontal Divergent Flows In Solar Active Regions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pre-emergence_signatures_of_horizontal_divergent_flows_in_solar_active_regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/pre-emergence_signatures_of_horizontal_divergent_flows_in_solar_active_regions/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Rees-Crockford
Solar active regions (ARs) play a fundamental role in driving many of the geo-effective eruptions which propagate into the Solar System. However, we are still unable to consistently predict where and when ARs will occur across the solar disk by identifying pre-emergence signatures in observables such as the Doppler velocity (without using Helioseismic methods). Here we aim to determine the earliest time at which pre-emergence signatures, specifically the Horizontal Divergent Flow (HDF), can be confidently detected using data from the Solar Dynamics Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Helioseismic and Magnetic Imager (SDO/HMI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intranight optical variability of low-mass Active Galactic Nuclei: A Pointer to blazar-like activity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intranight_optical_variability_of_low-mass_active_galactic_nuclei_a_pointer_to_blazar-like_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intranight_optical_variability_of_low-mass_active_galactic_nuclei_a_pointer_to_blazar-like_activity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gopal-Krishna
This study aims to characterise, for the first time, intranight optical variability (INOV) of low-mass active galactic nuclei (LMAGN) which host a black hole (BH) of mass $M_{BH} \sim 10^6 M_{\odot}$, i.e., even less massive than the Galactic centre black hole Sgr A* and 2-3 orders of magnitude below the supermassive black holes (SMBH, $M_{BH}$ $\sim$ $10^8 - 10^9 M_{\odot}$) which are believed to power quasars. Thus, LMAGN are a crucial subclass of AGN filling the wide gap between SMBH and stellar-mass BHs of Galactic X-ray binaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accretion and Host-Galaxy Properties of 14 New &#34;Changing-Look&#34; Active Galactic Nuclei Identified from the SDSS-V Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion_and_host-galaxy_properties_of_14_new_changing-look_active_galactic_nuclei_identified_from_the_sdss-v_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/accretion_and_host-galaxy_properties_of_14_new_changing-look_active_galactic_nuclei_identified_from_the_sdss-v_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Wang
The widely accepted active galactic nucleus (AGN) paradigm has been recently challenged by the discovery of the so-called changing-look&#39;&#39; (CL) phenomenon characterized by spectral-type transitions. By comparing the SDSS-V and SDSS DR16 spectroscopic datasets, here we report the identification of 14 new CL-AGNs (redshift $z&amp;lt;0.5$) exhibiting spectral-type changes on a timescale of $\sim 10$yr. Follow-up spectroscopy was conducted with the Lick Shane 3m and Keck 10m telescopes for three of the objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragment Dynamics in Active Asteroid 331P/Gibbs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fragment_dynamics_in_active_asteroid_331p_gibbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fragment_dynamics_in_active_asteroid_331p_gibbs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Man-To Hui
We present a dynamical analysis of the fragmented active asteroid 331P/Gibbs. Using archival images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope from 2015 to 2018, we measured the astrometry of the primary and the three brightest (presumably the largest) components. Conventional orbit determination revealed a high-degree of orbital similarity between the components. We then applied a fragmentation model to fit the astrometry, obtaining key parameters including the fragmentation epochs and separation velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun-as-a-star Analyses of Various Solar Active Events Using H$α$ Spectral Images Taken by SMART/SDDI</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sun-as-a-star_analyses_of_various_solar_active_events_using_h%CE%B1_spectral_images_taken_by_smart_sddi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sun-as-a-star_analyses_of_various_solar_active_events_using_h%CE%B1_spectral_images_taken_by_smart_sddi/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takato Otsu
Sun-as-a-star analyses, in which observational data is spatially integrated, are useful for interpreting stellar data. For future applications to stellar observations, we performed Sun-as-a-star analyses of H$\alpha$ spectra for various active events on the Sun, not only for flares and filament eruptions/surges on the solar disk, but also for eruptions of off limb prominences using H$\alpha$ spectral images taken by the Solar Magnetic Activity Research Telescope / Solar Dynamics Doppler Imager (SMART/SDDI) at Hida Observatory, Kyoto University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and Differential Emission Measure Profiles in Turbulent Solar Active Region Loops</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temperature_and_differential_emission_measure_profiles_in_turbulent_solar_active_region_loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/temperature_and_differential_emission_measure_profiles_in_turbulent_solar_active_region_loops/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Gordon Emslie
We examine the temperature structure of static coronal active region loops in regimes where thermal conductive transport is driven by Coulomb collisions, by turbulent scattering, or by a combination of the two. (In the last case collisional scattering dominates the heat transport at lower levels in the loop where temperatures are low and densities are high, while turbulent scattering dominates the heat transport at higher temperatures/lower densities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relation between the Optical eii Emission and the Dimensionless Accretion Rate for Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_relation_between_the_optical_%5Cfeii_emission_and_the_dimensionless_accretion_rate_for_active_galactic_nuclei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_relation_between_the_optical_%5Cfeii_emission_and_the_dimensionless_accretion_rate_for_active_galactic_nuclei/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liu Y. S.
It was suggested that the prominent feature of the optical Fe II emission has a connection with the accretion process in active galactic nuclei (AGN). For a large sample of 4037 quasars ($z &amp;lt; 0.8$) with measured $\rm H\beta$ line dispersion ($\sigma_{\rm H\beta}$) selected from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) and 120 compiled reverberation-mapped (RM) AGN, we use $\sigma_{\rm H\beta}$ and the extended $R_{\rm BLR}-L_{\rm 5100}$ relation to calculate supermassive black holes masses ($M_{\rm BH}$) from the single-epoch spectra for the SDSS subsample, and $\sigma_{\rm H\beta}$ from the mean spectra for the RM subsample.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
