<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Active galactic nucleus on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/active-galactic-nucleus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Data-constrained Magnetohydrodynamic Simulation of the X1.0 Solar Flare of 2021 October 28</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_data-constrained_magnetohydrodynamic_simulation_of_the_x1.0_solar_flare_of_2021_october_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/a_data-constrained_magnetohydrodynamic_simulation_of_the_x1.0_solar_flare_of_2021_october_28/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daiki Yamasaki
The solar active region NOAA 12887 produced a strong X1.0 flare on 2021 October 28, which exhibits X-shaped flare ribbons and a circle-shaped erupting filament. To understand the eruption process with these characteristics, we conducted a data-constrained magnetohydrodynamics simulation using a nonlinear force-free field of the active region about an hour before the flare as the initial condition. Our simulation reproduces the filament eruption observed in the Ha images of GONG and the 304 angstrom images of SDO/AIA and suggests that two mechanisms can possibly contribute to the magnetic eruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Simulation of Solar Magnetic Flux Emergence Using the AMR--CESE--MHD Code</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulation_of_solar_magnetic_flux_emergence_using_the_amr--cese--mhd_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/numerical_simulation_of_solar_magnetic_flux_emergence_using_the_amr--cese--mhd_code/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhipeng Liu
Magnetic flux emergence from the solar interior to the atmosphere is believed to be a key process of formation of solar active regions and driving solar eruptions. Due to the limited capability of observation, the flux emergence process is commonly studied using numerical simulations. In this paper, we developed a numerical model to simulate the emergence of a twisted magnetic flux tube from the convection zone to the corona using the AMR&amp;ndash;CESE&amp;ndash;MHD code, which is based on the conservation-element solution-element method with adaptive mesh refinement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
