<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>most recent update (Thu Jan 5 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-thu-jan-5-2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in most recent update (Thu Jan 5 2023) on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/tags/most-recent-update-thu-jan-5-2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength Scrutiny of X-ray Sources in Dwarf Galaxies: ULXs versus AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.01317/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2301.01317/</guid>
      <description>Erica Thygesen
Owing to their quiet evolutionary histories, nearby dwarf galaxies (stellar masses $M_\star \lesssim 3 \times 10^9 M_\odot$) have the potential to teach us about the mechanism(s) that &amp;amp;#39;seeded&amp;amp;#39; the growth of supermassive black holes, and also how the first stellar mass black holes formed and interacted with their environments. Here, we present high spatial-resolution observations of three dwarf galaxies in the X-ray (Chandra), the optical/near-infrared (Hubble Space Telescope), and the radio (Karl G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Method to Determine X-ray Luminosity Functions of AGN and their Evolution with Redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_to_determine_x-ray_luminosity_functions_of_agn_and_their_evolution_with_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_to_determine_x-ray_luminosity_functions_of_agn_and_their_evolution_with_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ahlam Alqasim
Almost all massive galaxies today are understood to contain supermassive black holes (SMBH) at their centers. SMBHs grew by accreting material from their surroundings, emitting X-rays as they did so. X-ray Luminosity Functions (XLFs) of Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) have been extensively studied in order to understand the AGN population&amp;rsquo;s cosmological properties and evolution. We present a new fixed rest-frame method to achieve a more accurate study of the AGN XLF evolution over cosmic time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The vertex coordinates of the Galaxy&#39;s stellar systems according to the Gaia DR3 catalogue</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_vertex_coordinates_of_the_galaxys_stellar_systems_according_to_the_gaia_dr3_catalogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_vertex_coordinates_of_the_galaxys_stellar_systems_according_to_the_gaia_dr3_catalogue/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. M. Dmytrenko
We present the results of determining the coordinates of the vertices of various stellar systems, the centroids of which are located in the Galactic plane. To do this, the positions, parallaxes, proper motions, and radial velocities of red giants and subgiants contained in the Gaia DR3 catalogue have been used. When determining the components of the deformation velocity tensors in local coordinate systems, we found the coordinates of the vertices of the stellar systems under study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Neural Network Approach to identify Stars and AGNs observed by XMM Newton</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_neural_network_approach_to_identify_stars_and_agns_observed_by_xmm_newton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesian_neural_network_approach_to_identify_stars_and_agns_observed_by_xmm_newton/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sarvesh Gharat
In today&amp;rsquo;s era, a tremendous amount of data is generated by different observatories and manual classification of data is something which is practically impossible. Hence, to classify and categorize the objects there are multiple machine and deep learning techniques used. However, these predictions are overconfident and won&amp;rsquo;t be able to identify if the data actually belongs to the trained class. To solve this major problem of overconfidence, in this study we propose a novel Bayesian Neural Network which randomly samples weights from a distribution as opposed to the fixed weight vector considered in the frequentist approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broad emission lines in optical spectra of hot dust-obscured galaxies can contribute significantly to JWST/NIRCam photometry</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/broad_emission_lines_in_optical_spectra_of_hot_dust-obscured_galaxies_can_contribute_significantly_to_jwst_nircam_photometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/broad_emission_lines_in_optical_spectra_of_hot_dust-obscured_galaxies_can_contribute_significantly_to_jwst_nircam_photometry/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jed McKinney
Selecting the first galaxies at z&amp;gt;7-10 from JWST surveys is complicated by z&amp;lt;6 contaminants with degenerate photometry. For example, strong optical nebular emission lines at z&amp;lt;6 may mimic JWST/NIRCam photometry of z&amp;gt;7-10 Lyman Break Galaxies (LBGs). Dust-obscured 3&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;6 galaxies in particular are potentially important contaminants, and their faint rest-optical spectra have been historically difficult to observe. A lack of optical emission line and continuum measures for 3&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;6 dusty galaxies now makes it difficult to test their expected JWST/NIRCam photometry for degenerate solutions with NIRCam dropouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEERS Key Paper IV: Galaxies at $4 &lt; z &lt; 9$ are Bluer than They Appear -- Characterizing Galaxy Stellar Populations from Rest-Frame $\sim 1$ micron Imaging</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ceers_key_paper_iv_galaxies_at__4__z__9__are_bluer_than_they_appear_--_characterizing_galaxy_stellar_populations_from_rest-frame___sim_1__micron_imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ceers_key_paper_iv_galaxies_at__4__z__9__are_bluer_than_they_appear_--_characterizing_galaxy_stellar_populations_from_rest-frame___sim_1__micron_imaging/</guid>
      <description>First author: Casey Papovich
We present results from the Cosmic Evolution Early Release Survey (CEERS) on the stellar-population parameters for 28 galaxies with redshifts $4&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;9$ using imaging data from the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) Mid-Infrared Instrument (MIRI) combined with data from the Hubble Space Telescope and the Spitzer Space Telescope. The JWST/MIRI 5.6 and 7.7 $\mu$m data extend the coverage of the rest-frame spectral-energy distribution (SED) to nearly 1 micron for galaxies in this redshift range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven photometric redshift estimation from type Ia supernovae light curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_photometric_redshift_estimation_from_type_ia_supernovae_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_photometric_redshift_estimation_from_type_ia_supernovae_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Felipe M F de Oliveira
Redshift measurement has always been a constant need in modern astronomy and cosmology. And as new surveys have been providing an immense amount of data on astronomical objects, the need to process such data automatically proves to be increasingly necessary. In this article, we use simulated data from the Dark Energy Survey, and from a pipeline originally created to classify supernovae, we developed a linear regression algorithm optimized through novel automated machine learning (AutoML) frameworks achieving an error score better than ordinary data pre-processing methods when compared with other modern algorithms (such as XGBOOST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of dwarf galaxies in f(R) gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.02306/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2210.02306/</guid>
      <description>Ivan de Martino
We use the kinematic data of the stars in eight dwarf spheroidal galaxies to assess whether $f(R)$ gravity can fit the observed profiles of the line-of-sight velocity dispersion of these systems without resorting to dark matter. Our model assumes that each galaxy is spherically symmetric and has a constant velocity anisotropy parameter $β$ and constant mass-to-light ratio consistent with stellar population synthesis models. We solve the spherical Jeans equation that includes the Yukawa-like gravitational potential appearing in the weak field limit of $f(R)$ gravity, and a Plummer density profile for the stellar distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eDIG-CHANGES I: Extended Hα Emission from the Extraplanar Diffuse Ionized Gas (eDIG) around CHANG-ES Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/edig-changes_i_extended_h%CE%B1_emission_from_the_extraplanar_diffuse_ionized_gas_edig_around_chang-es_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/edig-changes_i_extended_h%CE%B1_emission_from_the_extraplanar_diffuse_ionized_gas_edig_around_chang-es_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Li-Yuan Lu
The extraplanar diffuse ionized gas (eDIG) represents the cool/warm ionized gas reservoir around galaxies. We present a spatial analysis of H$\alpha$ images of 22 nearby edge-on spiral galaxies from the CHANG-ES sample (the eDIG-CHANGES project), taken with the APO 3.5m telescope, in order to study their eDIG. We conduct an exponential fit to the vertical intensity profiles of the sample galaxies, of which 16 can be decomposed into a thin disk plus an extended thick disk component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Surface-Brightness Galaxies are missing in the observed Stellar Mass Function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-surface-brightness_galaxies_are_missing_in_the_observed_stellar_mass_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/low-surface-brightness_galaxies_are_missing_in_the_observed_stellar_mass_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Juhan Kim
We investigate the impact of the surface brightness (SB) limit on the galaxy stellar mass functions (GSMFs) using mock surveys generated from the Horizon Run 5 (HR5) simulation. We compare the stellar-to-halo-mass relation, GSMF, and size-stellar mass relation of the HR5 galaxies with empirical data and other cosmological simulations. The mean SB of simulated galaxies are computed using their effective radii, luminosities, and colors. To examine the cosmic SB dimming effect, we compute $k$-corrections from the spectral energy distributions of individual simulated galaxy at each redshift, apply the $k$-corrections to the galaxies, and conduct mock surveys based on the various SB limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the impact of the AGN and the torus properties on the evolution of spiral galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_the_agn_and_the_torus_properties_on_the_evolution_of_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_the_agn_and_the_torus_properties_on_the_evolution_of_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. A. Abdulrahman
For spiral galaxies, the active galactic nucleus (AGN) and some physical parameters that concern the host galaxy such as spiral arm radius and density can play an important role in the morphological evolution of these galaxies. Considering the gravitational effect of the central black hole as a feeding mechanism, the gas flows from spiral arms to the accretion disk. Accordingly, we constructed our approach and derived an equation for the AGN luminosity that depends on parameters such as the black hole mass and the spiral arm density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The physical and chemical processes in protoplanetary disks: constraints on the composition of comets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_and_chemical_processes_in_protoplanetary_disks_constraints_on_the_composition_of_comets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_physical_and_chemical_processes_in_protoplanetary_disks_constraints_on_the_composition_of_comets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yuri Aikawa
We review the recent observations of protoplanetary disks together with relevant theoretical studies with an emphasis on the evolution of volatiles. In the last several years Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) provided evidence of grain growth, gas-dust decoupling, and sub-structures such as rings and gaps in the dust continuum. Molecular line observations revealed radial and vertical distributions of molecular abundances and also provided significant constraints on the gas dynamics such as turbulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Simulations of Two-Component Wave Dark Matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_simulations_of_two-component_wave_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_simulations_of_two-component_wave_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hsinhao Huang
Wave (fuzzy) dark matter consists of ultralight bosons ($m \sim 10^{-22} \textrm{&amp;ndash;} 10^{-20},{\rm eV}$), featuring a compact solitonic core at the centre of a granular halo. Here we extend this model to a two-component wave dark matter, with distinct particle masses and coupled only through gravity, and investigate the resulting soliton-halo structure via cosmological simulations. Specifically, we assume wave dark matter contains $75$ per cent major component and $25$ per cent minor component, fix the major-component particle mass to $m_{\rm major}=1\times10^{-22},{\rm eV}$, and explore two different minor-component particle masses with $m_{\rm major}:m_{\rm minor}=3:1$ and $1:3$, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New description of the scaling evolution of the cosmological magneto-hydrodynamic system</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_description_of_the_scaling_evolution_of_the_cosmological_magneto-hydrodynamic_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/new_description_of_the_scaling_evolution_of_the_cosmological_magneto-hydrodynamic_system/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fumio Uchida
We present a new description of cosmological evolution of the primordial magnetic field under the condition that it is non-helical and its energy density is larger than the kinetic energy density. We argue that the evolution can be described by four different regimes, according to whether the decay dynamics is linear or not, and whether the dominant dissipation term is the shear viscosity or the drag force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The $γ$-ray deposition histories of Calcium-rich supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the__%CE%B3_-ray_deposition_histories_of_calcium-rich_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the__%CE%B3_-ray_deposition_histories_of_calcium-rich_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amir Sharon
Calcium-rich supernovae (Ca-rich SNe) are faint, rapidly evolving transients whose progenitor system is yet to be determined. We derive the $\gamma$-ray deposition histories of five Ca-rich SNe from the literature in order to place constraints on possible progenitor systems. We find that the $ \gamma $-ray escape time, $ t_0 $, of the Ca-rich SNe sample is $\approx35$-$65 ,\rm{d}$, within the unoccupied region between Type Ia SNe and stripped envelope supernovae (SESNe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 3-Dimension Model of Volcanism Volatiles Contribution on Atmospheric Chemical Abundance of Habitable Planets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_3-dimension_model_of_volcanism_volatiles_contribution_on_atmospheric_chemical_abundance_of_habitable_planets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_3-dimension_model_of_volcanism_volatiles_contribution_on_atmospheric_chemical_abundance_of_habitable_planets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zihan Huang
The volcanism plays an important part in mass exchange circle to bring matter from core of planet to atmosphere. Thus, it is a possible method to research the change of elements abundance in atmosphere by modeling the process of volatiles from volcanism get through and mix in atmosphere, which is the focused point of this article. This article penetrates from the generation of volatiles, talks the species, mass, and mole fractions of different typical elements in magma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Panchromatic Study of Massive Stars in the Extremely Metal-Poor Local Group Dwarf Galaxy Leo A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.14349/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2211.14349/</guid>
      <description>Maude Gull
We characterize massive stars (M&amp;amp;gt;8 M_sun) in the nearby (D~0.8 Mpc) extremely metal-poor (Z~5% Z_sun) galaxy Leo A using Hubble Space Telescope ultra-violet (UV), optical, and near-infrared (NIR) imaging along with Keck/LRIS and MMT/Binospec optical spectroscopy for 18 main sequence OB stars. We find that: (a) 12 of our 18 stars show emission lines, despite not being associated with an H II region, suggestive of stellar activity (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overmassive black holes in dwarf galaxies out to z∼0.9 in the VIPERS survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.14057/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.14057/</guid>
      <description>M. Mezcua,
Supermassive black holes (SMBHs) are thought to originate from early Universe seed black holes of mass $M_\mathrm{BH} \sim 10^2$-10$^5$ M$_{\odot}$ and grown through cosmic time. Such seeds could be powering the active galactic nuclei (AGN) found in today&amp;amp;#39;s dwarf galaxies. However, probing a connection between the early seeds and local SMBHs has not yet been observationally possible. Massive black holes hosted in dwarf galaxies at intermediate redshifts, on the other hand, may represent the evolved counterparts of the seeds formed at very early times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overmassive black holes in dwarf galaxies out to z$\sim$0.9 in the VIPERS survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/overmassive_black_holes_in_dwarf_galaxies_out_to_z__sim_0.9_in_the_vipers_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/overmassive_black_holes_in_dwarf_galaxies_out_to_z__sim_0.9_in_the_vipers_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Mezcua
Supermassive black holes (SMBHs) are thought to originate from early Universe seed black holes of mass $M_\mathrm{BH} \sim 10^2$-10$^5$ M${\odot}$ and grown through cosmic time. Such seeds could be powering the active galactic nuclei (AGN) found in today&amp;rsquo;s dwarf galaxies. However, probing a connection between the early seeds and local SMBHs has not yet been observationally possible. Massive black holes hosted in dwarf galaxies at intermediate redshifts, on the other hand, may represent the evolved counterparts of the seeds formed at very early times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiative coupling the easy way: Using transfer coefficients to model series-connected multi-junction solar cells</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.13920/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/arxiv.2212.13920/</guid>
      <description>Rune Strandberg
When the quality of multijunction solar cells becomes sufficiently high, radiative exchange of photons between cells has to be taken into account to properly model these devices. In this work it is shown how this radiative coupling can be accounted for in series connected multi-junction solar cells by constants called transfer coefficients. Under the assumption that the exchanged radiation only travels one way, from higher to lower band gaps, the transfer coefficients allows the relation between the voltage and current of the device to be expressed by a convenient mathematical expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Cluster Formation and Survival in the First Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_cluster_formation_and_survival_in_the_first_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/star_cluster_formation_and_survival_in_the_first_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fred Angelo Batan Garcia
Using radiation-hydrodynamic cosmological simulations, we present a detailed ($0.1$ pc resolution), physically motivated portrait of a typical-mass dwarf galaxy before the epoch of reionization, resolving the formation and evolution of star clusters into individual $10:\mathrm{M_{\odot}}$ star particles. In the rest-frame UV, the galaxy has an irregular morphology with no bulge or galactic disk, dominated by light emitted from numerous, compact, and gravitationally-bound star clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential signature of a quadrupolar Hubble expansion in Pantheon&#43; supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_signature_of_a_quadrupolar_hubble_expansion_in_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_signature_of_a_quadrupolar_hubble_expansion_in_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica A. Cowell
The assumption of isotropy &amp;ndash; that the Universe looks the same in all directions on large scales &amp;ndash; is fundamental to the standard cosmological model. This model forms the building blocks of essentially all of our cosmological knowledge to date. It is therefore critical to empirically test in which regimes its core assumptions hold. Anisotropies in the cosmic expansion are expected on small scales due to nonlinear structures in the late Universe, however, the extent to which these anisotropies might impact our low-redshift observations remains to be fully tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Analysis of the Chemical Compositions of Gaia-Enceladus/Sausage and Milky Way Satellites using APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_comparative_analysis_of_the_chemical_compositions_of_gaia-enceladus_sausage_and_milky_way_satellites_using_apogee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_comparative_analysis_of_the_chemical_compositions_of_gaia-enceladus_sausage_and_milky_way_satellites_using_apogee/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Fernandes
We use data from the 17th data release of the Apache Point Observatory Galactic Evolution Experiment (APOGEE 2) to contrast the chemical composition of the recently discovered Gaia Enceladus/Sausage system (GE/S) to those of ten Milky Way (MW) dwarf satellite galaxies: LMC, SMC, Bo&amp;quot;otes I, Carina, Draco, Fornax, Sagittarius, Sculptor, Sextans and Ursa Minor. Our main focus is on the distributions of the stellar populations of those systems in the $[Mg/Fe]$-$[Fe/H]$ and $[Mg/Mn]$-$[Al/Fe]$ planes, which are commonly employed in the literature for chemical diagnosis and where dwarf galaxies can be distinguished from in situ populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Cosmological Tensions by Non-Local Gravity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/addressing_cosmological_tensions_by_non-local_gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/addressing_cosmological_tensions_by_non-local_gravity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Filippo Bouchè
Alternative cosmological models have been under deep scrutiny in recent years, aiming to address the main shortcomings of the $\Lambda$CDM model. Moreover, as the accuracy of cosmological surveys improved, new tensions have risen between the model-dependent analysis of the Cosmic Microwave Background and lower redshift probes. Within this framework, we review two quantum-inspired non-locally extended theories of gravity, whose main cosmological feature is a geometrically driven accelerated expansion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGN Feedback Through Multiple Jet Cycles in the Seyfert Galaxy NGC 2639</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_through_multiple_jet_cycles_in_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc_2639/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/agn_feedback_through_multiple_jet_cycles_in_the_seyfert_galaxy_ngc_2639/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vaishnav V. Rao
The Seyfert galaxy NGC 2639 is known to exhibit three episodes of AGN jet/lobe activity. We present here the upgraded Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope (uGMRT) 735 MHz image of NGC 2639 showing a fourth episode as witnessed by the discovery of $\sim9$ kpc radio lobes misaligned with the previously known $\sim1.5$ kpc, $\sim360$ parsec, and $\sim3$ parsec jet features detected through the Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array (VLA) and the Very Long Baseline Array (VLBA), respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brightest Cluster Galaxy Formation in the z=4.3 Protocluster SPT2349-56: Discovery of a Radio-Loud AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/brightest_cluster_galaxy_formation_in_the_z4.3_protocluster_spt2349-56_discovery_of_a_radio-loud_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/brightest_cluster_galaxy_formation_in_the_z4.3_protocluster_spt2349-56_discovery_of_a_radio-loud_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Scott C. Chapman
We have observed the z=4.3 protocluster SPT2349-56 with ATCA with the aim of detecting radio-loud active galactic nuclei (AGN) amongst the ~30 submillimeter galaxies identified in the structure. We detect the central complex of SMGs at 2.2,GHz with a luminosity of L_2.2=(4.42pm0.56)x10^{25} W/Hz. The ASKAP also detects the source at 888 MHz, constraining the radio spectral index to alpha=-1.6pm0.3, consistent with ATCA non-detections at 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological constraints from HSC survey first-year data using deep learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_hsc_survey_first-year_data_using_deep_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological_constraints_from_hsc_survey_first-year_data_using_deep_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tianhuan Lu
We present cosmological constraints from the Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) first-year weak lensing shear catalogue using convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and conventional summary statistics. We crop 19 $3\times3,\mathrm{{deg}^2}$ sub-fields from the first-year area, divide the galaxies with redshift $0.3\le z\le1.5$ into four equally-spaced redshift bins, and perform tomographic analyses. We develop a pipeline to generate simulated convergence maps from cosmological $N$-body simulations, where we account for effects such as intrinsic alignments (IAs), baryons, photometric redshift errors, and point spread function errors, to match characteristics of the real catalogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for AGN-Regulated Cooling in Clusters at $z \sim 1.4$: A Multi-Wavelength View of SPT-CL J0607-4448</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_agn-regulated_cooling_in_clusters_at__z__sim_1.4__a_multi-wavelength_view_of_spt-cl_j0607-4448/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_agn-regulated_cooling_in_clusters_at__z__sim_1.4__a_multi-wavelength_view_of_spt-cl_j0607-4448/</guid>
      <description>First author: Megan Masterson
We present a multi-wavelength analysis of the galaxy cluster SPT-CL J0607-4448 (SPT0607), which is one of the most distant clusters discovered by the South Pole Telescope (SPT) at $z=1.4010\pm0.0028$. The high-redshift cluster shows clear signs of being relaxed with well-regulated feedback from the active galactic nucleus (AGN) in the brightest cluster galaxy (BCG). Using Chandra X-ray data, we construct thermodynamic profiles and determine the properties of the intracluster medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From dark matter halos to pre-stellar cores: High resolution follow-up of cosmological Lyman-Werner simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_dark_matter_halos_to_pre-stellar_cores_high_resolution_follow-up_of_cosmological_lyman-werner_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/from_dark_matter_halos_to_pre-stellar_cores_high_resolution_follow-up_of_cosmological_lyman-werner_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lewis R. Prole
Molecular hydrogen allows cooling in primordial gas, facilitating its collapse into Population III stars within primordial halos. Lyman-Werner (LW) radiation from these stars can escape the halo and delay further star formation by destroying H$2$ in other halos. As cosmological simulations show that increasing the background LW field strength increases the average halo mass required for star formation, we perform follow-up simulations of selected halos to investigate the knock-on effects this has on the Population III IMF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST high redshift galaxy observations have a strong tension with Planck CMB measurements</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_high_redshift_galaxy_observations_have_a_strong_tension_with_planck_cmb_measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_high_redshift_galaxy_observations_have_a_strong_tension_with_planck_cmb_measurements/</guid>
      <description>First author: Deng Wang
JWST high redshift galaxy observations predict a higher star formation efficiency than the standard cosmology does, which poses a new tension to $\Lambda$CDM. We find that the situation is worse than expected. The true situation is that the Planck CMB measurement has a strong tension with JWST high redshift galaxy observations. Specifically, we make a trial to alleviate this tension by considering alternative cosmological models including dark matter-baryon interaction, $f(R)$ gravity and dynamical dark energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Curves of Type IIP Supernovae from Neutrino-driven Explosions of Red Supergiants Obtained by a Semi-analytic Approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_type_iip_supernovae_from_neutrino-driven_explosions_of_red_supergiants_obtained_by_a_semi-analytic_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_type_iip_supernovae_from_neutrino-driven_explosions_of_red_supergiants_obtained_by_a_semi-analytic_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuai Zha
Type IIP supernovae (SNe IIP) mark the explosive death of red supergiants (RSGs), evolved massive stars with an extended hydrogen envelope. They are the most common supernova type and allow for benchmarking of supernova explosion models by statistical comparison to observed population properties rather than comparing individual models and events. We construct a large synthetic set of SNe IIP light curves (LCs) using the radiation hydrodynamics code \texttt{SNEC} and explosion energies and nickel masses obtained from an efficient semi-analytic model for two different sets of stellar progenitor models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength Scrutiny of X-ray Sources in Dwarf Galaxies: ULXs versus AGN</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_scrutiny_of_x-ray_sources_in_dwarf_galaxies_ulxs_versus_agn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_scrutiny_of_x-ray_sources_in_dwarf_galaxies_ulxs_versus_agn/</guid>
      <description>First author: Erica Thygesen
Owing to their quiet evolutionary histories, nearby dwarf galaxies (stellar masses $M_\star \lesssim 3 \times 10^9 M_\odot$) have the potential to teach us about the mechanism(s) that &amp;lsquo;seeded&amp;rsquo; the growth of supermassive black holes, and also how the first stellar mass black holes formed and interacted with their environments. Here, we present high spatial-resolution observations of three dwarf galaxies in the X-ray (Chandra), the optical/near-infrared (Hubble Space Telescope), and the radio (Karl G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-sky performance of new 90 GHz detectors for the Cosmology Large Angular Scale Surveyor (CLASS)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on-sky_performance_of_new_90_ghz_detectors_for_the_cosmology_large_angular_scale_surveyor_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on-sky_performance_of_new_90_ghz_detectors_for_the_cosmology_large_angular_scale_surveyor_class/</guid>
      <description>First author: Carolina Núñez
The Cosmology Large Angular Scale Surveyor (CLASS) is a polarization-sensitive telescope array located at an altitude of 5,200 m in the Chilean Atacama Desert and designed to measure the polarized Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) over large angular scales. The CLASS array is currently observing with three telescopes covering four frequency bands: one at 40 GHz (Q); one at 90 GHz (W1); and one dichroic system at 150/220 GHz (HF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHANGS-JWST First Results: Mapping the 3.3 micron Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbon Vibrational Band in Nearby Galaxies with NIRCam Medium Bands</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs-jwst_first_results_mapping_the_3.3_micron_polycyclic_aromatic_hydrocarbon_vibrational_band_in_nearby_galaxies_with_nircam_medium_bands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs-jwst_first_results_mapping_the_3.3_micron_polycyclic_aromatic_hydrocarbon_vibrational_band_in_nearby_galaxies_with_nircam_medium_bands/</guid>
      <description>First author: Karin Sandstrom
We present maps of the 3.3 micron polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) emission feature in NGC 628, NGC 1365, and NGC 7496 as observed with the Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) imager on JWST from the PHANGS-JWST Cycle 1 Treasury project. We create maps that isolate the 3.3 micron PAH feature in the F335M filter (F335M${\rm PAH}$) using combinations of the F300M and F360M filters for removal of starlight continuum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primordial black holes, early galaxies, and antimatter in the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_black_holes_early_galaxies_and_antimatter_in_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/primordial_black_holes_early_galaxies_and_antimatter_in_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. D. Dolgov
Astronomical observations strongly incompatible with the canonical cosmological model are reviewed. In particular too early formation of galaxies, as discovered by HST and JWST, are discussed in detail. Other data revealing highly dense population of the very young universe with plethora of other different types of objects are presented. It is demonstrated that similar or maybe even more pronounced problems can be seen also in the present day universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three new spiral galaxies with active nuclei producing double radio lobes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_new_spiral_galaxies_with_active_nuclei_producing_double_radio_lobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_new_spiral_galaxies_with_active_nuclei_producing_double_radio_lobes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gao Xuyang
Double radio lobes are generally believed to be produced by active nuclei of elliptical galaxies. However, several double-lobed radio sources have been solidly found to be associated with spiral galaxies. By cross-matching $\sim9\times10^5$ spiral galaxies selected from the SDSS DR8 data with the full 1.4-GHz radio source catalogs of NVSS and FIRST, we identify three new spiral galaxies: J0326$-$0623, J1110+0321 and J1134+3046 that produce double radio lobes, in addition to five double-lobed spirals previously known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velocity waves in the Hubble diagram: signature of local galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/velocity_waves_in_the_hubble_diagram_signature_of_local_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/velocity_waves_in_the_hubble_diagram_signature_of_local_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jenny G. Sorce
The Universe expansion rate is modulated around local inhomogeneities due to their gravitational potential. Velocity waves are then observed around galaxy clusters in the Hubble diagram. This paper studies them in a ~738 Mpc wide, with 2048^3 particles, cosmological simulation of our cosmic environment (a.k.a. CLONE: Constrained LOcal &amp;amp; Nesting Environment Simulation). For the first time, the simulation shows that velocity waves that arise in the lines-of-sight of the most massive dark matter halos agree with those observed in local galaxy velocity catalogs in the lines-of-sight of Coma and several other local (Abell) clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
