<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A JWST Near- and Mid-Infrared Nebular Spectrum of the Type Ia Supernova 2021aefx</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_near-_and_mid-infrared_nebular_spectrum_of_the_type_ia_supernova_2021aefx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_near-_and_mid-infrared_nebular_spectrum_of_the_type_ia_supernova_2021aefx/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lindsey A. Kwok
We present JWST near- and mid-infrared spectroscopic observations of the nearby normal Type Ia supernova SN 2021aefx in the nebular phase at $+255$ days past maximum light. Our Near Infrared Spectrograph (NIRSpec) and Mid Infrared Instrument (MIRI) observations, combined with ground-based optical data from the South African Large Telescope (SALT), constitute the first complete optical $+$ NIR $+$ MIR nebular SN Ia spectrum covering 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-gas phases in supernova remnant IC 443: Mapping shocked H$_2$ with VLT/KMOS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-gas_phases_in_supernova_remnant_ic_443_mapping_shocked_h__2__with_vlt_kmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-gas_phases_in_supernova_remnant_ic_443_mapping_shocked_h__2__with_vlt_kmos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yunwei Deng
Supernovae and their remnants provide energetic feedback to the ambient interstellar medium (ISM), which is often distributed in multiple gas phases. Among them, warm molecular hydrogen (H$_2$) often dominates the cooling of the shocked molecular ISM, which has been observed with the H$_2$ emission lines at near-infrared wavelengths. Such studies, however, were either limited in narrow filter imaging or sparsely sampled mid-infrared spectroscopic observations with relatively poor angular resolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Rubin Observatory cadence choices on supernovae photometric classification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_rubin_observatory_cadence_choices_on_supernovae_photometric_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_rubin_observatory_cadence_choices_on_supernovae_photometric_classification/</guid>
      <description>First author: Catarina S. Alves
The Vera C. Rubin Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST) will discover an unprecedented number of supernovae (SNe), making spectroscopic classification for all the events infeasible. LSST will thus rely on photometric classification, whose accuracy depends on the not-yet-finalized LSST observing strategy. In this work, we analyze the impact of cadence choices on classification performance using simulated multi-band light curves. First, we simulate SNe with an LSST baseline cadence, a non-rolling cadence, and a presto-color cadence which observes each sky location three times per night instead of twice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$Hubble~Space~Telescope$ Reveals Spectacular Light Echoes Associated with the Stripped-envelope Supernova 2016adj in the Iconic Dust Lane of Centaurus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maximilian Stritzinger
We present a multi-band sequence of $Hubble~Space~Telescope$ images documenting the emergence and evolution of multiple light echoes (LEs) linked to the stripped-envelope supernova (SN) 2016adj located in the central dust-lane of Centaurus A. Following point-spread function subtraction, we identify the earliest LE emission associated with a SN at only $+$34 days (d) past the epoch of $B$-band maximum. Additional HST images extending through $+$578 d cover the evolution of LE1 taking the form of a ring, while images taken on $+$1991 d reveals not only LE1, but also segments of a new inner LE ring (LE2) as well as two additional outer LE rings (LE3 &amp;amp; LE4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of post-kick jets in core collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Noam Soker
I argue that the assumption that the jets that shape the axisymmetrical morphological features of core collapse supernova (CCSN) remnants are post-kick jets, i.e., the neutron star (NS) launches these jets after the explosion and after it acquired its natal kick velocity, leads to the conclusion that the pre-collapse cores of CCSN progenitors have sufficient angular momentum fluctuations to support jittering jets that explode the star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Type Iax Supernova 2019muj in the Late Phase: Existence, Nature and Origin of the Iron-rich Dense Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Type Iax Supernovae (SNe Iax) form a class of peculiar SNe Ia, whose early-phase spectra share main spectral line identifications with canonical SNe Ia but with higher ionization and much lower line velocities. Their late-time behaviors deviate from usual SNe Ia in many respects; SNe Iax keep showing photospheric spectra over several 100 days and the luminosity decline is very slow. In the present work, we study the late-time spectra of SN Iax 2019muj including a newly-presented spectrum at ~500 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Black-Hole Excision Scheme for General Relativistic Core-Collapse Supernova Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Sykes
Fallback supernovae and the collapsar scenario for long-gamma ray burst and hypernovae have received considerable interest as pathways to black-hole formation and extreme transient events. Consistent simulations of these scenarios require a general relativistic treatment and need to deal appropriately with the formation of a singularity. Free evolution schemes for the Einstein equations can handle the formation of black holes by means of excision or puncture schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
