<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to solve the mass-discrepancy problem of SESNe -- I. Testing model approximations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_to_solve_the_mass-discrepancy_problem_of_sesne_--_i._testing_model_approximations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_to_solve_the_mass-discrepancy_problem_of_sesne_--_i._testing_model_approximations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrea P. Nagy
Here, we present a systematic study of 59 stripped-envelope supernovae (SESNe) (including Type IIb, Ib, Ic, and transitional events) to map a possible reason for the so-called mass-discrepancy problem. In this scenario, we assume the tension between the estimated ejected masses from early- and late-time light curves (LC) is due to approximations generally used in analytical models. First, we examine the assumption that the R-band light curve is indeed a good approximation of the bolometric light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of weak lensing on Type Ia supernovae luminosity distances</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_weak_lensing_on_type_ia_supernovae_luminosity_distances/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_weak_lensing_on_type_ia_supernovae_luminosity_distances/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paul Shah
When Type Ia supernovae are used to infer cosmological parameters, their luminosities are compared to those from a homogeneous cosmology. In this note we propose a test to examine to what degree SN Ia have been observed on lines of sight where the average matter density is \textit{not} representative of the homogeneous background. We use a modification to the Tripp estimator to explicitly de-lens SN Ia magnitudes, and show that it reduces scatter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for relativistic ejecta in a sample of ZTF broad-lined Type Ic supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_relativistic_ejecta_in_a_sample_of_ztf_broad-lined_type_ic_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_relativistic_ejecta_in_a_sample_of_ztf_broad-lined_type_ic_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alessandra Corsi
The dividing line between gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) and ordinary stripped-envelope core-collapse supernovae (SNe) is yet to be fully understood. Observationally mapping the variety of ejecta outcomes (ultra-relativistic, mildly-relativistic or non-relativistic) in SNe of Type Ic with broad lines (Ic-BL) can provide a key test to stellar explosion models. However, this requires large samples of the rare Ic-BL events with follow-up observations in the radio, where fast ejecta can be probed largely free of geometry and viewing angle effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the effects of curvature on the cosmological models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_the_effects_of_curvature_on_the_cosmological_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/revealing_the_effects_of_curvature_on_the_cosmological_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Weiqiang Yang
In this paper we consider the effects of adding curvature in extended cosmologies involving a free-to-vary neutrino sector and different parametrizations of Dark Energy (DE). We make use of the Planck 2018 cosmic microwave background temperature and polarization data, Baryon Acoustic Oscillations and Pantheon type Ia Supernovae data. Our main result is that a non-flat Universe cannot be discarded in light of the current astronomical data, because we find an indication for a closed Universe in most of the DE cosmologies explored in this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skynet&#39;s New Observing Mode: The Campaign Manager</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/skynets_new_observing_mode_the_campaign_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/skynets_new_observing_mode_the_campaign_manager/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dylan A. Dutton
Built in 2004, the Skynet robotic telescope network originally consisted of six 0.4 m telescopes located at the Cerro-Tololo Inter-American Observatory in the Chilean Andes. The network was designed to carry out simultaneous multi-wavelength observations of gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) when they are only tens of seconds old. To date, the network has been expanded to ~20 telescopes, including a 20 m radio telescope, that span four continents and five countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological-model-independent determination of Hubble constant from fast radio bursts and Hubble parameter measurements</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological-model-independent_determination_of_hubble_constant_from_fast_radio_bursts_and_hubble_parameter_measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmological-model-independent_determination_of_hubble_constant_from_fast_radio_bursts_and_hubble_parameter_measurements/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yang Liu
We establish a new cosmological-model-independent method to determine the Hubble constant $H_0$ from the localized FRBs and the Hubble parameter measurements and obtain a first such determination $H_0=70.60\pm2.11~\mathrm{km/s/Mpc}$ of about 3.00% uncertainty with data from the eighteen localized FRBs and nineteen Hubble parameter measurements in the redshift range $0&amp;lt;z\leq0.66$. This value, which is independent of the cosmological model, lies in the middle of the results from the Planck CMB observations and the nearby type Ia supernovae (SN Ia) data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecast of Cosmological Constraints with Type Ia Supernovae from the Chinese Space Station Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forecast_of_cosmological_constraints_with_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_chinese_space_station_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forecast_of_cosmological_constraints_with_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_chinese_space_station_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shi-Yu Li
The 2-m aperture Chinese Space Station Telescope (CSST), which observes at wavelengths ranging from 255 to 1000 nm, is expected to start science operations in 2024. An ultra-deep field observation program covering approximately 10 square degrees is proposed with supernovae (SNe) and other transients as one of its primary science drivers. This paper presents the simulated detection results of type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) and explores the impact of new datasets on the determinations of cosmological parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Type II-P Supernova 2019mhm and Constraints on Its Progenitor System</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ii-p_supernova_2019mhm_and_constraints_on_its_progenitor_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ii-p_supernova_2019mhm_and_constraints_on_its_progenitor_system/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Vazquez
We present pre- and post-explosion observations of the Type II-P supernova (SN II-P) 2019mhm located in NGC 6753. Based on optical spectroscopy and photometry, we show that SN 2019mhm exhibits broad lines of hydrogen with a velocity of $-8500\pm200$ km s$^{-1}$ and a $111\pm2$ day extended plateau in its luminosity, typical of the Type II-P subclass. We also fit its late-time bolometric light curve and infer that it initially produced a ${}^{56}$Ni mass of $5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble tensions: a historical statistical analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_tensions_a_historical_statistical_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_tensions_a_historical_statistical_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martin Lopez-Corredoira
Statistical analyses of the measurements of the Hubble-Lema^itre constant $H_0$ (163 measurements between 1976 and 2019) show that the statistical error bars associated with the observed parameter measurements have been underestimated &amp;ndash; or the systematic errors were not properly taken into account &amp;ndash; in at least 15-20% of the measurements. The fact that the underestimation of error bars for $H_0$ is so common might explain the apparent discrepancy of values, which is formally known today as the Hubble tension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAPUM upper limits on pulsed radio emission for SMC X-ray pulsar J0058-7218</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/trapum_upper_limits_on_pulsed_radio_emission_for_smc_x-ray_pulsar_j0058-7218/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/trapum_upper_limits_on_pulsed_radio_emission_for_smc_x-ray_pulsar_j0058-7218/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Carli
The TRAPUM collaboration has used the MeerKAT telescope to conduct a search for pulsed radio emission from the young Small Magellanic Cloud pulsar J0058-7218 located in the supernova remnant IKT 16, following its discovery in X-rays with XMM-Newton. We report no significant detection of dispersed, pulsed radio emission from this source in three 2-hour L-band observations using the core dishes of MeerKAT, setting an upper limit of 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An X-ray Proper Motion Study of the LMC SNR 0509-67.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_x-ray_proper_motion_study_of_the_lmc_snr_0509-67.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_x-ray_proper_motion_study_of_the_lmc_snr_0509-67.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benson T. Guest
We present a third epoch of Chandra observations of the Type Ia Large Magellanic Cloud Supernova remnant (SNR) 0509-67.5. With these new observations from 2020, the baseline for proper motion measurements of the expansion has grown to 20 years (from the earliest Chandra observations in 2000). We report here the results of these new expansion measurements. The lack of nearby bright point sources renders absolute image alignment difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning method in testing the cosmic distance duality relation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_learning_method_in_testing_the_cosmic_distance_duality_relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_learning_method_in_testing_the_cosmic_distance_duality_relation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Li Tang
The cosmic distance duality relation (DDR) is constrained from the combination of type-Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) and strong gravitational lensing (SGL) systems using deep learning method. To make use of the full SGL data, we reconstruct the luminosity distance from SNe Ia up to the highest redshift of SGL using deep learning, then it is compared with the angular diameter distance obtained from SGL. Considering the influence of lens mass profile, we constrain the possible violation of DDR in three lens mass models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explosive nucleosynthesis with fast neutrino-flavor conversion in core-collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explosive_nucleosynthesis_with_fast_neutrino-flavor_conversion_in_core-collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/explosive_nucleosynthesis_with_fast_neutrino-flavor_conversion_in_core-collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shin-ichiro Fujimoto
Fast neutrino -flavor conversion (FFC) is a possible game-changing ingredient in core-collapse supernova (CCSN) theory. In this Letter, we examine the impact of FFC on explosive nucleosynthesis by including the effects of FFC in conjunction with asymmetric neutrino emission into nucleosynthetic computations in a parametric way. We find that the ejecta compositions are not appreciably affected by FFC for elements lighter than Co, while the compositions are influenced by FFC for the heavier elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-energy neutrinos from choked-jet supernovae: searches and implications</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-energy_neutrinos_from_choked-jet_supernovae_searches_and_implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-energy_neutrinos_from_choked-jet_supernovae_searches_and_implications/</guid>
      <description>First author: Po-Wen Chang
The origin of the high-energy astrophysical neutrinos discovered by IceCube remains largely unknown. Multi-messenger studies have indicated that the majority of these neutrinos come from gamma-ray-dark sources. Choked-jet supernovae (cjSNe), which are supernovae powered by relativistic jets stalled in stellar materials, may lead to neutrino emission via photohadronic interactions while the coproduced gamma rays are absorbed. In this paper, we perform an unbinned-maximum-likelihood analysis to search for correlations between IceCube&amp;rsquo;s 10-year muon-track events and our SN Ib/c sample, collected from publicly available catalogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The luminous Type IIN supernova SN 2017hcc: Infrared bright, X-ray and radio faint</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_luminous_type_iin_supernova_sn_2017hcc_infrared_bright_x-ray_and_radio_faint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_luminous_type_iin_supernova_sn_2017hcc_infrared_bright_x-ray_and_radio_faint/</guid>
      <description>First author: Poonam Chandra
We present multiwavelength observations of supernova (SN) 2017hcc with the Chandra X-ray telescope and the X-ray telescope onboard Swift (Swift-XRT) in X-ray bands, with the Spitzer and the TripleSpec spectrometer in near-infrared (IR) and mid-IR bands and with the Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array (VLA) for radio bands. The X-ray observations cover a period of 29 to 1310 days, with the first X-ray detection on day 727 with the Chandra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UV Excesses of Supernovae and the Implications for Studying Supernovae and Other Optical Transients</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_uv_excesses_of_supernovae_and_the_implications_for_studying_supernovae_and_other_optical_transients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_uv_excesses_of_supernovae_and_the_implications_for_studying_supernovae_and_other_optical_transients/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tao Wang
Supernovae (SNe), kilonovae (KNe), tidal disruption events (TDEs), optical afterglows of gamma ray bursts (GRBs), and many other optical transients are important phenomena in time-domain astronomy. Fitting the multi-band light curves (LCs) or the synthesized (pseudo-)bolometric LCs can be used to constrain the physical properties of optical transients. The (UV absorbed) blackbody module is one of the most important modules used to fit the multi-band LCs of optical transients having (UV absorbed) blackbody spectral energy distributions (SEDs).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
