<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Sensitive Search for Supernova Emission Associated with the Extremely Energetic and Nearby GRB 221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sensitive_search_for_supernova_emission_associated_with_the_extremely_energetic_and_nearby_grb_221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_sensitive_search_for_supernova_emission_associated_with_the_extremely_energetic_and_nearby_grb_221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gokul P. Srinivasaragavan
We report observations of the optical counterpart of the long gamma-ray burst (LGRB) GRB 221009A. Due to the extreme rarity of being both nearby ($z = 0.151$) and highly energetic ($E_{\gamma,\mathrm{iso}} \geq 10^{54}$ erg), GRB 221009A offers a unique opportunity to probe the connection between massive star core collapse and relativistic jet formation. Adopting a phenomenological power-law model for the afterglow and host galaxy estimates from high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging, we use Bayesian model comparison techniques to determine the likelihood of an associated SN contributing excess flux to the optical light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferring the progenitor mass-kinetic energy relation of stripped-envelope core-collapse supernovae from nebular spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_the_progenitor_mass-kinetic_energy_relation_of_stripped-envelope_core-collapse_supernovae_from_nebular_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferring_the_progenitor_mass-kinetic_energy_relation_of_stripped-envelope_core-collapse_supernovae_from_nebular_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Qiliang Fang
The relation between the progenitor mass and the kinetic energy of the explosion is a key toward revealing the explosion mechanism of stripped-envelope (SE) core-collapse (CC) supernovae (SNe). Here, we present a method to derive this relation using the nebular spectra of SESNe, based on the correlation between the $[O~I]$/$[Ca~II]$, which is an indicator of the progenitor mass, and the width of $[O~I]$, which measures the expansion velocity of the oxygen-rich material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing of materials in magnetised core-collapse supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mixing_of_materials_in_magnetised_core-collapse_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mixing_of_materials_in_magnetised_core-collapse_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Meyer D. M. -A.
Core-collapse supernova remnants are structures of the interstellar medium (ISM) left behind the explosive death of most massive stars (smaller or equal to 40 Mo). Since they result in the expansion of the supernova shock wave into the gaseous environment shaped by the star wind history, their morphology constitutes an insight into the past evolution of their progenitor star. Particularly, fast-moving massive stars can produce asymmetric core-collapse supernova remnants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleosynthesis in jet-driven and jet-associated supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_jet-driven_and_jet-associated_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_jet-driven_and_jet-associated_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Obergaulinger
In contrast to regular core-collapse supernovae, explosions of rapidly rotating massive stars can develop jets, fast collimated outflows directed along the rotational axis. Depending on the rate of rotation and the magnetic field strength before collapse as well as on possible mechanisms amplifying the magnetic field, such a core can explode magnetorotationally rather than via the standard supernova mechanism based on neutrino heating. This scenario can explain the highest kinetic energies observed in the class of hypernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio and infrared study of the supernova remnant candidate HESS J1912&#43;101</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_infrared_study_of_the_supernova_remnant_candidate_hess_j1912&#43;101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_infrared_study_of_the_supernova_remnant_candidate_hess_j1912&#43;101/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Duvidovich
Aims: We provide new insights into the gamma-ray emission from HESS J1912+101, a TeV supernova remnant candidate probably associated with the radio pulsar PSR J1913+1011. Methods: We obtained new observations at 1.5 GHz using the VLA in the D configuration, with the purpose of detecting the radio shell of the putative remnant. In addition, we observed a single pointing at 6.0 GHz toward PSR J1913+1011 to look for a radio pulsar wind nebula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-lived radioisotope enrichment in star-forming regions from stellar winds and supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radioisotope_enrichment_in_star-forming_regions_from_stellar_winds_and_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/short-lived_radioisotope_enrichment_in_star-forming_regions_from_stellar_winds_and_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Richard J. Parker
The abundance of the short-lived radioisotopes 26-Al and 60-Fe in the early Solar system is usually explained by the Sun either forming from pre-enriched material, or the Sun&amp;rsquo;s protosolar disc being polluted by a nearby supernova explosion from a massive star. Both hypotheses suffer from significant drawbacks: the former does not account for the dynamical evolution of star-forming regions, while in the latter the time for massive stars to explode as supernovae can be similar to, or even longer than, the lifetime of protoplanetary discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-rising Type II supernovae resembling supernova 1987A -- I. A comparative study through scaling relations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-rising_type_ii_supernovae_resembling_supernova_1987a_--_i._a_comparative_study_through_scaling_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-rising_type_ii_supernovae_resembling_supernova_1987a_--_i._a_comparative_study_through_scaling_relations/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. L. Pumo
With the aim of improving our knowledge about their nature, we conduct a comparative study on a sample of long-rising Type II supernovae (SNe) resembling SN 1987A. To do so, we deduce various scaling relations from different analytic models of H-rich SNe, discussing their robustness and feasibility. Then we use the best relations in terms of accuracy to infer the SN progenitor&amp;rsquo;s physical properties at the explosion for the selected sample of SN 1987A-like objects, deriving energies of $\sim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleosynthesis in neutrino-heated ejecta and neutrino-driven winds of core-collapse supernovae; neutrino-induced nucleosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_neutrino-heated_ejecta_and_neutrino-driven_winds_of_core-collapse_supernovae_neutrino-induced_nucleosynthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nucleosynthesis_in_neutrino-heated_ejecta_and_neutrino-driven_winds_of_core-collapse_supernovae_neutrino-induced_nucleosynthesis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shinya Wanajo
The innermost ejecta of core-collapse supernovae are considered to be the sources of some iron-group and heavier nuclei. The ejecta are predominantly driven by neutrino heating, principally due to neutrino capture on free neutrons and protons. Such neutrino interaction plays a crucial role for setting neutron richness in the ejecta. Recent hydrodynamics work with sophisticated neutrino transport indicates that the ejecta are only mildly neutron rich or even proton rich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric study of the late-time near-infrared plateau in Type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_study_of_the_late-time_near-infrared_plateau_in_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_study_of_the_late-time_near-infrared_plateau_in_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Deckers
We present an in-depth study of the late-time near-infrared plateau in Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia), which occurs between 70-500 d. We double the existing sample of SNe Ia observed during the late-time near-infrared plateau with new observations taken with the Hubble Space Telescope, Gemini, New Technology Telescope, the 3.5m Calar Alto Telescope, and the Nordic Optical Telescope. Our sample consists of 24 nearby SNe Ia at redshift &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of pre-supernova feedback in spherical clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_pre-supernova_feedback_in_spherical_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/simulations_of_pre-supernova_feedback_in_spherical_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michalis Kourniotis
We present a one-dimensional radiation-hydrodynamic model of a spherically symmetric cloud evolving under the influence of the self-gravity and the feedback from a star cluster forming in its centre. On one hand, the model is simple due to its 1D geometry, on the other hand, the feedback includes the ionising radiation, stellar winds and the radiation pressure acting on gas and dust. The star cluster is formed from the gas flowing into the cloud centre and the feedback parameters are determined from stellar evolution models and the cluster star forming history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Ia supernovae SN 2013bz, PSN J0910&#43;5003 and ASASSN-16ex: similar to 09dc-like?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_sn_2013bz_psn_j0910&#43;5003_and_asassn-16ex_similar_to_09dc-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_sn_2013bz_psn_j0910&#43;5003_and_asassn-16ex_similar_to_09dc-like/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Tiwari
We present optical photometric and spectroscopic studies of three supernovae (SNe) SN 2013bz, PSN J0910+5003 and ASASSN-16ex. UV-optical photometric data of ASASSN-16ex obtained with Swift-UVOT are also analyzed. These objects were initially classified as 09dc-like type Ia SNe. The decline rate parameters ($\Delta m_{15}(B){true}$) are derived as 0.92 $\pm$ 0.04 (SN 2013bz), 0.70 $\pm$ 0.05 (PSN J0910+5003) and 0.73 $\pm$ 0.03 (ASASSN-16ex). The estimated $B$ band absolute magnitudes at maximum: $-$19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometry and spectroscopy of the Type Icn supernova 2021ckj: The diverse properties of the ejecta and circumstellar matter of Type Icn SNe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometry_and_spectroscopy_of_the_type_icn_supernova_2021ckj_the_diverse_properties_of_the_ejecta_and_circumstellar_matter_of_type_icn_sne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometry_and_spectroscopy_of_the_type_icn_supernova_2021ckj_the_diverse_properties_of_the_ejecta_and_circumstellar_matter_of_type_icn_sne/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Nagao
We present photometric and spectroscopic observations of the Type Icn supernova (SN) 2021ckj. Spectral modeling of SN 2021ckj reveals that its composition is dominated by oxygen, carbon and iron group elements, and the photospheric velocity at peak is ~10000 km/s. From the light curve (LC) modeling applied to SNe 2021ckj, 2019hgp, and 2021csp, we find that the ejecta and CSM properties of Type Icn SNe are diverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamma-Ray Bursts, Quasars, Baryonic Acoustic Oscillations, and Supernovae Ia: new statistical insights and cosmological constraints</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_bursts_quasars_baryonic_acoustic_oscillations_and_supernovae_ia_new_statistical_insights_and_cosmological_constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gamma-ray_bursts_quasars_baryonic_acoustic_oscillations_and_supernovae_ia_new_statistical_insights_and_cosmological_constraints/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Bargiacchi
The recent $\sim 4 , \sigma$ Hubble constant, $H_{0}$, tension is observed between the value of $H_{0}$ from the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Type Ia Supernovae (SNe Ia). It is a decade since this tension is excruciating the modern astrophysical community. To shed light on this problem is key to consider probes at intermediate redshifts between SNe Ia and CMB and reduce the uncertainty on $H_0$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Masses of Supernova Remnant Progenitors in M33</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_masses_of_supernova_remnant_progenitors_in_m33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_masses_of_supernova_remnant_progenitors_in_m33/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brad Koplitz
Using resolved optical stellar photometry from the Panchromatic Hubble Andromeda Treasury Triangulum Extended Region (PHATTER) survey, we measured the star formation history (SFH) near the position of 85 supernova remnants (SNRs) in M33. We constrained the progenitor masses for 60 of these SNRs, finding the remaining 25 remnants had no local SF in the last 56 Myr consistent with core-collapse SNe (CCSNe), making them potential Type Ia candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectropolarimetry of the type IIP supernova 2021yja: an unusually high continuum polarization during the photospheric phase</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectropolarimetry_of_the_type_iip_supernova_2021yja_an_unusually_high_continuum_polarization_during_the_photospheric_phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectropolarimetry_of_the_type_iip_supernova_2021yja_an_unusually_high_continuum_polarization_during_the_photospheric_phase/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergiy S. Vasylyev
We present six epochs of optical spectropolarimetry of the Type IIP supernova (SN) 2021yja ranging from $\sim$ 25 to 95 days after the explosion. An unusually high continuum linear polarization of $p \sim 0.9%$ is measured during the early photospheric phase, followed by a steady decrease well before the onset of the nebular phase. This behavior has not been observed before in Type IIP supernovae (SNe IIP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effective volume of supernovae samples and sample variance</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effective_volume_of_supernovae_samples_and_sample_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_effective_volume_of_supernovae_samples_and_sample_variance/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zhongxu Zhai
The source of the tension between local SN Ia based Hubble constant measurements and those from the CMB or BAO+BBN measurements is one of the most interesting unknowns of modern cosmology. Sample variance forms a key component of the error on the local measurements, and will dominate the error budget in the future as more supernovae are observed. Many methods have been proposed to estimate sample variance in many contexts, and we compared results from a number of them in Zhai &amp;amp; Percival (2022), confirming that sample variance for the Pantheon supernovae sample does not solve the Hubble tension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications of Machine Learning to Detecting Fast Neutrino Flavor Instabilities in Core-Collapse Supernova and Neutron Star Merger Models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/applications_of_machine_learning_to_detecting_fast_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_core-collapse_supernova_and_neutron_star_merger_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/applications_of_machine_learning_to_detecting_fast_neutrino_flavor_instabilities_in_core-collapse_supernova_and_neutron_star_merger_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sajad Abbar
Neutrinos propagating in a dense neutrino gas, such as those expected in core-collapse supernovae (CCSNe) and neutron star mergers (NSMs), can experience fast flavor conversions on relatively short scales. This can happen if the neutrino electron lepton number ($\nu$ELN) angular distribution crosses zero in a certain direction. Despite this, most of the state-of-the-art CCSN and NSM simulations do not provide such detailed angular information and instead, supply only a few moments of the neutrino angular distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common envelope jets supernova with thermonuclear outburst progenitor for the enigmatic supernova remnant W49B</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/common_envelope_jets_supernova_with_thermonuclear_outburst_progenitor_for_the_enigmatic_supernova_remnant_w49b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/common_envelope_jets_supernova_with_thermonuclear_outburst_progenitor_for_the_enigmatic_supernova_remnant_w49b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aldana Grichener
We suggest a common envelope jets supernova (CEJSN) origin to the supernova remnant (SNR) W49B where jets launched by a neutron star (NS) that collapsed to a black hole (BH) together with a thermonuclear outburst of the disrupted red super giant&amp;rsquo;s (RGS&amp;rsquo;s) core powered and shaped the ejecta. The jets account for the highly non-spherical morphology of W49B and the thermonuclear outburst to its high iron abundance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Ejecta and Cold Dust in the Young Supernova Remnant N132D</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_ejecta_and_cold_dust_in_the_young_supernova_remnant_n132d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_ejecta_and_cold_dust_in_the_young_supernova_remnant_n132d/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeonghee Rho
We present Spitzer, WISE, and Herschel observations of the young supernova remnant (SNR) N132D in the LMC, including 3-40 microns Spitzer IRS mapping, 12 microns WISE and 70, 100, 160, 250, 350, and 500 microns Herschel images. The high-velocity lines of $[Ne II]$ at 12.8 microns, $[Ne III]$ at 15.5 microns, and $[O IV]$ 26 microns reveal infrared ejecta concentrated in a central ring and coincide the optical and X-ray ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Light Curve of a Type Ia Supernova 2021hpr in NGC 3147: Progenitor Constraints with the Companion Interaction Model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_early_light_curve_of_a_type_ia_supernova_2021hpr_in_ngc_3147_progenitor_constraints_with_the_companion_interaction_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_early_light_curve_of_a_type_ia_supernova_2021hpr_in_ngc_3147_progenitor_constraints_with_the_companion_interaction_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gu Lim
The progenitor system of Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) is expected to be a close binary system of a carbon/oxygen white dwarf (WD) and a non-degenerate star or another WD. Here, we present results from a high-cadence monitoring observation of SN 2021hpr in a spiral galaxy, NGC 3147, and constraints on the progenitor system based on its early multi-color light curve data. First, we classify SN 2021hpr as a normal SN Ia from its long-term photometric and spectroscopic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining High-Energy Neutrino Emission from Supernovae with IceCube</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_supernovae_with_icecube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_high-energy_neutrino_emission_from_supernovae_with_icecube/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. Abbasi
Core-collapse supernovae are a promising potential high-energy neutrino source class. We test for correlation between seven years of IceCube neutrino data and a catalog containing more than 1000 core-collapse supernovae of types IIn and IIP and a sample of stripped-envelope supernovae. We search both for neutrino emission from individual supernovae, and for combined emission from the whole supernova sample through a stacking analysis. No significant spatial or temporal correlation of neutrinos with the cataloged supernovae was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Expansion of the Young Type Ia Supernova Remnant 0519-69.0: More Evidence for a Circumstellar Shell</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_expansion_of_the_young_type_ia_supernova_remnant_0519-69.0_more_evidence_for_a_circumstellar_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rapid_expansion_of_the_young_type_ia_supernova_remnant_0519-69.0_more_evidence_for_a_circumstellar_shell/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benson T. Guest
The nature of Type Ia supernovae remains controversial. The youngest remnants of Ia supernovae hold clues to the explosion and to the immediate surroundings. We present a third epoch of Chandra observations of the $\sim600$-year-old Type Ia remnant 0519-69.0 in the Large Magellanic Cloud, extending the time baseline to 21 years from the initial 2000 observations. We find rapid expansion of X-ray emitting material, with an average velocity of 4760 km s$^{-1}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN2017egm: A Helium-rich Superluminous Supernova with Multiple Bumps in the Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn2017egm_a_helium-rich_superluminous_supernova_with_multiple_bumps_in_the_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn2017egm_a_helium-rich_superluminous_supernova_with_multiple_bumps_in_the_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiazheng Zhu
When discovered, SN~2017egm was the closest (redshift $z=0.03$) hydrogen-poor superluminous supernova (SLSN-I) and a rare case that exploded in a massive and metal-rich galaxy. Thus, it has since been extensively observed and studied. We report spectroscopic data showing strong emission at around He~I $\lambda$10,830 and four He~I absorption lines in the optical. Consequently, we classify SN~2017egm as a member of an emerging population of helium-rich SLSNe-I (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An archival search for type Ia supernova siblings</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_archival_search_for_type_ia_supernova_siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_archival_search_for_type_ia_supernova_siblings/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Kelsey
By searching the Open Supernova Catalog, an extra-galactic transient host galaxy database, and literature analyses, I present the largest sample of type Ia supernova (SN Ia) siblings to date. The sample comprises 158 galaxies, consisting of 327 confirmed SNe Ia - over 10 times larger than existing sibling SN Ia samples. SN siblings share host galaxies, and thus share global environmental properties and associated systematic uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth-rate measurement with type-Ia supernovae using ZTF survey simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growth-rate_measurement_with_type-ia_supernovae_using_ztf_survey_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/growth-rate_measurement_with_type-ia_supernovae_using_ztf_survey_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bastien Carreres
Measurements of the growth rate of structures at $z &amp;lt; 0.1$ with peculiar velocity surveys have the potential of testing the validity of general relativity on cosmic scales. In this work, we present growth-rate measurements from realistic simulated sets of type-Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF). We describe our simulation methodology, the light-curve fitting and peculiar velocity estimation. Using the maximum likelihood method, we derive constraints on $f\sigma_8$ using only ZTF SN Ia peculiar velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic red supergiant explosion model grid for systematic characterization of Type II supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synthetic_red_supergiant_explosion_model_grid_for_systematic_characterization_of_type_ii_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synthetic_red_supergiant_explosion_model_grid_for_systematic_characterization_of_type_ii_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takashi J. Moriya
A new model grid containing 228,016 synthetic red supergiant explosions (Type II supernovae) is introduced. Time evolution of spectral energy distributions from 1 A to 50,000 A (100 frequency bins in a log scale) is computed at each time step up to 500 days after explosion in each model. We provide light curves for the filters of the Vera C. Rubin Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST), Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF), Sloan Digital Sky Servey (SDSS), and the Neil Gehrels Swift Observatory, but light curves for any photometric filters can be constructed by convolving any filter response functions to the synthetic spectral energy distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The restframe ultraviolet of superluminous supernovae -- I. Potential as cosmological probes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_restframe_ultraviolet_of_superluminous_supernovae_--_i._potential_as_cosmological_probes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_restframe_ultraviolet_of_superluminous_supernovae_--_i._potential_as_cosmological_probes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nandita Khetan
Superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) have been detected to $z\sim4$ and can be detected to $z\gtrsim15$ using current and upcoming facilities. SLSNe are extremely UV luminous, and hence objects at $z\gtrsim7$ are detected exclusively via their rest-frame UV using optical and infrared facilities. SLSNe have great utility in multiple areas of stellar and galactic evolution. Here, we explore the potential use of SLSNe type-I as high-redshift cosmological distance indicators in their rest-frame UV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution X-Ray Spectroscopy of Supernova Remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_x-ray_spectroscopy_of_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_x-ray_spectroscopy_of_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Satoru Katsuda
Thermal X-ray spectra from supernova remnants (SNRs) are dominated by a number of line emission from various elements. Resolving the individual lines is critically important for a variety of scientific topics such as diagnosing high-temperature and low-density non-equilibrium plasmas, identifying spectral features like charge exchange and resonance line scattering, revealing kinematics and elemental abundances of SN ejecta and the circumstellar medium, and studying the interstellar medium or planets&amp;rsquo; atmospheres from extinction features seen in X-ray spectra of very bright SNRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study of GeV Gamma-ray Emission toward Supernova Remnant G51.26&#43;0.11 and Its Molecular Environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_study_of_gev_gamma-ray_emission_toward_supernova_remnant_g51.26&#43;0.11_and_its_molecular_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_study_of_gev_gamma-ray_emission_toward_supernova_remnant_g51.26&#43;0.11_and_its_molecular_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Wen-Juan Zhong
We reanalyze the Fermi-LAT GeV $\gamma$-ray emission in the region of supernova remnant (SNR) G51.26+0.11 and investigate its interstellar molecular environment with the CO-line data. At GeV energies, based on 13.2 years of Fermi-LAT data, the extended $\gamma$-ray emission observed in this region is resolved into a uniform-disk source (&amp;lsquo;Src A&amp;rsquo;) with a significance of 19.5$\sigma$ and a point source (4FGL J1924.3+1628) with a significance of 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Flash and Spectral Formation of Type Ia Supernovae with An Envelope: Applications to Over-luminous SNe Ia</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/initial_flash_and_spectral_formation_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_an_envelope_applications_to_over-luminous_sne_ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/initial_flash_and_spectral_formation_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_an_envelope_applications_to_over-luminous_sne_ia/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Over-luminous type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) show peculiar observational features, for which an explosion of a super-massive white dwarf (WD) beyond the classical Chandrasekhar-limiting mass has been suggested, largely based on their high luminosities and slow light-curve evolution. However, their observational features are diverse, with a few extremely peculiar features whose origins have not been clarified; strong and persisting C II lines, late-time accelerated luminosity decline and red spectra, and a sub-day time-scale initial flash clearly identified so far at least for three over-luminous SNe Ia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A search for transients in the Reionization Lensing Cluster Survey (RELICS): Three new supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_transients_in_the_reionization_lensing_cluster_survey_relics_three_new_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_search_for_transients_in_the_reionization_lensing_cluster_survey_relics_three_new_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Miriam Golubchik
The Reionization Cluster Survey (RELICS) imaged 41 galaxy clusters with the Hubble Space Telescope (HST), in order to detect lensed and high-redshift galaxies. Each cluster was imaged to about 26.5 AB mag in three optical and four near-infrared bands, taken in two distinct visits separated by varying time intervals. We make use of the multiple near-infrared epochs to search for transient sources in the cluster fields, with the primary motivation of building statistics for bright caustic crossing events in gravitational arcs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Supernova Physics through Gravitational-Wave Observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_supernova_physics_through_gravitational-wave_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_supernova_physics_through_gravitational-wave_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gergely Dálya
We examine the potential for using the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA network of gravitational-wave detectors to provide constraints on the physical properties of core-collapse supernovae through the observation of their gravitational radiation. We use waveforms generated by 14 of the latest 3D hydrodynamic core-collapse supernova simulations, which are added to noise samples based on the predicted sensitivities of the GW detectors during the O5 observing run. Then we use the BayesWave algorithm to model-independently reconstruct the gravitational-wave waveforms, which are used as input for various machine learning algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carnegie Supernova Project-I. Optical spectroscopy of stripped-envelope supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._optical_spectroscopy_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._optical_spectroscopy_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. D. Stritzinger
We present 170 optical spectra of 35 low-redshift stripped-envelope core-collapse supernovae observed by the Carnegie Supernova Project-I between 2004 and 2009. The data extend from as early as -19 days (d) prior to the epoch of B-band maximum to +322 d, with the vast majority obtained during the so-called photospheric phase covering the weeks around peak luminosity. In addition to histogram plots characterizing the red-shift distribution, number of spectra per object, and the phase distribution of the sample, spectroscopic classification is also provided following standard criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carnegie Supernova Project-I. Spectroscopic analysis of stripped-envelope supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._spectroscopic_analysis_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_carnegie_supernova_project-i._spectroscopic_analysis_of_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Holmbo
An analysis leveraging 170 optical spectra of 35 stripped-envelope (SE) core-collapse supernovae observed by the Carnegie Supernova Project-I and published in a companion paper is presented. Mean template spectra are constructed for the SNe IIb, Ib and Ic sub-types and parent ions associated with designated spectral features are identified with the aid of the spectral synthesis code SYNAPPS. Our modeled mean spectra suggest the ~6150~\AA\ feature in SNe~IIb may have an underlying contribution due to silicon, while the same feature in some SNe Ib may have an underlying contribution due to hydrogen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limits on compression of cosmic rays in supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/limits_on_compression_of_cosmic_rays_in_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/limits_on_compression_of_cosmic_rays_in_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Iurii Sushch
The spectral shape of the gamma-ray emission observed for dynamically old supernova remnants that interact with molecular clouds triggered an exciting scenario of adiabatic compression and farther re-acceleration of Galactic cosmic rays (GCRs) in radiative shells of the remnants, which was extensively discussed and applied to various sources over recent years. Indeed, the observed gamma-ray spectrum from a number of remnants strongly resembles the expected spectrum of the gamma-ray emission from the compressed population of Galactic cosmic rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraint on the minimally extended varying speed of light using time dilations in type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraint_on_the_minimally_extended_varying_speed_of_light_using_time_dilations_in_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraint_on_the_minimally_extended_varying_speed_of_light_using_time_dilations_in_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Seokcheon Lee
The Friedmann-Lema^{i}tre-Robertson-Walker model establishes the correlation between redshifts and distances. It has a metric expansion of space. As a result, the wavelength of photons propagating through the expanding space is stretched, creating the cosmological redshift, $z$. It also relates the frequency of light detected by a local observer to that emitted from a distant source. In standard cosmology (\textit{i.e.} a constant speed light model, $c =$ constant), this relation is given by a factor $1/(1+z)$$[1]$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of optical emission associated with the supernova remnant G107.5-1.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_optical_emission_associated_with_the_supernova_remnant_g107.5-1.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_of_optical_emission_associated_with_the_supernova_remnant_g107.5-1.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hicran Bakis
We present the first results from an imaging and a spectroscopic survey of the optical emission associated with supernova remnant (SNR) G107.5$-$1.5. We discovered optical diffuse and filamentary emission from G107.5$-$1.5 using the 1.5-m and 1-m telescopes. The optical emission from the North East (NE) and North West (NW) regions show the diffuse structure, while the South East (SE) and East (E) regions show filamentary structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Scalarization as a New Core-Collapse Supernova Mechanism and its Multi-Messenger Signals</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spontaneous_scalarization_as_a_new_core-collapse_supernova_mechanism_and_its_multi-messenger_signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spontaneous_scalarization_as_a_new_core-collapse_supernova_mechanism_and_its_multi-messenger_signals/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takami Kuroda
We perform multi-dimensional core-collapse supernova (CCSN) simulations in a massive scalar-tensor theory for the first time with a realistic equation of state and multi-energy neutrino radiation. Among the set of our models varying the scalar mass and the coupling strength between the scalar and gravitational fields, a particular model allows for recurrent spontaneous scalarizations (SSs) in the proto-neutron star (PNS). Each SS induces the PNS collapse and subsequent bounce, from which devastating shock waves emanate and eject the PNS envelope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Ia supernovae in NS&#43;He star systems and the isolated mildly recycled pulsars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_in_ns&#43;he_star_systems_and_the_isolated_mildly_recycled_pulsars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernovae_in_ns&#43;he_star_systems_and_the_isolated_mildly_recycled_pulsars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yun-Lang Guo
Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are successful cosmological distance indicators and important element factories in the chemical evolution of galaxies. They are generally thought to originate from thermonuclear explosions of carbon-oxygen white dwarfs in close binaries. However, the observed diversity among SNe Ia implies that they have different progenitor models. In this article, we performed the long-term evolution of NS+He star binaries with different initial He star masses ($M_{\rm He}^{\rm i}$) and orbital periods ($P_{\rm orb}^{\rm i}$) for the first time, in which the He star companions can explode as SNe Ia eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapsars as Sites of r-process Nucleosynthesis: Systematic Near-Infrared Follow-up of Type Ic-BL Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapsars_as_sites_of_r-process_nucleosynthesis_systematic_near-infrared_follow-up_of_type_ic-bl_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapsars_as_sites_of_r-process_nucleosynthesis_systematic_near-infrared_follow-up_of_type_ic-bl_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shreya Anand
One of the open questions following the discovery of GW170817 is whether neutron star mergers are the only astrophysical sites capable of producing r-process elements. Simulations have shown that 0.01-0.1M$_\odot$ of r-process material could be generated in the outflows originating from the accretion disk surrounding the rapidly rotating black hole that forms as a remnant to both neutron star mergers and collapsing massive stars associated with long-duration gamma-ray bursts (collapsars).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Statistical Analysis of Galactic Radio Supernova Remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_analysis_of_galactic_radio_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_statistical_analysis_of_galactic_radio_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Ranasinghe
We present an revised table of 390 Galactic radio supernova remnants (SNRs) and their basic parameters. Statistical analyses are performed on SNR diameters, ages, spectral indices, Galactic heights and spherical symmetries. Furthermore, the accuracy of distances estimated using the $\Sigma$-D relation is examined. The arithmetic mean of the Galactic SNR diameters is $30.5$ pc with standard error $1.7$ pc and standard deviation $25.4$ pc. The geometric mean and geometric standard deviation factor of Galactic SNR diameters is $21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERITAS and Fermi-LAT constraints on the Gamma-ray Emission from Superluminous Supernovae SN2015bn and SN2017egm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/veritas_and_fermi-lat_constraints_on_the_gamma-ray_emission_from_superluminous_supernovae_sn2015bn_and_sn2017egm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/veritas_and_fermi-lat_constraints_on_the_gamma-ray_emission_from_superluminous_supernovae_sn2015bn_and_sn2017egm/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Acharyya
Superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) are a rare class of stellar explosions with luminosities ~10-100 times greater than ordinary core-collapse supernovae. One popular model to explain the enhanced optical output of hydrogen-poor (Type I) SLSNe invokes energy injection from a rapidly spinning magnetar. A prediction in this case is that high-energy gamma rays, generated in the wind nebula of the magnetar, could escape through the expanding supernova ejecta at late times (months or more after optical peak).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Rotating 25 M$_{\odot}$ Population III star: Physical Properties and Resulting Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_25_m___odot__population_iii_star_physical_properties_and_resulting_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_25_m___odot__population_iii_star_physical_properties_and_resulting_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amar Aryan
In this Letter, we report the outcomes of 1-D modelling of a rotating 25 M$_{\odot}$ zero-age main-sequence Population III star up to the stage of the onset of core collapse. Rapidly rotating models display violent and sporadic mass losses after the Main-Sequence stage. In comparison to the solar metallicity model, Pop III models show very small pre-supernova radii. Further, with models at the stage of the onset of core collapse, we simulate the hydrodynamic simulations of resulting supernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Further evidence that galaxy age drives observed type Ia supernova luminosity differences</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/further_evidence_that_galaxy_age_drives_observed_type_ia_supernova_luminosity_differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/further_evidence_that_galaxy_age_drives_observed_type_ia_supernova_luminosity_differences/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Wiseman
Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are explosions of white dwarf stars that facilitate exquisite measurements of cosmological expansion history, but improvements in accuracy and precision are hindered by observational biases. Of particular concern is the apparent difference in the corrected brightnesses of SNe Ia in different host galaxy environments. SNe Ia in more massive, passive, older environments appear brighter after having been standardized by their light-curve properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rates and properties of type Ia supernovae in galaxy clusters within the Dark Energy Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rates_and_properties_of_type_ia_supernovae_in_galaxy_clusters_within_the_dark_energy_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rates_and_properties_of_type_ia_supernovae_in_galaxy_clusters_within_the_dark_energy_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Toy
We use the Dark Energy Survey (DES) 5 year catalogue of photometrically-classified type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) to identify 70 SNe Ia that have occurred within red-sequence selected clusters of galaxies. We compare the cluster SN light-curve properties and environmental properties to 1020 DES SNe Ia located in the field, the largest comparison of two such samples to date. We find an tentative indication (98.5 per cent confidence level) that, on average, SNe Ia located in galaxy clusters are faster declining compared to those located in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Superluminous Type IIn Supernova ASASSN-15ua: Part of a continuum in extreme precursor mass loss</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_superluminous_type_iin_supernova_asassn-15ua_part_of_a_continuum_in_extreme_precursor_mass_loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_superluminous_type_iin_supernova_asassn-15ua_part_of_a_continuum_in_extreme_precursor_mass_loss/</guid>
      <description>First author: Danielle Dickinson
We present a series of ground-based photometry and spectroscopy of the superluminous Type IIn supernova (SN) ASASSN-15ua, which shows evidence for strong interaction with pre-existing dense circumstellar material (CSM). Our observations constrain the speed, mass-loss rate, and extent of the progenitor wind shortly before explosion. A narrow P Cygni absorption component reveals a progenitor wind speed of $\sim$100 km s$^{-1}$. As observed in previous SNe IIn, the intermediate-width H$\alpha$ emission became progressively more asymmetric and blueshifted, suggesting either an asymmetric CSM, an asymmetric explosion, or increasing selective extinction from dust within the post-shock shell or SN ejecta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing coincidence search for supernova neutrinos with optical transient surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/timing_coincidence_search_for_supernova_neutrinos_with_optical_transient_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/timing_coincidence_search_for_supernova_neutrinos_with_optical_transient_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sean Heston
Neutrinos allow the probing of stellar interiors during core collapse, helping to understand the different stages and processes in the collapse. To date, supernova neutrinos have only been detected from a single event, SN1987A. Most studies from then on have focused on two distance extremes: Galactic/local supernovae and all past cosmic supernovae forming the diffuse supernova neutrino background. We focus on the intermediate distance regime as a target for detecting core-collapse supernova neutrinos at next generation detectors like Hyper-Kamiokande.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lack of Bright Supernova Emission in the Brightest Gamma-ray Burst, GRB~221009A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lack_of_bright_supernova_emission_in_the_brightest_gamma-ray_burst_grb~221009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lack_of_bright_supernova_emission_in_the_brightest_gamma-ray_burst_grb~221009a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Manisha Shrestha
We present photometric and spectroscopic observations of the extraordinary gamma-ray burst (GRB) 221009A in search of an associated supernova. Some past GRBs have shown bumps in the optical light curve that coincide with the emergence of supernova spectral features, but we do not detect any significant light curve features in GRB~221009A, nor do we detect any clear sign of supernova spectral features. Using two well-studied GRB-associated supernovae (SN~2013dx, $M_{r,max} = -19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST NIRSpec observations of Supernova 1987A -- from the inner ejecta to the reverse shock</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_observations_of_supernova_1987a_--_from_the_inner_ejecta_to_the_reverse_shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_nirspec_observations_of_supernova_1987a_--_from_the_inner_ejecta_to_the_reverse_shock/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Larsson
We present initial results from JWST NIRSpec integral field unit observations of the nearby Supernova (SN) 1987A. The observations provide the first spatially-resolved spectroscopy of the ejecta and equatorial ring (ER) over the 1-5 $\mu$m range. We construct 3D emissivity maps of the $[Fe I]$ 1.443 $\mu$m line from the inner ejecta and the He I 1.083 $\mu$m line from the reverse shock (RS), where the former probes the explosion geometry and the latter traces the structure of the circumstellar medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fermi-LAT Gamma-ray Emission Discovered from the Composite Supernova Remnant B0453-685 in the Large Magellanic Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fermi-lat_gamma-ray_emission_discovered_from_the_composite_supernova_remnant_b0453-685_in_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/fermi-lat_gamma-ray_emission_discovered_from_the_composite_supernova_remnant_b0453-685_in_the_large_magellanic_cloud/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jordan Eagle
We report the second extragalactic pulsar wind nebula (PWN) to be detected in the MeV-GeV band by the Fermi-LAT, located within the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC). The only other known PWN to emit in the Fermi band outside of the Milky Way Galaxy is N 157B which lies to the west of the newly detected gamma-ray emission at an angular distance of 4 degrees. Faint, point-like gamma-ray emission is discovered at the location of the composite supernova remnant (SNR) B0453-685 with a ~ 4 sigma significance from energies 300 MeV - 2 TeV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-population Bayesian hierarchical model of type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/two-population_bayesian_hierarchical_model_of_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/two-population_bayesian_hierarchical_model_of_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Radosław Wojtak
The currently used standardisation of type Ia supernovae results in Hubble residuals whose physical origin is unaccounted for. This poses a limitation to the accuracy and precision of distances that can be derived from supernova observations. Here, we present a complete physical interpretation of the Hubble residuals based on a novel Bayesian hierarchical model of type Ia supernovae in which latent variables describing intrinsic and extrinsic (dust related) supernova properties originate from two populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term gravitational wave asteroseismology of supernova: from core collapse to 20 seconds postbounce</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_gravitational_wave_asteroseismology_of_supernova_from_core_collapse_to_20_seconds_postbounce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/long-term_gravitational_wave_asteroseismology_of_supernova_from_core_collapse_to_20_seconds_postbounce/</guid>
      <description>First author: Masamitsu Mori
We use an asteroseismology method to calculate the frequencies of gravitational waves in a long-term core-collapse supernova simulation, with a mass of 9.6 $M_\odot$. The simulation, which includes neutrino transport in general relativity is performed from core-collapse, bounce, explosion and cooling of protoneutron stars (PNSs) up to 20 s after the bounce self-consistently. Based on the hydrodynamics background, we calculate eigenmodes of the PNS oscillation through a perturbation analysis on fluid and metric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D-Spatiotemporal Forecasting the Expansion of Supernova Shells Using Deep Learning toward High-Resolution Galaxy Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d-spatiotemporal_forecasting_the_expansion_of_supernova_shells_using_deep_learning_toward_high-resolution_galaxy_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d-spatiotemporal_forecasting_the_expansion_of_supernova_shells_using_deep_learning_toward_high-resolution_galaxy_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiya Hirashima
Small integration timesteps for a small fraction of short-timescale regions are bottlenecks for high-resolution galaxy simulations using massively parallel computing. This is an urgent issue that needs to be resolved for future higher-resolution galaxy simulations. One possible solution is to use an (approximate) Hamiltonian splitting method, in which only regions requiring small timesteps are integrated with small timesteps, separated from the entire galaxy. In particular, gas affected by supernova (SN) explosions often requires the smallest timestep in such a simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-mass X-ray binary descended from an ultra-stripped supernova</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_high-mass_x-ray_binary_descended_from_an_ultra-stripped_supernova/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_high-mass_x-ray_binary_descended_from_an_ultra-stripped_supernova/</guid>
      <description>First author: Noel D. Richardson
Ultra-stripped supernovae are different from other terminal explosions of massive stars, as they show little or no ejecta from the actual supernova event. They are thought to occur in massive binary systems after the exploding star has lost its surface through interactions with its companion. Such supernovae produce little to no kick, leading to the formation of a neutron star without loss of the binary companion, which itself may also evolve into another neutron star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernova connection of unidentified ultra high energy gamma-ray source LHAASO J2108&#43;5157</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_connection_of_unidentified_ultra_high_energy_gamma-ray_source_lhaaso_j2108&#43;5157/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_connection_of_unidentified_ultra_high_energy_gamma-ray_source_lhaaso_j2108&#43;5157/</guid>
      <description>First author: Agnibha De Sarkar
We present a simple phenomenological model of hadronic interaction between protons accelerated in an old supernova remnant (SNR) and cold protons situated within the associated molecular clouds (MCs). The accelerated protons from the old SNR escaped the SNR shock front, and got injected into the MCs at an earlier time, producing ultra high energy gamma-rays and neutrinos through inelastic proton-proton interaction. We also take into account the acceleration and subsequent escape of electrons from the SNR shock front.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negative Dark Energy Density from High Redshift Pantheon&#43; Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/negative_dark_energy_density_from_high_redshift_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/negative_dark_energy_density_from_high_redshift_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mohammad Malekjani
Given a \textit{model building} assumption on the (effective) equation of state (EoS) of the Universe, the Hubble constant $H_0$ arises as an integration constant when one solves the Friedmann equations. Therefore, while $H_0$ is \textit{mathematically} a constant, it need not be a constant \textit{observationally}, unless the EoS or model accurately describes the Universe. Building on earlier results, we show that redshift evolution of flat $\Lambda$CDM cosmological parameters $(H_0, \Omega_{m})$ persists in the most up-to-date Pantheon+ sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST Discovery of Dust Reservoirs in Nearby Type IIP Supernovae 2004et and 2017eaw</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_discovery_of_dust_reservoirs_in_nearby_type_iip_supernovae_2004et_and_2017eaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_discovery_of_dust_reservoirs_in_nearby_type_iip_supernovae_2004et_and_2017eaw/</guid>
      <description>First author: Melissa Shahbandeh
Supernova (SN) explosions have been sought for decades as a possible source of dust in the Universe, providing the seeds of galaxies, stars, and planetary systems. SN 1987A offers one of the most promising examples of significant SN dust formation, but until the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), instruments have traditionally lacked the sensitivity at both late times (&amp;gt;1 yr post-explosion) and longer wavelengths (i.e., &amp;gt;10 um) to detect analogous dust reservoirs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiative Acceleration of Dense Circumstellar Material in Interacting Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiative_acceleration_of_dense_circumstellar_material_in_interacting_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radiative_acceleration_of_dense_circumstellar_material_in_interacting_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daichi Tsuna
Early-time light curves/spectra of some hydrogen-rich supernovae (SNe) give firm evidence on the existence of confined, dense circumstellar matter (CSM) surrounding dying massive stars. We numerically and analytically study radiative acceleration of CSM in such systems, where the radiation is mainly powered by the interaction between the SN ejecta and the CSM. We find that the acceleration of the ambient CSM is larger for massive and compact CSM, with velocities reaching up to $\sim 10^3\ {\rm km\ s^{-1}}$ for a CSM of order $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles of fast neutrino-flavor conversion on the neutrino-heating mechanism of core-collapse supernova</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/roles_of_fast_neutrino-flavor_conversion_on_the_neutrino-heating_mechanism_of_core-collapse_supernova/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/roles_of_fast_neutrino-flavor_conversion_on_the_neutrino-heating_mechanism_of_core-collapse_supernova/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hiroki Nagakura
One of the greatest uncertainties in any modeling of inner engine of core-collapse supernova (CCSN) is neutrino flavor conversions driven by neutrino self-interactions. We carry out large-scale numerical simulations of multi-energy, multi-angle, three-flavor framework, and general relativistic quantum kinetic neutrino transport in spherical symmetry with an essential set of neutrino-matter interactions under a realistic fluid profile of CCSN. Our result suggests that the neutrino heating in the gain region is reduced by $\sim 50%$ due to fast neutrino-flavor conversion (FFC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The optical light curve of GRB 221009A: the afterglow and detection of the emerging supernova SN 2022xiw</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_optical_light_curve_of_grb_221009a_the_afterglow_and_detection_of_the_emerging_supernova_sn_2022xiw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_optical_light_curve_of_grb_221009a_the_afterglow_and_detection_of_the_emerging_supernova_sn_2022xiw/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. D. Fulton
We present extensive optical photometry of the afterglow of GRB 221009A. Our data cover $0.9 - 59.9$ days from the time of Swift and Fermi GRB detections. Photometry in $rizy$-band filters was collected primarily with Pan-STARRS and supplemented by multiple 1- to 4-meter imaging facilities. We analyzed the Swift X-ray data of the afterglow and found a single decline rate power-law $f(t) \propto t^{-1.556\pm0.002}$ best describes the light curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Coupling Constants&#39; Variation with Supernovae, Quasars, and GRBs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_coupling_constants_variation_with_supernovae_quasars_and_grbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_coupling_constants_variation_with_supernovae_quasars_and_grbs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rajendra P. Gupta
Dirac, in 1937 proposed the variation of coupling constants derived from his large number hypothesis. Efforts have continued since then to constrain their variation by various methods. We briefly discuss several methods used for the purpose while focusing primarily on the use of supernovae type 1a, quasars, and gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) as cosmological probes for determining cosmological distances. Supernovae type Ia (SNeIa) are considered the best standard candles since their intrinsic luminosity can be determined precisely from their light curves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadronic versus leptonic origin of gamma-ray emission from supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hadronic_versus_leptonic_origin_of_gamma-ray_emission_from_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hadronic_versus_leptonic_origin_of_gamma-ray_emission_from_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Corso
GeV and TeV emission from the forward shocks of supernova remnants (SNRs) indicates that they are capable particle accelerators, making them promising sources of Galactic cosmic rays (CRs). However, it remains uncertain whether this $\gamma$-ray emission arises primarily from the decay of neutral pions produced by very high energy hadrons, or from inverse-Compton and/or bremsstrahlung emission from relativistic leptons. By applying a semi-analytic approach to non-linear diffusive shock acceleration (NLDSA) and calculating the particle and photon spectra produced in different astrophysical environments, we parametrize the relative strength of hadronic and leptonic emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference of proto-neutron star properties in core-collapse supernovae from a gravitational-wave detector network</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_of_proto-neutron_star_properties_in_core-collapse_supernovae_from_a_gravitational-wave_detector_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inference_of_proto-neutron_star_properties_in_core-collapse_supernovae_from_a_gravitational-wave_detector_network/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Bruel
The next Galactic core-collapse supernova (CCSN) will be a unique opportunity to study within a fully multi-messenger approach the explosion mechanism responsible for the formation of neutron stars and stellar-mass black holes. State-of-the-art numerical simulations of those events reveal the complexity of the gravitational-wave emission which is highly stochastic. This challenges the possibility to infer the properties of the compact remnant and of its progenitor using the information encoded in the waveforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Ia supernova constraints on compact object dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernova_constraints_on_compact_object_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/type_ia_supernova_constraints_on_compact_object_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Dhawan
The nature of dark matter (DM) is an open question in cosmology, despite its abundance in the universe. While elementary particles have been posited to explain DM, compact astrophysical objects such as black holes formed in the early universe offer a theoretically appealing alternate route. Here, we constrain the fraction of DM that can be made up of primordial black holes (PBHs) with masses $M \gtrsim 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSTM and CNN application for core-collapse supernova search in gravitational wave real data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lstm_and_cnn_application_for_core-collapse_supernova_search_in_gravitational_wave_real_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lstm_and_cnn_application_for_core-collapse_supernova_search_in_gravitational_wave_real_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alberto Iess
$Context.$ Core-collapse supernovae (CCSNe) are expected to emit gravitational wave signals that could be detected by current and future generation interferometers within the Milky Way and nearby galaxies. The stochastic nature of the signal arising from CCSNe requires alternative detection methods to matched filtering. $Aims.$ We aim to show the potential of machine learning (ML) for multi-label classification of different CCSNe simulated signals and noise transients using real data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The morphing of decay powered to interaction powered Type II supernova ejecta at nebular times</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_morphing_of_decay_powered_to_interaction_powered_type_ii_supernova_ejecta_at_nebular_times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_morphing_of_decay_powered_to_interaction_powered_type_ii_supernova_ejecta_at_nebular_times/</guid>
      <description>First author: Luc Dessart
Much excitement surrounds the intense mass loss that seems to take place in some massive stars immediately before core collapse. However, occurring too late, it has a negligible impact on the star&amp;rsquo;s evolution or the final yields, which are influenced instead by the longer-term, quasi-steady mass loss taking place during H and He burning. Late-time observations of core-collapse supernovae interacting with the progenitor wind are one means to constrain this secular mass loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarimetry of Hydrogen-Poor Superluminous Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarimetry_of_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarimetry_of_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Pursiainen
We present linear polarimetry for seven hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae (SLSNe-I). For SN 2017gci, for which we present two epochs of spectropolarimetry at +3 d and +29 d post-peak in rest frame, accompanied by four epochs of imaging polarimetry up to +108 d. The spectropolarimetry at +3 d shows increasing polarisation degree P towards the redder wavelengths and exhibits signs of axial symmetry, but at +29 d P=0 throughout the spectrum implying that the photosphere of SN 2017gci evolved from a slightly aspherical configuration to a more spherical one in the first month post-peak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernova model discrimination with a kilotonne-scale Gd-H$_{2}$O Cherenkov detector</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_model_discrimination_with_a_kilotonne-scale_gd-h__2_o_cherenkov_detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_model_discrimination_with_a_kilotonne-scale_gd-h__2_o_cherenkov_detector/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. Schnellbach
The supernova model discrimination capabilities of the WATCHMAN detector concept are explored. This cylindrical kilotonne-scale water Cherenkov detector design has been developed to detect reactor antineutrinos through inverse $\beta$-decay for non-proliferation applications but also has the ability to observe antineutrino bursts of core-collapse supernovae within our galaxy. Detector configurations with sizes ranging from 16 m to 22 m tank diameter and 10% to 20% PMT coverage are used to compare the expected observable antineutrino spectra based on the Nakazato, Vartanyan and Warren supernova models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resurrection of type IIL supernova 2018ivc: Implications for a binary evolution sequence connecting hydrogen-rich and -poor progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resurrection_of_type_iil_supernova_2018ivc_implications_for_a_binary_evolution_sequence_connecting_hydrogen-rich_and_-poor_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/resurrection_of_type_iil_supernova_2018ivc_implications_for_a_binary_evolution_sequence_connecting_hydrogen-rich_and_-poor_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Long-term observations of synchrotron emission from supernovae (SNe), covering more than a year after the explosion, provide a unique opportunity to study the poorly-understood evolution of massive stars in the final millennium of their lives via changes in the mass-loss rate. Here, we present a result of our long-term monitoring of a peculiar type IIL SN 2018ivc, using the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA). Following the initial decay, it showed unprecedented rebrightening starting at ~ a year after the explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong gravitational lensing and microlensing of supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_gravitational_lensing_and_microlensing_of_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/strong_gravitational_lensing_and_microlensing_of_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sherry H. Suyu
Strong gravitational lensing and microlensing of supernovae (SNe) are emerging as a new probe of cosmology and astrophysics in recent years. We provide an overview of this nascent research field, starting with a summary of the first discoveries of strongly lensed SNe. We describe the use of the time delays between multiple SN images as a way to measure cosmological distances and thus constrain cosmological parameters, particularly the Hubble constant, whose value is currently under heated debates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray polarimetry reveals the magnetic field topology on sub-parsec scales in Tycho&#39;s supernova remnant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_polarimetry_reveals_the_magnetic_field_topology_on_sub-parsec_scales_in_tychos_supernova_remnant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_polarimetry_reveals_the_magnetic_field_topology_on_sub-parsec_scales_in_tychos_supernova_remnant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Riccardo Ferrazzoli
Supernova remnants are commonly considered to produce most of the Galactic cosmic rays via diffusive shock acceleration. However, many questions about the physical conditions at shock fronts, such as the magnetic-field morphology close to the particle acceleration sites, remain open. Here we report the detection of a localized polarization signal from some synchrotron X-ray emitting regions of Tycho&amp;rsquo;s supernova remnant made by the Imaging X-ray Polarimetry Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Fast-spinning Neutron Stars in Close Binaries and Magnetar-driven Stripped-envelope Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_fast-spinning_neutron_stars_in_close_binaries_and_magnetar-driven_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_fast-spinning_neutron_stars_in_close_binaries_and_magnetar-driven_stripped-envelope_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rui-Chong Hu
Extreme stripped-envelope supernovae (SESNe), including Type Ic superluminous supernovae (SLSNe), broad-line Type Ic SNe (SNe Ic-BL), and fast blue optical transients (FBOTs), are widely believed to harbor a newborn fast-spinning highly-magnetized neutron star (``magnetar&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;), which can lose its rotational energy via spin-down processes to accelerate and heat the ejecta. The progenitor(s) of these magnetar-driven SESNe, and the origin of considerable angular momentum (AM) in the cores of massive stars to finally produce such fast-spinning magnetars upon core-collapse are still under debate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Waves from a Core g-Mode in Supernovae as Probes of the High-Density Equation of State</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_waves_from_a_core_g-mode_in_supernovae_as_probes_of_the_high-density_equation_of_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gravitational_waves_from_a_core_g-mode_in_supernovae_as_probes_of_the_high-density_equation_of_state/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pia Jakobus
Using relativistic supernova simulations of massive progenitor stars with a quark-hadron equation of state (EoS) and a purely hadronic EoS, we identify a distinctive feature in the gravitational-wave signal that originates from a buoyancy-driven mode (g-mode) below the proto-neutron star convection zone. The mode frequency lies in the range $200\lesssim f\lesssim 800,\text{Hz}$ and decreases with time. As the mode lives in the core of the proto-neutron star, its frequency and power are highly sensitive to the EoS, in particular the sound speed around twice saturation density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical simulations of the random angular momentum in convection II: delayed explosions of red supergiants following &#34;failed&#39;&#39; supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_simulations_of_the_random_angular_momentum_in_convection_ii_delayed_explosions_of_red_supergiants_following_failed_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/numerical_simulations_of_the_random_angular_momentum_in_convection_ii_delayed_explosions_of_red_supergiants_following_failed_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrea Antoni
When collapse of the iron core in a massive red or yellow supergiant does not lead to a neutrino-driven explosion, a significant fraction of the convective hydrogen envelope will fall in towards the black hole formed from the collapsing core. The random velocity field in the convective envelope results in finite specific angular momentum in each infalling shell. Using 3D hydrodynamical simulations, we follow the infall of this material to small radii, resolving the circularization radii of the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The implications of large binding energies of massive stripped core collapse supernova progenitors on the explosion mechanism</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_implications_of_large_binding_energies_of_massive_stripped_core_collapse_supernova_progenitors_on_the_explosion_mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_implications_of_large_binding_energies_of_massive_stripped_core_collapse_supernova_progenitors_on_the_explosion_mechanism/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dmitry Shishkin
We examine the binding energy of massive stripped-envelope core collapse supernova (SECCSN) progenitors with the stellar evolution code MESA, and find that only the jittering jets explosion mechanism can account for explosions where carbon-oxygen cores with masses of $&amp;gt;20M_\odot$ collapse to leave a neutron star (NS) remnant. We calculate the binding energy at core collapse under the assumption that the remnant is a NS. Namely, stellar gas above mass coordinate of $~1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path from the Chinese and Japanese Observations of Supernova 1181 AD, to a Type Iax Supernova, to the Merger of CO and ONe White Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_path_from_the_chinese_and_japanese_observations_of_supernova_1181_ad_to_a_type_iax_supernova_to_the_merger_of_co_and_one_white_dwarfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_path_from_the_chinese_and_japanese_observations_of_supernova_1181_ad_to_a_type_iax_supernova_to_the_merger_of_co_and_one_white_dwarfs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bradley E. Schaefer
In 1181 AD, Chinese and Japanese observers reported a bright Guest Star&#39; in the constellation Chuanshe, unmoving and visible for 185 days. In 2013, D. Patchick discovered a unique nebula surrounding a unique star, with two groups attributing this structure, named Pa 30&amp;rsquo;, to be the supernova remnant of SN 1181, as a sub-subclass of supernova, the low-luminosity Type Iax. Here, I provide a wide range of new observational evidence: First, a detailed analysis of the original Chinese and Japanese reports places the `Guest Star&amp;rsquo; of 1181 into a small region with the only interesting source being Pa 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Study of Ia-CSM Supernovae from the ZTF Bright Transient Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_systematic_study_of_ia-csm_supernovae_from_the_ztf_bright_transient_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_systematic_study_of_ia-csm_supernovae_from_the_ztf_bright_transient_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yashvi Sharma
Among the supernovae (SNe) that show strong interaction with the circumstellar medium, there is a rare subclass of Type Ia supernovae, SNe Ia-CSM, that show strong narrow hydrogen emission lines much like SNe IIn but on top of a diluted over-luminous Type Ia spectrum. In the only previous systematic study of this class (Silverman et al. 2013), 16 objects were identified, 8 historic and 8 from the Palomar Transient Factory (PTF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2020bio: A Double-peaked Type IIb Supernova with Evidence of Early-time Circumstellar Interaction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2020bio_a_double-peaked_type_iib_supernova_with_evidence_of_early-time_circumstellar_interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2020bio_a_double-peaked_type_iib_supernova_with_evidence_of_early-time_circumstellar_interaction/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Pellegrino
We present photometric and spectroscopic observations of SN 2020bio, a double-peaked Type IIb supernova (SN) discovered within a day of explosion, primarily obtained by Las Cumbres Observatory and Swift. SN 2020bio displays a rapid and long-lasting initial decline throughout the first week of its light curve, similar to other well-studied Type IIb SNe. This early-time emission is thought to originate from the cooling of the extended outer envelope of the progenitor star that is shock-heated by the SN explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Core Normal Type Ia Supernova 2019np: An Overall Spherical Explosion with an Aspherical Surface Layer and an Aspherical 56Ni Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_core_normal_type_ia_supernova_2019np_an_overall_spherical_explosion_with_an_aspherical_surface_layer_and_an_aspherical_56ni_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_core_normal_type_ia_supernova_2019np_an_overall_spherical_explosion_with_an_aspherical_surface_layer_and_an_aspherical_56ni_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Hoeflich
Optical spectropolarimetry of the normal thermonuclear supernova SN2019np from -14.5 to +14.5 days relative to B-band maximum detected an intrinsic continuum polarization, p(cont), of 0.21+-0.09% at the first epoch. Between days -11.5 to +05, p(cont) remained about 0 and by day +14.5 was again significant at 0.19+-0.10%. Not considering the first epoch, the dominant axis of SiII(6355A) was roughly constant, staying close to the continuum until both rotated in opposite directions on day +14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic rate of type IIn supernovae and its evolution with redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_rate_of_type_iin_supernovae_and_its_evolution_with_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_rate_of_type_iin_supernovae_and_its_evolution_with_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Cold
Type IIn supernovae potentially constitute a large fraction of the gravitationally lensed supernovae predicted to be found with upcoming facilities. However, the local rate is used for these estimates, which is assumed to be independent of properties such as the host galaxy mass. Some studies hint that a host galaxy mass bias may exist for IIn supernovae. This paper aims to provide an updated local IIn supernova-to-core-collapse ratio based on data from the Palomar Transient Factory (PTF) and the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) Bright Transient Survey (BTS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST Low-Resolution MIRI Spectral Observations of SN~2021aefx: High-density Burning in a Type Ia Supernova</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_low-resolution_miri_spectral_observations_of_sn~2021aefx_high-density_burning_in_a_type_ia_supernova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_low-resolution_miri_spectral_observations_of_sn~2021aefx_high-density_burning_in_a_type_ia_supernova/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. DerKacy
We present a JWST/MIRI low-resolution mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopic observation of the normal Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) SN 2021aefx at +323 days past rest-frame B-band maximum light. The spectrum ranges from 4-14 um, and shows many unique qualities including a flat-topped $[Ar III]$ 8.991 um profile, a strongly tilted $[Co III]$ 11.888 um feature, and multiple stable Ni lines. These features provide critical information about the physics of the explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective Search for Strongly Lensed Supernovae in the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/retrospective_search_for_strongly_lensed_supernovae_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/retrospective_search_for_strongly_lensed_supernovae_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Sheu
The introduction of deep wide-field surveys in recent years and the adoption of machine learning techniques have led to the discoveries of $\mathcal{O}(10^4)$ strong gravitational lensing systems and candidates. However, the discovery of multiply lensed transients remains a rarity. Lensed transients and especially lensed supernovae are invaluable tools to cosmology as they allow us to constrain cosmological parameters via lens modeling and the measurements of their time delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sculpting of rectangular and jet-like morphologies in supernova remnants by anisotropic equatorially-confined progenitor stellar winds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sculpting_of_rectangular_and_jet-like_morphologies_in_supernova_remnants_by_anisotropic_equatorially-confined_progenitor_stellar_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sculpting_of_rectangular_and_jet-like_morphologies_in_supernova_remnants_by_anisotropic_equatorially-confined_progenitor_stellar_winds/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. F. Velazquez
Thermonuclear and core-collapse supernova remnants (SNRs) are the nebular leftovers of defunct stars. Their morphology and emission properties provide insights into the evolutionary history of the progenitor star. But while some SNRs are spherical, as expected from a point-like explosion expanding into a roughly uniform medium, many others exhibit complex non-spherical morphologies which are often not easily explained. In this work, we use three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic simulations to show that rectangular and jet-like morphologies can be explained by supernovae (SNe), either type Ia or type II, expanding within anisotropic, bipolar stellar wind bubbles driven by the progenitor star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating the $^{56}$Ni Problem in Core-collapse Supernova Explosion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/updating_the__56_ni_problem_in_core-collapse_supernova_explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/updating_the__56_ni_problem_in_core-collapse_supernova_explosion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryo Sawada
Details of the core-collapse supernova (CCSN) explosion mechanism still need to be fully understood. There is an increasing number of successful examples of reproducing explosions in multidimensional hydrodynamic simulations, but subsequent studies pointed out that the growth rates of the explosion energy $\dot{E}\mathrm{expl}$ of these simulations are insufficient to produce enough $^{56}$Ni to match observations. This issue is known as the `$^{56}$Ni problem&#39; in CCSNe. Recently, however, some studies have suggested that this $^{56}$Ni problem is derived from the simplicity of the explosion model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of stellar rotation on the development of post-shock instabilities during core-collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effect_of_stellar_rotation_on_the_development_of_post-shock_instabilities_during_core-collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effect_of_stellar_rotation_on_the_development_of_post-shock_instabilities_during_core-collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. -C. Buellet
The growth of instabilities is key to trigger a supernova explosion during the phase of stalled shock, immediately after the birth of a proto-neutron star (PNS). We assess the effect of stellar rotation on neutrino-driven convection and SASI when neutrino heating is taken into account. Rotation affects the frequency of the mode m=2 detectable with gravitational waves (GW). We use a linear stability analysis in the equatorial plane between the PNS and the stationary shock and consider a large range of specific angular momenta, neutrino luminosities and mass accretion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HST Proper Motion Measurements of Supernova Remnant N132D: Center of Expansion and Age</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_proper_motion_measurements_of_supernova_remnant_n132d_center_of_expansion_and_age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_proper_motion_measurements_of_supernova_remnant_n132d_center_of_expansion_and_age/</guid>
      <description>First author: John Banovetz
We present proper motion measurements of oxygen-rich ejecta of the LMC supernova remnant N132D using two epochs of Hubble Space Telescope Advanced Camera for Surveys data spanning 16 years. The proper motions of 120 individual knots of oxygen-rich gas were measured and used to calculate a center of expansion (CoE) of $\alpha$=05:25:01.71 and $\delta$=-69:38:41.64 (J2000) with a 1-$\sigma$ uncertainty of 2.90 arcseconds. This new CoE measurement is 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light-curves and nucleosynthesis of CNO-rp driven general relativistic instability supernovae in metal enriched supermassive protostars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light-curves_and_nucleosynthesis_of_cno-rp_driven_general_relativistic_instability_supernovae_in_metal_enriched_supermassive_protostars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light-curves_and_nucleosynthesis_of_cno-rp_driven_general_relativistic_instability_supernovae_in_metal_enriched_supermassive_protostars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chris Nagele
The assembly of supermassive black holes poses a challenge primarily because of observed quasars at high redshift, but additionally because of the current lack of observations of intermediate mass black holes. One plausible scenario for creating supermassive black holes is direct collapse triggered by the merger of two gas rich galaxies. This scenario allows the creation of supermassive stars with up to solar metallicity, where the enhanced metallicity is enabled by extremely rapid accretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven photometric redshift estimation from type Ia supernovae light curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_photometric_redshift_estimation_from_type_ia_supernovae_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_photometric_redshift_estimation_from_type_ia_supernovae_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Felipe M F de Oliveira
Redshift measurement has always been a constant need in modern astronomy and cosmology. And as new surveys have been providing an immense amount of data on astronomical objects, the need to process such data automatically proves to be increasingly necessary. In this article, we use simulated data from the Dark Energy Survey, and from a pipeline originally created to classify supernovae, we developed a linear regression algorithm optimized through novel automated machine learning (AutoML) frameworks achieving an error score better than ordinary data pre-processing methods when compared with other modern algorithms (such as XGBOOST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The $γ$-ray deposition histories of Calcium-rich supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the__%CE%B3_-ray_deposition_histories_of_calcium-rich_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the__%CE%B3_-ray_deposition_histories_of_calcium-rich_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amir Sharon
Calcium-rich supernovae (Ca-rich SNe) are faint, rapidly evolving transients whose progenitor system is yet to be determined. We derive the $\gamma$-ray deposition histories of five Ca-rich SNe from the literature in order to place constraints on possible progenitor systems. We find that the $ \gamma $-ray escape time, $ t_0 $, of the Ca-rich SNe sample is $\approx35$-$65 ,\rm{d}$, within the unoccupied region between Type Ia SNe and stripped envelope supernovae (SESNe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential signature of a quadrupolar Hubble expansion in Pantheon&#43; supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_signature_of_a_quadrupolar_hubble_expansion_in_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_signature_of_a_quadrupolar_hubble_expansion_in_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica A. Cowell
The assumption of isotropy &amp;ndash; that the Universe looks the same in all directions on large scales &amp;ndash; is fundamental to the standard cosmological model. This model forms the building blocks of essentially all of our cosmological knowledge to date. It is therefore critical to empirically test in which regimes its core assumptions hold. Anisotropies in the cosmic expansion are expected on small scales due to nonlinear structures in the late Universe, however, the extent to which these anisotropies might impact our low-redshift observations remains to be fully tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The environments of Type Ia supernovae with different relative equivalent width of Si II feature in their spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_environments_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_different_relative_equivalent_width_of_si_ii_feature_in_their_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_environments_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_different_relative_equivalent_width_of_si_ii_feature_in_their_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiang-Cun Meng
Although type Ia supernovae are so important in many astrophysical field, e.g. in cosmology, their explosion mechanism and progenitor system are still unclear. In physics, the relative equivalent width (REW) of the Si II 635.5 nm absorption feature reflects the velocity interval of silicon in the supernova ejecta and then may provide constraints on the explosion mechanism of SNe Ia. In this paper, we divide the SNe Ia into broad line (BL) and normal line (NL) subsamples based on their REW of Si II 635.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of Searching for Type Ia Supernovae with 2.5-m Wide Field Survey Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_of_searching_for_type_ia_supernovae_with_2.5-m_wide_field_survey_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_of_searching_for_type_ia_supernovae_with_2.5-m_wide_field_survey_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maokai Hu
Type Ia Supernovae (SNe Ia) are the thermonuclear explosion of a carbon-oxygen white dwarf (WD) and are well-known as a distance indicator. However, it is still unclear how WDs increase their mass near the Chandrasekhar limit and how the thermonuclear runaway happens. The observational clues associated with these open questions, such as the photometric data within hours to days since the explosion, are scarce. Thus, an essential way is to discover SNe Ia at specific epochs with optimal surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio and Gamma-ray Evidence for the Supernova Origin of High Velocity Cloud Complex M</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_gamma-ray_evidence_for_the_supernova_origin_of_high_velocity_cloud_complex_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_gamma-ray_evidence_for_the_supernova_origin_of_high_velocity_cloud_complex_m/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joan T. Schmelz
Using $\lambda$-21-cm galactic neutral atomic hydrogen data from the HI4PI survey of Bekhti et al. (2016) and 0.75-30 MeV $\gamma$-ray emission from the Imaging Compton Telescope, we have searched for the origin event that accelerated high velocity cloud Complex M. Radio plots of $l-b$, $l-v$, and $b-v$ show a cavity centered at ($l$, $b$) $\sim$ (150$^{\circ}$, 50.$^{\circ}$) and extending about $\pm$33$^{\circ}$. The best view of the cavity is at a velocity of -25 km s$^{-1}$, which shows a circular cross section on the back (receding) face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurring outbursts of the supernova impostor AT 2016blu in NGC 4559</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recurring_outbursts_of_the_supernova_impostor_at_2016blu_in_ngc_4559/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recurring_outbursts_of_the_supernova_impostor_at_2016blu_in_ngc_4559/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mojgan Aghakhanloo
We present the first analysis of photometric observations of the supernova (SN) impostor AT 2016blu located in the galaxy NGC 4559. This transient source was discovered by the Lick Observatory Supernova Search in January 2012 and has continued its eruptive variability since then. Photometry of AT 2016blu reveals at least 19 outbursts in 2012-2022. AT 2016blu&amp;rsquo;s outbursts show irregular variability with multiple closely spaced peaks of varying brightness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Late Time Optical Evolution of Twelve Core-Collapse Supernovae: Detection of Normal Stellar Winds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_late_time_optical_evolution_of_twelve_core-collapse_supernovae_detection_of_normal_stellar_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_late_time_optical_evolution_of_twelve_core-collapse_supernovae_detection_of_normal_stellar_winds/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Rizzo Smith
We analyze the late time evolution of 12 supernovae (SNe) occurring over the last ${\sim}$41 years, including nine Type IIP/L, two IIb, and one Ib/c, using UBVR optical data from the Large Binocular Telescope (LBT) and difference imaging. We see late time (5 to 42 years) emission from nine of the eleven Type II SNe (eight Type IIP/L, one IIb). We consider radioactive decay, circumstellar medium (CSM) interactions, pulsar/engine driven emission, dust echoes, and shock perturbed binary companions as possible sources of emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Supernovae in HETDEX Data Release 3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_supernovae_in_hetdex_data_release_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_supernovae_in_hetdex_data_release_3/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Vinko
We have extracted 636 spectra taken at the positions of 583 transient sources from the third Data Release of the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy eXperiment (HETDEX). The transients were discovered by the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) during 2018 - 2022. The HETDEX spectra are useful to classify a large number of objects found by photometric surveys for free. We attempt to explore and classify the spectra by utilizing machine learning (ML) and template matching techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminating a common envelope jets supernova impostor event with a super-Eddington blue supergiant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/terminating_a_common_envelope_jets_supernova_impostor_event_with_a_super-eddington_blue_supergiant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/terminating_a_common_envelope_jets_supernova_impostor_event_with_a_super-eddington_blue_supergiant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tamar Cohen
We conducted one-dimensional stellar evolutionary numerical simulations to build blue supergiant stellar models with a very low-envelope mass and a super-Eddington luminosity of 10^7Lo that mimic the last phase of a common envelope evolution (CEE) where a neutron star (NS) accretes mass from the envelope and launches jets that power the system. Common envelope jets supernovae (CEJSNe) are CEE transient events where a NS spirals-in inside the envelope and then the core of a red supergiant (RSG) star accretes mass and launches jets that power the transient event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical polarization and spectral properties of the H-poor superluminous supernovae SN 2021bnw and SN 2021fpl</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_polarization_and_spectral_properties_of_the_h-poor_superluminous_supernovae_sn_2021bnw_and_sn_2021fpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_polarization_and_spectral_properties_of_the_h-poor_superluminous_supernovae_sn_2021bnw_and_sn_2021fpl/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Poidevin
New optical photometric, spectrocopic and imaging polarimetry data are combined with publicly available data to study some of the physical properties of the two H-poor superluminous supernovae (SLSN) SN 2021bnw and SN 2021fpl. For each SLSN, the best-fit parameters obtained from the magnetar model with \texttt{MOSFiT} do not depart from the range of parameter obtained on other SLSNe discussed in the literature. A spectral analysis with \texttt{SYN++} shows that SN 2021bnw is a W Type, Fast evolver, while SN 2021fpl is a 15bn Type, Slow evolver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics and Equation of State Dependencies of Relevance for Nucleosynthesis in Supernovae and Neutron Star Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_and_equation_of_state_dependencies_of_relevance_for_nucleosynthesis_in_supernovae_and_neutron_star_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_and_equation_of_state_dependencies_of_relevance_for_nucleosynthesis_in_supernovae_and_neutron_star_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. -Thomas Janka
Neutron stars (NSs) and black holes (BHs) are born when the final collapse of the stellar core terminates the lives of stars more massive than about 9 Msun. This can trigger the powerful ejection of a large fraction of the star&amp;rsquo;s material in a core-collapse supernova (CCSN), whose extreme luminosity is energized by the decay of radioactive isotopes such as 56Ni and 56Co. When evolving in close binary systems, the compact relics of such infernal catastrophes spiral towards each other on orbits gradually decaying by gravitational-wave emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Supernovae as an Optically Thick Fireball</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_supernovae_as_an_optically_thick_fireball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_supernovae_as_an_optically_thick_fireball/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacob Marshall
We calculate the properties of 135 stellar supernovae using data from the Open Supernova Catalog. We generate temperatures, radii, luminosities, and expansion velocities using a spherically symmetric optically thick fireball model. These modeled parameters reveal trends that are common across different types of supernovae. We have identified distinct phases that appear across Type Ia, II, II P, and IIb supernovae. We note that there is a long period of reasonable continuous growth (Phase 1), giving credence to our simple model of an optically thick fireball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracer particles for core-collapse supernova nucleosynthesis: The advantages of moving backward</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer_particles_for_core-collapse_supernova_nucleosynthesis_the_advantages_of_moving_backward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer_particles_for_core-collapse_supernova_nucleosynthesis_the_advantages_of_moving_backward/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andre Sieverding
After decades, the theoretical study of core-collapse supernova explosions is moving from parameterized, spherically symmetric models to increasingly realistic multi-dimensional simulations. Obtaining nucleosynthesis yields based on such multi-dimensional core-collapse supernova (CCSN) simulations, however, is not straightforward and frequently tracer particles are employed. Tracer particles may be tracked in situ during the simulation, but often they are reconstructed in a post-processing step based on the information saved during the hydrodynamics simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2021fxy: Mid-Ultraviolet Flux Suppression is a Common Feature of Type Ia Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2021fxy_mid-ultraviolet_flux_suppression_is_a_common_feature_of_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2021fxy_mid-ultraviolet_flux_suppression_is_a_common_feature_of_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. DerKacy
We present ultraviolet (UV) to near-infrared (NIR) observations and analysis of the nearby Type Ia supernova SN 2021fxy. Our observations include UV photometry from Swift/UVOT, UV spectroscopy from HST/STIS, and high-cadence optical photometry with the Swope 1-m telescope capturing intra-night rises during the early light curve. Early $B-V$ colours show SN 2021fxy is the first &amp;ldquo;shallow-silicon&amp;rdquo; (SS) SN Ia to follow a red-to-blue evolution, compared to other SS objects which show blue colours from the earliest observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Spectra of Supernova Remnants in M83</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Frank Winkler
In order to better characterize the rich supernova remnant (SNR) population of M83 (NGC 5236), we have obtained high-resolution (about 85 km/s) spectra of 119 of the SNRs and SNR candidates in M83 with Gemini/GMOS, as well as new spectra of the young SNRs B12-174a and SN1957D. Most of the SNRs and SNR candidates have [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios that exceed 0.4. Combining these results with earlier studies we have carried out with MUSE and at lower spectroscopic resolution with GMOS, we have confirmed a total of 238 emission nebulae to be SNRs on the basis of their [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios, about half of which have emission lines that show velocity broadening greater than 100 km/s, providing a kinematic confirmation that they are SNRs and not H II regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repeating periodic eruptions of the supernova impostor SN 2000ch</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mojgan Aghakhanloo
We analyse photometric observations of the supernova (SN) impostor SN 2000ch in NGC 3432 covering the time since its discovery. This source was previously observed to have four outbursts in 2000&amp;ndash;2010. Observations now reveal at least two additional outbursts in 2004-2006, and ten outbursts in 2013-2022. Outburst light curves are irregular and multipeaked, exhibiting a wide variety of peak magnitude, duration, and shape. The more recent outbursts (after 2010) repeat with a period of $198.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernova 2020wnt: An Atypical Superluminous Supernova with a Hidden Central Engine</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samaporn Tinyanont
We present observations of a peculiar hydrogen- and helium-poor stripped-envelope (SE) supernova (SN) 2020wnt, primarily in the optical and near-infrared (near-IR). Its peak absolute bolometric magnitude of -20.9 mag and a rise time of 69~days are reminiscent of hydrogen-poor superluminous SNe (SLSNe~I), luminous transients potentially powered by spinning-down magnetars. Before the main peak, there is a brief peak lasting &amp;lt;10 days post-explosion, likely caused by interaction with circumstellar medium (CSM) ejected ~years before the SN explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The disappearances of six supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Schuyler D. Van Dyk
As part of a larger completed Hubble Space Telescope (HST) Snapshot program, we observed the sites of six nearby core-collapse supernovae (SNe) at high spatial resolution: SN 2012A, SN 2013ej, SN 2016gkg, SN 2017eaw, SN 2018zd, and SN 2018aoq. These observations were all conducted at sufficiently late times in each SN&amp;rsquo;s evolution to demonstrate that the massive-star progenitor candidate identified in each case in pre-explosion imaging data had indeed vanished and was therefore most likely the actual progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for supernova feedback sustaining gas turbulence in nearby star-forming galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
HI and CO observations indicate that the cold gas in galaxies is very turbulent. However, the turbulent energy is expected to be quickly dissipated, implying that some energy source is needed to explain the observations. The nature of such turbulence was long unclear, as even the main candidate, supernova (SN) feedback, seemed insufficient. Other mechanisms have been proposed, but without reaching a general consensus. The key novelty of our work is considering that the gas disc thickness and flaring increase the dissipation timescale of turbulence, thus reducing the energy injection rate required to sustain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard X-ray Observations of the Hydrogen-poor Superluminous Supernova SN 2018hti with NuSTAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Igor Andreoni
Some Hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae are likely powered by a magnetar central engine, making their luminosity larger than common supernovae. Although a significant amount of X-ray flux is expected from the spin down of the magnetar, direct observational evidence is still to be found, giving rise to the &amp;ldquo;missing energy&amp;rdquo; problem. Here we present NuSTAR observations of nearby SN 2018hti 2.4y (rest frame) after its optical peak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferencing Progenitor and Explosion Properties of Evolving Core-collapse Supernovae from Zwicky Transient Facility Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bhagya M. Subrayan
We analyze a sample of 45 Type II supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) public survey using a grid of hydrodynamical models in order to assess whether theoretically-driven forecasts can intelligently guide follow up observations supporting all-sky survey alert streams. We estimate several progenitor properties and explosion physics parameters including zero-age-main-sequence (ZAMS) mass, mass-loss rate, kinetic energy, 56Ni mass synthesized, host extinction, and the time of explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at supernovae as seeds for galactic magnetization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_closer_look_at_supernovae_as_seeds_for_galactic_magnetization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_closer_look_at_supernovae_as_seeds_for_galactic_magnetization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Evangelia Ntormousi
Explaining the currently observed magnetic fields in galaxies requires relatively strong seeding in the early Universe. One theory proposes that magnetic fields of the order of $\mu$G were expelled by supernova (SN) explosions after primordial, nG or weaker fields were amplified in stellar interiors. In this work, we calculate the maximum magnetic energy that can be injected in the interstellar medium by a stellar cluster of mass $M_{cl}$ based on what is currently known about stellar magnetism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peering into the Milky Way by FAST: IV. Identification of two new Galactic supernova remnants G203.1&#43;6.6 and G206.7&#43;5.9</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peering_into_the_milky_way_by_fast_iv._identification_of_two_new_galactic_supernova_remnants_g203.1&#43;6.6_and_g206.7&#43;5.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peering_into_the_milky_way_by_fast_iv._identification_of_two_new_galactic_supernova_remnants_g203.1&#43;6.6_and_g206.7&#43;5.9/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xuyang Gao
A $5^{\circ} \times 7^{\circ}$ sky area containing two large radio structures of G203.1+6.6 and G206.7+5.9 with a size of about 2.5$^{\circ}$ and 3.5$^{\circ}$ respectively is scanned by using the L-band 19-beam receiver of the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope (FAST). The FAST L-band receiver covers a frequency range of 1.0 GHz $-$ 1.5 GHz. Commissioning of the receiving system, including the measurements of the half-power beam width, gain, and main-beam efficiency is made by observing the calibrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing a supernova&#39;s Standing Accretion Shock Instability with neutrinos and gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zidu Lin
We perform a novel multi-messenger analysis for the identification and parameter estimation of the Standing Accretion Shock Instability (SASI) in a core collapse supernova with neutrino and gravitational wave (GW) signals. In the neutrino channel, this method performs a likelihood ratio test for the presence of SASI in the frequency domain. For gravitational wave signals we process an event with a modified constrained likelihood method. Using simulated supernova signals, the properties of the Hyper-Kamiokande neutrino detector, and O3 LIGO Interferometric data, we produce the two-dimensional probability density distribution (PDF) of the SASI activity indicator and calculate the probability of detection $P_\mathrm{D}$ as well as the false identification probability $P_\mathrm{FI}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of the 4.4-MeV gamma rays from $^{16}$O($ν, ν^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O(12.97 ${\rm MeV}, 2^-)$ with a water-Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Makoto Sakuda
We first discuss and determine the isospin mixing of the two $2^-$ states (12.53 MeV and 12.97 MeV) of $^{16}$O nucleus using the inelastic electron scattering data. We then evaluate the cross section of 4.4-MeV $\gamma$ rays produced in the neutrino neutral-current (NC) reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(12.97~{\rm MeV}, 2^-$) in a water Cherenkov detector at the low energy below 100 MeV. The detection of $\gamma$ rays for $E_{\gamma}&amp;gt;5$~MeV from the NC reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(E_x&amp;gt;16\ {\rm MeV}, T=1$) with a water Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts has been proposed and discussed by several authors previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A BayeSN Distance Ladder: $H_0$ from a consistent modelling of Type Ia supernovae from the optical to the near infrared</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suhail Dhawan
The local distance ladder estimate of the Hubble constant ($H_0$) is important in cosmology, given the recent tension with the early universe inference. We estimate $H_0$ from the Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) distance ladder, inferring SN Ia distances with the hierarchical Bayesian SED model, BayeSN. This method has a notable advantage of being able to continuously model the optical and near-infrared (NIR) SN Ia light curves simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonthermal processes and particle acceleration in supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacco Vink
Shocks of supernova remnants (SNRs) accelerate charged particles up to 100 TeV range via diffusive shock acceleration (DSA) mechanism. It is believed that shocks of SNRs are the main contributors to the pool of Galactic cosmic rays, although it is still under debate whether they can accelerate particles up to the &amp;ldquo;knee&amp;rdquo; energy (10^15.5 eV) or not. In this chapter, we start with introducing SNRs as likely sources of cosmic rays and the radiation mechanisms associated with cosmic rays (section 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1): Light Curves and Photometric Classification of 1975 Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. D. Aleo
We present the Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1), comprised of processed multi-color Pan-STARRS1 (PS1) griz and Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) gr photometry of 1975 transients with host-galaxy associations, redshifts, spectroscopic/photometric classifications, and additional data products from 2019 November 24 to 2021 December 20. YSE DR1 spans discoveries and observations from young and fast-rising supernovae (SNe) to transients that persist for over a year, with a redshift distribution reaching z~0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the evolution of Type Ia supernovae with their ejecta velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. -C. Pan
There is growing evidence that Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are likely produced via multiple explosion channels. Understanding how different channels evolve with redshift is critical in determining their precision in measuring cosmological parameters. Previous studies indicated that SN Ia ejecta velocity is one powerful tool to differentiate between different channels. It was also suspected that the tight correlation with the host-galaxy environment could result in the evolution of SN ejecta velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A JWST Near- and Mid-Infrared Nebular Spectrum of the Type Ia Supernova 2021aefx</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_near-_and_mid-infrared_nebular_spectrum_of_the_type_ia_supernova_2021aefx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_near-_and_mid-infrared_nebular_spectrum_of_the_type_ia_supernova_2021aefx/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lindsey A. Kwok
We present JWST near- and mid-infrared spectroscopic observations of the nearby normal Type Ia supernova SN 2021aefx in the nebular phase at $+255$ days past maximum light. Our Near Infrared Spectrograph (NIRSpec) and Mid Infrared Instrument (MIRI) observations, combined with ground-based optical data from the South African Large Telescope (SALT), constitute the first complete optical $+$ NIR $+$ MIR nebular SN Ia spectrum covering 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-gas phases in supernova remnant IC 443: Mapping shocked H$_2$ with VLT/KMOS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-gas_phases_in_supernova_remnant_ic_443_mapping_shocked_h__2__with_vlt_kmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-gas_phases_in_supernova_remnant_ic_443_mapping_shocked_h__2__with_vlt_kmos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yunwei Deng
Supernovae and their remnants provide energetic feedback to the ambient interstellar medium (ISM), which is often distributed in multiple gas phases. Among them, warm molecular hydrogen (H$_2$) often dominates the cooling of the shocked molecular ISM, which has been observed with the H$_2$ emission lines at near-infrared wavelengths. Such studies, however, were either limited in narrow filter imaging or sparsely sampled mid-infrared spectroscopic observations with relatively poor angular resolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Rubin Observatory cadence choices on supernovae photometric classification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_rubin_observatory_cadence_choices_on_supernovae_photometric_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_rubin_observatory_cadence_choices_on_supernovae_photometric_classification/</guid>
      <description>First author: Catarina S. Alves
The Vera C. Rubin Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST) will discover an unprecedented number of supernovae (SNe), making spectroscopic classification for all the events infeasible. LSST will thus rely on photometric classification, whose accuracy depends on the not-yet-finalized LSST observing strategy. In this work, we analyze the impact of cadence choices on classification performance using simulated multi-band light curves. First, we simulate SNe with an LSST baseline cadence, a non-rolling cadence, and a presto-color cadence which observes each sky location three times per night instead of twice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$Hubble~Space~Telescope$ Reveals Spectacular Light Echoes Associated with the Stripped-envelope Supernova 2016adj in the Iconic Dust Lane of Centaurus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maximilian Stritzinger
We present a multi-band sequence of $Hubble~Space~Telescope$ images documenting the emergence and evolution of multiple light echoes (LEs) linked to the stripped-envelope supernova (SN) 2016adj located in the central dust-lane of Centaurus A. Following point-spread function subtraction, we identify the earliest LE emission associated with a SN at only $+$34 days (d) past the epoch of $B$-band maximum. Additional HST images extending through $+$578 d cover the evolution of LE1 taking the form of a ring, while images taken on $+$1991 d reveals not only LE1, but also segments of a new inner LE ring (LE2) as well as two additional outer LE rings (LE3 &amp;amp; LE4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of post-kick jets in core collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Noam Soker
I argue that the assumption that the jets that shape the axisymmetrical morphological features of core collapse supernova (CCSN) remnants are post-kick jets, i.e., the neutron star (NS) launches these jets after the explosion and after it acquired its natal kick velocity, leads to the conclusion that the pre-collapse cores of CCSN progenitors have sufficient angular momentum fluctuations to support jittering jets that explode the star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Type Iax Supernova 2019muj in the Late Phase: Existence, Nature and Origin of the Iron-rich Dense Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Type Iax Supernovae (SNe Iax) form a class of peculiar SNe Ia, whose early-phase spectra share main spectral line identifications with canonical SNe Ia but with higher ionization and much lower line velocities. Their late-time behaviors deviate from usual SNe Ia in many respects; SNe Iax keep showing photospheric spectra over several 100 days and the luminosity decline is very slow. In the present work, we study the late-time spectra of SN Iax 2019muj including a newly-presented spectrum at ~500 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Black-Hole Excision Scheme for General Relativistic Core-Collapse Supernova Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Sykes
Fallback supernovae and the collapsar scenario for long-gamma ray burst and hypernovae have received considerable interest as pathways to black-hole formation and extreme transient events. Consistent simulations of these scenarios require a general relativistic treatment and need to deal appropriately with the formation of a singularity. Free evolution schemes for the Einstein equations can handle the formation of black holes by means of excision or puncture schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapse of rotating massive stars leading to black hole formation and energetic supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapse_of_rotating_massive_stars_leading_to_black_hole_formation_and_energetic_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapse_of_rotating_massive_stars_leading_to_black_hole_formation_and_energetic_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sho Fujibayashi
We explore a possible scenario of the explosion as a result of core collapses of rotating massive stars that leave a black hole by performing a radiation-viscous-hydrodynamics simulation in numerical relativity. We take moderately and rapidly rotating compact pre-collapse stellar models derived in stellar evolution calculations as the initial conditions. We find that the viscous heating in the disk formed around the central black hole powers an outflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Curves of Type IIP Supernovae from Neutrino-driven Explosions of Red Supergiants Obtained by a Semi-analytic Approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_type_iip_supernovae_from_neutrino-driven_explosions_of_red_supergiants_obtained_by_a_semi-analytic_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_type_iip_supernovae_from_neutrino-driven_explosions_of_red_supergiants_obtained_by_a_semi-analytic_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuai Zha
Type IIP supernovae (SNe IIP) mark the explosive death of red supergiants (RSGs), evolved massive stars with an extended hydrogen envelope. They are the most common supernova type and allow for benchmarking of supernova explosion models by statistical comparison to observed population properties rather than comparing individual models and events. We construct a large synthetic set of SNe IIP light curves (LCs) using the radiation hydrodynamics code \texttt{SNEC} and explosion energies and nickel masses obtained from an efficient semi-analytic model for two different sets of stellar progenitor models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength studies of G298.6$-$0.0: An old GeV supernova remnant interacting with molecular clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_studies_of_g298.6_-_0.0_an_old_gev_supernova_remnant_interacting_with_molecular_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_studies_of_g298.6_-_0.0_an_old_gev_supernova_remnant_interacting_with_molecular_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paul K. H. Yeung
Hadronic $\gamma$-ray sources associated with supernova remnants (SNRs) can serve as stopwatches for the escape of cosmic rays from SNRs, which gradually develops from highest-energy particles to lowest-energy particles with time. In this work, we analyze the 13.7~yr \emph{Fermi}-LAT data to investigate the $\gamma$-ray feature in/around the SNR G298.6$-$0.0 region. With $\gamma$-ray spatial analyses, we detect three point-like components. Among them, Src-NE is at the eastern SNR shell, and Src-NW is adjacent to the western edge of this SNR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarized radio emission unveils the structure of the pre-supernova circumstellar magnetic field and the radio emission in SN1987A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. Petruk
The detected polarized radio emission from remnant of SN1987A opens the possibility to unveil the structure of the pre-supernova magnetic field in the circumstellar medium. Properties derived from direct measurements would be of importance for understanding the progenitor stars and their magnetic fields. As the first step to this goal, we adopted the hydrodynamic data from an elaborated three-dimensional (3-D) numerical model of SN1987A. We have developed an approximate method for reconstruction&#39; of 3-D magnetic field structure inside supernova remnant on the hydrodynamic background&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prevalence and influence of circumstellar material around hydrogen-rich supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_prevalence_and_influence_of_circumstellar_material_around_hydrogen-rich_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_prevalence_and_influence_of_circumstellar_material_around_hydrogen-rich_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rachel J. Bruch
Spectroscopic detection of transient narrow emission lines (flash-ionisation features) traces the presence of circumstellar material (CSM) around massive stars exploding as core-collapse supernovae. Transient emission lines disappearing shortly after the SN explosion suggest that the spatial extent of this material is compact; hence implying that the progenitor star experienced episodes of enhanced mass loss shortly prior to explosion. The early light curves of Type II supernovae (SNe II) are assumed to be initially powered by shock-cooling emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Type Ibn Supernova 2019kbj -- Indications for Diversity in Type Ibn Supernova Progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ibn_supernova_2019kbj_--_indications_for_diversity_in_type_ibn_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ibn_supernova_2019kbj_--_indications_for_diversity_in_type_ibn_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tom Ben-Ami
Type Ibn supernovae (SNe) are a rare class of stellar explosions whose progenitor systems are not yet well determined. We present and analyze observations of the Type Ibn SN 2019kbj, and model its light curve in order to constrain its progenitor and explosion parameters. SN 2019kbj shows roughly constant temperature during the first month after peak, indicating a power source (likely CSM interaction) that keeps the continuum emission hot at ~15000K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three dimensional magnetorotational core-collapse supernova explosions of a 39 solar mass progenitor star</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jade Powell
We perform three-dimensional simulations of magnetorotational supernovae using a $39,M_{\odot}$ progenitor star with two different initial magnetic field strengths of $10^{10}$ G and $10^{12}$ G in the core. Both models rapidly undergo shock revival and their explosion energies asymptote within a few hundred milliseconds to values of $\gtrsim 2\times10^{51}$ erg after conservatively correcting for the binding energy of the envelope. Magnetically collimated, non-relativistic jets form in both models, though the jets are subject to non-axisymmetric instabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
