<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in supernovae on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/supernovae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic rate of type IIn supernovae and its evolution with redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_rate_of_type_iin_supernovae_and_its_evolution_with_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_rate_of_type_iin_supernovae_and_its_evolution_with_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Cold
Type IIn supernovae potentially constitute a large fraction of the gravitationally lensed supernovae predicted to be found with upcoming facilities. However, the local rate is used for these estimates, which is assumed to be independent of properties such as the host galaxy mass. Some studies hint that a host galaxy mass bias may exist for IIn supernovae. This paper aims to provide an updated local IIn supernova-to-core-collapse ratio based on data from the Palomar Transient Factory (PTF) and the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) Bright Transient Survey (BTS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWST Low-Resolution MIRI Spectral Observations of SN~2021aefx: High-density Burning in a Type Ia Supernova</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_low-resolution_miri_spectral_observations_of_sn~2021aefx_high-density_burning_in_a_type_ia_supernova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/jwst_low-resolution_miri_spectral_observations_of_sn~2021aefx_high-density_burning_in_a_type_ia_supernova/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. DerKacy
We present a JWST/MIRI low-resolution mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopic observation of the normal Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) SN 2021aefx at +323 days past rest-frame B-band maximum light. The spectrum ranges from 4-14 um, and shows many unique qualities including a flat-topped $[Ar III]$ 8.991 um profile, a strongly tilted $[Co III]$ 11.888 um feature, and multiple stable Ni lines. These features provide critical information about the physics of the explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective Search for Strongly Lensed Supernovae in the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/retrospective_search_for_strongly_lensed_supernovae_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/retrospective_search_for_strongly_lensed_supernovae_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Sheu
The introduction of deep wide-field surveys in recent years and the adoption of machine learning techniques have led to the discoveries of $\mathcal{O}(10^4)$ strong gravitational lensing systems and candidates. However, the discovery of multiply lensed transients remains a rarity. Lensed transients and especially lensed supernovae are invaluable tools to cosmology as they allow us to constrain cosmological parameters via lens modeling and the measurements of their time delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sculpting of rectangular and jet-like morphologies in supernova remnants by anisotropic equatorially-confined progenitor stellar winds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sculpting_of_rectangular_and_jet-like_morphologies_in_supernova_remnants_by_anisotropic_equatorially-confined_progenitor_stellar_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_sculpting_of_rectangular_and_jet-like_morphologies_in_supernova_remnants_by_anisotropic_equatorially-confined_progenitor_stellar_winds/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. F. Velazquez
Thermonuclear and core-collapse supernova remnants (SNRs) are the nebular leftovers of defunct stars. Their morphology and emission properties provide insights into the evolutionary history of the progenitor star. But while some SNRs are spherical, as expected from a point-like explosion expanding into a roughly uniform medium, many others exhibit complex non-spherical morphologies which are often not easily explained. In this work, we use three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic simulations to show that rectangular and jet-like morphologies can be explained by supernovae (SNe), either type Ia or type II, expanding within anisotropic, bipolar stellar wind bubbles driven by the progenitor star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating the $^{56}$Ni Problem in Core-collapse Supernova Explosion</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/updating_the__56_ni_problem_in_core-collapse_supernova_explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/updating_the__56_ni_problem_in_core-collapse_supernova_explosion/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ryo Sawada
Details of the core-collapse supernova (CCSN) explosion mechanism still need to be fully understood. There is an increasing number of successful examples of reproducing explosions in multidimensional hydrodynamic simulations, but subsequent studies pointed out that the growth rates of the explosion energy $\dot{E}\mathrm{expl}$ of these simulations are insufficient to produce enough $^{56}$Ni to match observations. This issue is known as the `$^{56}$Ni problem&#39; in CCSNe. Recently, however, some studies have suggested that this $^{56}$Ni problem is derived from the simplicity of the explosion model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of stellar rotation on the development of post-shock instabilities during core-collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effect_of_stellar_rotation_on_the_development_of_post-shock_instabilities_during_core-collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effect_of_stellar_rotation_on_the_development_of_post-shock_instabilities_during_core-collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. -C. Buellet
The growth of instabilities is key to trigger a supernova explosion during the phase of stalled shock, immediately after the birth of a proto-neutron star (PNS). We assess the effect of stellar rotation on neutrino-driven convection and SASI when neutrino heating is taken into account. Rotation affects the frequency of the mode m=2 detectable with gravitational waves (GW). We use a linear stability analysis in the equatorial plane between the PNS and the stationary shock and consider a large range of specific angular momenta, neutrino luminosities and mass accretion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HST Proper Motion Measurements of Supernova Remnant N132D: Center of Expansion and Age</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_proper_motion_measurements_of_supernova_remnant_n132d_center_of_expansion_and_age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hst_proper_motion_measurements_of_supernova_remnant_n132d_center_of_expansion_and_age/</guid>
      <description>First author: John Banovetz
We present proper motion measurements of oxygen-rich ejecta of the LMC supernova remnant N132D using two epochs of Hubble Space Telescope Advanced Camera for Surveys data spanning 16 years. The proper motions of 120 individual knots of oxygen-rich gas were measured and used to calculate a center of expansion (CoE) of $\alpha$=05:25:01.71 and $\delta$=-69:38:41.64 (J2000) with a 1-$\sigma$ uncertainty of 2.90 arcseconds. This new CoE measurement is 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light-curves and nucleosynthesis of CNO-rp driven general relativistic instability supernovae in metal enriched supermassive protostars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light-curves_and_nucleosynthesis_of_cno-rp_driven_general_relativistic_instability_supernovae_in_metal_enriched_supermassive_protostars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light-curves_and_nucleosynthesis_of_cno-rp_driven_general_relativistic_instability_supernovae_in_metal_enriched_supermassive_protostars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chris Nagele
The assembly of supermassive black holes poses a challenge primarily because of observed quasars at high redshift, but additionally because of the current lack of observations of intermediate mass black holes. One plausible scenario for creating supermassive black holes is direct collapse triggered by the merger of two gas rich galaxies. This scenario allows the creation of supermassive stars with up to solar metallicity, where the enhanced metallicity is enabled by extremely rapid accretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven photometric redshift estimation from type Ia supernovae light curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_photometric_redshift_estimation_from_type_ia_supernovae_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/data-driven_photometric_redshift_estimation_from_type_ia_supernovae_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Felipe M F de Oliveira
Redshift measurement has always been a constant need in modern astronomy and cosmology. And as new surveys have been providing an immense amount of data on astronomical objects, the need to process such data automatically proves to be increasingly necessary. In this article, we use simulated data from the Dark Energy Survey, and from a pipeline originally created to classify supernovae, we developed a linear regression algorithm optimized through novel automated machine learning (AutoML) frameworks achieving an error score better than ordinary data pre-processing methods when compared with other modern algorithms (such as XGBOOST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The $γ$-ray deposition histories of Calcium-rich supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the__%CE%B3_-ray_deposition_histories_of_calcium-rich_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the__%CE%B3_-ray_deposition_histories_of_calcium-rich_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amir Sharon
Calcium-rich supernovae (Ca-rich SNe) are faint, rapidly evolving transients whose progenitor system is yet to be determined. We derive the $\gamma$-ray deposition histories of five Ca-rich SNe from the literature in order to place constraints on possible progenitor systems. We find that the $ \gamma $-ray escape time, $ t_0 $, of the Ca-rich SNe sample is $\approx35$-$65 ,\rm{d}$, within the unoccupied region between Type Ia SNe and stripped envelope supernovae (SESNe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential signature of a quadrupolar Hubble expansion in Pantheon&#43; supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_signature_of_a_quadrupolar_hubble_expansion_in_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/potential_signature_of_a_quadrupolar_hubble_expansion_in_pantheon&#43;_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica A. Cowell
The assumption of isotropy &amp;ndash; that the Universe looks the same in all directions on large scales &amp;ndash; is fundamental to the standard cosmological model. This model forms the building blocks of essentially all of our cosmological knowledge to date. It is therefore critical to empirically test in which regimes its core assumptions hold. Anisotropies in the cosmic expansion are expected on small scales due to nonlinear structures in the late Universe, however, the extent to which these anisotropies might impact our low-redshift observations remains to be fully tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The environments of Type Ia supernovae with different relative equivalent width of Si II feature in their spectra</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_environments_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_different_relative_equivalent_width_of_si_ii_feature_in_their_spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_environments_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_different_relative_equivalent_width_of_si_ii_feature_in_their_spectra/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiang-Cun Meng
Although type Ia supernovae are so important in many astrophysical field, e.g. in cosmology, their explosion mechanism and progenitor system are still unclear. In physics, the relative equivalent width (REW) of the Si II 635.5 nm absorption feature reflects the velocity interval of silicon in the supernova ejecta and then may provide constraints on the explosion mechanism of SNe Ia. In this paper, we divide the SNe Ia into broad line (BL) and normal line (NL) subsamples based on their REW of Si II 635.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of Searching for Type Ia Supernovae with 2.5-m Wide Field Survey Telescope</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_of_searching_for_type_ia_supernovae_with_2.5-m_wide_field_survey_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/prospects_of_searching_for_type_ia_supernovae_with_2.5-m_wide_field_survey_telescope/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maokai Hu
Type Ia Supernovae (SNe Ia) are the thermonuclear explosion of a carbon-oxygen white dwarf (WD) and are well-known as a distance indicator. However, it is still unclear how WDs increase their mass near the Chandrasekhar limit and how the thermonuclear runaway happens. The observational clues associated with these open questions, such as the photometric data within hours to days since the explosion, are scarce. Thus, an essential way is to discover SNe Ia at specific epochs with optimal surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio and Gamma-ray Evidence for the Supernova Origin of High Velocity Cloud Complex M</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_gamma-ray_evidence_for_the_supernova_origin_of_high_velocity_cloud_complex_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/radio_and_gamma-ray_evidence_for_the_supernova_origin_of_high_velocity_cloud_complex_m/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joan T. Schmelz
Using $\lambda$-21-cm galactic neutral atomic hydrogen data from the HI4PI survey of Bekhti et al. (2016) and 0.75-30 MeV $\gamma$-ray emission from the Imaging Compton Telescope, we have searched for the origin event that accelerated high velocity cloud Complex M. Radio plots of $l-b$, $l-v$, and $b-v$ show a cavity centered at ($l$, $b$) $\sim$ (150$^{\circ}$, 50.$^{\circ}$) and extending about $\pm$33$^{\circ}$. The best view of the cavity is at a velocity of -25 km s$^{-1}$, which shows a circular cross section on the back (receding) face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurring outbursts of the supernova impostor AT 2016blu in NGC 4559</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recurring_outbursts_of_the_supernova_impostor_at_2016blu_in_ngc_4559/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recurring_outbursts_of_the_supernova_impostor_at_2016blu_in_ngc_4559/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mojgan Aghakhanloo
We present the first analysis of photometric observations of the supernova (SN) impostor AT 2016blu located in the galaxy NGC 4559. This transient source was discovered by the Lick Observatory Supernova Search in January 2012 and has continued its eruptive variability since then. Photometry of AT 2016blu reveals at least 19 outbursts in 2012-2022. AT 2016blu&amp;rsquo;s outbursts show irregular variability with multiple closely spaced peaks of varying brightness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Late Time Optical Evolution of Twelve Core-Collapse Supernovae: Detection of Normal Stellar Winds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_late_time_optical_evolution_of_twelve_core-collapse_supernovae_detection_of_normal_stellar_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_late_time_optical_evolution_of_twelve_core-collapse_supernovae_detection_of_normal_stellar_winds/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Rizzo Smith
We analyze the late time evolution of 12 supernovae (SNe) occurring over the last ${\sim}$41 years, including nine Type IIP/L, two IIb, and one Ib/c, using UBVR optical data from the Large Binocular Telescope (LBT) and difference imaging. We see late time (5 to 42 years) emission from nine of the eleven Type II SNe (eight Type IIP/L, one IIb). We consider radioactive decay, circumstellar medium (CSM) interactions, pulsar/engine driven emission, dust echoes, and shock perturbed binary companions as possible sources of emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Supernovae in HETDEX Data Release 3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_supernovae_in_hetdex_data_release_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/searching_for_supernovae_in_hetdex_data_release_3/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Vinko
We have extracted 636 spectra taken at the positions of 583 transient sources from the third Data Release of the Hobby-Eberly Telescope Dark Energy eXperiment (HETDEX). The transients were discovered by the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) during 2018 - 2022. The HETDEX spectra are useful to classify a large number of objects found by photometric surveys for free. We attempt to explore and classify the spectra by utilizing machine learning (ML) and template matching techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminating a common envelope jets supernova impostor event with a super-Eddington blue supergiant</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/terminating_a_common_envelope_jets_supernova_impostor_event_with_a_super-eddington_blue_supergiant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/terminating_a_common_envelope_jets_supernova_impostor_event_with_a_super-eddington_blue_supergiant/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tamar Cohen
We conducted one-dimensional stellar evolutionary numerical simulations to build blue supergiant stellar models with a very low-envelope mass and a super-Eddington luminosity of 10^7Lo that mimic the last phase of a common envelope evolution (CEE) where a neutron star (NS) accretes mass from the envelope and launches jets that power the system. Common envelope jets supernovae (CEJSNe) are CEE transient events where a NS spirals-in inside the envelope and then the core of a red supergiant (RSG) star accretes mass and launches jets that power the transient event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical polarization and spectral properties of the H-poor superluminous supernovae SN 2021bnw and SN 2021fpl</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_polarization_and_spectral_properties_of_the_h-poor_superluminous_supernovae_sn_2021bnw_and_sn_2021fpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/optical_polarization_and_spectral_properties_of_the_h-poor_superluminous_supernovae_sn_2021bnw_and_sn_2021fpl/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Poidevin
New optical photometric, spectrocopic and imaging polarimetry data are combined with publicly available data to study some of the physical properties of the two H-poor superluminous supernovae (SLSN) SN 2021bnw and SN 2021fpl. For each SLSN, the best-fit parameters obtained from the magnetar model with \texttt{MOSFiT} do not depart from the range of parameter obtained on other SLSNe discussed in the literature. A spectral analysis with \texttt{SYN++} shows that SN 2021bnw is a W Type, Fast evolver, while SN 2021fpl is a 15bn Type, Slow evolver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics and Equation of State Dependencies of Relevance for Nucleosynthesis in Supernovae and Neutron Star Mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_and_equation_of_state_dependencies_of_relevance_for_nucleosynthesis_in_supernovae_and_neutron_star_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dynamics_and_equation_of_state_dependencies_of_relevance_for_nucleosynthesis_in_supernovae_and_neutron_star_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. -Thomas Janka
Neutron stars (NSs) and black holes (BHs) are born when the final collapse of the stellar core terminates the lives of stars more massive than about 9 Msun. This can trigger the powerful ejection of a large fraction of the star&amp;rsquo;s material in a core-collapse supernova (CCSN), whose extreme luminosity is energized by the decay of radioactive isotopes such as 56Ni and 56Co. When evolving in close binary systems, the compact relics of such infernal catastrophes spiral towards each other on orbits gradually decaying by gravitational-wave emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Supernovae as an Optically Thick Fireball</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_supernovae_as_an_optically_thick_fireball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modeling_supernovae_as_an_optically_thick_fireball/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacob Marshall
We calculate the properties of 135 stellar supernovae using data from the Open Supernova Catalog. We generate temperatures, radii, luminosities, and expansion velocities using a spherically symmetric optically thick fireball model. These modeled parameters reveal trends that are common across different types of supernovae. We have identified distinct phases that appear across Type Ia, II, II P, and IIb supernovae. We note that there is a long period of reasonable continuous growth (Phase 1), giving credence to our simple model of an optically thick fireball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracer particles for core-collapse supernova nucleosynthesis: The advantages of moving backward</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer_particles_for_core-collapse_supernova_nucleosynthesis_the_advantages_of_moving_backward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/tracer_particles_for_core-collapse_supernova_nucleosynthesis_the_advantages_of_moving_backward/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andre Sieverding
After decades, the theoretical study of core-collapse supernova explosions is moving from parameterized, spherically symmetric models to increasingly realistic multi-dimensional simulations. Obtaining nucleosynthesis yields based on such multi-dimensional core-collapse supernova (CCSN) simulations, however, is not straightforward and frequently tracer particles are employed. Tracer particles may be tracked in situ during the simulation, but often they are reconstructed in a post-processing step based on the information saved during the hydrodynamics simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SN 2021fxy: Mid-Ultraviolet Flux Suppression is a Common Feature of Type Ia Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2021fxy_mid-ultraviolet_flux_suppression_is_a_common_feature_of_type_ia_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sn_2021fxy_mid-ultraviolet_flux_suppression_is_a_common_feature_of_type_ia_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. M. DerKacy
We present ultraviolet (UV) to near-infrared (NIR) observations and analysis of the nearby Type Ia supernova SN 2021fxy. Our observations include UV photometry from Swift/UVOT, UV spectroscopy from HST/STIS, and high-cadence optical photometry with the Swope 1-m telescope capturing intra-night rises during the early light curve. Early $B-V$ colours show SN 2021fxy is the first &amp;ldquo;shallow-silicon&amp;rdquo; (SS) SN Ia to follow a red-to-blue evolution, compared to other SS objects which show blue colours from the earliest observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Spectra of Supernova Remnants in M83</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/high-resolution_spectra_of_supernova_remnants_in_m83/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. Frank Winkler
In order to better characterize the rich supernova remnant (SNR) population of M83 (NGC 5236), we have obtained high-resolution (about 85 km/s) spectra of 119 of the SNRs and SNR candidates in M83 with Gemini/GMOS, as well as new spectra of the young SNRs B12-174a and SN1957D. Most of the SNRs and SNR candidates have [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios that exceed 0.4. Combining these results with earlier studies we have carried out with MUSE and at lower spectroscopic resolution with GMOS, we have confirmed a total of 238 emission nebulae to be SNRs on the basis of their [S II]:H{\alpha} ratios, about half of which have emission lines that show velocity broadening greater than 100 km/s, providing a kinematic confirmation that they are SNRs and not H II regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repeating periodic eruptions of the supernova impostor SN 2000ch</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/repeating_periodic_eruptions_of_the_supernova_impostor_sn_2000ch/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mojgan Aghakhanloo
We analyse photometric observations of the supernova (SN) impostor SN 2000ch in NGC 3432 covering the time since its discovery. This source was previously observed to have four outbursts in 2000&amp;ndash;2010. Observations now reveal at least two additional outbursts in 2004-2006, and ten outbursts in 2013-2022. Outburst light curves are irregular and multipeaked, exhibiting a wide variety of peak magnitude, duration, and shape. The more recent outbursts (after 2010) repeat with a period of $198.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernova 2020wnt: An Atypical Superluminous Supernova with a Hidden Central Engine</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/supernova_2020wnt_an_atypical_superluminous_supernova_with_a_hidden_central_engine/</guid>
      <description>First author: Samaporn Tinyanont
We present observations of a peculiar hydrogen- and helium-poor stripped-envelope (SE) supernova (SN) 2020wnt, primarily in the optical and near-infrared (near-IR). Its peak absolute bolometric magnitude of -20.9 mag and a rise time of 69~days are reminiscent of hydrogen-poor superluminous SNe (SLSNe~I), luminous transients potentially powered by spinning-down magnetars. Before the main peak, there is a brief peak lasting &amp;lt;10 days post-explosion, likely caused by interaction with circumstellar medium (CSM) ejected ~years before the SN explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The disappearances of six supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_disappearances_of_six_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Schuyler D. Van Dyk
As part of a larger completed Hubble Space Telescope (HST) Snapshot program, we observed the sites of six nearby core-collapse supernovae (SNe) at high spatial resolution: SN 2012A, SN 2013ej, SN 2016gkg, SN 2017eaw, SN 2018zd, and SN 2018aoq. These observations were all conducted at sufficiently late times in each SN&amp;rsquo;s evolution to demonstrate that the massive-star progenitor candidate identified in each case in pre-explosion imaging data had indeed vanished and was therefore most likely the actual progenitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for supernova feedback sustaining gas turbulence in nearby star-forming galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_supernova_feedback_sustaining_gas_turbulence_in_nearby_star-forming_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
HI and CO observations indicate that the cold gas in galaxies is very turbulent. However, the turbulent energy is expected to be quickly dissipated, implying that some energy source is needed to explain the observations. The nature of such turbulence was long unclear, as even the main candidate, supernova (SN) feedback, seemed insufficient. Other mechanisms have been proposed, but without reaching a general consensus. The key novelty of our work is considering that the gas disc thickness and flaring increase the dissipation timescale of turbulence, thus reducing the energy injection rate required to sustain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard X-ray Observations of the Hydrogen-poor Superluminous Supernova SN 2018hti with NuSTAR</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hard_x-ray_observations_of_the_hydrogen-poor_superluminous_supernova_sn_2018hti_with_nustar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Igor Andreoni
Some Hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae are likely powered by a magnetar central engine, making their luminosity larger than common supernovae. Although a significant amount of X-ray flux is expected from the spin down of the magnetar, direct observational evidence is still to be found, giving rise to the &amp;ldquo;missing energy&amp;rdquo; problem. Here we present NuSTAR observations of nearby SN 2018hti 2.4y (rest frame) after its optical peak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferencing Progenitor and Explosion Properties of Evolving Core-collapse Supernovae from Zwicky Transient Facility Light Curves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/inferencing_progenitor_and_explosion_properties_of_evolving_core-collapse_supernovae_from_zwicky_transient_facility_light_curves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bhagya M. Subrayan
We analyze a sample of 45 Type II supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) public survey using a grid of hydrodynamical models in order to assess whether theoretically-driven forecasts can intelligently guide follow up observations supporting all-sky survey alert streams. We estimate several progenitor properties and explosion physics parameters including zero-age-main-sequence (ZAMS) mass, mass-loss rate, kinetic energy, 56Ni mass synthesized, host extinction, and the time of explosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at supernovae as seeds for galactic magnetization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_closer_look_at_supernovae_as_seeds_for_galactic_magnetization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_closer_look_at_supernovae_as_seeds_for_galactic_magnetization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Evangelia Ntormousi
Explaining the currently observed magnetic fields in galaxies requires relatively strong seeding in the early Universe. One theory proposes that magnetic fields of the order of $\mu$G were expelled by supernova (SN) explosions after primordial, nG or weaker fields were amplified in stellar interiors. In this work, we calculate the maximum magnetic energy that can be injected in the interstellar medium by a stellar cluster of mass $M_{cl}$ based on what is currently known about stellar magnetism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peering into the Milky Way by FAST: IV. Identification of two new Galactic supernova remnants G203.1&#43;6.6 and G206.7&#43;5.9</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peering_into_the_milky_way_by_fast_iv._identification_of_two_new_galactic_supernova_remnants_g203.1&#43;6.6_and_g206.7&#43;5.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peering_into_the_milky_way_by_fast_iv._identification_of_two_new_galactic_supernova_remnants_g203.1&#43;6.6_and_g206.7&#43;5.9/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xuyang Gao
A $5^{\circ} \times 7^{\circ}$ sky area containing two large radio structures of G203.1+6.6 and G206.7+5.9 with a size of about 2.5$^{\circ}$ and 3.5$^{\circ}$ respectively is scanned by using the L-band 19-beam receiver of the Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope (FAST). The FAST L-band receiver covers a frequency range of 1.0 GHz $-$ 1.5 GHz. Commissioning of the receiving system, including the measurements of the half-power beam width, gain, and main-beam efficiency is made by observing the calibrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing a supernova&#39;s Standing Accretion Shock Instability with neutrinos and gravitational waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/characterizing_a_supernovas_standing_accretion_shock_instability_with_neutrinos_and_gravitational_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Zidu Lin
We perform a novel multi-messenger analysis for the identification and parameter estimation of the Standing Accretion Shock Instability (SASI) in a core collapse supernova with neutrino and gravitational wave (GW) signals. In the neutrino channel, this method performs a likelihood ratio test for the presence of SASI in the frequency domain. For gravitational wave signals we process an event with a modified constrained likelihood method. Using simulated supernova signals, the properties of the Hyper-Kamiokande neutrino detector, and O3 LIGO Interferometric data, we produce the two-dimensional probability density distribution (PDF) of the SASI activity indicator and calculate the probability of detection $P_\mathrm{D}$ as well as the false identification probability $P_\mathrm{FI}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of the 4.4-MeV gamma rays from $^{16}$O($ν, ν^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O(12.97 ${\rm MeV}, 2^-)$ with a water-Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/detection_of_the_4.4-mev_gamma_rays_from__16_o_%CE%BD_%CE%BD_prime__16_o12.97___rm_mev_2-__with_a_water-cherenkov_detector_in_the_supernova_neutrino_bursts/</guid>
      <description>First author: Makoto Sakuda
We first discuss and determine the isospin mixing of the two $2^-$ states (12.53 MeV and 12.97 MeV) of $^{16}$O nucleus using the inelastic electron scattering data. We then evaluate the cross section of 4.4-MeV $\gamma$ rays produced in the neutrino neutral-current (NC) reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(12.97~{\rm MeV}, 2^-$) in a water Cherenkov detector at the low energy below 100 MeV. The detection of $\gamma$ rays for $E_{\gamma}&amp;gt;5$~MeV from the NC reaction $^{16}$O($\nu, \nu^{\prime}$)$^{16}$O$(E_x&amp;gt;16\ {\rm MeV}, T=1$) with a water Cherenkov detector in the supernova neutrino bursts has been proposed and discussed by several authors previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A BayeSN Distance Ladder: $H_0$ from a consistent modelling of Type Ia supernovae from the optical to the near infrared</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_bayesn_distance_ladder__h_0__from_a_consistent_modelling_of_type_ia_supernovae_from_the_optical_to_the_near_infrared/</guid>
      <description>First author: Suhail Dhawan
The local distance ladder estimate of the Hubble constant ($H_0$) is important in cosmology, given the recent tension with the early universe inference. We estimate $H_0$ from the Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) distance ladder, inferring SN Ia distances with the hierarchical Bayesian SED model, BayeSN. This method has a notable advantage of being able to continuously model the optical and near-infrared (NIR) SN Ia light curves simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonthermal processes and particle acceleration in supernova remnants</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nonthermal_processes_and_particle_acceleration_in_supernova_remnants/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jacco Vink
Shocks of supernova remnants (SNRs) accelerate charged particles up to 100 TeV range via diffusive shock acceleration (DSA) mechanism. It is believed that shocks of SNRs are the main contributors to the pool of Galactic cosmic rays, although it is still under debate whether they can accelerate particles up to the &amp;ldquo;knee&amp;rdquo; energy (10^15.5 eV) or not. In this chapter, we start with introducing SNRs as likely sources of cosmic rays and the radiation mechanisms associated with cosmic rays (section 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1): Light Curves and Photometric Classification of 1975 Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_young_supernova_experiment_data_release_1_yse_dr1_light_curves_and_photometric_classification_of_1975_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: P. D. Aleo
We present the Young Supernova Experiment Data Release 1 (YSE DR1), comprised of processed multi-color Pan-STARRS1 (PS1) griz and Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) gr photometry of 1975 transients with host-galaxy associations, redshifts, spectroscopic/photometric classifications, and additional data products from 2019 November 24 to 2021 December 20. YSE DR1 spans discoveries and observations from young and fast-rising supernovae (SNe) to transients that persist for over a year, with a redshift distribution reaching z~0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the evolution of Type Ia supernovae with their ejecta velocities</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_evolution_of_type_ia_supernovae_with_their_ejecta_velocities/</guid>
      <description>First author: Y. -C. Pan
There is growing evidence that Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) are likely produced via multiple explosion channels. Understanding how different channels evolve with redshift is critical in determining their precision in measuring cosmological parameters. Previous studies indicated that SN Ia ejecta velocity is one powerful tool to differentiate between different channels. It was also suspected that the tight correlation with the host-galaxy environment could result in the evolution of SN ejecta velocities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A JWST Near- and Mid-Infrared Nebular Spectrum of the Type Ia Supernova 2021aefx</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_near-_and_mid-infrared_nebular_spectrum_of_the_type_ia_supernova_2021aefx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_jwst_near-_and_mid-infrared_nebular_spectrum_of_the_type_ia_supernova_2021aefx/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lindsey A. Kwok
We present JWST near- and mid-infrared spectroscopic observations of the nearby normal Type Ia supernova SN 2021aefx in the nebular phase at $+255$ days past maximum light. Our Near Infrared Spectrograph (NIRSpec) and Mid Infrared Instrument (MIRI) observations, combined with ground-based optical data from the South African Large Telescope (SALT), constitute the first complete optical $+$ NIR $+$ MIR nebular SN Ia spectrum covering 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-gas phases in supernova remnant IC 443: Mapping shocked H$_2$ with VLT/KMOS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-gas_phases_in_supernova_remnant_ic_443_mapping_shocked_h__2__with_vlt_kmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multi-gas_phases_in_supernova_remnant_ic_443_mapping_shocked_h__2__with_vlt_kmos/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yunwei Deng
Supernovae and their remnants provide energetic feedback to the ambient interstellar medium (ISM), which is often distributed in multiple gas phases. Among them, warm molecular hydrogen (H$_2$) often dominates the cooling of the shocked molecular ISM, which has been observed with the H$_2$ emission lines at near-infrared wavelengths. Such studies, however, were either limited in narrow filter imaging or sparsely sampled mid-infrared spectroscopic observations with relatively poor angular resolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Rubin Observatory cadence choices on supernovae photometric classification</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_rubin_observatory_cadence_choices_on_supernovae_photometric_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/impact_of_rubin_observatory_cadence_choices_on_supernovae_photometric_classification/</guid>
      <description>First author: Catarina S. Alves
The Vera C. Rubin Observatory&amp;rsquo;s Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST) will discover an unprecedented number of supernovae (SNe), making spectroscopic classification for all the events infeasible. LSST will thus rely on photometric classification, whose accuracy depends on the not-yet-finalized LSST observing strategy. In this work, we analyze the impact of cadence choices on classification performance using simulated multi-band light curves. First, we simulate SNe with an LSST baseline cadence, a non-rolling cadence, and a presto-color cadence which observes each sky location three times per night instead of twice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$Hubble~Space~Telescope$ Reveals Spectacular Light Echoes Associated with the Stripped-envelope Supernova 2016adj in the Iconic Dust Lane of Centaurus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/_hubble~space~telescope__reveals_spectacular_light_echoes_associated_with_the_stripped-envelope_supernova_2016adj_in_the_iconic_dust_lane_of_centaurus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Maximilian Stritzinger
We present a multi-band sequence of $Hubble~Space~Telescope$ images documenting the emergence and evolution of multiple light echoes (LEs) linked to the stripped-envelope supernova (SN) 2016adj located in the central dust-lane of Centaurus A. Following point-spread function subtraction, we identify the earliest LE emission associated with a SN at only $+$34 days (d) past the epoch of $B$-band maximum. Additional HST images extending through $+$578 d cover the evolution of LE1 taking the form of a ring, while images taken on $+$1991 d reveals not only LE1, but also segments of a new inner LE ring (LE2) as well as two additional outer LE rings (LE3 &amp;amp; LE4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of post-kick jets in core collapse supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/implications_of_post-kick_jets_in_core_collapse_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Noam Soker
I argue that the assumption that the jets that shape the axisymmetrical morphological features of core collapse supernova (CCSN) remnants are post-kick jets, i.e., the neutron star (NS) launches these jets after the explosion and after it acquired its natal kick velocity, leads to the conclusion that the pre-collapse cores of CCSN progenitors have sufficient angular momentum fluctuations to support jittering jets that explode the star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Type Iax Supernova 2019muj in the Late Phase: Existence, Nature and Origin of the Iron-rich Dense Core</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_type_iax_supernova_2019muj_in_the_late_phase_existence_nature_and_origin_of_the_iron-rich_dense_core/</guid>
      <description>First author: Keiichi Maeda
Type Iax Supernovae (SNe Iax) form a class of peculiar SNe Ia, whose early-phase spectra share main spectral line identifications with canonical SNe Ia but with higher ionization and much lower line velocities. Their late-time behaviors deviate from usual SNe Ia in many respects; SNe Iax keep showing photospheric spectra over several 100 days and the luminosity decline is very slow. In the present work, we study the late-time spectra of SN Iax 2019muj including a newly-presented spectrum at ~500 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Black-Hole Excision Scheme for General Relativistic Core-Collapse Supernova Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_black-hole_excision_scheme_for_general_relativistic_core-collapse_supernova_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. Sykes
Fallback supernovae and the collapsar scenario for long-gamma ray burst and hypernovae have received considerable interest as pathways to black-hole formation and extreme transient events. Consistent simulations of these scenarios require a general relativistic treatment and need to deal appropriately with the formation of a singularity. Free evolution schemes for the Einstein equations can handle the formation of black holes by means of excision or puncture schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapse of rotating massive stars leading to black hole formation and energetic supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapse_of_rotating_massive_stars_leading_to_black_hole_formation_and_energetic_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/collapse_of_rotating_massive_stars_leading_to_black_hole_formation_and_energetic_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sho Fujibayashi
We explore a possible scenario of the explosion as a result of core collapses of rotating massive stars that leave a black hole by performing a radiation-viscous-hydrodynamics simulation in numerical relativity. We take moderately and rapidly rotating compact pre-collapse stellar models derived in stellar evolution calculations as the initial conditions. We find that the viscous heating in the disk formed around the central black hole powers an outflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Curves of Type IIP Supernovae from Neutrino-driven Explosions of Red Supergiants Obtained by a Semi-analytic Approach</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_type_iip_supernovae_from_neutrino-driven_explosions_of_red_supergiants_obtained_by_a_semi-analytic_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/light_curves_of_type_iip_supernovae_from_neutrino-driven_explosions_of_red_supergiants_obtained_by_a_semi-analytic_approach/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuai Zha
Type IIP supernovae (SNe IIP) mark the explosive death of red supergiants (RSGs), evolved massive stars with an extended hydrogen envelope. They are the most common supernova type and allow for benchmarking of supernova explosion models by statistical comparison to observed population properties rather than comparing individual models and events. We construct a large synthetic set of SNe IIP light curves (LCs) using the radiation hydrodynamics code \texttt{SNEC} and explosion energies and nickel masses obtained from an efficient semi-analytic model for two different sets of stellar progenitor models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiwavelength studies of G298.6$-$0.0: An old GeV supernova remnant interacting with molecular clouds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_studies_of_g298.6_-_0.0_an_old_gev_supernova_remnant_interacting_with_molecular_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/multiwavelength_studies_of_g298.6_-_0.0_an_old_gev_supernova_remnant_interacting_with_molecular_clouds/</guid>
      <description>First author: Paul K. H. Yeung
Hadronic $\gamma$-ray sources associated with supernova remnants (SNRs) can serve as stopwatches for the escape of cosmic rays from SNRs, which gradually develops from highest-energy particles to lowest-energy particles with time. In this work, we analyze the 13.7~yr \emph{Fermi}-LAT data to investigate the $\gamma$-ray feature in/around the SNR G298.6$-$0.0 region. With $\gamma$-ray spatial analyses, we detect three point-like components. Among them, Src-NE is at the eastern SNR shell, and Src-NW is adjacent to the western edge of this SNR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarized radio emission unveils the structure of the pre-supernova circumstellar magnetic field and the radio emission in SN1987A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/polarized_radio_emission_unveils_the_structure_of_the_pre-supernova_circumstellar_magnetic_field_and_the_radio_emission_in_sn1987a/</guid>
      <description>First author: O. Petruk
The detected polarized radio emission from remnant of SN1987A opens the possibility to unveil the structure of the pre-supernova magnetic field in the circumstellar medium. Properties derived from direct measurements would be of importance for understanding the progenitor stars and their magnetic fields. As the first step to this goal, we adopted the hydrodynamic data from an elaborated three-dimensional (3-D) numerical model of SN1987A. We have developed an approximate method for reconstruction&#39; of 3-D magnetic field structure inside supernova remnant on the hydrodynamic background&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prevalence and influence of circumstellar material around hydrogen-rich supernova progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_prevalence_and_influence_of_circumstellar_material_around_hydrogen-rich_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_prevalence_and_influence_of_circumstellar_material_around_hydrogen-rich_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rachel J. Bruch
Spectroscopic detection of transient narrow emission lines (flash-ionisation features) traces the presence of circumstellar material (CSM) around massive stars exploding as core-collapse supernovae. Transient emission lines disappearing shortly after the SN explosion suggest that the spatial extent of this material is compact; hence implying that the progenitor star experienced episodes of enhanced mass loss shortly prior to explosion. The early light curves of Type II supernovae (SNe II) are assumed to be initially powered by shock-cooling emission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Type Ibn Supernova 2019kbj -- Indications for Diversity in Type Ibn Supernova Progenitors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ibn_supernova_2019kbj_--_indications_for_diversity_in_type_ibn_supernova_progenitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_type_ibn_supernova_2019kbj_--_indications_for_diversity_in_type_ibn_supernova_progenitors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tom Ben-Ami
Type Ibn supernovae (SNe) are a rare class of stellar explosions whose progenitor systems are not yet well determined. We present and analyze observations of the Type Ibn SN 2019kbj, and model its light curve in order to constrain its progenitor and explosion parameters. SN 2019kbj shows roughly constant temperature during the first month after peak, indicating a power source (likely CSM interaction) that keeps the continuum emission hot at ~15000K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three dimensional magnetorotational core-collapse supernova explosions of a 39 solar mass progenitor star</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/three_dimensional_magnetorotational_core-collapse_supernova_explosions_of_a_39_solar_mass_progenitor_star/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jade Powell
We perform three-dimensional simulations of magnetorotational supernovae using a $39,M_{\odot}$ progenitor star with two different initial magnetic field strengths of $10^{10}$ G and $10^{12}$ G in the core. Both models rapidly undergo shock revival and their explosion energies asymptote within a few hundred milliseconds to values of $\gtrsim 2\times10^{51}$ erg after conservatively correcting for the binding energy of the envelope. Magnetically collimated, non-relativistic jets form in both models, though the jets are subject to non-axisymmetric instabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
