<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hydrodynamics on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/hydrodynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hydrodynamics on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/hydrodynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of rotating massive stars with new hydrodynamic wind models</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_massive_stars_with_new_hydrodynamic_wind_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evolution_of_rotating_massive_stars_with_new_hydrodynamic_wind_models/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex Camilo Gormaz-Matamala
Mass loss due to line-driven winds is central to our understanding of the evolution of massive stars. We extend the evolution models introduced in Paper I, where the mass loss recipe is based on the simultaneous calculation of the wind hydrodynamics and the line-acceleration, by incorporating the effects of stellar rotation. We introduce a grid of self-consistent line-force parameters for a set of standard evolutionary tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Radiation-Hydrodynamic Simulations Resolving Interior of Rapidly Accreting Primordial Protostar</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation-hydrodynamic_simulations_resolving_interior_of_rapidly_accreting_primordial_protostar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_radiation-hydrodynamic_simulations_resolving_interior_of_rapidly_accreting_primordial_protostar/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kazutaka Kimura
Direct collapse of supermassive stars is a possible pathway to form supermassive black hole seeds at high redshifts. Whereas previous three-dimensional (3D) simulations demonstrate that supermassive stars form via rapid mass accretion, those resolving the stellar interior have been limited. We here report 3D radiation-hydrodynamic (RHD) simulations following the evolution of rapidly accreting protostars resolving the stellar interior. We use an adaptive mesh refinement code with our newly developed RHD solver employing an explicit M1 closure method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical Evolution of Black-Hole Binaries Embedded in AGN Discs: III. The Effects of Viscosity</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_evolution_of_black-hole_binaries_embedded_in_agn_discs_iii._the_effects_of_viscosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_evolution_of_black-hole_binaries_embedded_in_agn_discs_iii._the_effects_of_viscosity/</guid>
      <description>First author: Rixin Li
Stellar-mass binary black holes (BBHs) embedded in active galactic nucleus (AGN) discs offer a distinct dynamical channel to produce black hole mergers detected in gravitational waves by LIGO/Virgo. To understand their orbital evolution through interactions with the disc gas, we perform a suite of 2D high-resolution, local shearing box, viscous hydrodynamical simulations of equal-mass binaries. We find that viscosity not only smooths the flow structure around prograde circular binaries, but also greatly raises their accretion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamics simulations of core convection in supermassive main-sequence stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_core_convection_in_supermassive_main-sequence_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_core_convection_in_supermassive_main-sequence_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Blouin
Supermassive stars are Population III stars with masses exceeding $10^4,M_{\odot}$ that could be the progenitors of the first supermassive black holes. Their interiors are in a regime where radiation pressure dominates the equation of state. In this work, we use the explicit gas dynamics code PPMstar to simulate the hydrogen-burning core of a $10^4,M_{\odot}$ supermassive main-sequence star. These are the first 3D hydrodynamics simulations of core convection in supermassive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamics simulations of internal gravity waves in red giant branch stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_internal_gravity_waves_in_red_giant_branch_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamics_simulations_of_internal_gravity_waves_in_red_giant_branch_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Simon Blouin
We present the first 3D hydrodynamics simulations of the excitation and propagation of internal gravity waves (IGWs) in the radiative interiors of low-mass stars on the red giant branch (RGB). We use the PPMstar explicit gas dynamics code to simulate a portion of the convective envelope and all the radiative zone down to the hydrogen-burning shell of a 1.2$M_{\odot}$ upper RGB star. We perform simulations for different grid resolutions (768$^3$, 1536$^3$ and 2880$^3$), a range of driving luminosities, and two different stratifications (corresponding to the bump luminosity and the tip of the RGB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamic simulations of massive main-sequence stars II. Convective excitation and spectra of internal gravity waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars_ii._convective_excitation_and_spectra_of_internal_gravity_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars_ii._convective_excitation_and_spectra_of_internal_gravity_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: William Thompson
Recent photometric observations of massive stars have identified a low-frequency power excess which appears as stochastic low-frequency variability in light curve observations. We present the oscillation properties of high resolution hydrodynamic simulations of a 25 $\mathrm{M}\odot$ star performed with the PPMStar code. The model star has a convective core mass of $\approx, 12, \mathrm{M}\odot$ and approximately half of the envelope simulated. From this simulation, we extract light curves from several directions, average them over each hemisphere, and process them as if they were real photometric observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D hydrodynamic simulations of massive main-sequence stars. I. Dynamics and mixing of convection and internal gravity waves</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars._i._dynamics_and_mixing_of_convection_and_internal_gravity_waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/3d_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_massive_main-sequence_stars._i._dynamics_and_mixing_of_convection_and_internal_gravity_waves/</guid>
      <description>First author: Falk Herwig
We performed 3D hydrodynamic simulations of the inner $\approx 50%$ radial extent of a $25\ \mathrm{M_\odot}$ star in the early phase of the main sequence and investigate core convection and internal gravity waves in the core-envelope boundary region. Simulations for different grid resolutions and driving luminosities establish scaling relations to constrain models of mixing for 1D applications. As in previous works, the turbulent mass entrainment rate extrapolated to nominal heating is unrealistically high ($1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic Simulations of a Relativistic Jet Interacting with the Intracluster Medium: Application to Cygnus A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_of_a_relativistic_jet_interacting_with_the_intracluster_medium_application_to_cygnus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_of_a_relativistic_jet_interacting_with_the_intracluster_medium_application_to_cygnus_a/</guid>
      <description>First author: John A. ZuHone
The Fanaroff-Riley class II radio galaxy Cygnus A hosts jets which produce radio emission, X-ray cavities, cocoon shocks, and X-ray hotspots where the jet interacts with the ICM. Surrounding one hotspot is a peculiar &amp;ldquo;hole&amp;rdquo; feature which appears as a deficit in X-ray emission. We use relativistic hydrodynamic simulations of a collimated jet interacting with an inclined interface between lobe and cluster plasma to model the basic processes which may lead to such a feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic Simulations and Time-dependent Photoionization Modeling of Starburst-driven Superwinds</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_and_time-dependent_photoionization_modeling_of_starburst-driven_superwinds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_simulations_and_time-dependent_photoionization_modeling_of_starburst-driven_superwinds/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Danehkar
Thermal energies deposited by OB stellar clusters in starburst galaxies lead to the formation of galactic superwinds. Multi-wavelength observations of starburst-driven superwinds pointed at complex thermal and ionization structures which cannot adequately be explained by simple adiabatic assumptions. In this study, we perform hydrodynamic simulations of a fluid model coupled to radiative cooling functions, and generate time-dependent non-equilibrium photoionization models to predict physical conditions and ionization structures of superwinds using the MAIHEM atomic and cooling package built on the program FLASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundary conditions in hydrodynamic simulations of isolated galaxies and their impact on the gas-loss processes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/boundary_conditions_in_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_isolated_galaxies_and_their_impact_on_the_gas-loss_processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/boundary_conditions_in_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_isolated_galaxies_and_their_impact_on_the_gas-loss_processes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anderson Caproni
Three-dimensional hydrodynamic simulations are commonly used to study the evolution of the gaseous content in isolated galaxies, besides its connection with galactic star formation histories. Stellar winds, supernova blasts, and black hole feedback are mechanisms usually invoked to drive galactic outflows and decrease the initial galactic gas reservoir. However, any simulation imposes the need of choosing the limits of the simulated volume, which depends, for instance, on the size of the galaxy and the required numerical resolution, besides the available computational capability to perform it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid preparation. XXX. Evaluating the weak lensing cluster mass biases using the Three Hundred Project hydrodynamical simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxx._evaluating_the_weak_lensing_cluster_mass_biases_using_the_three_hundred_project_hydrodynamical_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxx._evaluating_the_weak_lensing_cluster_mass_biases_using_the_three_hundred_project_hydrodynamical_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Euclid Collaboration
The photometric catalogue of galaxy clusters extracted from ESA Euclid data is expected to be very competitive for cosmological studies. Using state-of-the-art hydrodynamical simulations, we present systematic analyses simulating the expected weak lensing profiles from clusters in a variety of dynamic states and at wide range of redshifts. In order to derive cluster masses, we use a model consistent with the implementation within the Euclid Consortium of the dedicated processing function and find that, when jointly modelling mass and the concentration parameter of the Navarro-Frenk-White halo profile, the weak lensing masses tend to be, on average, biased low with respect to the true mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of ionizing background on the statistics of metal absorbers in hydrodynamical simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/role_of_ionizing_background_on_the_statistics_of_metal_absorbers_in_hydrodynamical_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/role_of_ionizing_background_on_the_statistics_of_metal_absorbers_in_hydrodynamical_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sukanya Mallik
We study the statistical properties of O VI, C IV, and Ne VIII absorbers at low-$z$ (i.e., $z&amp;lt;0.5$) using Sherwood simulations with &amp;ldquo;WIND&amp;rdquo; only and &amp;ldquo;WIND+AGN&amp;rdquo; feedback and Massive black simulation that incorporates both &amp;ldquo;WIND&amp;rdquo; and AGN feedbacks. For each simulation, by considering a wide range of metagalactic ionizing UV background (UVB), we show the statistical properties such as distribution functions of column density ($N$), $b$-paramerer and velocity spread ($\Delta V_{90}$), the relationship between $N$ and $b$-parameter and the fraction of Lya absorbers showing detectable metal lines as a function of $N$(H I) are influenced by the UVB used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Spots in Sgr A* Accretion Disk: Hydrodynamic Insights</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hot_spots_in_sgr_a_accretion_disk_hydrodynamic_insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hot_spots_in_sgr_a_accretion_disk_hydrodynamic_insights/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. P. Tito
The recent image of our galaxy&amp;rsquo;s supermassive black hole Sgr A* derived from the 7 April 2017 data of the Event Horizon Telescope Collaboration shows multiple hot spots in its accretion disk. Using the analytical framework, we demonstrate that the observed hot spots may not be disjoint elements but causally linked components (&amp;ldquo;petals&amp;rdquo;) of one rotating quasi-stationary macro-structure formed in the thermo-vorticial field within the accretion disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A study of convective core overshooting as a function of stellar mass based on two-dimensional hydrodynamical simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_study_of_convective_core_overshooting_as_a_function_of_stellar_mass_based_on_two-dimensional_hydrodynamical_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_study_of_convective_core_overshooting_as_a_function_of_stellar_mass_based_on_two-dimensional_hydrodynamical_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. Baraffe
We perform two-dimensional numerical simulations of core convection for zero-age-main-sequence stars covering a mass range from 3 $M_\odot$ to 20 $M_\odot$. The simulations are performed with the fully compressible time-implicit code MUSIC. We study the efficiency of overshooting, which describes the ballistic process of convective flows crossing a convective boundary, as a function of stellar mass and luminosity. We also study the impact of artificially increasing the stellar luminosity for 3 $M_\odot$ models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic turbulence in disks with embedded planets</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_turbulence_in_disks_with_embedded_planets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamic_turbulence_in_disks_with_embedded_planets/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alexandros Ziampras
The vertical shear instability (VSI) is a source of hydrodynamic turbulence that can drive vigorous vertical mixing and moderate levels of accretion in protoplanetary disks, and it could be observable in the near future. With high-resolution three-dimensional numerical hydrodynamics simulations, we modeled the behavior of the VSI in protoplanetary disks with and without embedded planets. We then measured its accretion and mixing capabilities by comparing the full Reynolds stress, which includes the contribution of nonaxisymmetric features, such as spiral arms and vortices, to the Reynolds stress due to the azimuthally averaged velocity field, which can be attributed to good approximation to the VSI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical Simulations of Circumbinary Accretion: Balance between Heating and Cooling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_of_circumbinary_accretion_balance_between_heating_and_cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_of_circumbinary_accretion_balance_between_heating_and_cooling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hai-Yang Wang
Hydrodynamical interaction in circumbinary discs (CBDs) plays a crucial role in various astrophysical systems, ranging from young stellar binaries to supermassive black hole binaries in galactic centers. Most previous simulations of binary-disc systems have adopted locally isothermal equation of state. In this study, we use the grid-based code $\texttt{Athena++}$ to conduct a suite of two-dimensional viscous hydrodynamical simulations of circumbinary accretion on a cartesian grid, resolving the central cavity of the binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphology of Shocked Lateral Outflows in Colliding Hydrodynamic Flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_of_shocked_lateral_outflows_in_colliding_hydrodynamic_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_of_shocked_lateral_outflows_in_colliding_hydrodynamic_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. N. Markwick
Supersonic interacting flows occurring in phenomena such as protostellar jets give rise to strong shocks, and have been demonstrated in several laboratory experiments. To study such colliding flows, we use the AstroBEAR AMR code to conduct hydrodynamic simulations in three dimensions. We introduce variations in the flow parameters of density, velocity, and cross sectional radius of the colliding flows %radius in order to study the propagation and conical shape of the bow shock formed by collisions between two, not necessarily symmetric, hypersonic flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GalaxyFlow: Upsampling Hydrodynamical Simulations for Realistic Gaia Mock Catalogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxyflow_upsampling_hydrodynamical_simulations_for_realistic_gaia_mock_catalogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxyflow_upsampling_hydrodynamical_simulations_for_realistic_gaia_mock_catalogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sung Hak Lim
Cosmological N-body simulations of galaxies operate at the level of &amp;ldquo;star particles&amp;rdquo; with a mass resolution on the scale of thousands of solar masses. Turning these simulations into stellar mock catalogs requires &amp;ldquo;upsampling&amp;rdquo; the star particles into individual stars following the same phase-space density. In this paper, we demonstrate that normalizing flows provide a viable upsampling method that greatly improves on conventionally-used kernel smoothing algorithms such as EnBiD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magneto hydrodynamic simulations of the supernova remnant G1.9&#43;0.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magneto_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_the_supernova_remnant_g1.9&#43;0.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magneto_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_the_supernova_remnant_g1.9&#43;0.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shaobo Zhang
The youngest Galactic supernova remnant G1.9+0.3 shows a discrete feature between its radio and X-ray morphologies. The observed radio morphology features a single maximum in the north, while the X-ray observation shows two opposite &amp;rsquo;ears&amp;rsquo; on the east and west sides. Using 3D magneto hydrodynamical simulations, we investigate the formation of the discrete feature of the remnant. We have tested different parameters for better simulation and reproduced similar discrete features under an environment with density gradient and an environment with clump, which provides a possible explanation of the observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Jupiter engulfment by a red giant in 3D hydrodynamics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hot_jupiter_engulfment_by_a_red_giant_in_3d_hydrodynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hot_jupiter_engulfment_by_a_red_giant_in_3d_hydrodynamics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mike Y. M. Lau
Transit and radial-velocity surveys over the past two decades have uncovered a significant population of short-period exoplanets. Among them are hot Jupiters, which are gas giant planets with orbital periods of a few days and found in 0.1-1% of Sun-like stars. Hot Jupiters are expected to be engulfed during their host star&amp;rsquo;s radial expansion on the red giant branch. Planetary engulfment has been studied extensively as it may account for observed rapidly rotating and chemically enriched giant stars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
