<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hydrodynamics on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/hydrodynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hydrodynamics on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/hydrodynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the depth of gaps opened by planets in eccentric orbit</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/estimating_the_depth_of_gaps_opened_by_planets_in_eccentric_orbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/estimating_the_depth_of_gaps_opened_by_planets_in_eccentric_orbit/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. J. Sanchez-Salcedo
Planets can carve gaps in the surface density of protoplanetary discs. The formation of these gaps can reduce the corotation torques acting on the planets. In addition, gaps can halt the accretion of solids onto the planets as dust and pebbles can be trapped at the edge of the gap. This accumulation of dust could explain the origin of the ring-like dust structures observed using high-resolution interferometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidal Disruption of Main-Sequence Stars by Intermediate-Mass Black Holes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/tidal_disruption_of_main-sequence_stars_by_intermediate-mass_black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/new_article/tidal_disruption_of_main-sequence_stars_by_intermediate-mass_black_holes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fulya Kıroğlu
We study close encounters of a $1,M_{\odot}$ middle-age main-sequence star (modelled using MESA) with massive black holes through hydrodynamic simulations, and explore in particular the dependence of the outcomes on the black hole mass. We consider here black holes in the intermediate-mass range, $M_{\rm BH}= 100-10^4,M_{\odot}$. Possible outcomes vary from a small tidal perturbation for weak encounters all the way to partial or full disruption for stronger encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
