<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hydrodynamics on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/hydrodynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hydrodynamics on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/hydrodynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamical Simulations of Circumbinary Accretion: Balance between Heating and Cooling</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_of_circumbinary_accretion_balance_between_heating_and_cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrodynamical_simulations_of_circumbinary_accretion_balance_between_heating_and_cooling/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hai-Yang Wang
Hydrodynamical interaction in circumbinary discs (CBDs) plays a crucial role in various astrophysical systems, ranging from young stellar binaries to supermassive black hole binaries in galactic centers. Most previous simulations of binary-disc systems have adopted locally isothermal equation of state. In this study, we use the grid-based code $\texttt{Athena++}$ to conduct a suite of two-dimensional viscous hydrodynamical simulations of circumbinary accretion on a cartesian grid, resolving the central cavity of the binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphology of Shocked Lateral Outflows in Colliding Hydrodynamic Flows</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_of_shocked_lateral_outflows_in_colliding_hydrodynamic_flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_of_shocked_lateral_outflows_in_colliding_hydrodynamic_flows/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. N. Markwick
Supersonic interacting flows occurring in phenomena such as protostellar jets give rise to strong shocks, and have been demonstrated in several laboratory experiments. To study such colliding flows, we use the AstroBEAR AMR code to conduct hydrodynamic simulations in three dimensions. We introduce variations in the flow parameters of density, velocity, and cross sectional radius of the colliding flows %radius in order to study the propagation and conical shape of the bow shock formed by collisions between two, not necessarily symmetric, hypersonic flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GalaxyFlow: Upsampling Hydrodynamical Simulations for Realistic Gaia Mock Catalogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxyflow_upsampling_hydrodynamical_simulations_for_realistic_gaia_mock_catalogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxyflow_upsampling_hydrodynamical_simulations_for_realistic_gaia_mock_catalogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sung Hak Lim
Cosmological N-body simulations of galaxies operate at the level of &amp;ldquo;star particles&amp;rdquo; with a mass resolution on the scale of thousands of solar masses. Turning these simulations into stellar mock catalogs requires &amp;ldquo;upsampling&amp;rdquo; the star particles into individual stars following the same phase-space density. In this paper, we demonstrate that normalizing flows provide a viable upsampling method that greatly improves on conventionally-used kernel smoothing algorithms such as EnBiD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magneto hydrodynamic simulations of the supernova remnant G1.9&#43;0.3</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magneto_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_the_supernova_remnant_g1.9&#43;0.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/magneto_hydrodynamic_simulations_of_the_supernova_remnant_g1.9&#43;0.3/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shaobo Zhang
The youngest Galactic supernova remnant G1.9+0.3 shows a discrete feature between its radio and X-ray morphologies. The observed radio morphology features a single maximum in the north, while the X-ray observation shows two opposite &amp;rsquo;ears&amp;rsquo; on the east and west sides. Using 3D magneto hydrodynamical simulations, we investigate the formation of the discrete feature of the remnant. We have tested different parameters for better simulation and reproduced similar discrete features under an environment with density gradient and an environment with clump, which provides a possible explanation of the observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Jupiter engulfment by a red giant in 3D hydrodynamics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hot_jupiter_engulfment_by_a_red_giant_in_3d_hydrodynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hot_jupiter_engulfment_by_a_red_giant_in_3d_hydrodynamics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Mike Y. M. Lau
Transit and radial-velocity surveys over the past two decades have uncovered a significant population of short-period exoplanets. Among them are hot Jupiters, which are gas giant planets with orbital periods of a few days and found in 0.1-1% of Sun-like stars. Hot Jupiters are expected to be engulfed during their host star&amp;rsquo;s radial expansion on the red giant branch. Planetary engulfment has been studied extensively as it may account for observed rapidly rotating and chemically enriched giant stars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
