<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>galaxies on Explosion Group Paper collection</title>
    <link>https://nebula0.github.io/categories/galaxies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in galaxies on Explosion Group Paper collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula0.github.io/categories/galaxies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A non-repeating fast radio burst in a dwarf host galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_non-repeating_fast_radio_burst_in_a_dwarf_host_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_non-repeating_fast_radio_burst_in_a_dwarf_host_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shivani Bhandari
We present the discovery of as-of-yet non-repeating Fast Radio Burst (FRB) with the Australian Square Kilometer Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) as a part of the Commensal Real-time ASKAP Fast Transients (CRAFT) Survey. FRB 20210117A was detected at the center frequency of 1271.5 MHz with a dispersion measure (DM) of $728.95\pm 0.01$ pc cm$^{-3}$. The sub-arcsecond localization of the burst led to the identification of its host galaxy at a $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Mode Gas Accretion on Two Galaxy Groups at z$\sim$2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cold_mode_gas_accretion_on_two_galaxy_groups_at_z__sim_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cold_mode_gas_accretion_on_two_galaxy_groups_at_z__sim_2/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrey Vayner
We present Keck Cosmic Web Imager (KCWI) integral field spectroscopy (IFS) observations of rest-frame UV emission lines $\rm Ly\alpha$, C IV $\lambda \lambda$ 1548 \AA, 1550\AA and He II 1640 \AA observed in the circumgalactic medium (CGM) of two $z=2$ radio-loud quasar host galaxies. We detect extended emission on 80-90 kpc scale in $\rm Ly\alpha$ in both systems with C IV, and He II emission also detected out to 30-50 kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of the Central Mass Concentration on Bar Formation in Disk Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_the_central_mass_concentration_on_bar_formation_in_disk_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_the_central_mass_concentration_on_bar_formation_in_disk_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dajeong Jang
While bars are common in disk galaxies, their formation conditions are not well understood. We use $N$-body simulations to study bar formation and evolution in isolated galaxies consisting of a stellar disk, a classical bulge, and a dark halo. We consider 24 galaxy models that are similar to the Milky Way but differ in the mass and compactness of the classical bulge and halo concentration. We find that the bar formation requires $(Q_{T,\text{min}}/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme nature of four blue-excess dust-obscured galaxies revealed by optical spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extreme_nature_of_four_blue-excess_dust-obscured_galaxies_revealed_by_optical_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extreme_nature_of_four_blue-excess_dust-obscured_galaxies_revealed_by_optical_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Akatoki Noboriguchi
We report optical spectroscopic observations of four blue-excess dust-obscured galaxies (BluDOGs) identified by Subaru Hyper Suprime-Cam. BluDOGs are a sub-class of dust-obscured galaxies (DOGs, defined with the extremely red color $(i-[22]){\rm AB} \geq 7.0$; Toba et al. 2015), showing a significant flux excess in the optical $g$- and $r$-bands over the power-law fits to the fluxes at the longer wavelengths. Noboriguchi et al. (2019) has suggested that BluDOGs may correspond to the blowing-out phase involved in a gas-rich major merger scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphological Parameters and Associated Uncertainties for 8 Million Galaxies in the Hyper Suprime-Cam Wide Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphological_parameters_and_associated_uncertainties_for_8_million_galaxies_in_the_hyper_suprime-cam_wide_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphological_parameters_and_associated_uncertainties_for_8_million_galaxies_in_the_hyper_suprime-cam_wide_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aritra Ghosh
We use the Galaxy Morphology Posterior Estimation Network (GaMPEN) to estimate morphological parameters and associated uncertainties for $\sim 8$ million galaxies in the Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) Wide survey with $z \leq 0.75$ and $m \leq 23$. GaMPEN is a machine learning framework that estimates Bayesian posteriors for a galaxy&amp;rsquo;s bulge-to-total light ratio ($L_B/L_T$), effective radius ($R_e$), and flux ($F$). By first training on simulations of galaxies and then applying transfer learning using real data, we trained GaMPEN with $&amp;lt;1%$ of our dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHANGS-JWST First Results: The Influence of Stellar Clusters on PAHs in Nearby Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs-jwst_first_results_the_influence_of_stellar_clusters_on_pahs_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/phangs-jwst_first_results_the_influence_of_stellar_clusters_on_pahs_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel A. Dale
We present a comparison of theoretical predictions of dust continuum and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) emission with new JWST observations in three nearby galaxies: NGC 628, NGC 1365, and NGC 7496. Our analysis focuses on a total of 1063 compact stellar clusters and 2654 stellar associations previously characterized by HST in the three galaxies. We find that the distributions and trends in the observed PAH-focused infrared colors generally agree with theoretical expectations, and that the bulk of the observations is more aligned with models of larger, ionized PAHs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSD measurements from BOSS galaxy power spectrum using the halo perturbation theory model</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rsd_measurements_from_boss_galaxy_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_perturbation_theory_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/rsd_measurements_from_boss_galaxy_power_spectrum_using_the_halo_perturbation_theory_model/</guid>
      <description>First author: Byeonghee Yu
We present growth of structure constraints from the cosmological analysis of the power spectrum multipoles of SDSS-III BOSS DR12 galaxies. We use the galaxy power spectrum model of Hand et al. (2017), which decomposes the galaxies into halo mass bins, each of which is modeled separately using the relations between halo biases and halo mass. The model combines Eulerian perturbation theory and halo model calibrated on $N$-body simulations to model the halo clustering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The galaxy mass-size relation in CARLA clusters and proto-clusters at 1.4 &lt; z &lt; 2.8: larger cluster galaxy sizes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_galaxy_mass-size_relation_in_carla_clusters_and_proto-clusters_at_1.4__z__2.8_larger_cluster_galaxy_sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_galaxy_mass-size_relation_in_carla_clusters_and_proto-clusters_at_1.4__z__2.8_larger_cluster_galaxy_sizes/</guid>
      <description>First author: Anton V. Afanasiev
(Abridged) We study the galaxy mass-size relation in CARLA spectroscopically confirmed clusters at $1.4&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2.8$, which span a total stellar mass $11.3&amp;lt;\mathrm{log}(M^c_*/M_{\odot})&amp;lt;12.6$ (halo mass $13.5 \lesssim \mathrm{log}(M^c_h/M_{\odot}) \lesssim 14.5$). Our main finding is that cluster passive ETG at $z \gtrsim 1.5$ with ${\rm log}(M/M_{\odot})&amp;gt;10.5$ are systematically $\gtrsim 0.2-0.3~{\rm dex}$ larger than field ETGs. The passive ETG average size evolution is slower at $1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;2$ when compared to the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The H$α$ and [O III] $λ5007$ Luminosity Functions of $1.2&lt;z&lt;1.9$ Emission-Line Galaxies from HST Grism Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__and_o_iii__%CE%BB5007__luminosity_functions_of__1.2z1.9__emission-line_galaxies_from_hst_grism_spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_h_%CE%B1__and_o_iii__%CE%BB5007__luminosity_functions_of__1.2z1.9__emission-line_galaxies_from_hst_grism_spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gautam Nagaraj
Euclid and the Roman Space Telescope (Roman) will soon use grism spectroscopy to detect millions of galaxies via H$\alpha$ and [O III] $\lambda 5007$ emission. To better constrain the expected galaxy counts from these instruments, we use a vetted sample of 4,239 emission-line galaxies from the 3D-HST survey to measure the H$\alpha$ and [O III] $\lambda 5007$ luminosity functions between $1.16&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;1.90$; this sample is $\sim 4$ times larger than previous studies at this redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one-loop bispectrum of galaxies in redshift space from the Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_one-loop_bispectrum_of_galaxies_in_redshift_space_from_the_effective_field_theory_of_large-scale_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_one-loop_bispectrum_of_galaxies_in_redshift_space_from_the_effective_field_theory_of_large-scale_structure/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guido D&amp;rsquo;Amico
We derive the kernels and the Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure counterterms for the one-loop bispectrum of dark matter and of biased tracers in real and redshift space. This requires the expansion of biased tracers up to fourth order in fluctuations. In the process, we encounter several subtleties related to renormalization. One is the fact that, in renormalizing the momentum, a local counterterm contributes non-locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The radio structure of the $γ$-ray narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy SDSS J211852.96$-$073227.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_radio_structure_of_the__%CE%B3_-ray_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_sdss_j211852.96_-_073227.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_radio_structure_of_the__%CE%B3_-ray_narrow-line_seyfert_1_galaxy_sdss_j211852.96_-_073227.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xi Shao
The $\gamma$-ray narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxies (NLS1s) can be considered to be the third class of $\gamma$-ray active galactic nuclei possessing relativistic jets. In this paper, we present multi-band high resolution Very Long Baseline Array (VLBA) images of the $\gamma$-ray NLS1, SDSS J211852.96$-$073227.5 (J2118$-$0732, $z=0.26$). We find a core-jet radio morphology and significant flux density variations in the radio core. The high brightness temperature estimated from VLBA images and core variability demonstrate that it exhibits substantial relativistic beaming effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibrating cosmological simulations with implicit likelihood inference using galaxy growth observables</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/calibrating_cosmological_simulations_with_implicit_likelihood_inference_using_galaxy_growth_observables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/calibrating_cosmological_simulations_with_implicit_likelihood_inference_using_galaxy_growth_observables/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yongseok Jo
In a novel approach employing implicit likelihood inference (ILI), also known as likelihood-free inference, we calibrate the parameters of cosmological hydrodynamic simulations against observations, which has previously been unfeasible due to the high computational cost of these simulations. For computational efficiency, we train neural networks as emulators on ~1000 cosmological simulations from the CAMELS project to estimate simulated observables, taking as input the cosmological and astrophysical parameters, and use these emulators as surrogates to the cosmological simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting the interstellar medium of a z=6.3 galaxy: X-shooter spectroscopy and HST imaging of the afterglow and environment of the Swift GRB 210905A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dissecting_the_interstellar_medium_of_a_z6.3_galaxy_x-shooter_spectroscopy_and_hst_imaging_of_the_afterglow_and_environment_of_the_swift_grb_210905a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dissecting_the_interstellar_medium_of_a_z6.3_galaxy_x-shooter_spectroscopy_and_hst_imaging_of_the_afterglow_and_environment_of_the_swift_grb_210905a/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Saccardi
The study of the properties of galaxies in the first billion years after the Big Bang is one of the major topic of current astrophysics. Optical/near-infrared spectroscopy of the afterglows of long Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) provide a powerful diagnostic tool to probe the interstellar medium (ISM) of their host galaxies and foreground absorbers, even up to the highest redshifts. We analyze the VLT/X-shooter afterglow spectrum of GRB 210905A, triggered by the Swift Neil Gehrels Observatory, and detect neutral-hydrogen, low-ionization, high-ionization, and fine-structure absorption lines from a complex system at z=6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for a Massive Andromeda Galaxy Using Satellite Galaxy Proper Motions</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_a_massive_andromeda_galaxy_using_satellite_galaxy_proper_motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/evidence_for_a_massive_andromeda_galaxy_using_satellite_galaxy_proper_motions/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ekta Patel
We present new mass estimates for Andromeda (M31) using the orbital angular momenta of four satellite galaxies (M33, NGC 185, NGC 147, IC 10) derived from existing proper motions, distances, and line-of-sight velocities. We infer two masses for M31: $M_{\rm vir}= 2.81^{+1.48}{-0.75}\times10^{12}, M{\odot}$ using satellite galaxy phase space information derived with HST-based M31 proper motions and $M_{\rm vir}=2.99^{+1.32}{-0.68}\times10^{12}, M{\odot}$ using phase space information derived with the weighted average of HST+Gaia-based M31 proper motions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA): The Dependence of Star Formation on Surface Brightness in Low Redshift Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_the_dependence_of_star_formation_on_surface_brightness_in_low_redshift_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_the_dependence_of_star_formation_on_surface_brightness_in_low_redshift_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: S. Phillipps
The star formation rate in galaxies is well known to correlate with stellar mass (the `star-forming main sequence&amp;rsquo;). Here we extend this further to explore any additional dependence on galaxy surface brightness, a proxy for stellar mass surface density. We use a large sample of low redshift ($z \leq 0.08$) galaxies from the GAMA survey which have both SED derived star formation rates and photometric bulge-disc decompositions, the latter providing measures of disc surface brightness and disc masses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lopsided Galaxies in a cosmological context: a new galaxy-halo connection</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lopsided_galaxies_in_a_cosmological_context_a_new_galaxy-halo_connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lopsided_galaxies_in_a_cosmological_context_a_new_galaxy-halo_connection/</guid>
      <description>First author: Silvio Varela-Lavin
Disc galaxies commonly show asymmetric features in their morphology, such as warps and lopsidedness. These features can provide key information regarding the recent evolution of a given disc galaxy. In the nearby Universe, up to ~30 percent of late-type galaxies display a global non-axisymmetric lopsided mass distribution, but little attention has been paid to the origin of this perturbation. In this work, we study the origin of lopsided perturbations in simulated disc galaxies extracted from the TNG50 simulation of the IllustrisTNG project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merger Signatures are Common, but not Universal, In Massive, Recently-Quenched Galaxies at z~0.7</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/merger_signatures_are_common_but_not_universal_in_massive_recently-quenched_galaxies_at_z~0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/merger_signatures_are_common_but_not_universal_in_massive_recently-quenched_galaxies_at_z~0.7/</guid>
      <description>First author: Margaret Verrico
We present visual classifications of merger-induced tidal disturbances in 143 $\rm{M}* \sim 10^{11}\rm{M}\odot$ post-starburst galaxies at z$\sim$0.7 identified in the SQuIGG$\vec{L}$E Sample. This sample spectroscopically selects galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey that have stopped their primary epoch of star formation within the past $\sim$500 Myrs. Visual classifications are performed on Hyper Suprime Cam (HSC) i-band imaging. We compare to a control sample of mass- and redshift-matched star-forming and quiescent galaxies from the Large Early Galaxy Census and find that post-starburst galaxies are more likely to be classified as disturbed than either category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the sociology and hierarchy of voids: a study of seven CAVITY nearby galaxy voids and their dynamical CosmicFlows-3 environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sociology_and_hierarchy_of_voids_a_study_of_seven_cavity_nearby_galaxy_voids_and_their_dynamical_cosmicflows-3_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_sociology_and_hierarchy_of_voids_a_study_of_seven_cavity_nearby_galaxy_voids_and_their_dynamical_cosmicflows-3_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: H. M. Courtois
Context. The present study addresses a key question for our understanding of the relation between void galaxies and their environment: the relationship between luminous and dark matter in and around voids. Aims. To explore how empty of matter local Universe voids are, we study the full (dark+luminous) matter content of seven nearby cosmic voids that are fully contained within the CosmicFlows-3 volume. Methods. The cosmic voids matter density profiles are independently obtained using two different methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientations of DM Halos in FIRE-2 Milky Way-mass Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/orientations_of_dm_halos_in_fire-2_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/orientations_of_dm_halos_in_fire-2_milky_way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jay Baptista
The shape and orientation of dark matter (DM) halos are sensitive to the micro-physics of the DM particle, yet in many mass models, the symmetry axes of the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s DM halo are often assumed to be aligned with the symmetry axes of the stellar disk. This is well-motivated for the inner DM halo but not for the outer halo. We use zoomed cosmological-baryonic simulations from the Latte suite of FIRE-2 Milky Way-mass galaxies to explore the evolution of the DM halo&amp;rsquo;s orientation with radius and time, with or without a major merger with a Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) analog, and when varying the DM model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the extended structure of multiple sources strongly lensed by the ultra-massive elliptical galaxy SDSS J0100&#43;1818</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_the_extended_structure_of_multiple_sources_strongly_lensed_by_the_ultra-massive_elliptical_galaxy_sdss_j0100&#43;1818/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_the_extended_structure_of_multiple_sources_strongly_lensed_by_the_ultra-massive_elliptical_galaxy_sdss_j0100&#43;1818/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Bolamperti
We study the total and baryonic mass distributions of the deflector SDSS J0100+1818 through a full strong lensing analysis. The system is composed by an ultra-massive early-type galaxy at $z=0.581$, with total stellar mass of $(1.5 \pm 0.3) 10^{12}$ M$\odot$ and stellar velocity dispersion of ($450 \pm 40$) km s$^{-1}$, surrounded by ten multiple images of three background sources, two of which spectroscopically confirmed at $z=1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Energy Survey Year 3 high redshift sample: Selection, characterization and analysis of galaxy clustering</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_energy_survey_year_3_high_redshift_sample_selection_characterization_and_analysis_of_galaxy_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_energy_survey_year_3_high_redshift_sample_selection_characterization_and_analysis_of_galaxy_clustering/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Sánchez
The fiducial cosmological analyses of imaging galaxy surveys like the Dark Energy Survey (DES) typically probe the Universe at redshifts $z &amp;lt; 1$. This is mainly because of the limited depth of these surveys, and also because such analyses rely heavily on galaxy lensing, which is more efficient at low redshifts. In this work we present the selection and characterization of high-redshift galaxy samples using DES Year 3 data, and the analysis of their galaxy clustering measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The volumetric star formation law in nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_volumetric_star_formation_law_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bacchini
Star formation laws are empirical relations between the cold gas (HI+H$_2$) content of a galaxy and its star formation rate (SFR), being crucial for any model of galaxy formation and evolution. A well known example of such laws is the Schmidt-Kennicutt law, which is based on the projected surface densities. However, it has been long unclear whether a more fundamental relation exists between the intrinsic volume densities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward Accurate Modeling of Galaxy Clustering on Small Scales: Halo Model Extensions &amp; Lingering Tension</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toward_accurate_modeling_of_galaxy_clustering_on_small_scales_halo_model_extensions__lingering_tension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/toward_accurate_modeling_of_galaxy_clustering_on_small_scales_halo_model_extensions__lingering_tension/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gillian D. Beltz-Mohrmann
This paper represents an effort to provide robust constraints on cosmology and the galaxy-halo connection using a fully numerical model of small-scale galaxy clustering. We explore two extensions to the standard Halo Occupation Distribution model: assembly bias, whereby halo occupation depends on both halo mass and the larger environment, and velocity bias, whereby galaxy velocities do not perfectly trace the velocity of the dark matter within the halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VERTICO III: The Kennicutt-Schmidt relation in Virgo cluster galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_iii_the_kennicutt-schmidt_relation_in_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vertico_iii_the_kennicutt-schmidt_relation_in_virgo_cluster_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. J. Jiménez-Donaire
In this VERTICO science paper we aim to study how the star formation process depends on galactic environment and gravitational interactions in the context of galaxy evolution. We explore the scaling relation between the star formation rate (SFR) surface density and the molecular gas surface density, also known as the Kennicutt-Schmidt (KS) relation, in a subsample of Virgo cluster spiral galaxies. We use new ACA and TP observations from the VERTICO-ALMA Large Program at 720pc resolution to resolve the molecular gas content, as traced by the 12CO(2-1) transition, across the disks of 37 spiral galaxies in the Virgo cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of star clusters and enrichment by massive stars in simulations of low-metallicity galaxies with a fully sampled initial stellar mass function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_star_clusters_and_enrichment_by_massive_stars_in_simulations_of_low-metallicity_galaxies_with_a_fully_sampled_initial_stellar_mass_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/formation_of_star_clusters_and_enrichment_by_massive_stars_in_simulations_of_low-metallicity_galaxies_with_a_fully_sampled_initial_stellar_mass_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Natalia Lahén
We present new GRIFFIN project hydrodynamical simulations that model the formation of galactic star cluster populations in low-metallicity ($Z=0.00021$) dwarf galaxies, including radiation, supernova and stellar wind feedback of individual massive stars. In the simulations, stars are sampled from the stellar initial mass function (IMF) down to the hydrogen burning limit of 0.08 M$_\odot$. Mass conservation is enforced within a radius of 1 pc for the formation massive stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pristine Inner Galaxy Survey (PIGS) VI: Different vertical distributions between two DIBs at 442.8 nm and 862.1 nm</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pristine_inner_galaxy_survey_pigs_vi_different_vertical_distributions_between_two_dibs_at_442.8_nm_and_862.1_nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pristine_inner_galaxy_survey_pigs_vi_different_vertical_distributions_between_two_dibs_at_442.8_nm_and_862.1_nm/</guid>
      <description>First author: He Zhao
Although diffuse interstellar bands (DIBs) were discovered over 100 years ago, for most of them, their origins are still unknown. Investigation on the correlations between different DIBs is an important way to study the behavior and distributions of their carriers. Based on stacking thousands of spectra from the Pristine Inner Galaxy Survey, we study the correlations between two DIBs at 442.8 nm ($\lambda$442.8) and 862.1 nm ($\lambda$862.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VINTERGATAN-GM: The cosmological imprints of early mergers on Milky-Way-mass galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vintergatan-gm_the_cosmological_imprints_of_early_mergers_on_milky-way-mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/vintergatan-gm_the_cosmological_imprints_of_early_mergers_on_milky-way-mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Martin P. Rey
We present a new suite of cosmological zoom-in hydrodynamical ($\approx 20, \mathrm{pc}$) simulations of Milky-Way mass galaxies to study how a varying mass ratio for a Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) progenitor impacts the $z=0$ chemodynamics of halo stars. Using the genetic modification approach, we create five cosmological histories for a Milky-Way-mass dark matter halo ($M_{200} \approx 10^{12} , M_\mathrm{\odot}$), incrementally increasing the stellar mass ratio of a $z\approx2$ merger from 1:25 to 1:2, while fixing the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s final dynamical, stellar mass and large-scale environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: HI gas kinematics of galaxy pairs in cluster environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_hi_gas_kinematics_of_galaxy_pairs_in_cluster_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_hi_gas_kinematics_of_galaxy_pairs_in_cluster_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shin-Jeong Kim
We examine the HI gas kinematics of galaxy pairs in two clusters and a group using Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) WALLABY pilot survey observations. We compare the HI properties of galaxy pair candidates in the Hydra I and Norma clusters, and the NGC 4636 group, with those of non-paired control galaxies selected in the same fields. We perform HI profile decomposition of the sample galaxies using a tool, {\sc baygaud} which allows us to de-blend a line-of-sight velocity profile with an optimal number of Gaussian components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Properties of OGLE4 Mira variables in our Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_properties_of_ogle4_mira_variables_in_our_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/infrared_properties_of_ogle4_mira_variables_in_our_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kyung-Won Suh
We investigate infrared properties of OGLE4 Mira variables in our Galaxy. For each object, we cross-identify the WISE, 2MASS, and IRAS counterparts. We present various IR two-color diagrams (2CDs) and period-magnitude and period-color relations for the Mira variables. Generally, the Miras variables with longer periods are brighter in the IR fluxes and redder in the IR colors. In this work, we also revise and update the previous catalog of AGB stars in our Galaxy using the new sample of OGLE4 Mira variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclid preparation. XXVII. Covariance model validation for the 2-point correlation function of galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxvii._covariance_model_validation_for_the_2-point_correlation_function_of_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/euclid_preparation._xxvii._covariance_model_validation_for_the_2-point_correlation_function_of_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Euclid Collaboration
Aims. We validate a semi-analytical model for the covariance of real-space 2-point correlation function of galaxy clusters. Methods. Using 1000 PINOCCHIO light cones mimicking the expected Euclid sample of galaxy clusters, we calibrate a simple model to accurately describe the clustering covariance. Then, we use such a model to quantify the likelihood analysis response to variations of the covariance, and investigate the impact of a cosmology-dependent matrix at the level of statistics expected for the Euclid survey of galaxy clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOREVER22: the first bright galaxies with population III stars at redshifts $z \simeq 10-20$ and comparisons with JWST data</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forever22_the_first_bright_galaxies_with_population_iii_stars_at_redshifts__z__simeq_10-20__and_comparisons_with_jwst_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/forever22_the_first_bright_galaxies_with_population_iii_stars_at_redshifts__z__simeq_10-20__and_comparisons_with_jwst_data/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hidenobu Yajima
We study the formation of the first galaxies in overdense regions modelled by the FOREVER22 simulation project. Our simulations successfully reproduce the star formation rates and the $M_{\rm UV}-M_{\rm star}$ relations of candidate galaxies at $z \sim 10-14$ observed by James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). We suggest that the observed galaxies are hosted by dark-matter haloes with $M_{\rm h} \sim 10^{11}~\rm M_{\odot}$ and are in short-period starburst phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA): Extended Intra-Group Light in a group at $z=0.2$ from deep Hyper-Suprime Cam images</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_extended_intra-group_light_in_a_group_at__z0.2__from_deep_hyper-suprime_cam_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_gama_extended_intra-group_light_in_a_group_at__z0.2__from_deep_hyper-suprime_cam_images/</guid>
      <description>First author: Cristina Martinez-Lombilla
We present a pilot study to assess the potential of Hyper Suprime-Cam Public Data Release 2 (HSC-PDR2) images for the analysis of extended faint structures within groups of galaxies. We examine the intra-group light (IGL) of the group 400138 ($M_{\rm{dyn}}= 1.3 \pm 0.5 \times 10^{13} $M${\odot}$, $z\sim 0.2$) from the Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) survey using Hyper-Suprime Cam Subaru Strategic Program Public Data Release 2 (HSC-PDR2) images in $g$, $r$, and $i$ bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Characterizing the Most Heavily Dust-Obscured Galaxies at $1 \le z \le 4$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_and_characterizing_the_most_heavily_dust-obscured_galaxies_at__1__le_z__le_4_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/identifying_and_characterizing_the_most_heavily_dust-obscured_galaxies_at__1__le_z__le_4_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nicholas S. Martis
We present 65 extremely dust-obscured galaxies from the UltraVISTA DR3 survey of the COSMOS field at $1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4$. In contrast to other studies of dusty galaxies, we select our sample based on dust attenuation measured by UV-MIR spectral energy distribution (SED) modeling that allows for extreme attenuation levels. We construct our sample by making cuts at $1 \le z \le 4$, A$V \ge 3$, and log(M$*$/M$_\odot$)$ \ge 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMaNGA: mock MaNGA galaxies based on IllustrisTNG-50 and MaStar SSPs. II. the catalogue</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imanga_mock_manga_galaxies_based_on_illustristng-50_and_mastar_ssps._ii._the_catalogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/imanga_mock_manga_galaxies_based_on_illustristng-50_and_mastar_ssps._ii._the_catalogue/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lorenza Nanni
To probe the current theory on galaxy formation and evolution, an increased synergy between observations and simulations is necessary. For this reason, in our previous paper of this series, we presented a method to mock SDSS-IV/MaNGA integral-field spectroscopic galaxy observations from cosmological simulations of galaxy formation. Here we present the resulting mock galaxy catalogue. This catalogue consists of 1,000 unique galaxies in IllustrisTNG-50 falling into the SDSS-IV/MaNGA-primary target footprint, defined in the redshift and i-band absolute magnitude space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Activity in the Low Metallicity Dwarf Galaxy SDSS J0944-0038: A Glimpse into the Primordial Universe</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_activity_in_the_low_metallicity_dwarf_galaxy_sdss_j0944-0038_a_glimpse_into_the_primordial_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nuclear_activity_in_the_low_metallicity_dwarf_galaxy_sdss_j0944-0038_a_glimpse_into_the_primordial_universe/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael Reefe
Local low metallicity dwarf galaxies are relics of the early universe and hold clues into the origins of supermassive black holes (SMBHs). In recent work, coronal lines have been used to unveil a population of candidate accreting black holes in dwarf galaxies with gas phase metallicities and stellar masses well below the host galaxies of any previously known AGNs. Using MUSE/VLT observations, we report the detection of [Fe X] $\lambda$6374 coronal line emission and a broad H$\alpha$ line in the nucleus of SDSS J094401.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints on modified gravity from the BOSS galaxy survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_modified_gravity_from_the_boss_galaxy_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraints_on_modified_gravity_from_the_boss_galaxy_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lorenzo Piga
We develop a pipeline to set new constraints on scale-independent modified gravity, from the galaxy power spectrum in redshift space of BOSS DR12. The latter is modelled using the effective field theory of large-scale structure up to 1-loop order in perturbation theory. We test our pipeline on synthetic and simulated data, to assess systematic biases on the inferred cosmological parameters due to marginalization and theoretical errors, and we apply it to the normal branch of the DGP model with a $\Lambda$CDM background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust-free starburst galaxies at redshifts $z&gt;10$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust-free_starburst_galaxies_at_redshifts__z10_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dust-free_starburst_galaxies_at_redshifts__z10_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Biman B. Nath
One of the most distant galaxies GN-z11 was formed when the Universe was $\le$ 400 Myr old, and it displays a burst-like star formation rate $\sim 25~\msun$ yr$^{-1}$ with a metallicity $Z\sim 0.2\pm 0.1Z_\odot$. It resembles $z=2-3$ galaxies (at ``cosmic noon&amp;quot;) except for the fact that the measured reddening $E(B-V)=0.01\pm 0.01$ indicates the presence of little or no dust. This marked absence of dust hints towards violent dynamical events that destroy or evacuate dust along with gas out of the galaxy on a relatively short time scale and make it transparent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAVN Astrometry toward the Extreme Outer Galaxy: Kinematic distance with the proper motion of G034.84-00.95</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eavn_astrometry_toward_the_extreme_outer_galaxy_kinematic_distance_with_the_proper_motion_of_g034.84-00.95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eavn_astrometry_toward_the_extreme_outer_galaxy_kinematic_distance_with_the_proper_motion_of_g034.84-00.95/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nobuyuki Sakai
We aim to reveal the structure and kinematics of the Outer-Scutum-Centaurus (OSC) arm located on the far side of the Milky Way through very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) astrometry using KaVA, which is composed of KVN (Korean VLBI Network) and VERA (VLBI Exploration of Radio Astrometry). We report the proper motion of a 22 GHz H${2}$O maser source, which is associated with the star-forming region G034.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrostatic Mass Profiles of Galaxy Clusters in the eROSITA Survey</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrostatic_mass_profiles_of_galaxy_clusters_in_the_erosita_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hydrostatic_mass_profiles_of_galaxy_clusters_in_the_erosita_survey/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominik Scheck
To assume hydrostatic equilibrium between the intracluster medium and the gravitational potential of galaxy clusters is an extensively used method to investigate their total masses. We want to test hydrostatic masses obtained with an observational code in the context of the SRG/eROSITA survey. We use the hydrostatic modeling code MBProj2 to fit surface-brightness profiles to simulated clusters with idealized properties as well as to a sample of 93 clusters taken from the Magneticum Pathfinder simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASCOT: Molecular gas depletion times and metallicity gradients -- evidence for feedback in quenching active galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mascot_molecular_gas_depletion_times_and_metallicity_gradients_--_evidence_for_feedback_in_quenching_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mascot_molecular_gas_depletion_times_and_metallicity_gradients_--_evidence_for_feedback_in_quenching_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Bertemes
We present results from the first public data release of the MaNGA-ARO Survey of CO Targets (MASCOT), focussing our study on galaxies whose star-formation rates and stellar masses place them below the ridge of the star-forming Main Sequence. In optically-selected type 2 AGN/LINERs/Composites, we find an empirical relation between gas-phase metallicity gradients $\nabla Z$ and global molecular gas depletion times $t_\mathrm{dep} = M_{H_2}$/SFR with &amp;ldquo;more quenched&amp;rdquo; systems showing flatter/positive gradients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesh-free hydrodynamics in PKDGRAV3 for galaxy formation simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mesh-free_hydrodynamics_in_pkdgrav3_for_galaxy_formation_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mesh-free_hydrodynamics_in_pkdgrav3_for_galaxy_formation_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Isaac Alonso Asensio
We extend the state-of-the-art N-body code PKDGRAV3 with the inclusion of mesh-free gas hydrodynamics for cosmological simulations. Two new hydrodynamic solvers have been implemented, the mesh-less finite volume and mesh-less finite mass methods. The solvers manifestly conserve mass, momentum and energy, and have been validated with a wide range of standard test simulations, including cosmological simulations. We also describe improvements to PKDGRAV3 that have been implemented for performing hydrodynamic simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The production of ionizing photons in UV-faint z~3-7 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_production_of_ionizing_photons_in_uv-faint_z~3-7_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_production_of_ionizing_photons_in_uv-faint_z~3-7_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gonzalo Prieto-Lyon
The demographics of the production and escape of ionizing photons from UV-faint early galaxies is a key unknown in discovering the primary drivers of reionization. With the advent of JWST it is finally possible to observe the rest-frame optical nebular emission from individual sub-L$^*$ z&amp;gt;3 galaxies to measure the production of ionizing photons, $\xi_\mathrm{ion}$. Here we study a sample of 380 z~3-7 galaxies spanning -23 &amp;lt;M$\mathrm{UV}$ &amp;lt; -15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spatially resolved view of star formation in galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spatially_resolved_view_of_star_formation_in_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spatially_resolved_view_of_star_formation_in_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Bianca M. Poggianti
Integral field spectroscopic studies of galaxies in dense environments, such as clusters and groups of galaxies, have provided new insights for understanding how star formation proceeds, and quenches. I present the spatially resolved view of the star formation activity and its link with the multiphase gas in cluster galaxies based on MUSE and multi-wavelength data of the GASP survey. I discuss the link among the different scales (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Witnessing a Galaxy Cluster Merger with JWST and a Chandra X-ray Temperature Map</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/witnessing_a_galaxy_cluster_merger_with_jwst_and_a_chandra_x-ray_temperature_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/witnessing_a_galaxy_cluster_merger_with_jwst_and_a_chandra_x-ray_temperature_map/</guid>
      <description>First author: Brian C. Alden
The first James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) image released was of galaxy cluster SMACSJ0723.3- 7327, a lensing cluster at z=0.39 showing detail only JWST can provide. While the majority of the focus has been on the brilliantly lensed galaxies at redshifts far beyond it, there is more to the story than it being just a lensing cluster. The Chandra X-ray temperature map tells a tale of a merging cluster with a significant subcluster leaving a wake in the intracluster medium (ICM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistent and simultaneous modelling of galaxy clustering and galaxy-galaxy lensing with Subhalo Abundance Matching</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/consistent_and_simultaneous_modelling_of_galaxy_clustering_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_with_subhalo_abundance_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/consistent_and_simultaneous_modelling_of_galaxy_clustering_and_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_with_subhalo_abundance_matching/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergio Contreras
The spatial distribution of galaxies and their gravitational lensing signal offer complementary tests of galaxy formation physics and cosmology. However, their synergy can only be fully exploited if both probes are modelled accurately and consistently. In this paper, we demonstrate that this can be achieved using an extension of Subhalo Abundance Matching, dubbed SHAMe. Specifically, we use mock catalogues built from the TNG300 hydrodynamical simulation to show that SHAMe can simultaneously model the multipoles of the redshift-space galaxy correlation function and galaxy-galaxy lensing, without noticeable bias within the statistical sampling uncertainties of a SDSS volume and on scales r = [0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity of dust properties in external galaxies confirmed by polarization signals from Type II supernovae</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/diversity_of_dust_properties_in_external_galaxies_confirmed_by_polarization_signals_from_type_ii_supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/diversity_of_dust_properties_in_external_galaxies_confirmed_by_polarization_signals_from_type_ii_supernovae/</guid>
      <description>First author: Takashi Nagao
Investigating interstellar (IS) dust properties in external galaxies is important not only to infer the intrinsic properties of astronomical objects but also to understand the star/planet formation in the galaxies. From the non-Milky-Way-like extinction and interstellar polarization (ISP) observed in reddened Type~Ia supernovae (SNe), it has been suggested that their host galaxies contain dust grains whose properties are substantially different from the Milky-Way (MW) dust. It is important to investigate the universality of such non-MW-like dust in the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MaNGIA: 10,000 mock galaxies for stellar population analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mangia_10000_mock_galaxies_for_stellar_population_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mangia_10000_mock_galaxies_for_stellar_population_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Regina Sarmiento
Modern astronomical observations give unprecedented access to the physical properties of nearby galaxies, including spatially resolved stellar populations. However, observations can only give a present-day view of the Universe, whereas cosmological simulations give access to the past record of the processes that galaxies have experienced in their evolution. To connect the events that happened in the past with galactic properties as seen today, simulations must be taken to a common ground before being compared to observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the accretion and feedback of supermassive black hole binaries in gas-rich galaxy mergers</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_the_accretion_and_feedback_of_supermassive_black_hole_binaries_in_gas-rich_galaxy_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/modelling_the_accretion_and_feedback_of_supermassive_black_hole_binaries_in_gas-rich_galaxy_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shihong Liao
We introduce a new model for the accretion and feedback of supermassive black hole (SMBH) binaries to the KETJU code, which enables us to resolve the evolution of SMBH binaries down to separations of tens of Schwarzschild radii in gas-rich galaxy mergers. Our subgrid binary accretion model extends the widely used Bondi&amp;ndash;Hoyle&amp;ndash;Lyttleton accretion into the binary phase and incorporates preferential mass accretion onto the secondary SMBH, which is motivated by results from small-scale hydrodynamical circumbinary disc simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting sub-millimeter flux densities from global galaxy properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/predicting_sub-millimeter_flux_densities_from_global_galaxy_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/predicting_sub-millimeter_flux_densities_from_global_galaxy_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: R. K. Cochrane
Recent years have seen growing interest in post-processing cosmological simulations with radiative transfer codes to predict observable fluxes for simulated galaxies. However, this can be slow, and requires a number of assumptions in cases where simulations do not resolve the ISM. Zoom-in simulations better resolve the detailed structure of the ISM and the geometry of stars and gas, however statistics are limited due to the computational cost of simulating even a single halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing and Classifying SDSS DR16 Galaxy Spectra with Machine-Learning and Dimensionality Reduction Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_and_classifying_sdss_dr16_galaxy_spectra_with_machine-learning_and_dimensionality_reduction_algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/reconstructing_and_classifying_sdss_dr16_galaxy_spectra_with_machine-learning_and_dimensionality_reduction_algorithms/</guid>
      <description>First author: Felix Pat
Optical spectra of galaxies and quasars from large cosmological surveys are used to measure redshifts and infer distances. They are also rich with information on the intrinsic properties of these astronomical objects. However, their physical interpretation can be challenging due to the substantial number of degrees of freedom, various sources of noise, and degeneracies between physical parameters that cause similar spectral characteristics. To gain deeper insights into these degeneracies, we apply two unsupervised machine learning frameworks to a sample from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey data release 16 (SDSS DR16).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dark side of galaxy stellar populations II: The dependence of star formation histories on halo mass and on the scatter of the main sequence</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_side_of_galaxy_stellar_populations_ii_the_dependence_of_star_formation_histories_on_halo_mass_and_on_the_scatter_of_the_main_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_dark_side_of_galaxy_stellar_populations_ii_the_dependence_of_star_formation_histories_on_halo_mass_and_on_the_scatter_of_the_main_sequence/</guid>
      <description>First author: Laura Scholz-Diaz
Nearby galaxies are the end result of their cosmological evolution, which is predicted to be influenced by the growth of their host dark matter halos. This co-evolution potentially leaves signatures in present-day observed galaxy properties, which might be essential to further understand how the growth and properties of galaxies are connected to those of their host halos. In this work, we study the evolutionary histories of nearby galaxies both in terms of their host halos and the scatter of the star-forming main sequence by investigating their time-resolved stellar populations using absorption optical spectra drawn from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A unified model for the co-evolution of galaxies and their circumgalactic medium: the relative roles of turbulence and atomic cooling physics</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unified_model_for_the_co-evolution_of_galaxies_and_their_circumgalactic_medium_the_relative_roles_of_turbulence_and_atomic_cooling_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_unified_model_for_the_co-evolution_of_galaxies_and_their_circumgalactic_medium_the_relative_roles_of_turbulence_and_atomic_cooling_physics/</guid>
      <description>First author: Viraj Pandya
The circumgalactic medium (CGM) plays a pivotal role in regulating gas flows around galaxies and thus shapes their evolution. However, the details of how galaxies and their CGM co-evolve remain poorly understood. We present a new time-dependent two-zone model that self-consistently tracks not just mass and metal flows between galaxies and their CGM but also the evolution of the global thermal and turbulent kinetic energy of the CGM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-based galaxy image deconvolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_learning-based_galaxy_image_deconvolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_learning-based_galaxy_image_deconvolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Utsav Akhaury
With the onset of large-scale astronomical surveys capturing millions of images, there is an increasing need to develop fast and accurate deconvolution algorithms that generalize well to different images. A powerful and accessible deconvolution method would allow for the reconstruction of a cleaner estimation of the sky. The deconvolved images would be helpful to perform photometric measurements to help make progress in the fields of galaxy formation and evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Space Telescope Observations of Tadpole Galaxies Kiso 3867, SBS0, SBS1, and UM461</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_space_telescope_observations_of_tadpole_galaxies_kiso_3867_sbs0_sbs1_and_um461/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/hubble_space_telescope_observations_of_tadpole_galaxies_kiso_3867_sbs0_sbs1_and_um461/</guid>
      <description>First author: Debra Meloy Elmegreen
Tadpole galaxies are metal-poor dwarfs with typically one dominant star-forming region, giving them a head-tail structure when inclined. A metallicity drop in the head suggests that gas accretion with even lower metallicity stimulated the star formation. Here we present multiband HST WFC3 and ACS images of four nearby (&amp;lt;25 Mpc) tadpoles, SBS0, SBS1, Kiso 3867, and UM461, selected for their clear metallicity drops shown in previous spectroscopic studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Alignments Between Galaxies and the Cosmic Web at $z\sim 1-2$ in the IllustrisTNG Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intrinsic_alignments_between_galaxies_and_the_cosmic_web_at__z_sim_1-2__in_the_illustristng_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/intrinsic_alignments_between_galaxies_and_the_cosmic_web_at__z_sim_1-2__in_the_illustristng_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Benjamin Zhang
Galaxy formation theories predict that galaxy shapes and angular momenta have intrinsic alignments (IA) with the cosmic web, which provides an observational test of various theories, and is important to quantify as a nuisance parameter for weak lensing. We study galaxy IA in the IllustrisTNG suite of hydrodynamical simulations at redshifts 1 and 2, finding that alignment trends are consistent with previous studies. However, we find that the magnitude of the spin alignment signal is $\sim 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mock Galaxy Surveys for HST and JWST from the IllustrisTNG Simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mock_galaxy_surveys_for_hst_and_jwst_from_the_illustristng_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mock_galaxy_surveys_for_hst_and_jwst_from_the_illustristng_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gregory F. Snyder
We present and analyze a series of synthetic galaxy survey fields based on the IllustrisTNG Simulation suite. With the Illustris public data release and JupyterLab service, we generated a set of twelve lightcone catalogs covering areas from 5 to 365 square arcminutes, similar to several JWST Cycle 1 programs, including JADES, CEERS, PRIMER, and NGDEEP. From these catalogs, we queried the public API to generate simple mock images in a series of broadband filters used by JWST-NIRCam and the Hubble Space Telescope cameras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric redshift estimation of galaxies in the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_redshift_estimation_of_galaxies_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_redshift_estimation_of_galaxies_in_the_desi_legacy_imaging_surveys/</guid>
      <description>First author: Changhua Li
The accurate estimation of photometric redshifts plays a crucial role in accomplishing science objectives of the large survey projects. The template-fitting and machine learning are the two main types of methods applied currently. Based on the training set obtained by cross-correlating the DESI Legacy Imaging Surveys DR9 galaxy catalogue and SDSS DR16 galaxy catalogue, the two kinds of methods are used and optimized, such as EAZY for template-fitting approach and CATBOOST for machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of star-forming rings in S0 galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_star-forming_rings_in_s0_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_star-forming_rings_in_s0_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. L. Tous
Spatially resolved IFS maps in a sample of $532$ S0 galaxies from the MaNGA survey have unveiled the existence of inner rings ($\langle R\rangle\sim 1,R_\mathrm{e}$) betraying ongoing star formation in a number of these objects. Activity gradients averaged over bins of galactocentric radius up to $\sim 1.5,R_\mathrm{e}$ have been measured in the subspace defined by the first two principal components of the optical spectra of these galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing ICM cooling and AGN feedback from the macro to the meso scales in the galaxy cluster ZwCl 235</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chasing_icm_cooling_and_agn_feedback_from_the_macro_to_the_meso_scales_in_the_galaxy_cluster_zwcl_235/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/chasing_icm_cooling_and_agn_feedback_from_the_macro_to_the_meso_scales_in_the_galaxy_cluster_zwcl_235/</guid>
      <description>First author: F. Ubertosi
We aim to investigate the AGN/ICM interplay in ZwCl 235, a galaxy cluster with high X-ray flux, an extended central radio galaxy, and evidence of multi-phase gas at its center. Using archival data from the Chandra telescope, the VLASS survey, the LOTSS survey and the VLBA telescope, we perform a complete study of ZwCl 235, dissecting the dynamics of the ICM, the thermodynamic state of the central gas, and the properties of the BCG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining quenching timescales in galaxy clusters by forward-modelling stellar ages and quiescent fractions in projected phase space</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_quenching_timescales_in_galaxy_clusters_by_forward-modelling_stellar_ages_and_quiescent_fractions_in_projected_phase_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_quenching_timescales_in_galaxy_clusters_by_forward-modelling_stellar_ages_and_quiescent_fractions_in_projected_phase_space/</guid>
      <description>First author: Andrew M. M. Reeves
We forward-model mass-weighted ages (MWAs) and quiescent fractions in projected phase space (PPS), using data from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, to jointly constrain an infall quenching model for galaxies in $\log(M_{\mathrm{vir}}/\mathrm{M}{\odot})&amp;gt;14$ galaxy clusters at $z\sim 0$. We find the average deviation in MWA from the MWA-$M\star$ relation depends on position in PPS, with a maximum difference between the inner cluster and infalling interloper galaxies of $\sim 1$ Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Synoptic Array science I: discovery of the host galaxy of FRB 20220912A</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_i_discovery_of_the_host_galaxy_of_frb_20220912a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/deep_synoptic_array_science_i_discovery_of_the_host_galaxy_of_frb_20220912a/</guid>
      <description>First author: Vikram Ravi
We report the detection and interferometric localization of the repeating fast radio burst (FRB) source FRB 20220912A during commissioning observations with the Deep Synoptic Array (DSA-110). Two bursts were detected from FRB 20220912A, one each on 2022 October 18 and 2022 October 25. The best-fit position is (R.A. J2000, decl. J2000) = (23:09:04.9, +48:42:25.4), with a 90% confidence error ellipse of $\pm2$ arcsec and $\pm1$ arcsec in right ascension and declination respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIGS: Deep Inference of Galaxy Spectra with Neural Posterior Estimation</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/digs_deep_inference_of_galaxy_spectra_with_neural_posterior_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/digs_deep_inference_of_galaxy_spectra_with_neural_posterior_estimation/</guid>
      <description>First author: Gourav Khullar
With the advent of billion-galaxy surveys with complex data, the need of the hour is to efficiently model galaxy spectral energy distributions (SEDs) with robust uncertainty quantification. The combination of Simulation-Based inference (SBI) and amortized Neural Posterior Estimation (NPE) has been successfully used to analyse simulated and real galaxy photometry both precisely and efficiently. In this work, we utilise this combination and build on existing literature to analyse simulated noisy galaxy spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dusty winds clear JWST super-early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dusty_winds_clear_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/dusty_winds_clear_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fabrizio Fiore
The JWST discovery of a number of super-early (redshift $z&amp;gt;10$), blue galaxies requires these systems to be essentially dust-free in spite of their large stellar masses. A possible explanation is that dust is evacuated by radiatively-driven outflows. We test this hypothesis by deriving the Eddington ratio, $\lambda_E$, for 134 galaxies at $6.5&amp;lt; z &amp;lt;16$. We find a strong anti-correlation between $\lambda_E$ and dust UV optical depth, $\tau_{1500} \propto \lambda_E^{-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Low-mass End of the Black Hole Mass Function via a Study of Faint Local Spiral Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_the_black_hole_mass_function_via_a_study_of_faint_local_spiral_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/probing_the_low-mass_end_of_the_black_hole_mass_function_via_a_study_of_faint_local_spiral_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael S. Fusco
We present an analysis of the pitch angle distribution function (PADF) for nearby galaxies and its resulting black hole mass function (BHMF) via the well-known relationship between pitch angle and black hole mass. Our sample consists of a subset of 74 spiral galaxies from the Carnegie-Irvine Galaxy Survey with absolute $B$-band magnitude $\mathfrak{M}{B}&amp;gt;-19.12$ mag and luminosity distance $D{\mathrm{L}} \leq 25.4$ Mpc, which is an extension of a complementary set of 140 more luminous ($\mathfrak{M}{B}\leq-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Galaxy Cluster Convergence from Lensed CMB with Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recovering_galaxy_cluster_convergence_from_lensed_cmb_with_generative_adversarial_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/recovering_galaxy_cluster_convergence_from_lensed_cmb_with_generative_adversarial_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Liam Parker
We present a new method which leverages conditional Generative Adversarial Networks (cGAN) to reconstruct galaxy cluster convergence from lensed CMB temperature maps. Our model is constructed to emphasize structure and high-frequency correctness relative to the Residual U-Net approach presented by Caldeira, et. al. (2019). Ultimately, we demonstrate that while both models perform similarly in the no-noise regime (as well as after random off-centering of the cluster center), cGAN outperforms ResUNet when processing CMB maps noised with 5uK/arcmin white noise or astrophysical foregrounds (tSZ and kSZ); this out-performance is especially pronounced at high l, which is exactly the regime in which the ResUNet under-performs traditional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shattering and growth of cold clouds in galaxy clusters: the role of radiative cooling, magnetic fields and thermal conduction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/shattering_and_growth_of_cold_clouds_in_galaxy_clusters_the_role_of_radiative_cooling_magnetic_fields_and_thermal_conduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/shattering_and_growth_of_cold_clouds_in_galaxy_clusters_the_role_of_radiative_cooling_magnetic_fields_and_thermal_conduction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Fred Jennings
In galaxy clusters, the hot intracluster medium (ICM) can develop a striking multi-phase structure around the brightest cluster galaxy. Much work has been done on understanding the origin of this central nebula, but less work has studied its eventual fate after the originally filamentary structure is broken into individual cold clumps. In this paper we perform a suite of 30 (magneto-)hydrodynamical simulations of kpc-scale cold clouds with typical parameters as found by galaxy cluster simulations, to understand whether clouds are mixed back into the hot ICM or can persist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pandora project. I: the impact of radiation and cosmic rays on baryonic and dark matter properties of dwarf galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pandora_project._i_the_impact_of_radiation_and_cosmic_rays_on_baryonic_and_dark_matter_properties_of_dwarf_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_pandora_project._i_the_impact_of_radiation_and_cosmic_rays_on_baryonic_and_dark_matter_properties_of_dwarf_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sergio Martin-Alvarez
Enshrouded in several well-known controversies, dwarf galaxies have been extensively studied to learn about the underlying cosmology, notwithstanding that physical processes regulating their properties are poorly understood. To shed light on these processes, we introduce the Pandora suite of 17 high-resolution (3.5 parsec half-cell side) dwarf galaxy formation cosmological simulations. Commencing with thermo-turbulent star formation and mechanical supernova feedback, we gradually increase the complexity of physics incorporated leading to full-physics models combining magnetism, on-the-fly radiative transfer and the corresponding stellar photoheating, and SN-accelerated cosmic rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A ~600 pc view of the strongly-lensed, massive main sequence galaxy J0901: a baryon-dominated, thick turbulent rotating disk with a clumpy cold gas ring at z = 2.259</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_~600_pc_view_of_the_strongly-lensed_massive_main_sequence_galaxy_j0901_a_baryon-dominated_thick_turbulent_rotating_disk_with_a_clumpy_cold_gas_ring_at_z__2.259/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_~600_pc_view_of_the_strongly-lensed_massive_main_sequence_galaxy_j0901_a_baryon-dominated_thick_turbulent_rotating_disk_with_a_clumpy_cold_gas_ring_at_z__2.259/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daizhong Liu
We present a high-resolution kinematic study of the massive main-sequence star-forming galaxy (SFG) SDSS J090122.37+181432.3 (J0901) at z=2.259, using 0.36 arcsec ALMA CO(3-2) and 0.1-0.5 arcsec SINFONI/VLT H-alpha observations. J0901 is a rare, strongly-lensed but otherwise normal massive (log(M_star/M_sun)~11) main sequence SFG, offering a unique opportunity to study a typical massive SFG under the microscope of lensing. Through forward dynamical modeling incorporating lensing deflection, we fit the CO and H-alpha kinematics in the image plane out to about one disk effective radius (R_e ~ 4 kpc) at a ~600pc delensed physical resolution along the kinematic major axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoencoding Galaxy Spectra I: Architecture</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/autoencoding_galaxy_spectra_i_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/autoencoding_galaxy_spectra_i_architecture/</guid>
      <description>First author: Peter Melchior
We introduce the neural network architecture SPENDER as a core differentiable building block for analyzing, representing, and creating galaxy spectra. It combines a convolutional encoder, which pays attention to up to 256 spectral features and compresses them into a low-dimensional latent space, with a decoder that generates a restframe representation, whose spectral range and resolution exceeds that of the observing instrument. The decoder is followed by explicit redshift, resampling, and convolution transformations to match the observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGER I. a large sample of [OIII]-emitting galaxies at $5.3 &lt; z &lt; 6.9$ and direct evidence for local reionization by galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_i._a_large_sample_of_oiii-emitting_galaxies_at__5.3__z__6.9__and_direct_evidence_for_local_reionization_by_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_i._a_large_sample_of_oiii-emitting_galaxies_at__5.3__z__6.9__and_direct_evidence_for_local_reionization_by_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daichi Kashino
We present a first sample of 117 [OIII]$\lambda\lambda$4960,5008-selected star-forming galaxies at $5.33 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 6.93$ detected in JWST/NIRCam 3.5$\mu$m slitless spectroscopy of a $6.5 \times 3.4$ arcmin$^2$ field centered on the hyperluminous quasar SDSS J0100+2802, obtained as part of the EIGER (Emission-line galaxies and Intergalactic Gas in the Epoch of Reionization) survey. Three prominent galaxy overdensities are observed, one of them at the redshift of the quasar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGER II. first spectroscopic characterisation of the young stars and ionised gas associated with strong H$β$ and [OIII] line-emission in galaxies at z=5-7 with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_ii._first_spectroscopic_characterisation_of_the_young_stars_and_ionised_gas_associated_with_strong_h_%CE%B2__and_oiii_line-emission_in_galaxies_at_z5-7_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/eiger_ii._first_spectroscopic_characterisation_of_the_young_stars_and_ionised_gas_associated_with_strong_h_%CE%B2__and_oiii_line-emission_in_galaxies_at_z5-7_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jorryt Matthee
We present emission-line measurements and physical interpretations for a sample of 117 [OIII] emitting galaxies at $z=5.33-6.93$, using the first deep JWST/NIRCam wide field slitless spectroscopic observations. Our 9.7-hour integration is centered upon the $z=6.3$ quasar J0100+2802 &amp;ndash; the first of six fields targeted by the EIGER survey &amp;ndash; and covers $\lambda=3-4$ microns. We detect 133 [OIII] doublets, but merge pairs within $\approx$10 kpc and 600 km s$^{-1}$, motivated by their small scale clustering excess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy And Mass Assembly: Galaxy Morphology in the Green Valley, Prominent rings and looser Spiral Arms</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_galaxy_morphology_in_the_green_valley_prominent_rings_and_looser_spiral_arms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/galaxy_and_mass_assembly_galaxy_morphology_in_the_green_valley_prominent_rings_and_looser_spiral_arms/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dominic Smith
Galaxies broadly fall into two categories: star-forming (blue) galaxies and quiescent (red) galaxies. In between, one finds the less populated ``green valley&amp;quot;. Some of these galaxies are suspected to be in the process of ceasing their star-formation through a gradual exhaustion of gas supply or already dead and are experiencing a rejuvenation of star-formation through fuel injection. We use the Galaxy And Mass Assembly database and the Galaxy Zoo citizen science morphological estimates to compare the morphology of galaxies in the green valley against those in the red sequence and blue cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric identification of compact galaxies, stars and quasars using multiple neural networks</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_identification_of_compact_galaxies_stars_and_quasars_using_multiple_neural_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_identification_of_compact_galaxies_stars_and_quasars_using_multiple_neural_networks/</guid>
      <description>First author: Siddharth Chaini
We present MargNet, a deep learning-based classifier for identifying stars, quasars and compact galaxies using photometric parameters and images from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) Data Release 16 (DR16) catalogue. MargNet consists of a combination of Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Artificial Neural Network (ANN) architectures. Using a carefully curated dataset consisting of 240,000 compact objects and an additional 150,000 faint objects, the machine learns classification directly from the data, minimising the need for human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of stochastic modeling on the predictive power of galaxy formation simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_stochastic_modeling_on_the_predictive_power_of_galaxy_formation_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_impact_of_stochastic_modeling_on_the_predictive_power_of_galaxy_formation_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Josh Borrow
All modern galaxy formation models employ stochastic elements in their sub-grid prescriptions to discretise continuous equations across the time domain. In this paper, we investigate how the stochastic nature of these models, notably star formation, black hole accretion, and their associated feedback, that act on small ($&amp;lt;$ kpc) scales, can back-react on macroscopic galaxy properties (e.g. stellar mass and size) across long ($&amp;gt;$ Gyr) timescales. We find that the scatter in scaling relations predicted by the EAGLE model implemented in the SWIFT code can be significantly impacted by random variability between re-simulations of the same object, even when galaxies are resolved by tens of thousands of particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inefficiency of stellar feedback in driving galactic outflows in massive galaxies at high redshift</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_inefficiency_of_stellar_feedback_in_driving_galactic_outflows_in_massive_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_inefficiency_of_stellar_feedback_in_driving_galactic_outflows_in_massive_galaxies_at_high_redshift/</guid>
      <description>First author: L. Bassini
Recent observations indicate that galactic outflows are ubiquitous in high redshift galaxies, including normal star forming galaxies, quasar hosts, and dusty star forming galaxies (DSFGs). However, the impact of outflows on the evolution of their hosts is still an open question. Here, we analyse the star formation histories (SFH) and galactic outflow properties of galaxies in massive haloes ($10^{12}M_{\odot}&amp;lt;M_{\rm vir} &amp;lt;5\times 10^{12}M_{\odot}$) at $z\gtrsim5.5$ in three zoom-in cosmological simulations from the MassiveFIRE suite, as part of the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new method for age-dating the formation of bars in disc galaxies: The TIMER view on NGC1433&#39;s old bar and the inside-out growth of its nuclear disc</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_for_age-dating_the_formation_of_bars_in_disc_galaxies_the_timer_view_on_ngc1433s_old_bar_and_the_inside-out_growth_of_its_nuclear_disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_new_method_for_age-dating_the_formation_of_bars_in_disc_galaxies_the_timer_view_on_ngc1433s_old_bar_and_the_inside-out_growth_of_its_nuclear_disc/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camila de Sá-Freitas
The epoch in which galactic discs settle is a major benchmark to test models of galaxy formation and evolution but is as yet largely unknown. Once discs settle and become self-gravitating enough, stellar bars are able to form; therefore, determining the ages of bars can shed light on the epoch of disc settling, and on the onset of secular evolution. Nevertheless, until now, timing when the bar formed has proven challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of local ultraluminous infrared galaxies and quasars with kernel principal component analysis</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classification_of_local_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_and_quasars_with_kernel_principal_component_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/classification_of_local_ultraluminous_infrared_galaxies_and_quasars_with_kernel_principal_component_analysis/</guid>
      <description>First author: Evangelos S. Papaefthymiou
We present a new diagnostic diagram for local ultraluminous infrared galaxies (ULIRGs) and quasars, analysing particularly the Spitzer Space Telescope&amp;rsquo;s Infrared Spectrograph (IRS) spectra of 102 local ULIRGs and 37 Palomar Green quasars. Our diagram is based on a special non-linear mapping of these data, employing the Kernel Principal Component Analysis method. The novelty of this map lies in the fact that it distributes the galaxies under study on the surface of a well-defined ellipsoid, which, in turn, links basic concepts from geometry to physical properties of the galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Census: Relative Distributions of Dark Matter, Galaxies and Diffuse Gas</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_census_relative_distributions_of_dark_matter_galaxies_and_diffuse_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_census_relative_distributions_of_dark_matter_galaxies_and_diffuse_gas/</guid>
      <description>First author: Raphaël Kou
Galaxies, diffuse gas and dark matter make up the cosmic web defining the large-scale structure of the universe. We constrain the joint distribution of these constituents by cross-correlating galaxy samples binned by stellar mass from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey CMASS catalogue with maps of lensing convergence and the thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich (tSZ) effect from the Planck mission. Fitting a halo-based model to our measured angular power spectra (galaxy-galaxy, galaxy-lensing convergence, galaxy-tSZ) at a median redshift of $z=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLARES VIII. The Emergence of Passive Galaxies in the Early Universe ($z &gt; 5$)</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flares_viii._the_emergence_of_passive_galaxies_in_the_early_universe__z__5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/flares_viii._the_emergence_of_passive_galaxies_in_the_early_universe__z__5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Christopher C. Lovell
Passive galaxies are ubiquitous in the local universe, and various physical channels have been proposed that lead to this passivity. To date, robust passive galaxy candidates have been detected up to $z \leqslant 5$, but it is still unknown if they exist at higher redshifts, what their relative abundances are, and what causes them to stop forming stars. We present predictions from the First Light And Reionisation Epoch Simulations (FLARES), a series of zoom simulations of a range of overdensities using the EAGLE code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globular Cluster Ultraluminous X-ray Sources in the Furthest Early-Type Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_sources_in_the_furthest_early-type_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/globular_cluster_ultraluminous_x-ray_sources_in_the_furthest_early-type_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: E. Thygesen
Ultraluminous X-ray Sources (ULXs) in globular clusters are low mass X-ray binaries that achieve high X-ray luminosities through a currently uncertain accretion mechanism. Using archival Chandra and Hubble Space Telescope observations, we perform a volume-limited search ($\lesssim$ 70 Mpc) of 21 of the most massive ($&amp;gt;10^{11.5} M_\odot$) early-type galaxies to identify ULXs hosted by globular cluster (GC) candidates. We find a total of 34 ULX candidates above the expected background within 5 times the effective radius of each galaxy, with 10 of these ($\sim29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Galaxy Morphological Visual Representation with Deep Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unsupervised_galaxy_morphological_visual_representation_with_deep_contrastive_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/unsupervised_galaxy_morphological_visual_representation_with_deep_contrastive_learning/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shoulin Wei
Galaxy morphology reflects structural properties which contribute to understand the formation and evolution of galaxies. Deep convolutional networks have proven to be very successful in learning hidden features that allow for unprecedented performance on galaxy morphological classification. Such networks mostly follow the supervised learning paradigm which requires sufficient labelled data for training. However, it is an expensive and complicated process of labeling for million galaxies, particularly for the forthcoming survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: Public release of HI data for almost 600 galaxies from phase 1 of ASKAP pilot observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_data_for_almost_600_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_data_for_almost_600_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: T. Westmeier
We present WALLABY pilot data release 1, the first public release of HI pilot survey data from the Wide-field ASKAP L-band Legacy All-sky Blind Survey (WALLABY) on the Australian Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder. Phase 1 of the WALLABY pilot survey targeted three $60~{\rm deg}^2$ regions on the sky in the direction of the Hydra and Norma galaxy clusters and the NGC 4636 galaxy group, covering the redshift range of z &amp;lt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WALLABY Pilot Survey: Public release of HI kinematic models for more than 100 galaxies from phase 1 of ASKAP pilot observations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_kinematic_models_for_more_than_100_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/wallaby_pilot_survey_public_release_of_hi_kinematic_models_for_more_than_100_galaxies_from_phase_1_of_askap_pilot_observations/</guid>
      <description>First author: N. Deg
We present the Widefield ASKAP L-band Legacy All-sky Blind surveY (WALLABY) Pilot Phase I HI kinematic models. This first data release consists of HI observations of three fields in the direction of the Hydra and Norma clusters, and the NGC 4636 galaxy group. In this paper, we describe how we generate and publicly release flat-disk tilted-ring kinematic models for 109/592 unique HI detections in these fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-detection of Broad Hydrogen Radio Recombination Lines in Circinus Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-detection_of_broad_hydrogen_radio_recombination_lines_in_circinus_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-detection_of_broad_hydrogen_radio_recombination_lines_in_circinus_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Junzhi Wang
The line widths of broad line regions (BLRs) of AGNs are key parameters for understanding the central super massive black holes (SMBHs). However, due to obscuration from dusty torus, optical recombination lines from BLRs in type II AGNs can not be directly detected. Radio recombination lines (RRLs), with low extinction, can be ideal tracers to probe emission from BLRs in type II AGNs. We performed RRL observations for H35$\alpha$ and H36$\alpha$ toward the center of Circinus galaxy with ALMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact symmetric ejection from the low mass AGN in the LINER galaxy NGC 4293</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_compact_symmetric_ejection_from_the_low_mass_agn_in_the_liner_galaxy_ngc_4293/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_compact_symmetric_ejection_from_the_low_mass_agn_in_the_liner_galaxy_ngc_4293/</guid>
      <description>First author: Xiaolong Yang
We conducted a Very Long Baseline Array (VLBA) observation of the low mass active galactic nucleus (AGN) in galaxy NGC 4293 ($z=0.003$). The object is associated with a low-ionization nuclear emission-line region (LINER). Its black hole mass is estimated as $\sim10^5$ or $\sim10^7 M_\odot$. The VLBA 1.5 GHz image shows an inverse symmetric structure with two discrete radio blobs separated by an angular distance of $\sim120$ mas, corresponding to $\sim7$ parsec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEERS Key Paper V: A triality on the nature of HST-dark galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ceers_key_paper_v_a_triality_on_the_nature_of_hst-dark_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ceers_key_paper_v_a_triality_on_the_nature_of_hst-dark_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pablo G. Pérez-González
The new capabilities that JWST offers in the near- and mid-infrared (IR) are used to investigate in unprecedented detail the nature of optical/near-IR faint, mid-IR bright sources, the so-called HST-dark galaxies among them. We gather JWST data from the CEERS survey in the EGS, jointly with HST data, to face this task by analyzing spatially resolved optical-to-mid-IR spectral energy distributions (SEDs) to estimate both photometric redshifts and stellar populations properties in two dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extragalactic magnetism with SOFIA (SALSA Legacy Program). VI. The magnetic fields in the multi-phase interstellar medium of the Antennae galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extragalactic_magnetism_with_sofia_salsa_legacy_program._vi._the_magnetic_fields_in_the_multi-phase_interstellar_medium_of_the_antennae_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extragalactic_magnetism_with_sofia_salsa_legacy_program._vi._the_magnetic_fields_in_the_multi-phase_interstellar_medium_of_the_antennae_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Enrique Lopez-Rodriguez
Mergers are thought to be a fundamental channel for galaxy growth, perturbing the gas dynamics and the magnetic fields (B-fields) in the interstellar medium (ISM). However, the mechanisms that amplify and dissipate B-fields during a merger remain unclear. We characterize the morphology of the ordered B-fields in the multi-phase ISM of the closest merger of two spiral galaxies, the Antennae galaxies. We compare the inferred B-fields using $154~\mu$m thermal dust and $11$ cm radio synchrotron emission polarimetric observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature of the Galaxies On Top Of Quasars producing MgII absorption</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nature_of_the_galaxies_on_top_of_quasars_producing_mgii_absorption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/nature_of_the_galaxies_on_top_of_quasars_producing_mgii_absorption/</guid>
      <description>First author: Labanya Kumar Guha
Quasar-galaxy pairs at small separations are important probes of gas flows in the disk-halo interface in galaxies. We study host galaxies of 198 MgII absorbers at $0.39\le z_{abs}\le1.05$ that show detectable nebular emission lines in the SDSS spectra. We report measurements of impact parameter (5.9$\le D[kpc]\le$16.9) and absolute B-band magnitude ($-18.7\le {\rm M_B}\le -22.3$ mag) of host galaxies of 74 of these absorbers using multi-band images from the DESI Legacy Imaging Survey, more than doubling the number of known host galaxies with $D\le17$ kpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of the Observed Lyman alpha EW Distribution of Dwarf Galaxies at z~2</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_the_observed_lyman_alpha_ew_distribution_of_dwarf_galaxies_at_z~2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_the_observed_lyman_alpha_ew_distribution_of_dwarf_galaxies_at_z~2/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. Snapp-Kolas
We present a rest-UV selected sample of 32 lensed galaxies at $z\sim 2$ observed with joint Keck/LRIS rest-UV and Keck/MOSFIRE rest-optical spectra behind the clusters Abell 1689, MACS J0717, and MACS J1149. The sample pushes towards the faintest UV luminosities observed ($-19 \le {\rm M_{\rm UV}} \le -17$) at this redshift. The fraction of dwarf galaxies identified as Ly$\alpha$ emitters ($\rm EW \ge 20\ \overset{\lower.5em\circ}{\mathrm{A}}$) is ${\rm X_{\rm LAE}}=25^{+15}{-10}%$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Dwarfs in Dwarf Spheroidal Galaxies: A New Class of Compact-Dark-Matter Detectors</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/white_dwarfs_in_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies_a_new_class_of_compact-dark-matter_detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/white_dwarfs_in_dwarf_spheroidal_galaxies_a_new_class_of_compact-dark-matter_detectors/</guid>
      <description>First author: Juri Smirnov
Recent surveys have discovered a population of faint supernovae, known as Ca-rich gap transients, inferred to originate from explosive ignitions of white dwarfs. In addition to their unique spectra and luminosities, these supernovae have an unusual spatial distribution and are predominantly found at large distances from their presumed host galaxies. We show that the locations of Ca-rich gap transients are well matched to the distribution of dwarf spheroidal galaxies surrounding large galaxies, in accordance with a scenario where dark matter interactions induce thermonuclear explosions among low-mass white dwarfs that may be otherwise difficult to ignite with standard stellar or binary evolution mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bright Supernova 1996cr in the Circinus Galaxy Imaged with VLBI: Shell Structure with Complex Evolution</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_bright_supernova_1996cr_in_the_circinus_galaxy_imaged_with_vlbi_shell_structure_with_complex_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_bright_supernova_1996cr_in_the_circinus_galaxy_imaged_with_vlbi_shell_structure_with_complex_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michael F. Bietenholz
We present broadband radio flux-density measurements supernova (SN) 1996cr, made with MeerKAT, ATCA and ALMA, and images made from very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) observations with the Australian Long Baseline Array. The spectral energy distribution of SN 1996cr in 2020, at age, $t \sim$8700 d, is a power-law, with flux density, $S\propto \nu^{-0.588 \pm 0.011}$ between 1 and 34 GHz, but may steepen at $&amp;gt;35$ GHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extragalactic Peaked-Spectrum Radio Sources at Low-Frequencies are Young Radio Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extragalactic_peaked-spectrum_radio_sources_at_low-frequencies_are_young_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/extragalactic_peaked-spectrum_radio_sources_at_low-frequencies_are_young_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. M. Slob
We present a sample of 373 peaked-spectrum (PS) sources with spectral peaks around 150MHz, selected using a subset of two LOFAR all-sky surveys, the LOFAR Two Meter Sky Survey and the LOFAR LBA Sky Survey. These surveys are the most sensitive low-frequency widefield surveys to date, allowing us to select low-luminosity PS sources. Our sample increases the number of known PS sources in our survey area by a factor 50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colliding Ghosts: Constraining Inflation with the Parity-Odd Galaxy Four-Point Function</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/colliding_ghosts_constraining_inflation_with_the_parity-odd_galaxy_four-point_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/colliding_ghosts_constraining_inflation_with_the_parity-odd_galaxy_four-point_function/</guid>
      <description>First author: Giovanni Cabass
Could new physics break the mirror symmetry of the Universe? Utilizing recent measurements of the parity-odd four-point correlation function of BOSS galaxies, we probe the physics of inflation by placing constraints on the amplitude of a number of parity-violating models. Within canonical models of (single-field, slow-roll) inflation, no parity-asymmetry can occur; however, it has recently been shown that breaking of the standard assumptions can lead to parity violation within the Effective Field Theory of Inflation (EFTI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoTSS Jellyfish Galaxies IV: Enhanced Star Formation on the Leading Half of Cluster Galaxies and Gas Compression in IC3949</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lotss_jellyfish_galaxies_iv_enhanced_star_formation_on_the_leading_half_of_cluster_galaxies_and_gas_compression_in_ic3949/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/lotss_jellyfish_galaxies_iv_enhanced_star_formation_on_the_leading_half_of_cluster_galaxies_and_gas_compression_in_ic3949/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ian D. Roberts
With MaNGA integral field spectroscopy, we present a resolved analysis of star formation for 29 jellyfish galaxies in nearby clusters, identified from radio continuum imaging taken by the Low Frequency Array. Simulations predict enhanced star formation on the &amp;ldquo;leading half&amp;rdquo; of galaxies undergoing ram pressure stripping, and in this work we report observational evidence for this elevated star formation. The dividing line (through the galaxy center) that maximizes this star formation enhancement is systematically tied to the observed direction of the ram pressure stripped tail, suggesting a physical connection between ram pressure and this star formation enhancement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red riding on hood: Exploring how galaxy colour depends on environment</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/red_riding_on_hood_exploring_how_galaxy_colour_depends_on_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/red_riding_on_hood_exploring_how_galaxy_colour_depends_on_environment/</guid>
      <description>First author: Pankaj C. Bhambhani
Galaxy populations are known to exhibit a strong colour bimodality, corresponding to blue star-forming and red quiescent subpopulations. The relative abundance of the two populations has been found to vary with stellar mass and environment. In this paper, we explore the effect of environment considering different types of measurements. We choose a sample of 49, 911 galaxie with $0.05 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.18$ from the Galaxy And Mass Assembly survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-calibrating optical galaxy cluster selection bias using cluster, galaxy, and shear cross-correlations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/self-calibrating_optical_galaxy_cluster_selection_bias_using_cluster_galaxy_and_shear_cross-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/self-calibrating_optical_galaxy_cluster_selection_bias_using_cluster_galaxy_and_shear_cross-correlations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Chenxiao Zeng
The clustering signals of galaxy clusters are known to be powerful tools for self-calibrating the mass-observable relation and are complementary to cluster abundance and lensing. In this work, we explore the possibility of combining three correlation functions &amp;ndash; cluster lensing, the cluster-galaxy cross-correlation function, and the galaxy auto-correlation function &amp;ndash; to self-calibrate optical cluster selection bias, the boosted clustering and lensing signals in a richness-selected sample mainly caused by projection effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shot in the Dark (Ages): a faint galaxy at $z=9.76$ confirmed with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_shot_in_the_dark_ages_a_faint_galaxy_at__z9.76__confirmed_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_shot_in_the_dark_ages_a_faint_galaxy_at__z9.76__confirmed_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Guido Roberts-Borsani
The appearance of galaxies over the first billion years after the Big Bang is believed to be responsible for the last dramatic change in the state of the Universe. Ultraviolet photons from galaxies within this time period - the Epoch of Reionization - ionized intergalactic Hydrogen, rendering the Universe transparent to UV radiation and ending the so-called cosmic Dark Ages, sometime after redshift $z\sim8$. The majority of ionizing photons in the first few hundred Myrs of cosmic history are thought to derive from galaxies significantly fainter than the characteristic luminosity $L^{}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of feedback on galaxies in the VELA simulations: elongation, clumps and compaction</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_feedback_on_galaxies_in_the_vela_simulations_elongation_clumps_and_compaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/effects_of_feedback_on_galaxies_in_the_vela_simulations_elongation_clumps_and_compaction/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Ceverino
The evolution of star-forming galaxies at high redshifts is very sensitive to the strength and nature of stellar feedback. Using two sets of cosmological, zoom-in simulations from the VELA suite, we compare the effects of two different models of feedback: with and without kinetic feedback. At a fixed halo mass and redshift, the stellar mass is reduced by a factor of 1-3 in the models with stronger feedback, so the stellar-mass-halo-mass relation is in better agreement with abundance matching results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematics of the Local Group gas and galaxies in the Hestia simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kinematics_of_the_local_group_gas_and_galaxies_in_the_hestia_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/kinematics_of_the_local_group_gas_and_galaxies_in_the_hestia_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Luis Biaus
We investigate the kinematic properties of gas and galaxies in the Local Group (LG) using high-resolution simulations performed by the {\sc Hestia} (High-resolution Environmental Simulations of The Immediate Area) collaboration. Our simulations include the correct cosmography surrounding LG-like regions consisting of two main spiral galaxies of $\sim 10^{12}$~M$_\odot$, their satellites and minor isolated galaxies, all sharing the same large-scale motion within a volume of a few Mpc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Globular Clusters in Galaxy Clusters: Sensitivity from the Formation and Evolution of Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_globular_clusters_in_galaxy_clusters_sensitivity_from_the_formation_and_evolution_of_globular_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/properties_of_globular_clusters_in_galaxy_clusters_sensitivity_from_the_formation_and_evolution_of_globular_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: So-Myoung Park
We investigate the properties of globular clusters in a galaxy cluster, using the particle tagging method with a semi-analytical approach in a cosmological context. We assume globular clusters form from dark matter halo mergers and their metallicity is assigned based on the stellar mass of the host dark matter halos and the formation redshift of GCs. Dynamical evolution and disruption of globular clusters are considered using semi-analytical approaches, controlled by several free parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quasi-stellar objects and galaxy mass density profiles derived using the submillimetre galaxies magnification bias</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quasi-stellar_objects_and_galaxy_mass_density_profiles_derived_using_the_submillimetre_galaxies_magnification_bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/quasi-stellar_objects_and_galaxy_mass_density_profiles_derived_using_the_submillimetre_galaxies_magnification_bias/</guid>
      <description>First author: D. Crespo
In this work, we want to exploit the magnification bias of the SMGs using two different foreground samples, quasi-stellar objects (QSOs) and galaxies. Our aim is to study and compare their mass density profiles and estimate their masses and concentrations. The background SMG sample consists of objects observed by \textit{Herschel} with 1.2&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;4.0. The foreground samples are QSOs and massive galaxies with spectroscopic redshifts between 0.2 and 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopy from Lyman alpha to [O III] 5007 of a Triply Imaged Magnified Galaxy at Redshift z = 9.5</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopy_from_lyman_alpha_to_o_iii_5007_of_a_triply_imaged_magnified_galaxy_at_redshift_z__9.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopy_from_lyman_alpha_to_o_iii_5007_of_a_triply_imaged_magnified_galaxy_at_redshift_z__9.5/</guid>
      <description>First author: Hayley Williams
Given their extremely faint apparent brightness, the nature of the first galaxies and how they reionized the Universe&amp;rsquo;s gas are not yet understood. Here we report the discovery, in James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) imaging, of a highly magnified, low-mass (log(M_*/M_sol)=7.70^{+0.11}{-0.09}) galaxy visible when the Universe was only 510 Myr old, and follow-up prism spectroscopy of the galaxy extending from Lyman alpha to [O III] 5007 in its rest frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Ultra-Diffuse Galaxies I: Mass-Size Outliers Among the Satellites of Milky Way Analogs</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_i_mass-size_outliers_among_the_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/beyond_ultra-diffuse_galaxies_i_mass-size_outliers_among_the_satellites_of_milky_way_analogs/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jiaxuan Li
Large diffuse galaxies are hard to find, but understanding the environments where they live, their numbers, and ultimately their origins, is of intense interest and importance for galaxy formation and evolution. Using Subaru&amp;rsquo;s Hyper Suprime-Cam Strategic Survey Program, we perform a systematic search for low surface brightness galaxies and present novel and effective methods for detecting and modeling them. As a case study, we surveyed 922 Milky Way analogs in the nearby Universe ($0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEERS Key Paper IV: The Diversity of Galaxy Structure and Morphology at z=3-9 with JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ceers_key_paper_iv_the_diversity_of_galaxy_structure_and_morphology_at_z3-9_with_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ceers_key_paper_iv_the_diversity_of_galaxy_structure_and_morphology_at_z3-9_with_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jeyhan S. Kartaltepe
We present a comprehensive analysis of the evolution of the morphological and structural properties of a large sample of galaxies at z=3-9 using early JWST CEERS NIRCam observations. Our sample consists of 850 galaxies at z&amp;gt;3 detected in both CANDELS HST imaging and JWST CEERS NIRCam images to enable a comparison of HST and JWST morphologies. Our team conducted a set of visual classifications, with each galaxy in the sample classified by three different individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Interpret Measurements of Diffuse Light in Stacked Observations of Groups and Clusters of Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_to_interpret_measurements_of_diffuse_light_in_stacked_observations_of_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/how_to_interpret_measurements_of_diffuse_light_in_stacked_observations_of_groups_and_clusters_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Syeda Lammim Ahad
The diffuse light within galaxy groups and clusters provides valuable insight into the growth of massive cosmic structures. Groups are particularly interesting in this context, because they represent the link between galactic haloes and massive clusters. However, low surface brightness makes their diffuse light extremely challenging to detect individually. Stacking many groups is a promising alternative, but its physical interpretation is complicated by possible systematic variations of diffuse light profiles with other group properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbit-Superposition Dynamical Modelling of Barred Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/orbit-superposition_dynamical_modelling_of_barred_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/orbit-superposition_dynamical_modelling_of_barred_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Behzad Tahmasebzadeh
Barred structures are important in understanding galaxy evolution, but they were not included explicitly in most dynamical models for nearby galaxies due to their complicated morphological and kinematic properties. We modify the triaxial orbit-superposition Schwarzschild implementation by Van den Bosch et al. (2008) to include barred structures explicitly. The gravitational potential is a combination of a spherical dark matter halo and stellar mass; with the 3D stellar density distribution de-projected from the observed 2D image using a two-component de-projection method, including an axisymmetric disk and a triaxial barred bulge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision Redshift-Space Galaxy Power Spectra using Zel&#39;dovich Control Variates</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/precision_redshift-space_galaxy_power_spectra_using_zeldovich_control_variates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/precision_redshift-space_galaxy_power_spectra_using_zeldovich_control_variates/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joseph DeRose
Numerical simulations in cosmology require trade-offs between volume, resolution and run-time that limit the volume of the Universe that can be simulated, leading to sample variance in predictions of ensemble-average quantities such as the power spectrum or correlation function(s). Sample variance is particularly acute at large scales, which is also where analytic techniques can be highly reliable. This provides an opportunity to combine analytic and numerical techniques in a principled way to improve the dynamic range and reliability of predictions for clustering statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stellar Chemical Abundances of Simulated Massive Galaxies at $z = 2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_stellar_chemical_abundances_of_simulated_massive_galaxies_at__z__2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_stellar_chemical_abundances_of_simulated_massive_galaxies_at__z__2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jee-Ho Kim
We analyze the stellar abundances of massive galaxies ($\log M_\ast/M_\odot&amp;gt;10.5$) at $z=2$ in the IllustrisTNG simulation with the goal of guiding the interpretation of current and future observations, particularly from the James Webb Space Telescope. We find that the effective size, $R_e$, of galaxies strongly affects the abundance measurements: both [Mg/H] and [Fe/H] are anti-correlated with $R_e$, while the relative abundance [Mg/Fe] slightly increases with $R_e$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virial theorem in clusters of galaxies with MOND</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/virial_theorem_in_clusters_of_galaxies_with_mond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/virial_theorem_in_clusters_of_galaxies_with_mond/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Lopez-Corredoira
A specific modification of Newtonian dynamics known as MOND has been shown to reproduce the dynamics of most astrophysical systems at different scales without invoking non-baryonic dark matter (DM). There is, however, a long-standing unsolved problem when MOND is applied to rich clusters of galaxies in the form of a deficit (by a factor around two) of predicted dynamical mass derived from the virial theorem with respect to observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Molecular Gas Ring Hidden in the Sombrero Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_molecular_gas_ring_hidden_in_the_sombrero_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_molecular_gas_ring_hidden_in_the_sombrero_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Jessica Sutter
We present Herschel, ALMA, and MUSE observations of the molecular ring of Messier 104, also known as the Sombrero galaxy. These previously unpublished archival data shed new light on the content of the interstellar medium of M104. In particular, molecular hydrogen measured by CO emission and dust measured by far-infrared light are uniformly distributed along the ring. The ionized gas revealed by H$\alpha$ and [CII] emission is distributed in knots along the ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Type Ia supernovae through their heights in edge-on galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_type_ia_supernovae_through_their_heights_in_edge-on_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/constraining_type_ia_supernovae_through_their_heights_in_edge-on_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lilit V. Barkhudaryan
In this Letter, using classified 197 supernovae (SNe) Ia, we perform an analyses of their height distributions from the disc in edge-on spirals and investigate their light-curve (LC) decline rates $(\Delta m_{15})$. We demonstrate, for the first time, that 91T-, 91bg-like, and normal SNe Ia subclasses are distributed differently toward the plane of their host disc. The average height from the disc and its comparison with scales of thin/thick disc components gives a possibility to roughly estimate the SNe Ia progenitor ages: 91T-like events, being at the smallest heights, originate from relatively younger progenitors with ages of about several 100 Myr, 91bg-like SNe, having the highest distribution, arise from progenitors with significantly older ages $\sim 10$ Gyr, and normal SNe Ia, which distributed between those of the two others, are from progenitors of about one up to $\sim 10$ Gyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is jet re-orientation the elusive trigger for star formation suppression in radio galaxies?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_jet_re-orientation_the_elusive_trigger_for_star_formation_suppression_in_radio_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/is_jet_re-orientation_the_elusive_trigger_for_star_formation_suppression_in_radio_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: David Garofalo
Jet re-orientation associated with the time evolution of radio quasars explains the formation of X-shaped radio galaxies and their preference for isolated environments. But since X-shaped radio galaxies are generally not found in dense environments (e.g. groups/clusters), the jet re-orientation phenomenon for radio galaxies in groups and clusters has been ignored. We take a closer look at the re-orientation of FRI jets with respect to FRII jets, and find that it may constitute the as-yet unidentified trigger for star formation suppression in radio galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphology driven evolution of barred galaxies in OMEGAWINGS Clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_driven_evolution_of_barred_galaxies_in_omegawings_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/morphology_driven_evolution_of_barred_galaxies_in_omegawings_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Amira A. Tawfeek
We present a study of barred galaxies in the cluster environment, exploiting a sample of galaxies drawn from the extended WIde-field Nearby Galaxy-cluster Survey (OmegaWINGS) that covers up to the outer regions of 32 local X-ray selected clusters. Barred galaxies are identified through a semi-automatic analysis of ellipticity and position angle profiles. We find, in agreement with previous studies, a strong co-dependence of the bar fraction with the galaxy stellar mass and morphological type, being maximum for massive late-type galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopy of High Redshift Galaxies with the ngVLA</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopy_of_high_redshift_galaxies_with_the_ngvla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/spectroscopy_of_high_redshift_galaxies_with_the_ngvla/</guid>
      <description>First author: C. L. Carilli
We present simulations of the capabilities of the ngVLA to image at $\sim 0.75$ kpc resolution ($0.085&amp;quot;$), molecular line emission from star forming disk galaxies at high redshift. The results are compared to the current capabilities of ALMA. ALMA can detect the integrated emission, and determine the velocity gradient and size across the brighter emission regions of the galaxy. The ngVLA is a factor $\sim 6$ more sensitive at the adopted spatial and velocity resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Galaxies and the Effect of Heterogeneous Enrichment from Primordial Stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_first_galaxies_and_the_effect_of_heterogeneous_enrichment_from_primordial_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_first_galaxies_and_the_effect_of_heterogeneous_enrichment_from_primordial_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: Azton I. Wells
We incorporate new scale-intelligent models of metal-enriched star formation (\starss) with surrogate models of primordial stellar feedback (\starnet) into the astrophysics simulation code \enzo to analyze the impact of heterogeneous metal enrichment on the first galaxies. Our study includes the earliest generations of stars and the protogalaxies ($10^6 \lesssim M_v/M_\odot \lesssim 10^8$) containing them. We compare results obtained with the new methods to two common paradigms of metallicity initial conditions in simulations: ignoring the metallicity initial condition and assuming a uniform metallicity floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spiral arms of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spiral_arms_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_spiral_arms_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: George Contopoulos
The most important theory of the spiral arms of galaxies is the density wave theory based on the Lin-Shu dispersion relation. However, the density waves move with the group velocity towards the inner Lindblad resonance and tend to disappear. Various mechanisms to replenish the spiral waves have been proposed. Nonlinear effects play an important role near the inner and outer Lindblad resonances and corotation. The orbits supporting the spiral arms are precessing ellipses in normal galaxies that extend up to the 4/1 resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ray Emission from the Interstellar and Circumgalactic Medium of Elliptical Galaxies based on MACER simulations</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_emission_from_the_interstellar_and_circumgalactic_medium_of_elliptical_galaxies_based_on_macer_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/x-ray_emission_from_the_interstellar_and_circumgalactic_medium_of_elliptical_galaxies_based_on_macer_simulations/</guid>
      <description>First author: Aditi Vijayan
Interstellar (ISM) and circumgalactic medium (CGM) around galaxies are linked to several physical processes that drive galaxy evolution. For example, the X-ray emission from the CGM gas around ellipticals has been linked to the AGN feedback occurring in the host. Upcoming telescopes such as HUBS, with ~ 1 eV resolution, can provide us with deep insights about the hot gas properties of such galaxies thus constrain these processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An empirical analysis of the dynamics of both individual galaxies and gravitational lensing in galaxy clusters without dark matter</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_empirical_analysis_of_the_dynamics_of_both_individual_galaxies_and_gravitational_lensing_in_galaxy_clusters_without_dark_matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/an_empirical_analysis_of_the_dynamics_of_both_individual_galaxies_and_gravitational_lensing_in_galaxy_clusters_without_dark_matter/</guid>
      <description>First author: G. Pascoli
The existence of the flat rotation curves of galaxies is still perplexing. The dark matter paradigm was proposed long ago to solve this conundrum; however, this proposal is still under debate. In this paper, we search for universal relationships solely involving the baryonic density that incorporate both galactic dynamics and gravitational lensing in galaxy clusters without requiring dark matter. If this type of formula exists, we show that it is possible that it can clearly indicate that dark matter is either perfectly tailored to baryonic matter or, from a more radical point of view, even perhaps useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A $γ$-ray emitting NLS1 galaxy SDSS J095909.51&#43;460014.3 identified by multiwavelength flares</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a__%CE%B3_-ray_emitting_nls1_galaxy_sdss_j095909.51&#43;460014.3_identified_by_multiwavelength_flares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a__%CE%B3_-ray_emitting_nls1_galaxy_sdss_j095909.51&#43;460014.3_identified_by_multiwavelength_flares/</guid>
      <description>First author: Yang-Ji Li
We report on the identification of a new $\gamma$-ray emitting narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxy ($\gamma$-NLS1), SDSS J095909.51+460014.3 (hereinafter J0959+4600, $z$ = 0.399), by establishing its association with a $\gamma$-ray source 4FGL 0959.6+4606, although its low-energy counterpart was suggested to be a radio galaxy 2MASX J09591976+4603515 (hereinafter J0959+4603). \emph{WISE} long-term light curves of these two sources reveal diverse infrared variability patterns. Violent infrared variations of J0959+4600 with an amplitude up to one order of magnitude has been detected, while variability is mild for the other one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fundamental plane of galaxy assembly and chemical enrichment within the first 700 Myr after the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_fundamental_plane_of_galaxy_assembly_and_chemical_enrichment_within_the_first_700_myr_after_the_big_bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_fundamental_plane_of_galaxy_assembly_and_chemical_enrichment_within_the_first_700_myr_after_the_big_bang/</guid>
      <description>First author: Kasper E. Heintz
Galaxies throughout the last 12 Gyr of cosmic time follow a single, universal fundamental plane that relates their star-formation rates (SFRs), stellar masses ($M_\star$) and chemical abundances. Deviation from these fundamental scaling relations would imply a drastic change in the processes that regulate galaxy evolution. Observations have hinted at the possibility that this relation may be broken in the very early universe. However, until recently, chemical abundances of galaxies could be only measured reliably as far back as redshift $z = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A possible tension between galaxy rotational velocity and observed physical properties</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_tension_between_galaxy_rotational_velocity_and_observed_physical_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_possible_tension_between_galaxy_rotational_velocity_and_observed_physical_properties/</guid>
      <description>First author: Lior Shamir
The discrepancy between the mass of galaxies and their rotational velocity is one of the most puzzling scientific phenomena. Despite over a century of research, this phenomenon is not fully understood. Common explanations include dark matter and MOND, among other theories. Here we report on another observation that shows tension between the physics of galaxy rotation and its rotational velocity. We compare the brightness of galaxies, and find that galaxies that spin in the same direction as the Milky Way have different brightness than galaxies that spin in the opposite direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of linearity of the ratio of dark matter to baryonic matter in galaxy clusters</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_linearity_of_the_ratio_of_dark_matter_to_baryonic_matter_in_galaxy_clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/a_test_of_linearity_of_the_ratio_of_dark_matter_to_baryonic_matter_in_galaxy_clusters/</guid>
      <description>First author: Varenya Upadhyaya
We search for a linearity in the ratio of dark matter to baryonic matter as a function of radius for galaxy clusters, motivated by a recent result by Lovas (arXiv:2206.11431), who has discovered such a linearity for a diverse suite of galaxies in the SPARC sample. For our analysis, we used a sample of 54 non-cool core clusters from the HIFLUGCS sample. We do not find any evidence for a linear trend in the aforementioned ratio as a function of radius for individual clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONCERTO: Simulating the CO, CII, and CI line emission of galaxies in a 117 $\rm deg^2$ field and the impact of field-to-field variance</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/concerto_simulating_the_co_cii_and_ci_line_emission_of_galaxies_in_a_117___rm_deg2__field_and_the_impact_of_field-to-field_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/concerto_simulating_the_co_cii_and_ci_line_emission_of_galaxies_in_a_117___rm_deg2__field_and_the_impact_of_field-to-field_variance/</guid>
      <description>First author: A. Gkogkou
In the submm regime, spectral line scans and line intensity mapping (LIM) are new promising probes for the cold gas content and star formation rate of galaxies across cosmic time. However, both of these two measurements suffer from field-to-field variance. We study the effect of field-to-field variance on the predicted CO and CII power spectra from future LIM experiments such as CONCERTO, as well as on the line luminosity functions (LFs) and the cosmic molecular gas mass density that are currently derived from spectral line scans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Sands: The Origin of Dusty, Star-forming Galaxies in the Epoch of Reionization</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_sands_the_origin_of_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_in_the_epoch_of_reionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmic_sands_the_origin_of_dusty_star-forming_galaxies_in_the_epoch_of_reionization/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sidney Lower
We present the Cosmic Sands suite of cosmological zoom-in simulations based on the Simba galaxy formation model in order to study the build up of the first massive and dusty galaxies in the early Universe. Residing in the most massive halos, we find that the compact proto-massive galaxies undergo nearly continuous mergers with smaller subhalos, boosting star formation rates (SFRs) and the build up of stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSMOS2020: The Galaxy Stellar Mass Function: On the assembly and star formation cessation of galaxies at $0.2\lt z \leq 7.5$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmos2020_the_galaxy_stellar_mass_function_on_the_assembly_and_star_formation_cessation_of_galaxies_at__0.2_lt_z__leq_7.5_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/cosmos2020_the_galaxy_stellar_mass_function_on_the_assembly_and_star_formation_cessation_of_galaxies_at__0.2_lt_z__leq_7.5_/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. R. Weaver
How galaxies form, assemble, and cease their star-formation is a central question within the modern landscape of galaxy evolution studies. These processes are indelibly imprinted on the galaxy stellar mass function (SMF). We present constraints on the shape and evolution of the SMF, the quiescent galaxy fraction, and the cosmic stellar mass density across 90% of the history of the Universe from $z=7.5\rightarrow0.2$ via the COSMOS survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and properties of the earliest galaxies with confirmed distances</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_and_properties_of_the_earliest_galaxies_with_confirmed_distances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/discovery_and_properties_of_the_earliest_galaxies_with_confirmed_distances/</guid>
      <description>First author: B. E. Robertson
Surveys with James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) have discovered candidate galaxies in the first 400 Myr of cosmic time. The properties of these distant galaxies provide initial conditions for understanding early galaxy formation and cosmic reionisation. Preliminary indications have suggested these candidate galaxies may be more massive and abundant than previously thought. However, without spectroscopic confirmation of their distances to constrain their intrinsic brightnesses, their inferred properties remain uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early-type Dwarf Galaxies in the Local Universe. Evidence of Ex-situ Growth</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early-type_dwarf_galaxies_in_the_local_universe._evidence_of_ex-situ_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/early-type_dwarf_galaxies_in_the_local_universe._evidence_of_ex-situ_growth/</guid>
      <description>First author: Sanjaya Paudel
We report the discovery of a rare early-type dwarf galaxy (dE), SDSS J125651.47+163024.2 (hereafter dE1256), possessing a tidal feature that was likely built up by accretion of an even smaller dwarf galaxy. dE1256 is located in a nearly isolated environment, at the outskirt of the Virgo cluster. A detailed morphological examination reveals that the accreted stellar population is mainly deposited in the outer part of dE1256, where the tidal tail is most prominent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emission-line properties of IllustrisTNG galaxies: from local diagnostic diagrams to high-redshift predictions for JWST</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emission-line_properties_of_illustristng_galaxies_from_local_diagnostic_diagrams_to_high-redshift_predictions_for_jwst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/emission-line_properties_of_illustristng_galaxies_from_local_diagnostic_diagrams_to_high-redshift_predictions_for_jwst/</guid>
      <description>First author: Michaela Hirschmann
We compute synthetic, rest-frame optical and ultraviolet (UV) emission-line properties of galaxy populations at redshifts from z$\approx$0 to z=8 in a full cosmological framework. We achieve this by coupling, in post-processing, the cosmological IllustrisTNG simulations with new-generation nebular-emission models, accounting for line emission from young stars, post-asymptotic-giant-branch (PAGB) stars, accreting black holes (BHs) and, for the first time, fast radiative shocks. The optical emission-line properties of simulated galaxies dominated by different ionizing sources are largely consistent with those expected from classical diagnostic diagrams and reflect the observed increase in OIII/H$\beta$ at fixed NII/H$\alpha$ and the evolution of the H$\alpha$, OIII$\lambda5007$ and OII$\lambda3727$ luminosity functions from z$\approx$0 to z$\sim$2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas-phase metallicity break radii of star-forming galaxies in IllustrisTNG</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas-phase_metallicity_break_radii_of_star-forming_galaxies_in_illustristng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/gas-phase_metallicity_break_radii_of_star-forming_galaxies_in_illustristng/</guid>
      <description>First author: Alex M. Garcia
We present radial gas-phase metallicity profiles, gradients, and break radii at redshift $z = 0 - 3$ from the TNG50-1 star-forming galaxy population. These metallicity profiles are characterized by an emphasis on identifying the steep inner gradient and flat outer gradient. From this, the break radius, $r_{\rm Break}$, is defined as the region where the transition occurs. We observe the break radius having a positive trend with mass that weakens with redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting ALMA non-detections of JWST super-early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpreting_alma_non-detections_of_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/interpreting_alma_non-detections_of_jwst_super-early_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Kohandel
Recent attempts to detect OIII 88$\mu$m emission from super-early ($z&amp;gt;10$) galaxy candidates observed by JWST have been unsuccessful. By using zoom-in simulations, we show that these galaxies are faint, and mostly fall below the local metal-poor $[OIII]-SFR$ relation as a result of their low ionization parameter, $U_{\rm ion}\lesssim 10^{-3}$. Such low $U_{\rm ion}$ values are found in galaxies that are in an early assembly stage, and whose stars are still embedded in high-density natal clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Narrow Line Region Dynamics in Nearby Active Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_narrow_line_region_dynamics_in_nearby_active_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/investigating_the_narrow_line_region_dynamics_in_nearby_active_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Beena Meena
We present dynamical models of the narrow line region (NLR) outflows in the nearby Seyfert galaxies Mrk 3, Mrk 78, NGC 1068, and NGC 4151 using observations from the Hubble Space Telescope and Apache Point Observatory. We employ long-slit spectroscopy to map the spatially-resolved outflow and rotational velocities of the ionized gas. We also perform surface brightness decompositions of host galaxy images to constrain the enclosed stellar mass distributions as functions of distance from the supermassive black holes (SMBHs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping dust attenuation and the 2175 Å bump at kpc scales in nearby galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_dust_attenuation_and_the_2175_%C3%A5_bump_at_kpc_scales_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/mapping_dust_attenuation_and_the_2175_%C3%A5_bump_at_kpc_scales_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Shuang Zhou
We develop a novel approach to measure dust attenuation properties of galaxies,including the dust opacity and shape of the attenuation curve in both optical and NUV, as well as the strength of the 2175{\AA} absorption feature. From an observed spectrum the method uses a model-independent approach to derive a relative attenuation curve.The absolute amplitude is then calibrated with the NIR photometry. The dust-corrected spectrum is fitted with stellar population models to derive the dust-free model spectrum covering the whole wavelength range from NUV to NIR and is compared with the observed SED/spectrum to determine dust attenuation properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-local contribution from small scales in galaxy-galaxy lensing: Comparison of mitigation schemes</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-local_contribution_from_small_scales_in_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_comparison_of_mitigation_schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/non-local_contribution_from_small_scales_in_galaxy-galaxy_lensing_comparison_of_mitigation_schemes/</guid>
      <description>First author: J. Prat
Recent cosmological analyses with large-scale structure and weak lensing measurements, usually referred to as 3$\times$2pt, had to discard a lot of signal-to-noise from small scales due to our inability to precisely model non-linearities and baryonic effects. Galaxy-galaxy lensing, or the position-shear correlation between lens and source galaxies, is one of the three two-point correlation functions that are included in such analyses, usually estimated with the mean tangential shear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the application of dimensionality reduction and clustering algorithms for the classification of kinematic morphologies of galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_application_of_dimensionality_reduction_and_clustering_algorithms_for_the_classification_of_kinematic_morphologies_of_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_application_of_dimensionality_reduction_and_clustering_algorithms_for_the_classification_of_kinematic_morphologies_of_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. S. Rosito
The morphological classification of galaxies is considered a relevant issue and can be approached from different points of view. The increasing growth in the size and accuracy of astronomical data sets brings with it the need for the use of automatic methods to perform these classifications. The aim of this work is to propose and evaluate a method for automatic unsupervised classification of kinematic morphologies of galaxies that yields a meaningful clustering and captures the variations of the fundamental properties of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the bright-end of the UV luminosity functions of galaxies at $z \sim 0.6-1.2$</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_bright-end_of_the_uv_luminosity_functions_of_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.6-1.2_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/on_the_bright-end_of_the_uv_luminosity_functions_of_galaxies_at__z__sim_0.6-1.2_/</guid>
      <description>First author: M. Sharma
We derive the Ultra-Violet (UV) luminosity function (LF) of star forming galaxies falling in the redshift range $z = 0.6 - 1.2$, in the rest-frame far-UV (1500 {\AA}) wavelength. For this work we are in particular interested in the bright end of the UV LF in this redshift range. The data from \textit{XMM-Newton} Optical Monitor (XMM-OM), near-ultraviolet (1600-4000 {\AA}) observations over 1.5 deg\textsuperscript{2} of the COSMOS field are employed for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peekaboo: the extremely metal poor dwarf galaxy HIPASS J1131-31</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peekaboo_the_extremely_metal_poor_dwarf_galaxy_hipass_j1131-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/peekaboo_the_extremely_metal_poor_dwarf_galaxy_hipass_j1131-31/</guid>
      <description>First author: I. D. Karachentsev
The dwarf irregular galaxy HIPASS J1131-31 was discovered as a source of HI emission at low redshift in such close proximity of a bright star that we call it Peekaboo. The galaxy resolves into stars in images with Hubble Space Telescope, leading to a distance estimate of 6.8+-0.7 Mpc. Spectral optical observations with the Southern African Large Telescope reveal HIPASS J1131-31 to be one of the most extremely metal-poor galaxies known with the gas-phase oxygen abundance 12+log(O/H) = 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric and Structural Parameters of Newly Discovered Nuclear Star Clusters in Local Volume Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_structural_parameters_of_newly_discovered_nuclear_star_clusters_in_local_volume_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_and_structural_parameters_of_newly_discovered_nuclear_star_clusters_in_local_volume_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Nils Hoyer
We use high-resolution Hubble Space Telescope imaging data of dwarf galaxies in the Local Volume ($\lesssim 11$ Mpc) to parameterise 19 newly discovered nuclear star clusters (NSCs). Most of the clusters have stellar masses of $M_{\star}^{nsc} \lesssim 10^6$ M${\odot}$ and compare to Galactic globular clusters in terms of ellipticity, effective radius, stellar mass, and surface density. The clusters are modelled with a S&#39;ersic profile and their surface brightness evaluated at the effective radius reveals a tight positive correlation to the host galaxy stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric Mass Estimation and the Stellar Mass-Halo Mass Relation for Low Mass Galaxies</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_mass_estimation_and_the_stellar_mass-halo_mass_relation_for_low_mass_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/photometric_mass_estimation_and_the_stellar_mass-halo_mass_relation_for_low_mass_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Dennis Zaritsky
We present a photometric halo mass estimation technique for local galaxies that enables us to establish the stellar mass-halo mass (SMHM) relation down to stellar masses of 10$^5$ M$\odot$. We find no detectable differences among the SMHM relations of four local galaxy clusters or between the cluster and field relations and we find agreement with extrapolations of previous SMHM relations derived using abundance matching approaches. We fit a power law to our empirical SMHM relation and find that for adopted NFW dark matter profiles and for M$* &amp;lt; 10^9$ M$\odot$, the halo mass is M$h = 10^{10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDSS-IV MaNGA: How Galaxy Interactions Influence Active Galactic Nuclei</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss-iv_manga_how_galaxy_interactions_influence_active_galactic_nuclei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/sdss-iv_manga_how_galaxy_interactions_influence_active_galactic_nuclei/</guid>
      <description>First author: Joshua L. Steffen
We present a comparative study of active galactic nuclei (AGN) between galaxy pairs and isolated galaxies with the final data release of the MaNGA integral field spectroscopic survey. We build a sample of 391 kinematic galaxy pairs within the footprint of the survey and select AGN using the survey&amp;rsquo;s spectra. We use the comoving volume densities of the AGN samples to quantify the effects that tidal interactions have on the triggering of nuclear accretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of the structure and kinematics of the Galaxy according to VLBI astrometry of masers and radio stars</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_the_structure_and_kinematics_of_the_galaxy_according_to_vlbi_astrometry_of_masers_and_radio_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/study_of_the_structure_and_kinematics_of_the_galaxy_according_to_vlbi_astrometry_of_masers_and_radio_stars/</guid>
      <description>First author: V. V. Bobylev
In recent years, radio interferometric observations have achieved high accuracy in determining the absolute values of trigonometric parallaxes and proper motions of maser radiation sources and radio stars. The error in determining the trigonometric parallaxes of these objects averages about 10 microarcseconds, which allows us to confidently study the geometric and kinematic properties of the distribution of stars located at great distances from the Sun, up to the center of the Galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synergy between CSST galaxy survey and gravitational-wave observation: Inferring the Hubble constant from dark standard sirens</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synergy_between_csst_galaxy_survey_and_gravitational-wave_observation_inferring_the_hubble_constant_from_dark_standard_sirens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/synergy_between_csst_galaxy_survey_and_gravitational-wave_observation_inferring_the_hubble_constant_from_dark_standard_sirens/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ji-Yu Song
Gravitational waves (GWs) from compact binary coalescences encode the absolute luminosity distances of GW sources. Once the redshifts of GW sources are known, one can use the distance-redshift relation to constrain cosmological parameters. One way to obtain the redshifts is to localize GW sources by GW observations and then use galaxy catalogs to determine redshifts from a statistical analysis of redshift information of the potential host galaxies, and such GW data are commonly referred to as dark sirens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Measuring Physical Parameters in Galaxies: A Critical Assessment of Spectral Energy Distribution Fitting Techniques</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_art_of_measuring_physical_parameters_in_galaxies_a_critical_assessment_of_spectral_energy_distribution_fitting_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_art_of_measuring_physical_parameters_in_galaxies_a_critical_assessment_of_spectral_energy_distribution_fitting_techniques/</guid>
      <description>First author: Camilla Pacifici
The study of galaxy evolution hinges on our ability to interpret multi-wavelength galaxy observations in terms of their physical properties. To do this, we rely on spectral energy distribution (SED) models which allow us to infer physical parameters from spectrophotometric data. In recent years, thanks to the wide and deep multi-waveband galaxy surveys, the volume of high quality data have significantly increased. Alongside the increased data, algorithms performing SED fitting have improved, including better modeling prescriptions, newer templates, and more extensive sampling in wavelength space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The molecular gas kinematics in the host galaxy of non-repeating FRB 180924B</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_molecular_gas_kinematics_in_the_host_galaxy_of_non-repeating_frb_180924b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_molecular_gas_kinematics_in_the_host_galaxy_of_non-repeating_frb_180924b/</guid>
      <description>First author: Tzu-Yin Hsu
Fast radio bursts (FRBs) are millisecond-duration transients with large dispersion measures. The origin of FRBs is still mysterious. One of the methods to comprehend FRB origin is to probe the physical environments of FRB host galaxies. Mapping molecular-gas kinematics in FRB host galaxies is critical because it results in star formation that is likely connected to the birth of FRB progenitors. However, most previous works of FRB host galaxies have focused on its stellar component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of double-peak emission-line galaxies: rotating discs, bars or galaxy mergers?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_double-peak_emission-line_galaxies_rotating_discs_bars_or_galaxy_mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_origin_of_double-peak_emission-line_galaxies_rotating_discs_bars_or_galaxy_mergers/</guid>
      <description>First author: Daniel Maschmann
Emission lines with a double-peak (DP) shape, detected in the centre of galaxies, have been extensively used in the past to identify peculiar kinematics such as dual active galactic nuclei, outflows or mergers. From a large DP galaxy sample, a connection to minor merger galaxies with ongoing star formation was suggested. To gain a better understanding of different mechanisms creating a DP signature, we here explore synthetic SDSS spectroscopic observations computed from disc models and simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PHANGS-JWST Treasury Survey: Star Formation, Feedback, and Dust Physics at High Angular resolution in Nearby GalaxieS</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_phangs-jwst_treasury_survey_star_formation_feedback_and_dust_physics_at_high_angular_resolution_in_nearby_galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_phangs-jwst_treasury_survey_star_formation_feedback_and_dust_physics_at_high_angular_resolution_in_nearby_galaxies/</guid>
      <description>First author: Janice C. Lee
The PHANGS collaboration has been building a reference dataset for the multi-scale, multi-phase study of star formation and the interstellar medium in nearby galaxies. With the successful launch and commissioning of JWST, we can now obtain high-resolution infrared imaging to probe the youngest stellar populations and dust emission on the scales of star clusters and molecular clouds ($\sim$5-50 pc). In Cycle 1, PHANGS is conducting an 8-band imaging survey from 2-21$\mu$m of 19 nearby spiral galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure and composition of multiphase galactic winds in a Large Magellanic Cloud mass simulated galaxy</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_structure_and_composition_of_multiphase_galactic_winds_in_a_large_magellanic_cloud_mass_simulated_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/the_structure_and_composition_of_multiphase_galactic_winds_in_a_large_magellanic_cloud_mass_simulated_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>First author: Ulrich P. Steinwandel
We present the first results from a high resolution simulation with a focus on galactic wind driving for an isolated galaxy with a halo mass of $\sim 10^{11}$ M${\odot}$ (similar to the Large Magellanic Cloud) and a total gas mass of $\sim 6 \times 10^{8}$ M${\odot}$, resulting in $\sim 10^{8}$ gas cells at $\sim 4$ M${\odot}$ mass resolution. We adopt a resolved stellar feedback model with non-equilibrium cooling and heating, including photoelectric heating and photo-ionizing radiation, as well as supernovae (SNe), coupled to the second order meshless finite mass (MFM) method for hydrodynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THESAN-HR: How does reionization impact early galaxy evolution?</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thesan-hr_how_does_reionization_impact_early_galaxy_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/thesan-hr_how_does_reionization_impact_early_galaxy_evolution/</guid>
      <description>First author: Josh Borrow
Early galaxies were the radiation source for reionization, with the photoheating feedback from the reionization process expected to reduce the efficiency of star formation in low mass haloes. Hence, to fully understand reionization and galaxy formation, we must study their impact on each other. The THESAN project has so far aimed to study the impact of galaxy formation physics on reionization, but here we present the new THESAN simulations with a factor 50 higher resolution ($m_{\rm b} \approx 10^4$~M$\odot$) that aim to self-consistently study the back-reaction of reionization on galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultraviolet imaging observations of three jellyfish galaxies: Star formation suppression in the centre and ongoing star formation in stripped tails</title>
      <link>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ultraviolet_imaging_observations_of_three_jellyfish_galaxies_star_formation_suppression_in_the_centre_and_ongoing_star_formation_in_stripped_tails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nebula0.github.io/article/ultraviolet_imaging_observations_of_three_jellyfish_galaxies_star_formation_suppression_in_the_centre_and_ongoing_star_formation_in_stripped_tails/</guid>
      <description>First author: Koshy George
Spiral galaxies undergo strong ram-pressure effects when they fall into the galaxy cluster potential. As a consequence, their gas is stripped to form extended tails within which star formation can happen, giving them the typical jellyfish appearance. The ultraviolet imaging observations of jellyfish galaxies provide an opportunity to understand ongoing star formation in the stripped tails. We report the ultraviolet observations of the jellyfish galaxies JW39, JO60, JO194 and compare with observations in optical continuum and $\mathrm{H}{\alpha}$.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
